<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comments on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/comments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comments on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/comments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the backseat of a taxi, a simple chat took a jarring turn, plunging me into a story that is all too common yet often goes untold. My goal was straightforward: to land a full-time role at a publishing house. However, what unfolded was an unexpected confrontation with racial and sexist prejudices — an incident that, though personal, reflects a broader issue pervasive in our workspaces and media today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journey reached a pivotal moment at the end-of-year company dinner party, a gathering that marked the culmination of a challenging yet rewarding internship. Having broached the subject of future prospects with my immediate male supervisor during training and discussed my aspirations with colleagues, I felt cautiously optimistic. However, the evening took an unforeseen turn on the ride home, sharing a taxi with a female supervisor who was less often seen during office hours. Her reaction to my shared ambitions was not of encouragement or guidance but one of anger and insinuation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Selective Outrage of the Tories: HS2 and Beyond</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:14:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rishi Sunak&amp;rsquo;s decision to axe the Birmingham to Manchester segment, packaged as a pragmatic financial choice, has ruffled feathers, not least those of former prime ministers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/David_Cameron/status/1709579002220867922&#34;&gt;David Cameron&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiktok.com/@dailymailuk/video/7284266548674563361&#34;&gt;Boris Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. Their collective critique, given their individual and joint legacies, is nothing short of ironic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunak, in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2023/10/4/uk-tory-conference-live-news-rishi-sunak-to-address-hs2-controversy&#34;&gt;address to the Conservative party&amp;rsquo;s annual rally&lt;/a&gt;, positioned himself as a radical reformer. His vision of axing HS2&amp;rsquo;s northern leg, introducing a broader Advanced British Standard to replace A-levels, and incrementally banning smoking are audacious moves. Yet, one cannot help but see these as emblematic of the Tories&amp;rsquo; recurring approach: prioritising headline-grabbing policies while seemingly neglecting dire issues such as child poverty, housing and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Pretender: Boris Johnson&#39;s Deceptive Finale to his Controversial Tenure</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Behold the curious tale of Boris Johnson, a leader whose exit from the political limelight has been less of a dignified adieu and more of a truculent retreat. Clad in the armour of self-pity, Johnson seems to have recast himself as a tragic hero, wronged by an ‘ungrateful nation’. However, as the curtains close, the audience sees through the artifice, observing a man who, in the throes of responsibility, chose subterfuge over substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s views on strikes in England: Laying the blame where it should be</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government&amp;rsquo;s treatment of workers and Unions asking for a fair pay rise during a cost of living crisis has been shameful. Nurses, ambulance drivers, paramedics, and other frontline workers have been demonised and blamed for the country&amp;rsquo;s economic woes, despite their tireless efforts to keep the country running during a global crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, those who have actually caused the economic damage – such as the former prime minister who blew a £30 billion hole in the economy overnight, the shambolic execution of Brexit that is estimated to have cost the country over £40 billion, the Tory government’s botched test and trace programme which costed £37 billion, their wasteful procurement of PPE resulting in £8.7 billion being wasted and ending up in the pockets of Tory donors and Richie Sunak’s decision to spend £11 billion by overpaying interest on UK debt – are allowed to escape accountability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is citizen journalism and there is The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world that moves at a dizzying speed, UN-aligned and The Gordian have stayed true to their values, fighting for a better UN and bringing our readers the insights and information they need to stay informed and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the editor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian magazine,&lt;/a&gt; I reflect upon the past year with both gratitude and concern. On the one hand, I am grateful for the dedication and hard work of our team, whose members have produced high-quality, fact-based, impactful journalism that has provided clarity and imagination in an unprecedented year. On the other hand, I am concerned about the numerous challenges and crises that have impacted our world in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let technology become a bane for future generations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology helps us improve our lives and make things easier. However, there are two sides to everything. Undoubtedly, for instance, Artificial Intelligence will grow further, but I am sure it has both a positive and a negative impact on the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me be honest, when technology just started to enter our lives in the early 90’s in India I was super thrilled with it. I was fascinated with the pagers and then the mobiles in the late 90’s and I liked the fact that at the press of a button I could reach my near and dear ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Glass Ceiling: Women in India are not Behind</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:47:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glass-ceiling-effect-in-the-west&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Ceiling Effect in the West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th century, women in other parts of the industrialised world had also experienced what is popularly known as the &amp;lsquo;glass ceiling&amp;rsquo; phenomenon, which meant that women found they could only rise to a certain level in corporations and no further. This raises two immediate questions. What were the reasons that could have led to such a thought? And, were men keeping women away from the top?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s view on the climate protests: the days of self-serving governments are over</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:22:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;were-at-war-with-nature-if-we-win-were-lost-hubert-reeves&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re at war with nature. If we win, we&amp;rsquo;re lost&amp;rdquo; Hubert Reeves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the level of CO2 emissions reach their highest level in 10 million years, children and adults,  from an estimated of 185 countries, unite across continents and time-zones to demonstrate against politicians’ incompetence in dealing with this extraordinary challenge of our time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These protests come at a time when the Amazon forests are being burnt to ashes, a “biological annihilation” of wildlife is in sight and the consequences of melting ice in Greenland is about to give birth to a whole new group of internationally displaced people: climate refugees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
