<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capitalism on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/capitalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capitalism on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 11:08:48 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/capitalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Growth Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 11:08:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>AytenAydin12</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-della-crescita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcending-simplistic-assumptions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transcending simplistic assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society is faced with a profound dilemma. To reject growth is to risk economic and social collapse. To pursue it relentlessly is to endanger the ecosystems on which we depend for long term survival. This delusional strategy has reached its limits. Simplistic assumptions that capitalism’s propensity for efficiency will stabilise the climate and solve the problems of resource scarcity are almost literally bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/The-growth-dilemma-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP is an impostor, so why are we still using it to measure happiness?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-PIL-non-significa-nulla-di-concreto-quindi-perche-lo-utilizziamo-ancora-per-misurare-la-felicita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDP is not a suitable measurement for happiness or welfare. It sucks. Assessing the economy using GDP is destroying our planet. The global community and the United Nation’s sustainable development solutions network (SDSN) need to find other suitable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, the SDSN, an initiative operating under the auspices of the United Nations, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/happiness-trust-and-deaths-under-covid-19/&#34;&gt;publishing a yearly report&lt;/a&gt; on how happy the world is. Embarking upon this fundamentally subjective and unquantifiable quest is no easy task and although the SDSN has significantly improved its methods to measure happiness throughout the years, it still has a long way to go before becoming perfect. This year the report used a host of different criteria to grade the happiness of a nation, these included: gross domestic product per capita (GDP), social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make your own life choices, generosity of the general population and perceptions of internal and external corruption levels. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/GDP-is-an-imposto-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Doughnut Economy: &#34;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 10:40:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/Doughnut-Economy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
