<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United Kingdom on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/united-kingdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United Kingdom on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/united-kingdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is UK&#39;s North Sea Drilling Plan a Sustainable Solution? An Impact Assessment Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-findings&#34;&gt;Key findings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK&amp;rsquo;s proposed drilling plan has minimal immediate impact on energy security, offering only short-term reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With sustainable energy advancements, extensive reliance on fossil fuels is becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan&amp;rsquo;s short-term financial benefits are economically short-sighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investing in a net-zero economy and green jobs is more beneficial for long-term economic growth and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drilling plan could harm climate commitments and marine biodiversity in the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shift to renewable energy and green bond financing is advised, echoing global body recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the backseat of a taxi, a simple chat took a jarring turn, plunging me into a story that is all too common yet often goes untold. My goal was straightforward: to land a full-time role at a publishing house. However, what unfolded was an unexpected confrontation with racial and sexist prejudices — an incident that, though personal, reflects a broader issue pervasive in our workspaces and media today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journey reached a pivotal moment at the end-of-year company dinner party, a gathering that marked the culmination of a challenging yet rewarding internship. Having broached the subject of future prospects with my immediate male supervisor during training and discussed my aspirations with colleagues, I felt cautiously optimistic. However, the evening took an unforeseen turn on the ride home, sharing a taxi with a female supervisor who was less often seen during office hours. Her reaction to my shared ambitions was not of encouragement or guidance but one of anger and insinuation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Selective Outrage of the Tories: HS2 and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:14:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rishi Sunak&amp;rsquo;s decision to axe the Birmingham to Manchester segment, packaged as a pragmatic financial choice, has ruffled feathers, not least those of former prime ministers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/David_Cameron/status/1709579002220867922&#34;&gt;David Cameron&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiktok.com/@dailymailuk/video/7284266548674563361&#34;&gt;Boris Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. Their collective critique, given their individual and joint legacies, is nothing short of ironic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunak, in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2023/10/4/uk-tory-conference-live-news-rishi-sunak-to-address-hs2-controversy&#34;&gt;address to the Conservative party&amp;rsquo;s annual rally&lt;/a&gt;, positioned himself as a radical reformer. His vision of axing HS2&amp;rsquo;s northern leg, introducing a broader Advanced British Standard to replace A-levels, and incrementally banning smoking are audacious moves. Yet, one cannot help but see these as emblematic of the Tories&amp;rsquo; recurring approach: prioritising headline-grabbing policies while seemingly neglecting dire issues such as child poverty, housing and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Pretender: Boris Johnson&#39;s Deceptive Finale to his Controversial Tenure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Behold the curious tale of Boris Johnson, a leader whose exit from the political limelight has been less of a dignified adieu and more of a truculent retreat. Clad in the armour of self-pity, Johnson seems to have recast himself as a tragic hero, wronged by an ‘ungrateful nation’. However, as the curtains close, the audience sees through the artifice, observing a man who, in the throes of responsibility, chose subterfuge over substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Drama in the Age of Self-Discovery: Significant Plays and Key Themes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In last month’s issue we surveyed the two literary genres of poetry and the novel at the turn of the 20th century which we defined as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/&#34;&gt;an Age of Self-Discovery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw how the tide began to change during the last two decades of Queen Victoria’s reign, when some writers sought a newer and fresher approach to literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then surveyed the literature that developed with the onset of the First World War, which had triggered in man the awareness to see life as an abyss of incessant self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An end to the “Fairytales of Eternal Economic Growth”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:35:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 27th February, a British appeals court ruled that a planned expansion of Heathrow airport is unconstitutional because the planning process was not in accordance with the government&amp;rsquo;s own climate policies set out in the Paris Agreement. Lords Justice Lindblom, Singh and Haddon-Cave ruled that when setting out their support for the measures in their National Policy Statement (NPS), the government did not take adequate account of its contribution to the Paris Agreement on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
