<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sculpting Change: Two Women Reshaping Iran&#39;s Pottery Scene</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</guid>
      <description>Emerging from the vibrant tapestry of Iranian culture, Samira Ghafori and Anahita Ahmadi shape clay into powerful narratives of resilience and personal evolution.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Sculpting-Change-Two-Women-Reshaping-Irans-Pottery-Scene.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Forest Boundaries: Sunil Pariyar on the Dalit Struggle and DANAR&#39;s Impact in Nepal</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Alexander Stoney</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</guid>
      <description>Sunil Kumar Pariyar talks about DANAR and the struggles and triumphs of the Dalit community as they strive to reclaim their rightful place in Nepal’s natural resource management.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Sunil-Pariyar-DANAR.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Elvira_Ineza</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>Personal interviews with Kevin, an immigrant from Rwanda, and a former employee of the International Rescue Committee, uncover the complex realities of immigration in America</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/The-Journey-of-Immigrants-in-America-Experiences-from-Within.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How CalAnimals is making a difference for animals in California</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Victoria-Davila</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people who love their companion animals, it may be surprising how so many animals wind up in shelters unclaimed, says Jill Tucker, CEO of California Animal Welfare Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucker, who originally started her career in software, shifted into the animal sector in 2003, where she moved from California to Vermont to run an animal humane society organisation. From starting as a foster parent to making her way as the president of that same organisation, Tucker found herself as a leader in protecting animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Californias-Animal-Welfare-Association.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mridul Wadhwa on Conversion Therapy and Edinburgh Rape Crisis Centre</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Victoria-Davila</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</guid>
      <description>Mridul Wadhwa, CEO of the Edinburgh Rape Crisis Centre, spoke with UN-aligned about her journey into the gender-based violence sector and ways to tackle conversion practices and promote LGBTQ+ rights worldwide.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Mridul-Wadhwa.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;All of the anger poured out of me like a volcano and I saw red&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School. This is the third and final part of Noor&#39;s story.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/All-of-the-anger-poured-out-of-me-like-a-volcano-and-I-saw-red-%E2%80%94-My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England-Part-3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“No, I wasn’t somebody just to be picked on”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:24:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of Noor’s story. Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I couldn&#39;t understand a word of it, but I loved choir singing”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:18:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</guid>
      <description>Noor shares her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, she didn’t speak a word of English and was thrust into the British Primary School education system.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I still have hope that we will all return to our warm home and beautiful city” — Interview with Syrian refugee, Somaya</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</guid>
      <description>In another piece from our series &#34;Diaries from Refugee Camps&#34;, Atika Harba talks to the Somaya, a mother of three and a refugee inside a Lebanese refugee camp. Are you a refugee and would like to share your story inside this series? Please contact us.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/nterview-with-Syrian-refugee-Somaya.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Standing up for the planet&#39;: An interview with climate activist Partho Chatterjee</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:46:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Partho Pratim Chatterjee, a citizen of India and a member of UN-aligned. I hail from the mineral rich eastern state of Jharkhand. I am an engineer by profession and working in the capacity of Co-Founder and Technical Advisor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adityabioinnovation.in/&#34;&gt;Aditya Bioinnovation&lt;/a&gt; Private Limited, Nagpur, India. I have a keen penchant for eco-friendly technologies which include clean nanofluids, clean energy and clean transportation. My hobbies include penning poems and biodiversity exploration. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Partho-interview.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>During her internship with UN-aligned, Atika Harba was asked to write about life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Atika, who at the time of publishing, was a 17-year-old refugee, wrote several articles and diaries that gives readers a glimpse inside the difficult life of inside the refugee camp.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Every-day-my-heart-squeezes-with-sadness-and-painAn-Interview-with-Amna-a-Syrian-refugee-in-Lebanons-Arsal-Camp.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayesha Kajee Talks to UN-aligned About Her Poem &#34;Silence&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The second place was awarded to Ayesha Kajee for her poem Silence. The following interview was conducted on the 2nd of November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the interview here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Read Ayesha&amp;rsquo;s poem “Silence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Ayesha-Kajee-interview.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Author Dean Gessie Talks to UN-aligned about his “Terra Australis Incognita”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:40:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The first place was awarded to Dean Gessie for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”. The following interview was conducted on the 31st of October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Read Dean&amp;rsquo;s poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch our interview with Dean Gessie here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Dean-Gessie-interview.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“A preventable tragedy”: How dementia became the catalyst that eroded Noor’s family</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine visiting your mother or father in their home. When you arrive, you discover that they are in distress in front of the television. They look at you with fear in their eyes; you look at them and then to the ordinary television screen, not understanding the problem. Your mother or father imagines that the people on the television are home intruders, and they ask you how those people got into the house. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/A-story-of-Dementia_-How-a-vivacious-and-vibrant-lady-fell-victim-to-her-own-lack-of-planning.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographer Anwar Sadat: “If you listen, people are always willing to talk”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:28:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 15th of February 2021, the 2020 UN-aligned photo competition winner, Anwar Sadat, tells us about the story behind his prize-winning photos and his love for photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-22Se-ascolti-le-persone-sono-sempre-disponibili-a-parlare22-Una-conversazione-con-il-fotografo-Anwar-Sadat.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;could-you-tell-us-a-bit-about-yourself-and-your-love-for-photography&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could you tell us a bit about yourself and your love for photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my name is Anwar Sadat and I am a photographer based in Nairobi Kenya. My focus in photography is documentary, photojournalism, street reportage and portraiture. I often tell stories of the buzzing streets of Nairobi and my community that often go unseen and unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/IMG_0228-copy-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Boy who Produces Golden Eggs – an interview with the 11 year old Andrea Piccinelli</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Il-ragazzo-che-produce-uova-doro.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Italian version of this interview can be read here.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;La versione originale italiana di questa intervista può essere letta qui.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview with UN-aligned coordinator, Adrian Liberto, the 11 year old &lt;strong&gt;Andrea Piccinelli&lt;/strong&gt; shares his story about how he developed a love and friendship with his chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some are literally golden in as much as they have a golden hue, but they are all golden in the sense that they are entirely cruelty free. Andrea Piccinelli lives in Magliano de Marsi, a small town in the Abruzzi, Italy, at the foot of the Monte Velino. His passion is looking after his chickens. His love for the animals and his determination are so strong that you would think that these traits must be in his genes. Maybe they are, a distant relative was a Franciscan Friar Pamfilo of Magliano, famous for compassion and for his part in founding &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sbu.edu/&#34;&gt;St. Bonaventure University&lt;/a&gt; in New York. What is certain, is that this young lad has come up with his own exit strategy for intensive chicken farming. His enterprise is also a wakeup call. What will the future be for all these farm animals we have enthralled for millennia? This is something that without doubt requires considerably more thought, especially now that intensive farming may be meeting its nemesis thanks to growing public awareness into the unethical practices of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Cover.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I want UN-aligned to be a place where people can come together without being judged&#34;: Interview with Katharina Wüstnienhaus</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This interview is part of an ongoing series about our members and how they wish to take charge of UN-aligned and use it as a beacon for hope and change. If you wish to participate in these interviews, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question: Tell us a little about yourself Katha. What is your background? Where do you live? What are some of your hobbies and things you are passionate about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am from the westernmost part of Germany, only a bike ride away from the Netherlands. I have recently quitted my job in Berlin because I wanted to travel; unfortunately, this just happened when the Covid-19 pandemic hit us, so I decided to move back home and stay here instead. I enjoy music, being surrounded by nature, travelling and making friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/6.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Traumatic Experience with Postpartum - An interview with Rahima El Harrak</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rahimaelharrak</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The period soon after childbirth poses substantial health risks for both mother and new-born infant. Yet the postpartum and postnatal period receives less attention from health care providers than pregnancy and childbirth. Models of postpartum and postnatal care have changed little since first developed a century ago. The World Health Organization (WHO) is in the process of revising and updating its guidance on postpartum and postnatal care delivered by skilled providers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Social-Media-post-2-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
