<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sculpting Change: Two Women Reshaping Iran&#39;s Pottery Scene</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whirling hum of the spinning wheel, the rhythm of skilled hands modelling shapeless clay and the mesmerising transformation in the kiln: the world of pottery is one of patience, resilience and creativity. And within this sphere in Iran, two exceptional women, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/samirghafori/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Samira Ghafori&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/anna_clayart/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Anahita Ahmadi,&lt;/a&gt; are shaping more than just clay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samira, an artist who started young, had her destiny intertwined with pottery before she even knew it. Her early fascination with the craft was born out of playful experimentation that evolved into a lifelong commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Forest Boundaries: Sunil Pariyar on the Dalit Struggle and DANAR&#39;s Impact in Nepal</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the northern region of the Indian subcontinent, at the base of the Himalayan Mountains, lies the country of Nepal. A place rich in cultural and natural diversity, Nepal&amp;rsquo;s vibrant history intertwines with the lives of its Dalit citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dalit communities in South Asian countries like India and Nepal endure persistent marginalisation, exclusion and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/pages/article/indias-untouchables-face-violence-discrimination&#34;&gt;human rights violations&lt;/a&gt;. They live in constant apprehension of public humiliation, assault and abuse, with upper-caste groups frequently using violence as a means to maintain societal hierarchies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years immigration has been a controversial subject in the US. Some Americans call for harsher policies against immigration, others for a revision of immigration policies to allow for easier processing and more assistance to refugees. All in all, one after the other, governments have tried to revise these policies in hopes of appeasing the American population, but neither has been able to fully address this issue in a manner favourable to all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How CalAnimals is making a difference for animals in California</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people who love their companion animals, it may be surprising how so many animals wind up in shelters unclaimed, says Jill Tucker, CEO of California Animal Welfare Association&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tucker, who originally started her career in software, shifted into the animal sector in 2003, where she moved from California to Vermont to run an animal humane society organisation. From starting as a foster parent to making her way as the president of that same organisation, Tucker found herself as a leader in protecting animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mridul Wadhwa on Conversion Therapy and Edinburgh Rape Crisis Centre</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mridul Wadhwa, and I am originally from India, and I’ve lived in Scotland since 2004. I started working in the violence against women or gender-based violence sector in 2005. With a small break in between, I’ve worked in that sector since then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I primarily worked with minority ethnic women, immigrant women, and women from communities of colour living in Scotland. For most of that time, my job was to work with the white majority community, primarily service providers, to help them develop an understanding of what kind of barriers minority ethnic women in Scotland face when experiencing and leaving abusive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;All of the anger poured out of me like a volcano and I saw red&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the third and final part of Noor&amp;rsquo;s story &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/at-school-in-70s-england/&#34;&gt;for this feature&lt;/a&gt;. Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have very vivid memories of 1977 specifically because it was the Queen&amp;rsquo;s Jubilee. There were huge street parties and a pure celebratory atmosphere on that day. By this time, my mum was on a road trip to Morocco and I&amp;rsquo;d stayed behind in England with my older sister.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“No, I wasn’t somebody just to be picked on”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:24:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1976 we moved to Poplar in London. One thing I remember is a Saturday market full of hustle and bustle, with working class people grabbing bargains under a wave of brightly coloured merchandise. We had moved into a four bedroomed Maisonette, not far from our new secondary school. We lived amongst a majority white community, but there was one black family who befriended my sister and I.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was February and incredibly cold. I remember walking to my new school that day with dread and fear twisting inside me. All that I could do was anticipate the worst things that could happen to me at the new school. The thought of having to face 30 children, not understanding much English, and trying to make sense of the school timetable, was nauseating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I couldn&#39;t understand a word of it, but I loved choir singing”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:18:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;4th-october-1974&#34;&gt;4th October 1974&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in England, my first memory was walking through Heathrow Airport with my three sisters and one brother. I am the middle child of seven children, two of my siblings had already arrived in England before us. My mother was holding two of our hands, and the air hostesses were holding the rest of our little hands. My brother didn’t need his hand to be held and walked behind us as we approached Passport Control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I still have hope that we will all return to our warm home and beautiful city” — Interview with Syrian refugee, Somaya</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-your-life-and-how-you-got-here&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your life and how you got here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am Somaya, a mother of three children, two daughters and a son. At the beginning of the war in my country, Syria, I lost my husband and did not know anything about what could have happened to him. When the battles intensified, I took my children and went to my father, as he lived alone in Damascus because my mother was dead. We lived with him for about a year, and then the war broke out in Damascus as well. One day we woke up to the sound of guns, bullets, and planes. I took my children and we went with my father to take refuge in the shelters. We stayed like this for three days until we finally decided to get away from this area. We actually made our way on foot, until we approached a car that was in a traffic jam on the way to the border with Lebanon. We accosted them and found that they too were leaving Syria for refuge in Lebanon. With them we eventually reached the Lebanese border and once in Lebanon, a tent was secured for us to live in. So after witnessing so much death, we finally found safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Standing up for the planet&#39;: An interview with climate activist Partho Chatterjee</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:46:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Partho Pratim Chatterjee, a citizen of India and a member of UN-aligned. I hail from the mineral rich eastern state of Jharkhand. I am an engineer by profession and working in the capacity of Co-Founder and Technical Advisor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adityabioinnovation.in/&#34;&gt;Aditya Bioinnovation&lt;/a&gt; Private Limited, Nagpur, India. I have a keen penchant for eco-friendly technologies which include clean nanofluids, clean energy and clean transportation. My hobbies include penning poems and biodiversity exploration. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following interview was conducted in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-yourself-and-your-children&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself and your children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Amna; I am 33 years old. I live in Lebanon in a Syrian refugee camp. I have two children, a son and a daughter. My husband was lost in Syria, and I fled with my children from the war and came to Arsal to seek safety away from the difficult conditions of the war that destroyed our lives and the childhood of my children. I tried to work to meet the needs of my children, but I could not for fear of leaving them alone in the tent and I wanted to teach them and follow their school lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayesha Kajee Talks to UN-aligned About Her Poem &#34;Silence&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The second place was awarded to Ayesha Kajee for her poem Silence. The following interview was conducted on the 2nd of November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch the interview here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Read Ayesha&amp;rsquo;s poem “Silence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Dean Gessie Talks to UN-aligned about his “Terra Australis Incognita”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:40:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The first place was awarded to Dean Gessie for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”. The following interview was conducted on the 31st of October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Read Dean&amp;rsquo;s poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch our interview with Dean Gessie here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“A preventable tragedy”: How dementia became the catalyst that eroded Noor’s family</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine visiting your mother or father in their home. When you arrive, you discover that they are in distress in front of the television. They look at you with fear in their eyes; you look at them and then to the ordinary television screen, not understanding the problem. Your mother or father imagines that the people on the television are home intruders, and they ask you how those people got into the house. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photographer Anwar Sadat: “If you listen, people are always willing to talk”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:28:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 15th of February 2021, the 2020 UN-aligned photo competition winner, Anwar Sadat, tells us about the story behind his prize-winning photos and his love for photography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-22Se-ascolti-le-persone-sono-sempre-disponibili-a-parlare22-Una-conversazione-con-il-fotografo-Anwar-Sadat.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;could-you-tell-us-a-bit-about-yourself-and-your-love-for-photography&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could you tell us a bit about yourself and your love for photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, my name is Anwar Sadat and I am a photographer based in Nairobi Kenya. My focus in photography is documentary, photojournalism, street reportage and portraiture. I often tell stories of the buzzing streets of Nairobi and my community that often go unseen and unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Boy who Produces Golden Eggs – an interview with the 11 year old Andrea Piccinelli</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Il-ragazzo-che-produce-uova-doro.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Italian version of this interview can be read here.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;La versione originale italiana di questa intervista può essere letta qui.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview with UN-aligned coordinator, Adrian Liberto, the 11 year old &lt;strong&gt;Andrea Piccinelli&lt;/strong&gt; shares his story about how he developed a love and friendship with his chickens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, some are literally golden in as much as they have a golden hue, but they are all golden in the sense that they are entirely cruelty free. Andrea Piccinelli lives in Magliano de Marsi, a small town in the Abruzzi, Italy, at the foot of the Monte Velino. His passion is looking after his chickens. His love for the animals and his determination are so strong that you would think that these traits must be in his genes. Maybe they are, a distant relative was a Franciscan Friar Pamfilo of Magliano, famous for compassion and for his part in founding &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sbu.edu/&#34;&gt;St. Bonaventure University&lt;/a&gt; in New York. What is certain, is that this young lad has come up with his own exit strategy for intensive chicken farming. His enterprise is also a wakeup call. What will the future be for all these farm animals we have enthralled for millennia? This is something that without doubt requires considerably more thought, especially now that intensive farming may be meeting its nemesis thanks to growing public awareness into the unethical practices of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I want UN-aligned to be a place where people can come together without being judged&#34;: Interview with Katharina Wüstnienhaus</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This interview is part of an ongoing series about our members and how they wish to take charge of UN-aligned and use it as a beacon for hope and change. If you wish to participate in these interviews, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question: Tell us a little about yourself Katha. What is your background? Where do you live? What are some of your hobbies and things you are passionate about?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am from the westernmost part of Germany, only a bike ride away from the Netherlands. I have recently quitted my job in Berlin because I wanted to travel; unfortunately, this just happened when the Covid-19 pandemic hit us, so I decided to move back home and stay here instead. I enjoy music, being surrounded by nature, travelling and making friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Traumatic Experience with Postpartum - An interview with Rahima El Harrak</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The period soon after childbirth poses substantial health risks for both mother and new-born infant. Yet the postpartum and postnatal period receives less attention from health care providers than pregnancy and childbirth. Models of postpartum and postnatal care have changed little since first developed a century ago. The World Health Organization (WHO) is in the process of revising and updating its guidance on postpartum and postnatal care delivered by skilled providers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
