<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let technology become a bane for future generations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology helps us improve our lives and make things easier. However, there are two sides to everything. Undoubtedly, for instance, Artificial Intelligence will grow further, but I am sure it has both a positive and a negative impact on the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me be honest, when technology just started to enter our lives in the early 90’s in India I was super thrilled with it. I was fascinated with the pagers and then the mobiles in the late 90’s and I liked the fact that at the press of a button I could reach my near and dear ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media in an Era of Invasion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From February 24th until now, nearly tens of thousands of people have been either injured or killed by the Russian invasion of Ukraine. This is an unfortunate number of people, especially so when considering the number of refugees fleeing Ukraine; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/conflict-ukraine&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;with more than five million leaving Ukraine in search of safety. The people of Ukraine have been pushed from their homes, forced to leave behind their lives, families, friends, and pets; but they are resilient people and have given the world personal insights to life in Ukraine post-invasion. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machines for the environment: 10 Simple machines that made our lives more sustainable</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The advent of machines has heralded a new dawn for Homo Sapiens. Machines date back to antiquity. They have been ubiquitous right from the era of the first industrial revolution till the present, contemporary fourth industrial revolution. From tangible mechanical gears to the intangible virtual space, the progress mankind has made in the field of technology from the 1st Industrial Revolution to the 4th has been stupendous and awe inspiring. The effects of machines on our homes has been astounding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
