<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>At School in 70S England on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/at-school-in-70s-england/</link>
    <description>Recent content in At School in 70S England on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:59 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/at-school-in-70s-england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;All of the anger poured out of me like a volcano and I saw red&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the third and final part of Noor&amp;rsquo;s story &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/at-school-in-70s-england/&#34;&gt;for this feature&lt;/a&gt;. Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have very vivid memories of 1977 specifically because it was the Queen&amp;rsquo;s Jubilee. There were huge street parties and a pure celebratory atmosphere on that day. By this time, my mum was on a road trip to Morocco and I&amp;rsquo;d stayed behind in England with my older sister.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“No, I wasn’t somebody just to be picked on”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:24:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1976 we moved to Poplar in London. One thing I remember is a Saturday market full of hustle and bustle, with working class people grabbing bargains under a wave of brightly coloured merchandise. We had moved into a four bedroomed Maisonette, not far from our new secondary school. We lived amongst a majority white community, but there was one black family who befriended my sister and I.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was February and incredibly cold. I remember walking to my new school that day with dread and fear twisting inside me. All that I could do was anticipate the worst things that could happen to me at the new school. The thought of having to face 30 children, not understanding much English, and trying to make sense of the school timetable, was nauseating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I couldn&#39;t understand a word of it, but I loved choir singing”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:18:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;4th-october-1974&#34;&gt;4th October 1974&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in England, my first memory was walking through Heathrow Airport with my three sisters and one brother. I am the middle child of seven children, two of my siblings had already arrived in England before us. My mother was holding two of our hands, and the air hostesses were holding the rest of our little hands. My brother didn’t need his hand to be held and walked behind us as we approached Passport Control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
