<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Picture Story on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/a-picture-story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Picture Story on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/a-picture-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diving Into the Enigmatic World of Deep Sea Creatures – A Photo Essay</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenging conditions of the deep sea, life thrives in this surreal world. The pressure can be unfathomable, temperatures can plummet to subzero, and darkness is all-consuming, yet a vast array of life forms, ranging from bioluminescent jellyfish to colossal squids, showcase exquisite diversity and beauty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deep sea is an enigmatic and mesmerising environment that never ceases to amaze us with its extraordinary inhabitants. Join us as we embark on an extraordinary expedition to the unfamiliar, as we unravel the wonders of the deep sea and the creatures that inhabit it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland’s troubled history with Russia — A Story in Photos</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:36:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-february-manifesto-and-the-russification-of-finland-1899&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The February Manifesto and the Russification of Finland (1899)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The February manifesto was part of the larger operation of the Russification of Finland during which Finnish territories were forced to align their cultures with that of the Russian empire. On the 5th of February 1899, Nicholas II of Russia, the Tsar of Russia, defined a new legislation order that asserted the imperial Russian government to rule over Finland without the consultation of the Finnish Senate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The painful history of Ukraine — A photo timeline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ukraine’s fate may be rooted in its heartbreaking past. In this photo timeline, which consists of more than 35 photos and 12 painful events, we’ll guide you through the county&amp;rsquo;s tragic history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukrainian-war-of-independence-1917-to-1921&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukrainian War of Independence (1917 to 1921)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 1917 to 1921, with the invasion of Bolsheviks, a series of conflicts and battles led to the establishment of the Ukrainian Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Ukrainian-War-of-Independence-1917-to-1921--1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A patriotic demonstration in Kyiv, Ukraine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;holodomor-1932-to-1933&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holodomor (1932 to 1933)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holodomor, meaning to kill by starvation, is another dark chapter in Ukraine’s history. It is widely believed that the famine was orchestrated by Joseph Stalin to impose collectivism and tamp down Ukrainian nationalism. Hunger was so common that the Soviet regime convicted more than 2,500 people for cannibalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
