<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex.liberto on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/alex.liberto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alex.liberto on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/alex.liberto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More than Just a Gay Icon: Edmund White (1940-2025) </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</guid>
      <description>June began with the death of two literary giants: Edmund White (died June 3, 2025 at 85) and Frederick Forsyth (died June 9,2025 at 86). Our literary editor, Alex Liberto, had met and corresponded with the former and has written this touching tribute.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Edmund_White_2_by_David_Shankbone_cropped.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Poetry After WWII: The Rise and Evolution of Post-War Literature in The UK</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>In a world recovering from the devastation of war, how did English literature find its footing? Here are the most pivotal figures and movements that reshaped the post-war literary landscape.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/TOWARDS-THE-THIRD-MILLENNIUM-The-Gordian.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Angry Young Men in British Drama</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</guid>
      <description>Exploring social injustice and generation gap in post-war Britain drama through the works of John Osborne and other playwrights of the Angry Young Men movement.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/The-Rise-of-the-Angry-Young-Men-in-British-Drama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>British Drama in the Age of Self-Discovery: Significant Plays and Key Themes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</guid>
      <description>Uncovering the hidden gems of 20th century British drama.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/British-Drama-in-the-Age-of-Self-Discovery-Significant-Plays-and-Key-Themes-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the age of self-discovery changed the English poetry and novel forever</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</guid>
      <description>The Age of Self-Discovery was a milestone for the English poetry and novel that opened the doors for the intellectual creativity and innovation of 20th-century writers.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/How-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-English-poetry-and-the-novel-forever-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Herbert Lawrence: The Freudian who hated industrialisation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</guid>
      <description>David Herbert Lawrence has captivated the imagination with his rich and substantial prose, painting a clear picture of reality with spontaneous language.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/David-Herbert-Lawrence-The-Freudian-who-hated-industrialisation-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocked and Unbolted: Virginia Woolf&#39;s Life and Works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 11:26:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>Virginia Woolf and her tumultuous psychological hardships should be considered an essential cornerstone of modernist fiction.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Virginal-Wolf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doris Lessing: Subjecting a Divided Civilisation to Scrutiny</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 10:40:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>Doris Lessing, a female writer who weighed in on the feminist front and who wrote about persecution, intolerance and injustice.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Doris-Lessing_-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edward Morgan Forster: Life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 11:17:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>Edward Morgan Forster: his life and his works.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/E.-M.-Forster.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From patriotism to pure poetry: Isaac Rosenberg’s Break of Day in the Trenches</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 11:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</guid>
      <description>Isaac Rosenberg (1890-1918) did not sing the praises of war; he reflected on its philosophical and poetical impact through symbolism and imagery.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/From-patriotism-to-pure-poetry_-Isaac-Rosenbergs-Break-of-Day-in-the-Trenches-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We support Ukraine because it represents the sacrosanct right to build one&#39;s own future</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine is supported by many countries because it represents the right to build one&#39;s own future, in peace within the safety of their borders, without the threats of aggression. Peace, principles, justice and self determination are sacrosanct. That is why the Ukrainians do not want war. They want to live harmoniously among their own people, sharing the culture and heritage with their neighbours and the world.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Wroclaw-Poland-2-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The master of the Bildungsroman: Leslie Poles Hartley’s life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>Born in 1895 L.P Hartley was an English poet and author of many notable works including The Go-Between and The Eustace and Hilda trilogy. Learn more about his life and works.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/The-master-of-the-Bildungsroman_-Leslie-Poles-Hartleys-life-and-works-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Osborne and The Angry Young Men</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 13:59:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our overview of post-war British drama with a survey of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1aFPD3yGlnWubBApVyOyjFgWhXeP1qBShaTKmbLeM_8I/edit#&#34;&gt;Theatre of the Absurd&lt;/a&gt;, let us now look at another important literary movement that developed after the end of World War II. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end of the war left a sense of discontent and disillusionment, especially with the younger generation. As society developed into a more affluent capitalistic and class-conscious structure, the younger generation became aware that the poorer classes were being exploited and this prompted them to voice their anger. A new class of writers, known as the Angry Young Men, came into being. They were expressing their anger through various literary genres, in particular through prose and drama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Photo-John-Osbornes-Wikipedia-page..jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harold Pinter: a mirror for the common people</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 12:50:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last issue we saw how Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/&#34;&gt;developed a new drama&lt;/a&gt; that was characterized by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time: the Theatre of the Absurd. In this issue we shall take a closer look at Nobel Prize winner Harold Pinter, one of the most influential modern British dramatists with a writing career spanning over more than 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Harold-Pinter_-a-mirror-for-the-common-people.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Beckett &amp; Harold Pinter: 2 Giants of the Theatre of the Absurd</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/literature/&#34;&gt;the last issue&lt;/a&gt; we saw how some 20th century writers envisioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/&#34;&gt;a dystopian future&lt;/a&gt; in reaction to the two world wars and to the dwindling human values. Protesting against society and the situation of man, but in a different way, were the giants of the Theatre of the Absurd Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter. Both playwrights developed a new drama which was characterised by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Giants-of-the-Theatre-of-the-Absurd-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dystopian Novel: &#34;Beyond Utopia&#34;!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dystopian novel developed during the 20th century when the reality of humanity’s volatile condition became evident after both the first and second world wars. The word, dystopia, refers to Utopia, the fictitious name of an ideal country, coined by Thomas More in his famous book Libellus &amp;hellip; de optimo reipublicae statu deque nova Insula &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/2130&#34;&gt;Utopia (1516)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was designed as a political, social and religious system which was not supposed to be reflected in reality, but proposed as an ideal model.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/George-Orwell-1981.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitzgerald&#39;s Great Gatsby VS T. S. Eliot&#39;s Waste Land: Portraying a dusty vastness where nothing thrives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The situation that plagued the world after World War One was one of callous apathy and emotional aridity. My last article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/&#34;&gt;T. S. Eliot’s poetic portrayal of the early 20th century&lt;/a&gt; ended with the line, “The dehumanisation of the modern world is complete.” This ‘dehumanisation’, which Eliot portrayed as a waste land in his poetry, was also described very clearly in prose by F. S. Fitzgerald in his novel &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Fitzgeralds-Great-Gatsby-vs-T.-S.-Eliots-Waste-Land-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your guide to T.S Eliot poems - April is the cruellest month</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:13:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;T.S Eliot is perhaps the best example of the modern metaphysical poet. Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/&#34;&gt;17th century poet, John Donne&lt;/a&gt;, Eliot veered from the ethereal world of romance and idealisation, to head directly towards a concrete reality through conceits and extended metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His work reflected the upheaval of the social order in the aftermath of World War I, and the failure of all of man’s social, political and philosophical aspirations. On the wake of death and destruction, all seemed to flounder on the crags of a festering humanity that had turned to superficial desires and material gain. Ethical and moral values were reduced to a vast expanse of ash and aridity; a waste land void of any humanity. Humankind had lost its soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/T.S-Eliot-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Donne&#39;s No Man is an Island: Feeling a Oneness With Humanity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 08:38:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s world besieged by isolationism, America First, Britain First, white supremacy, cyber bullying, homophobia, racism, vaccine tug-of-war, colonialist withdrawal symptoms (… shall I go on?) and the like, never before have the words of John Donne been more relevant; “No man is an island…”. In the age of Brexit, the very notion that every man is part of a greater humanity is a powerful assertion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the profound conviction that ‘every man is a piece of the continent, a part of the main’ has a far more universal metaphorical significance; a spiritual and existential significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/John-Donne.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Greatest Metaphysical Poet&#34;: Your Full Guide to John Donne’s Life, Career &amp; Poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;family-background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Donne was born in London in 1572 to a relatively wealthy family.  His father, who died when Donne was only four, was a successful tradesman and his mother, Elizabeth, was the daughter of the writer John Heywood.  Both parents were Roman Catholics and were in obvious difficulty to come to terms with the newly established Church of England.  Donne’s family, especially on his mother’s side, were persecuted for being Roman Catholics and for refusing to swear the Oath of Supremacy which acknowledged the English monarch as the Head of the Church of England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/8.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Pepys: A peep into the life of a gentleman in the Restoration period</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cannot speak of a literary career for Samuel Pepys (1633 -1703), since he wrote predominantly for his own private reading. He is known for his diary which was written in a special code (Shelton’s system of tachygraphy) and was not meant to have been deciphered and read by others.  This naturally makes his account of life during the Restoration period free from prejudice and all the more authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diary of Pepys is of paramount importance since it illustrates an informative and unique picture of Restoration life. It is a stunning self-portrait of the middle-class gentleman whose social position exemplifies the Restoration years of readjustment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/10.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution Gaming fires hundreds of employees as it buys NetEnt for $2.1 billion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/evolution-gaming-fires-hundreds-of-employees-as-it-buys-netent-for-2-1-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 14:38:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/evolution-gaming-fires-hundreds-of-employees-as-it-buys-netent-for-2-1-billion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following article, written by Alex Liberto, concerns one of our Maltese members who was a victim of a ruthless mass sacking following the takeover of one company by another.  Sadly, the coronavirus has already caused havoc in the jobs market around the world, but if anyone one can suggest what UN-aligned can do to support these people, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-ugly-side-to-capitalism&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another Ugly Side to Capitalism…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was the first day of December, the month of merriment and Christmas spirit. The staff at NetEnt were already planning Yuletide activities, trying to balance Covid restrictions with the desire to celebrate. They were unaware that this Christmas would be hijacked by something much more nefarious for them than Covid; the heartless stripping away of their livelihood. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/190305-getting-fired-al-0912_e1efba86103adc7a55509db7f830a78b.fit-760w.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blame Game: Blame Breeds Blame in a Never Ending Game of Hate</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-blame-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-blame-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I blame my bed&lt;br&gt;
For my bad back&lt;br&gt;
I blame my shoes&lt;br&gt;
For my flat feet&lt;br&gt;
I blame my wife&lt;br&gt;
Our daily strife&lt;br&gt;
I blame the heat&lt;br&gt;
For my fatigue&lt;br&gt;
I blame the cold&lt;br&gt;
For my clogged nose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blame them all&lt;br&gt;
For my bad traits&lt;br&gt;
It’s all their fault&lt;br&gt;
I live in hate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I die&lt;br&gt;
I’ll blame my God&lt;br&gt;
For a hateful life&lt;br&gt;
A painful death&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a culture of litigation. We sue Starbucks if their coffee is too hot and scalds us. We sue our hosts if we get involved in an alcohol-related accident after drinking at their home. We sue teachers if our children fall and hurt themselves at school. We would sue God if we could, for making us sick, for making us unhappy, for not preventing the death of a loved one. This is the blame game. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/6.png.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maurice and Sexual Awakening</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:55:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to start a short cycle on love with a work about the “love that dare not speak its name”; the love between two men. Maurice was written by E. M. Forster back in the Edwardian England of respectability and bigotry. Not that any other period in the last few centuries were any more progressive or open minded. As Forster put it, “England has always been disinclined to accept human nature.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/10-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Taylor Coleridge: The Supernatural Poet</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coleridge, like Wordsworth, loved nature and together they enjoyed walking in the Lake District, in the heart of the natural surroundings. However, Coleridge also loved the supernatural. His fantastic and mysterious imagination was an infinite source of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was this poetic process of creation that laid the foundations for the haunting scenes of &lt;em&gt;The Rime of The Ancient&lt;/em&gt; Mariner and the visionary surrealistic world of &lt;em&gt;Kubla Khan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Samuel-Taylor-Coleridge-KublaKhan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kubla Khan handwritten sketch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/WP-Photo-6.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bluster of Arrogance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 12:40:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Popular leaders nowadays seem to owe their success to noise, aggression and self-aggrandisement. I call this the Cassius Clay syndrome. The louder they shout, the more they are respected. The more brazen they are, the more they gain trust. The more they blow their own trumpet, the more credible they appear. This is the leader of our 21st century populist culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These loudmouths are distorted Machiavellian politicians. Distorted because the ends justified by their means are void of any political or social ideals. Their modus operandi is not based on any strategic acumen, it is improvised and opportunistic. It is sheer megalomania. They wallow in their own narcissism and arrogance, advocating an impoverished makeshift political agenda. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Culture of Subterfuge - Lest We Forget</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-culture-of-subterfuge-lest-we-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:27:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>alex.liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-culture-of-subterfuge-lest-we-forget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lies, half truths, deceit and hypocrisy are so embedded in our society that people have become immune to them, accept them and often believe that subterfuge is a way of life. Some, indeed, revel in fake news, willingly spreading fictitious slander in jest. Others use fabricated tales of deception for more malevolent objectives, knowing too well that the pseudo facts will filter down into our social fabric. Whatever the reasons, the real fact is that we are living in an era of “alternative facts”, to quote the paradoxical claim by U.S. Counselor to President Trump, Kellyanne Conway. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/The-Culture-of-Subterfuge-%E2%80%93-Lest-We-Forget.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
