<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Issues on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/categories/social-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Issues on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/social-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘If it ain’t broke... break it’: How the US betrayed  free speech and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>From hounding WikiLeaks&#39; Assange to stifling peaceful students protesting genocide, America has abandoned its democratic values along with all notions of decency.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/The-US-betrayal-of-free-speech-and-the-First-Amendment.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s sexist and racist remarks to her guest, Mustafa Barghouti, reflect a troubling norm in many workplaces.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Julia-Hartley-Brewers-racism.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>India ascends on the world stage, projecting power and prosperity, yet within its borders, the stark reality of disparity and unfulfilled promises persists. What are the steps forward?</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Behind-the-Headlines-Indias-Rising-Power-Lingering-Poverty-and-the-Quest-for-Balance-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Wealth Gap: A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication</title>
      <link>/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</guid>
      <description>Redefining 21st century economics to eradicate poverty.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Bridging-the-Wealth-Gap-A-Blueprint-for-Poverty-Eradication.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education’s Paradigm Shift: “Another Brick in the Wall!”</title>
      <link>/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 12:05:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive critique of traditional schooling and a vision of a more dynamic system for the future</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Educations-Paradigm-Shift-Another-Brick-in-the-Wall.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five benefits of legalising drugs that may change your perspective</title>
      <link>/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</guid>
      <description>Legalising drugs would make drug use safer, but the bigger impact of moving to a regulated drug market is that it would defy racism, reduce chaos and violence and make us wealthier.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs-that-may-change-your-perspective-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking Behind the Fig Leaf: Our Journey to Sexual Liberation</title>
      <link>/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Society is a raft made from the wreckage of our dreams and fears. Space is limited and we struggle to keep aboard, scrambling for the middle ground so we do not have to witness those sacrificed at the rim: pushed, or slipping, or just unable to grab a hold. Smug, we pretend that they are not there or that they are so out of reach that we are quite exonerated from any obligation to assist them from their demise. Some would rather swim. Others choose to drown. Reality, as we perceive it, as we live it, is a fragile thing, so we cling on to the raft despite its many flaws. We ignore them. We justify them. We acknowledge and accept them. Often, religions sanction them. And so we paddle on, tossed by abysmal waves, never quite certain where we are heading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Peeking-Behind-the-Fig-Leaf.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>Our silence is pernicious and yet we seem to not care; not when caring can threaten the comfort zones we have become so used to. Here are five points that will shed some light on the issue of migration.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Citizenship-is-a-construct-our-primary-duty-is-to-humankind_-5-problems-solutions-to-the-migrant-problem-2-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Selective-Justice_-Nine-Rings-of-Moral-Tunnel-Vision.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Syrian-Refugees-Heading-for-Another-Tough-Winter.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title>
      <link>/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-federalism-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Yugoslavias-Failed-Social-Contract-Lessons-Worth-Learning-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When it was illegal for me to be alive</title>
      <link>/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster&amp;hellip; it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us&amp;hellip; Then, out of the blue, or through a slow and inevitable twist of events, it does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Adrian-Liberto.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN is failing to eradicate poverty</title>
      <link>/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>jay.davis</author>
      <guid>/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty, to put it simply, is one of humankind’s greatest ills and despite various ways to quantify, analyse or measure it, the problem remains unsolved. With the world finding itself in unprecedented straits owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, which has not only claimed the lives of 4,000,000, but has revealed ominous and record-breaking poverty worldwide, humanity more than ever needs its leaders to come together and work towards effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/%E2%80%98Unanimous-Verdict_-the-UN-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
