<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Issues on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/social-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Issues on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/social-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘If it ain’t broke... break it’: How the US betrayed  free speech and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;loving-guns-hating-free-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loving guns, hating free speech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely amazing how the US government bows with such unquestioning fervour and reverence to the Second Amendment, while comfortably sticking its middle finger up to the First.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Second Amendment, ratified in 1791, in the heyday of the Wild West and almost 100 years before the iconic gunfight at the O.K. Corral (1881), stipulates “the right of the people to keep and bear Arms”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the backseat of a taxi, a simple chat took a jarring turn, plunging me into a story that is all too common yet often goes untold. My goal was straightforward: to land a full-time role at a publishing house. However, what unfolded was an unexpected confrontation with racial and sexist prejudices — an incident that, though personal, reflects a broader issue pervasive in our workspaces and media today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journey reached a pivotal moment at the end-of-year company dinner party, a gathering that marked the culmination of a challenging yet rewarding internship. Having broached the subject of future prospects with my immediate male supervisor during training and discussed my aspirations with colleagues, I felt cautiously optimistic. However, the evening took an unforeseen turn on the ride home, sharing a taxi with a female supervisor who was less often seen during office hours. Her reaction to my shared ambitions was not of encouragement or guidance but one of anger and insinuation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India has certainly been in the spotlight these last few months and anyone not looking too closely would be justified in thinking that the country was rising, phoenix-like, from its post-colonial ashes to virtual super power status. In April 2023 it overtook China as the most populous nation on Earth with well over 1.4 billion people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 4, Rahul Gandhi, champion of the Congress Party and heir to the Nehru-Gandhi dynasty, had his two-year prison sentence for disparaging comments made against Modi, suspended by India’s supreme court, suggesting a robust democratic rule of law. Also in August (23rd), India’s Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft landed on the lunar surface. This was all the more spectacular coming so soon after Russia’s failed moon mission. Moreover, it was the very first successful landing on the dark side of the moon. Then, in September, with much pomp and circumstance, India hosted the 2023 G20 Summit. Its presidency may not have been a roaring success, but it was a success nonetheless. Though Russia’s President Vladimir Putin and China’s Xi Jinping did not attend, and organisers had to forego the traditional “family” photo owing to disagreements over Ukraine, the overall outcome was positive, with the African Union’s addition to the block being one of this G20’s notable achievements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Wealth Gap: A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Redefining our modern self-serving economics to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reality is what keeps us safe. It informed our past and it guides our present. Reality is our safe zone. It is the anchor on which our boat is secured. It is the devil we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as anyone who has owned a boat can tell you, a tight anchor is the surest way to sink your boat: a change in tide, a swell… and without the leeway in your rope, you are underwater. The fact is, reality changes and unless we adapt and evolve with it, we are done for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education’s Paradigm Shift: “Another Brick in the Wall!”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 12:05:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a child, one gets fed a lot of crap from one’s elders. Fortunately, not all of it is swallowed. “You’ll see! As you grow older, you’ll look back at your school days and you’ll remember them as the best days of your life!” Whether the many grownups who preached this believed it or not (it may have been true for some of them), I wonder how they could have possibly thought that these words could have been considered reassuring in any way. It is like telling a prisoner in a torture chamber: “You think this is bad, wait until they put you on the rack!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five benefits of legalising drugs that may change your perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-decriminalisation-of-drugs-mean-vs-what-does-it-mean-to-legalise-drugs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does decriminalisation of drugs mean VS&lt;/strong&gt; what does it mean to legalise drugs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about decriminalising all drugs, within a legal framework, we don’t necessarily refer to them being legalised. In other words, drug ownership and personal use would itself still be legally prohibited, but violations of those prohibitions are deemed to be exclusively administrative violations and are removed completely from the criminal realm. Ideally, we want the legalisation of all drugs, however, decriminalising them could also be an attractive short-term solution. Here are five arguments for legalising drugs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeking Behind the Fig Leaf: Our Journey to Sexual Liberation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Society is a raft made from the wreckage of our dreams and fears. Space is limited and we struggle to keep aboard, scrambling for the middle ground so we do not have to witness those sacrificed at the rim: pushed, or slipping, or just unable to grab a hold. Smug, we pretend that they are not there or that they are so out of reach that we are quite exonerated from any obligation to assist them from their demise. Some would rather swim. Others choose to drown. Reality, as we perceive it, as we live it, is a fragile thing, so we cling on to the raft despite its many flaws. We ignore them. We justify them. We acknowledge and accept them. Often, religions sanction them. And so we paddle on, tossed by abysmal waves, never quite certain where we are heading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migrant-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The migrant problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied their history will know that migrations are what shaped the world as we know it today, both politically and ethnically. At times these migrations were peaceful. Often, they were predatory. At times they were gradual, spreading like an oil stain; often, they were sudden and quite alien, like a frenzied splash from a Jackson Pollock paintbrush. At times the end result was growth and a fusion of cultures; often, it was genocide. So we built walls of brick and paper to keep the undesirables out. Most of us belonged to those undesirables once, but that was a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-federalism-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it was illegal for me to be alive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster&amp;hellip; it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us&amp;hellip; Then, out of the blue, or through a slow and inevitable twist of events, it does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is failing to eradicate poverty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty, to put it simply, is one of humankind’s greatest ills and despite various ways to quantify, analyse or measure it, the problem remains unsolved. With the world finding itself in unprecedented straits owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, which has not only claimed the lives of 4,000,000, but has revealed ominous and record-breaking poverty worldwide, humanity more than ever needs its leaders to come together and work towards effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
