<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italy on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/italy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italy on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:48:43 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graffiti through history: 3 magnificent examples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/3-magnificent-historical-graffiti-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:48:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/3-magnificent-historical-graffiti-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My cultural background and my personal tastes have always made my interests oscillate (also for the purposes of research and study) between figurative and written art. There is a topic that thanks to certain dynamics of realisation and conception, allows me to combine these two main fields of interest in a single analysis: graffiti. In fact, in this &amp;ldquo;category&amp;rdquo;, the testimonies on the wall and the writing often merge into a single genre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/11-Goat-1024x787.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caprone: this goat from the Giustiniani collection highlights the care that went into the restoration of these ancient sculptures. The body dates from the 1st century CE, but the head is attributed to Gian Lorenzo Bernini (1598-1680).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/12-Athena-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Athena Giustiniani (Greek marble with Italian marble additions: c. 140-160 CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/13-Ptolemy-757x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ptolemy (Pentelic marble: c. 120-140 CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/14-Germanicus-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Germanicus (Bronze: 1st century CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/15-Artemis-693x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artemis Ephesia: this statue from the Giustiniani collection was restored using black marble (2nd century CE).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-Seated-Philosopher--768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This sculpture of a seated philosopher formally belonged to the Cesarini collection and is known as the Cesarini Chrysippus (Greek marble: 1st Century CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2-Apollo-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apollo holding the skin of the satyr Marsyas after having skinned him alive. One of the more popular versions of the story relates how Marsyas had challenged the god to a musical contest that was to be judged by the Muses. The winner would have had the right to do as he pleased with the loser and when Apollo won (in some versions via a ruse) he chose to flay Marsyas for having dared challenge a god. The statue from the Giustiniani collection may have been very different in its original form and was restored extensively and with much imagination. (1st century CE)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The freedom to choose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following article is taken from a speech given by Carla Pietrobattista on Dante Day, March 25, which is traditionally held as the day the “divine poet” started his masterpiece, the &lt;em&gt;Divine Comedy&lt;/em&gt;. 2021 also marks the 700th anniversary of Dante’s death. The event was presided by the Mayor of Magliano dei Marsi, Pasqualino di Cristofano. Ms. Pietrobattista will also be collaborating on the new Art Section of &lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;, which will start next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the road: The story behind Santa Maria church in Valle Porclaneta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 09:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The perfect balance and harmony that govern the elements present in the church of Santa Maria in the Porclaneta in Rosciolo, Abruzzo, Italy, tends to arouse one’s curiosity with regards to its origins and history. Although much has already been said by historians and art experts, I firmly believe there are still many secrets hidden in the iconography the church is steeped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;unexplored-secrets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unexplored secrets&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until now the elements that have found greater exposure in the historical and stylistic examination are the sculptural ones. However, I believe that the paintings in the church of Santa Maria, despite the simplicity of execution of some of them, still have much to reveal. This is particularly true of the triptych placed at the end of the right nave of the church. Here, the Virgin and Child is flanked by St. Michael holding scales in his hands and a saint with a long liturgical robe grasping a chain: St. Leonard of Noblat (also known as San Leonardo de Noblac, from the Latin &amp;rsquo;nobiliacum&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
