<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unravelling the Un on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/unravelling-the-un/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unravelling the Un on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/unravelling-the-un/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The UN is failing to eradicate poverty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty, to put it simply, is one of humankind’s greatest ills and despite various ways to quantify, analyse or measure it, the problem remains unsolved. With the world finding itself in unprecedented straits owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, which has not only claimed the lives of 4,000,000, but has revealed ominous and record-breaking poverty worldwide, humanity more than ever needs its leaders to come together and work towards effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve a robust legal system? Solutions towards comprehensive global justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in last month’s issue of The Gordian, I highlighted some of the weaknesses of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and the International Criminal Court (ICC). Whilst these bodies are merely a part of a wider international legal system that is also governed by various treaties, conventions and accords, they are pivotal in as much as their focus is on safeguarding human life and world peace. My conclusion was that these two institutions were flawed, compromised and generally ineffective. In this issue, therefore, I intend to offer some concrete ideas for a robust legal system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Abandon all hope ye who enter here”: The shitshow that is the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-shitshow-that-is-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 11:49:57 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-shitshow-that-is-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-unsc-becoming-obsolete&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the UNSC becoming obsolete?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not that the Security Council (UNSC) is no longer fit for purpose, it has never really been designed to fit its purpose. In 1946, after the League of Nations ceased its operations, the Security Council was invested with most of the power of the brand new organisation, the United Nations. The five winners, let’s face it bullies, of the war, none of whom possessed any moral authority, were tasked with one noble purpose: to advocate peace. What could possibly go wrong with tasking a group of warlords with the maintenance of international peace and security? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-La-giustizia-di-chi.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding and Fiscal Responsibility of the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Unravelling-United-Nations-Argead-style/dp/B08T7J1QX4/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1612176186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;UN-aligned’s new publication&lt;/a&gt; that highlights the shortcomings of the United Nations with details that cover its foundation, structure and monumental failures. You may be surprised at the murky facts that this book will bring to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thorough critique of the UN finances would therefore involve a massive amount of time and investigation, which exceeds the remit of this work. Nevertheless, even without specific details regarding UN spending, some of its weaknesses in this regard have been manifestly exposed from within the organisation. The two main criticisms concern the manifold overlaps in UN operations and the inflated salaries of UN personnel. These issues go hand in hand and can be summed up in one word: bureaucracy. They give rise to an unnecessary multiplying of well-paid personnel and a replication of resources, which means that while employees and their administrative needs receive the lion’s share of the allocated funds, identified problems are left with the crumbs. Of course, decision-making is also impaired, which in turn affects efficiency in general. Speaking at a UN Reform Event in September 2017, Secretary General António Guterres summed up the situation without mincing his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is The United Nations General Assembly?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-the-united-nations-general-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:28:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-the-united-nations-general-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Unravelling-United-Nations-Argead-style/dp/B08T7J1QX4/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1612176186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;UN-aligned’s new publication&lt;/a&gt; that highlights the shortcomings of the United Nations with details that cover its foundation, structure and monumental failures. You may be surprised at the murky facts that this book will bring to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly is the community of UN members in their representative role. It is subordinate to the Security Council and it was stipulated that it could only engage in resolving issues that were not already being dealt with by the Security Council (Article 12.1). It is the duty of the Secretary General, “with the consent of the Security Council”, to keep the Assembly informed of matters that are being tackled by the Council, so that the latter’s deliberations are not infringed upon. (Article 12.2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
