<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More than Just a Gay Icon: Edmund White (1940-2025) </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When we are young… we often experience things in the present with a nostalgia-in-advance, but we seldom guess what we will truly prize years from now.” (City boy: My Life in New York in the 1960s and 70s)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As the outpouring of tributes to author Edmund White continues to flood the world, I cannot help feeling how the man, Edmund White, would have reacted to the adulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was a very reserved and unassuming gentle soul, with a wicked sense of humour; always on board for a laugh. I met Edmund several years back when I was a lecturer at the American University of Rome. Our first encounter was fraught with laughter and surreptitious jokes. He was about to give a talk and a reading of his book A Married Man at John Cabot University in Trastevere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Michelangelo’s &#34;Fruit Basket&#34; captures the fleeting essence of life</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/michelangelos-fruit-basket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/michelangelos-fruit-basket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always postponed examining the canvas: the &amp;ldquo;Fruit Basket&amp;rdquo; for various, and undoubtedly futile, reasons. The first and foremost relates to the subjects, or rather objects to be examined. In fact, the absence of any human presence seemed to me to be an almost insurmountable hurdle in my search for feelings, in contrast to the various subjects depicted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/caravaggio/&#34;&gt;Caravaggio in his other works&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, the setting of the canvas also initially blocked me, because it lacked the obvious theatricality of Merisi&amp;rsquo;s Roman works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Caravaggio&#39;s &#39;The Burial of Saint Lucy&#39; Transforms the Divine into the Earthly</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-caravaggios-the-burial-of-saint-lucy-transforms-the-divine-into-the-earthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-caravaggios-the-burial-of-saint-lucy-transforms-the-divine-into-the-earthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-from-iconic-traditions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking from iconic traditions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both artistic and sculptural representations traditionally depict St. Lucy in celestial grandeur. She is often shown holding the palm of her martyrdom, which occurred in Syracuse in 304, in one hand, and a saucer containing her eyes in the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This iconographic element is a nod to her role as the protector of sight, although it bears no relation to the martyrdom she endured. The origin of this specific veneration is tied to her name: Lucy, or Lucia, derives from the Latin term &amp;rsquo;lux,&amp;rsquo; meaning light—an element naturally associated with eyesight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Transcending Strokes&#39;: Caravaggio&#39;s Unmistakable Emotion in &#34;Judith and Holofernes&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/transcending-strokes-caravaggios-unmistakable-emotion-in-judith-and-holofernes-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:15:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/transcending-strokes-caravaggios-unmistakable-emotion-in-judith-and-holofernes-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The repetition of distinctive stylistic elements helps art scholars, when necessary, to identify and recognise the authors. In the case of Caravaggio, the most frequent distinctive elements are different: the stroke of the drawing; the choice of the same models for the various characters; the way of interpreting the colours; the contrast between shadow and light…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet what in my eyes makes Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s hand truly unmistakable, even more than the presence of these objective stylistic elements, is the emotional tension that shines through the faces of the characters who, in most cases, tell us about the eternal conflict between good and evil that has always accompanied man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Poetry After WWII: The Rise and Evolution of Post-War Literature in The UK</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-war-english-literature&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-War English Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have already seen while analysing the literary background of previous periods, the literature of each historical age often reflected the political and social situation of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post World War II literature was no different. Those terrible years of violence and devastation created a sense of general pessimism, cynicism and disillusionment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Literature after the Second World War clearly portrayed man&amp;rsquo;s disorientation, which was not only evident in the content of literary works but also characterised by the absence of one specific major school of thought or movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caravaggio&#39;s Crucifixion of St. Peter: The Unseen Heroism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-the-crucifixion-of-saint-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 13:38:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-the-crucifixion-of-saint-peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My fixation with Caravaggio is one that prompts me to continually seek avenues to discuss his work. The necessity to scrutinise the Crucifixion of St. Peter, residing in the Cerasi Chapel, provides a convenient pretext. This painting, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/&#34;&gt;the Conversion of St. Paul,&lt;/a&gt; was crafted for the same patron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, the underlying motivation is less about circumstance and more about an earnest fascination with Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s life and artistic creations, even though the root of this allure remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Torke&#39;s &#39;Being&#39;: Dreadful Art Cover, Glorious Music</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/michael-torkes-being-dreadful-art-cover-glorious-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:24:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/michael-torkes-being-dreadful-art-cover-glorious-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;American composer Michael Torke has once again delivered an album that showcases his unique voice and style, drawing inspiration from jazz and minimalism to create a work that shimmers with vibrant timbrel palettes and infectious energy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finished in 2019, “Being” is a continuous 43-minute composition that consists of nine parts, each building on the previous and creating a hypnotic and immersive experience for the listener.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the music, we need to talk about the elephant in the room – that album cover. It looks like someone typed in “women holding coffee staring into the abyss” on a stock photo website and called it a day. But don&amp;rsquo;t let the questionable art direction deter you, the music inside is worth every quid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conversion of St. Paul by Caravaggio: A Masterpiece of Dramatic Intensity and Transformative Power</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-conversion-and-its-relevance-to-the-painting&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meaning of ‘Conversion’ and Its Relevance to the Painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;lsquo;conversion&amp;rsquo; is derived from the Latin word &amp;lsquo;conversio&amp;rsquo;, which denotes a movement from one place to another, a turning towards something or someone, or a change of direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the word itself does not necessarily connote any religious or moral significance, it presents boundless possibilities for internal and external transformation. Change can happen by deliberate choice or can be brought about unexpectedly by life&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable events, which often add new shades and dimensions to our existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Angry Young Men in British Drama</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-look-back-in-anger-by-john-osborne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘A Look Back in Anger’ by John Osborne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drama, like the novel, reflected the discontent and disillusionment of the younger generations. The Angry Young Men were not only novelists but also playwrights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look Back in Anger by John Osborne was certainly the turning point of British drama. The main character, Jimmy Porter, an intellectual who had to work in the market-place to support his family, represented that new kind of dissatisfaction and rage. He, in fact, was rejected by society and subsequently turned against it with indiscriminate fury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Than a Mere Copycat? The Rise of AI-Generated Art and its Implications</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/artificial-intelligence/more-than-a-mere-copycat-the-rise-of-ai-generated-art-and-its-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/artificial-intelligence/more-than-a-mere-copycat-the-rise-of-ai-generated-art-and-its-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you scrolled through Instagram recently, did you stumble across pieces of digital artwork that looked like it was custom-made for the user? The chances are, it was generated by an AI using a trendy new app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lensa is just one of many apps that have recently gained popularity, allowing users to generate portraits, illustrations and other types of artwork at the click of a button. But while these AI-powered tools can produce impressive results, they have also sparked a debate about the implications of using AI to create art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Detailed Look at the Ancient Nativity Fresco in the Catacombs of Santa Priscilla</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/a-detailed-look-at-catacombs-of-santa-priscilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/a-detailed-look-at-catacombs-of-santa-priscilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over time, I have learned that when it comes to art it is not necessary to be original at all costs, I simply understood that I have to write what I think, in the way and in the times that most belong to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I certainly would not try to be original and captivating during Christmas, a time that most of all tells us about traditions and the need to go back to basics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Drama in the Age of Self-Discovery: Significant Plays and Key Themes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In last month’s issue we surveyed the two literary genres of poetry and the novel at the turn of the 20th century which we defined as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/&#34;&gt;an Age of Self-Discovery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw how the tide began to change during the last two decades of Queen Victoria’s reign, when some writers sought a newer and fresher approach to literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then surveyed the literature that developed with the onset of the First World War, which had triggered in man the awareness to see life as an abyss of incessant self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story of My Great Uncle Pamfilo of Magliano</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/pamfilo-of-magliano-the-story-of-great-uncle-giovanni-paolo-pietrobattista/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/pamfilo-of-magliano-the-story-of-great-uncle-giovanni-paolo-pietrobattista/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The story of Giovanni Paolo Pietrobattista, although chronologically distant, are incredibly close, because their protagonist was my great uncle. Despite never having met Giovanni Paolol, he is very dear to me thanks to the stories my grandmother and my father have shared with me. Nor only have they instilled in me admiration for what my uncle had been able to achieve, but also a strong affection and empathy towards him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the age of self-discovery changed the English poetry and novel forever</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Literature during the Victorian Era identified itself with the ethical values of that society. The superficial optimism and bigotry of a self-righteous attitude forged a kind of literature that was condescending and emotionally wanting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from the few exceptions like Emily Bronte’s Wuthering Heights, most of the production of that period lacked the emotional intensity or the daring experimentation of writers belonging to other periods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tide began to change during the last two decades of Victoria’s reign, when some writers sought a newer and fresher approach to literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dante Alighieri&#39;s Vision for World Government: The Pathway to Abolishing War</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dante&amp;rsquo;s death 700 years ago marked the end of an era. But his lasting legacy may be his vision for a world government, outlined in his work De Monarchia. Written in 1313, this work may be the first literature to present a comprehensive solution to the problem of war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to imagine any sort of connection between the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, and something that occurred in an unremarkable bedroom in Italy almost exactly 700 years prior. It has nothing whatsoever to do with the deep historical connections between Russia and Ukraine, at many times one and the same state, during the preceding seven centuries. But last autumn marked the 700th anniversary of the death of the great Italian poet Dante Alighieri, from malaria, in Ravenna, on September 14, 1321. His bones lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>86 Billion: The human spirt&#39;s fight to live a meaningful life</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LED,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where is Dendrite?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;That Synapse - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To my fiery colours of hope&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To feed my soul, To feel my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my soul, To kiss my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my fire&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hear me&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To talk to me!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Speech me - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To hold me in words,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hold me in paint,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To violins,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To my treasures, to loves.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Anode and Cathode before the dark -&#xA;A light emitting diode,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A neural implant, never was,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To trigger years loves, laughter, dreams, memories, hope, passion;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pain, despair, angst, anxiety, fear -&#xA;Fiery Colours of hope always. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Herbert Lawrence: The Freudian who hated industrialisation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-life&#34;&gt;Early Life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David Herbert Lawrence was born on the 11th September 1885 at Eastwood, a poor small mining town near Nottingham. He was the fourth of five children. His father was an uneducated collier who was fond of drinking and having a good time. His mother, on the contrary, was a well-educated retired teacher whose determination and puritanical strength of character greatly influenced her son&amp;rsquo;s psyche. The social difference between D.H. Lawrence&amp;rsquo;s parents was the major cause of the endless quarrels and rows that used to take place in the Lawrence family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caravaggio and the unveiling of truth</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-and-the-unveiling-of-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-and-the-unveiling-of-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each of us is constantly torn between comfortable facade truths, and those deep and real truths that sometimes elude us. For most people, it is relatively easy to keep the uncomfortable aspects of authentic truths hidden. In the case of artists, on the other hand, especially the best known ones, this secrecy is lost because their lives, and their works, are often under the lens of historical and stylistic research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Stop this rape in Ukraine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gruesome rape and torment in Ukraine&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Causing women and children agonising pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Horrific headlines curdles one to the bone.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Russian soldiers have no hearts of their own.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can&amp;rsquo;t they leave the innocent alone?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Women like prisoners tied to a chain,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gory details of Women and babies raped&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s no escape.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bodies of women and children everywhere.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rape is a weapon of war.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The innocent have no sword or spear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only the bloody scar.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers strangle them with hatred,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Is this why you were created?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Innocent lives are wasted.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing sacred.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;How can this evil be tolerated?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s London through the eyes of an old Communist hag</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/2022-london-through-the-eyes-of-an-old-communist-hag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/2022-london-through-the-eyes-of-an-old-communist-hag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communism forbade any dreams of travelling abroad. Apart from going to some other communist countries nearby, one couldn’t imagine any trip to Europe unless they belonged to the upper echelon of the Party. My parents did not belong to the Party at all- minor intellectuals could escape such honour, since they were neither the praised workforce nor dangerous through their profession. I also managed to avoid becoming a member of the Romanian Communist Party, but only for a couple of years - and then in 1989 the Revolution came and many things changed. For me, the most important achievements were the freedom of speech and the fact that my dream of travelling across the borders could finally become true.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petronilla Paolini: Her tragic life and daring poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Up to now, I have mostly shared my impressions on art intended as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/art&#34;&gt;visual art&lt;/a&gt;, examining paintings or sculptures. I have rarely strayed into technical intricacies when writing about art because when I decide to talk about a topic, I do not follow particular selective criteria, I simply rely on my instinct, on the urgency to share emotions and these are almost always solicited by the great works of art history. This time I felt the same solicitations and emotions that I have just mentioned, and I discovered them in part thanks to a casual &amp;ldquo;encounter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocked and Unbolted: Virginia Woolf&#39;s Life and Works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 11:26:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-life&#34;&gt;Early life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Virginia Woolf was born in London on the 25th of January 1882. Her father, Leslie Stephen, was an eminent Victorian critic and man of letters. He was the first editor of the Dictionary of National Biography. He was married twice. His first wife was William Thackeray’s daughter Minny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After her death, he married Virginia’s mother, Julia Duckworth, who was also from an illustrious family. She was a widow and had three children from her first marriage. One of these children, George Duckworth, sexually harassed Virginia later on in life, devastating her psychological stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graffiti through history: 3 magnificent examples</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/3-magnificent-historical-graffiti-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:48:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/3-magnificent-historical-graffiti-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My cultural background and my personal tastes have always made my interests oscillate (also for the purposes of research and study) between figurative and written art. There is a topic that thanks to certain dynamics of realisation and conception, allows me to combine these two main fields of interest in a single analysis: graffiti. In fact, in this &amp;ldquo;category&amp;rdquo;, the testimonies on the wall and the writing often merge into a single genre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doni Tondo: A Visual Analysis of Michelangelo&#39;s Masterpiece</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/doni-tondo-a-visual-analysis-of-michelangelos-masterpiece/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 11:55:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/doni-tondo-a-visual-analysis-of-michelangelos-masterpiece/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doni Tondo, a renowned artwork by Michelangelo, has long been a source of inspiration for art enthusiasts and critics alike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But for me, this masterpiece holds a deeper significance, evoking a sense of personal validation and ego boost. Join me in exploring the depths of Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s Doni Tondo as we analyse its style and history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-was-the-doni-tondo-painted&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When was the Doni Tondo painted&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Doni Tondo, a masterpiece created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/michelangelo/&#34;&gt;Michelangelo Buonarroti,&lt;/a&gt; was painted between 1505 and 1507. Despite being a young artist at the time, Michelangelo had already achieved significant success with his earlier works, earning widespread praise from patrons and the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Curse of Babel: The Drawbacks of Language for Communication and Thought</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 10:54:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biblical story of the Tower of Babel portrays God rather like the trickster Loki, more intent on mischief, than promoting harmony. Surveying the city and the tower that the descendants of Noah had started to build in order to achieve a level of security and prestige, God says: “If as one people, all sharing a common language they have begun to do this, then nothing they plan to do will be beyond them. Come, let’s go down and confuse their language so they won’t be able to understand each other.&amp;quot; (Genesis 11: 6-7) The final touch was scattering the people all over the world. (Genesis 11:8)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doris Lessing: Subjecting a Divided Civilisation to Scrutiny</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 10:40:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doris Lessing was born in Iran on the 22nd of October 1919 to Alfred Cook Taylor and Emily Maud McVeigh. Her parents were both very involved in the Second World War. Her father was an active fighter and her mother was a nurse. It was in this capacity that Emily Maud met Alfred, who had been seriously injured in battle. His leg was, in fact, eventually amputated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doris Lessing spent the first six years of her life in Tehran, where her father worked at the Imperial Bank of Persia. After a brief return to England the family moved to Zimbabwe, which was then known as Rhodesia. There, Alfred invested all his capital on a 3000 acre farm which he hoped to develop. Life in southern Africa was to leave an indelible influence on Doris Lessing&amp;rsquo;s existence and on her written work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The last judgement of Michelangelo Buonarroti</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-last-judgement-of-michelangelo-buonarroti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 11:04:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-last-judgement-of-michelangelo-buonarroti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is amazing how the mind and hands of artists make abstract and elusive concepts visible. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about all those stories whose origins are lost in the mists of time: mythological stories, religious testimonies, legends, which although familiar in terms of knowledge, lack a real visual concreteness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The images chosen by artists to convey their thoughts, their inspiration regarding these stories, become something possible, even real, for us observers. Perhaps it is thanks to these numerous testimonies that have always accompanied us in a more or less conscious way that concepts that are difficult to understand, as they are far from our daily life, become less cryptic and even, as already mentioned, familiar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edward Morgan Forster: Life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 11:17:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Morgan Forster was born in London on the 1st January 1879. His family was typically upper-middle class. Edward Forster senior was a Cambridge graduate architect and Lily, his wife, was the adopted child of a rich family. However, when E.M. Forster was still a baby, Edward, his father, died of tuberculosis leaving his only son in the care of Lily. The child was brought up only by women, a fact which was to influence his formative years. After his father&amp;rsquo;s death, mother and son moved to Stevenage in Hertfordshire. There they lived in a large house in the middle of the English countryside, visited only by Lily&amp;rsquo;s female relatives and friends. Lily and her son developed a deep and loving relationship. In later years Forster wrote that his mother had given him &amp;ldquo;a sort of rich subsoil where I have been able to rest and grow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russian and Ukrainian are often mistaken as the same language, especially by people who have no prior exposure to Slavic languages. This confusion is justified considering that both Russian and Ukrainian use the Cyrillic alphabet, and they both belong to the language family of East Slavic (Slavonic languages). In fact, the only other East Slavic language is Belarusian. Many sources estimate Old East Slavic to have diverged into these three sub-languages as early as the fifth century. This left a large window of time for these languages to develop independently. Historical and geographical aspects have also influenced the development of these languages. This article compares Russian and Ukrainian from a number of linguistic aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Like Rings in The Water: Dante’s impact on Michelangelo</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dantes-impact-on-michelangelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 10:50:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dantes-impact-on-michelangelo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a stone is thrown into the water, the greater the power of the blow, the greater the number of circles produced on the surface. The image of these circles that indicate the passage of the stone in the water, is the symbol that most represents the power of art. In fact, creating a work of art means launching a message whose strength, just like that of a stone, cannot be confined to falling silently into the consciousness of the recipients of the art itself; the impact must generate waves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems For a Better World: This War of MMXXII</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:54:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Invasion for pure greed and gratification.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else can this be?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Civilians, soldiers, casualties dying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In their blood lying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lives are meaningless,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The soul is downcast and sighing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is the battlefield, blood, brutality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Politicians lacking  rationality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aggression, destruction, death and ravished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers and innocent lying on the streets.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Surely logic has perished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The cold carnage continues …&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Unleashed on humanity.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mourning for innocent lives.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who will stop the insanity?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can people not see such torment and tragedy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is only depravity and brutality…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From patriotism to pure poetry: Isaac Rosenberg’s Break of Day in the Trenches</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 11:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The darkness crumbles away&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is the same old druid Time as ever,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only a live thing leaps my hand,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A queer sardonic rat,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As I pull the parapet&amp;rsquo;s poppy&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To stick behind my ear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Droll rat, they would shoot you if they knew&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Your cosmopolitan sympathies,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now you have touched this English hand&lt;br&gt;&#xA;You will do the same to a German&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soon, no doubt, if it be your pleasure&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To cross the sleeping green between.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It seems you inwardly grin as you pass&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Strong eyes, fine limbs, haughty athletes,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Less chanced than you for life,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bonds to the whims of murder,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sprawled in the bowels of the earth,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The torn fields of France.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What do you see in our eyes&lt;br&gt;&#xA;At the shrieking iron and flame&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hurled through still heavens?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What quaver - what heart aghast?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Poppies whose roots are in men&amp;rsquo;s veins&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Drop, and are ever dropping;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But mine in my ear is safe,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Just a little white with the dust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Art for all”: Della Robbia and the glazed sculptures of the Renaissance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/della-robbia-glazed-sculptures-of-the-renaissance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 10:46:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/della-robbia-glazed-sculptures-of-the-renaissance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are living in a difficult historical moment, in which each of us, myself included, in a more or less &amp;ldquo;blatant&amp;rdquo; way, has had the need to talk about covid. In this article, however, I would like to describe how covid spoke to me. Fortunately, I have not experienced the disease, but I have certainly experienced all the restrictions associated with it in a conscious way. The silence and being at home awakened in me memories: images and situations from the past that everyday life had made me put aside. With a different and certainly more mature awareness, I was able to clearly define what is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The master of the Bildungsroman: Leslie Poles Hartley’s life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leslie Poles Hartley was born in England on the 30th of December 1895. He grew up in the relatively peaceful period of Edwardian England. He had an excellent education at Harrow and subsequently at Oxford University. After the outbreak of the First World War, the peace and tranquillity of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trafalgar.com/real-word/definitive-downton-a-guide-to-edwardian-britain/&#34;&gt;Edwardian English society&lt;/a&gt;, which he had been accustomed to, was suddenly disrupted. Hartley joined the army as an officer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was never involved in fighting, but gained a certain amount of experience of the military world. After the war, he became a journalist, reviewing literature for the Spectator, the Observer and other London papers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: When People Gather</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 10:37:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-people-gather&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When People Gather&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news is published everywhere&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It tells us the world is in disrepair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you turn and pretend it&amp;rsquo;s not there&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you consume the news in despair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you say that you&amp;rsquo;re not political&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What a privilege you have, that&amp;rsquo;s not typical!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Things only seem to get worse by the day&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods and plagues, corruption, decay&lt;br&gt;&#xA;While thoughts and prayers might be a gesture&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Stand up, be proactive or the problems fester&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These are man-made issues and ours to undo&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where do we start? You haven&amp;rsquo;t a clue.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Well there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just I can do&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But what if your neighbour thought that too?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And their neighbour thought they didn&amp;rsquo;t matter&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Changes happen when people gather &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/in-english/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s message&lt;/a&gt; is loud and clear&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The earth is for sharing, all welcome here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Caravaggio&#39;s Nativity with Saints Lorenzo and Francesco</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:02:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lost-nativity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lost Nativity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The multiplicity of subjects and themes present in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/&#34;&gt;Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s works&lt;/a&gt; allows me to continue talking about him, through his works, even in the period of the year when each of us could succumb to the easy temptation to choose discounted topics, through clichés. During the month of December we were constantly bombarded with images that create romantic and idealised suggestions. Despite the decidedly muffled atmosphere, I will try to talk with you about the nativity in art trying to maintain a critical, attentive and open attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: An Ode to Environmental Restoration</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 10:20:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ode-to-environmental-restoration&#34;&gt;An Ode to Environmental Restoration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human Beings since the onset of the Industrial Revolution have been obtuse,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The contemporary generation now finds the effects of global warming abstruse. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pernicious effects of climate change are no longer covert, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods, droughts, and forest fires have now become rampant and overt. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The indiscriminate chopping of trees, which we would all agree, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Has pared the earth’s carbon sinks to a substantial degree. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is high time that the words of the environmentalists are heard, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Or our next generations might not hear the chirp of a single bird.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powerful women: The story of Artemisia Gentileschi and her 1639 self-portrait</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-of-artemisia-gentileschi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 09:49:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-of-artemisia-gentileschi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Artemisia, also known as the mugwort flower, is a symbol of gratitude, the leaves of the plant give energy and certainly have nothing to do with addiction to absinthe, a substance obtained from them, which generates addiction when associated with alcoholic substances. Gratitude is the feeling that each of us should have towards every artist. Here, we can also grasp the energy and strength in art through historical information referable to a great woman and artist: Artemisia Gentileschi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Osborne and The Angry Young Men</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 13:59:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our overview of post-war British drama with a survey of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1aFPD3yGlnWubBApVyOyjFgWhXeP1qBShaTKmbLeM_8I/edit#&#34;&gt;Theatre of the Absurd&lt;/a&gt;, let us now look at another important literary movement that developed after the end of World War II. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The end of the war left a sense of discontent and disillusionment, especially with the younger generation. As society developed into a more affluent capitalistic and class-conscious structure, the younger generation became aware that the poorer classes were being exploited and this prompted them to voice their anger. A new class of writers, known as the Angry Young Men, came into being. They were expressing their anger through various literary genres, in particular through prose and drama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Michelangelo to Michelangelo: The story behind Caravaggio his &#34;Death of the Virgin&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have yet reached my own style in writing and I don&amp;rsquo;t even think I want to reach it so as not to end up entangled in webs created by myself. I do not love to rely on chance, but do enjoy spontaneous and sudden thoughts. Precisely for this reason, following what came to my mind as soon as I delivered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/when-art-is-mystery-the-sculpture-of-the-veiled-christ/&#34;&gt;last article&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to continue talking about freedom of expression in art, just as I had already done when talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-perfected-thought-michelangelo-buonarroti/&#34;&gt;Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s Pietà Rondanini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language to Unite, Language to Separate: The Tale of Serbian &amp; Croatian</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:35:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Croatia and Serbia, once brothers united, have experienced many conflicts since the collapse of Yugoslavia in 1991. In fact, conflicts existed even prior to the demolition of Yugoslavia and can even be traced back as a cause for its collapse. Thus, it is worth looking at the role of language in this conflict. More specifically, how the classification of two languages can be utilized as a tool, sometimes even a weapon. We do this by answering the following question: “Are Serbian and Croatian two different languages, or simply two dialects of the same language”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harold Pinter: a mirror for the common people</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 12:50:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last issue we saw how Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/&#34;&gt;developed a new drama&lt;/a&gt; that was characterized by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time: the Theatre of the Absurd. In this issue we shall take a closer look at Nobel Prize winner Harold Pinter, one of the most influential modern British dramatists with a writing career spanning over more than 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayesha Kajee Talks to UN-aligned About Her Poem &#34;Silence&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The second place was awarded to Ayesha Kajee for her poem Silence. The following interview was conducted on the 2nd of November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch the interview here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Read Ayesha&amp;rsquo;s poem “Silence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Silence</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;i&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silence is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Silence is complicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Complicity is violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So in the violence of our silence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let us take stock of our complicity &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;ii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our complicity silences truth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muffles honour, rapes innocence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The same innocence we plead&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Confronted by shattered delusion&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“We didn’t know” &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;iii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wished to not know&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Blinded, deafened, deadened&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We turned away Bedecked ourselves in laurel&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Which now turns to rue &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;iv&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our silence - yours and mine - is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is complicit It is violent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And in its complicit explicit violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We too have bloodied our souls&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Terra Australis Incognita&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Dean Gessie Talks to UN-aligned about his “Terra Australis Incognita”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:40:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The first place was awarded to Dean Gessie for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”. The following interview was conducted on the 31st of October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Read Dean&amp;rsquo;s poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch our interview with Dean Gessie here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Terra Australis Incognita</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;and those black fellas believed these white fellas spirits of their ancestors (pale time travellers of everywhen) and those black fellas received venereal, opium, rum and pox and they returned witchetty grubs, honey ants and fruit bats and the white fellas killed no one with their guns because the new land was called &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (land belonging to no one) and it was fair to say that these white fellas did not include themselves nor irony in their census taking and the captain struck the collarbone of the elder (he that had helped himself to the white fellas shovel) and the aborigine elder embraced the captain and spread his arm to indicate everything he could see and the captain surrendered his shovel of wrought iron just as black fellas shared their axes of polished greenstone and so it was with ropes and stakes and sacred land; these white fellas pushed the black fellas further from the sea, scattered burial totems of coral, red basket and seagull feather and there was bile and spleen between the groups and dead black fellas (females and young, too) and the aborigine elder pushed the collarbone of the captain and the captain knew it was wrong to survey and deed what wasn’t theirs and he was ashamed and he agreed that his voice was no greater than the magpie or the blue winged kookaburra and he negotiated to settle the interior space of &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (that ground that was less hospitable like them) and handcuffs and leg irons fell from the poors and politicals and these made a mountain of metal where everyone was free to piss and the captain cast off his blue jacket and white waistcoat and humbled himself to learn yellomundi (or storyteller) and butbut (or heart) and he was granted initiation by they that met and decided he was ten years old and he was painted with red clay and fat of the wallroo and wombat and he received cuts to his chest arms shoulders and buttocks and sand in each produced voluminous scars and the penis of this white fella was split with a stone knife and a front tooth was knocked out to mark him as community and he danced the tree lion climbing ripping and pulling but laying in peace with brother and sister alike and he sang the songlines that trek creation and he blew didjerry didjerry through termite eucalyptus, pressed his lips to beeswax and shook out grins and guffaws and the black fellas did not call him apostle but he returned his blind eye seeing to the white sails of sirius of the orion and he stayed the cannons and six-pounder guns and his voice was dreamtime and ancestral beings and why it is that men and women walk upright and those that saw and heard were ashamed and they pushed the collarbone one of the other and they agreed against greed to call this place “must be there somewhere land” and it remains so to this day&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Beckett &amp; Harold Pinter: 2 Giants of the Theatre of the Absurd</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/literature/&#34;&gt;the last issue&lt;/a&gt; we saw how some 20th century writers envisioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/&#34;&gt;a dystopian future&lt;/a&gt; in reaction to the two world wars and to the dwindling human values. Protesting against society and the situation of man, but in a different way, were the giants of the Theatre of the Absurd Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter. Both playwrights developed a new drama which was characterised by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Mystery of the Veiled Christ: A Look into the Sansevero Chapel and its Creator</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/when-art-is-mystery-the-sculpture-of-the-veiled-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/when-art-is-mystery-the-sculpture-of-the-veiled-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We empower you to shape the world! &lt;a href=&#34;http://un-aligned.org/the-gordian&#34;&gt;Subscribe to The Gordian for free.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the works that I believe to be wrapped in mysterious perfection, as though made by divine hands, there is the sculpture of the Veiled Christ by Giuseppe Sanmartino in the Sansevero chapel in Naples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As was the case with &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-perfected-thought-michelangelo-buonarroti/&#34;&gt;Michelangelo&lt;/a&gt;, it will be difficult to excel in interpretative originality because this sculpture has reached such levels of stylistic perfection that it has struck and interested many art historians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Titulus as a safe haven: Case Romane del Celio</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-titulus-as-a-safe-haven-case-romane-del-celio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-titulus-as-a-safe-haven-case-romane-del-celio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If talking about what you don&amp;rsquo;t know well is frightening, trying to convey to others what you have studied for a long time with enthusiasm and passion is disorienting, because you proceed with the constant feeling of not saying everything or at least not saying enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Years ago, when I was still a university student, I was deeply impressed by Christian archeology not only as a matter of faith, but because when art is placed at the service of any kind of religion or religious thought, it generates artistic phenomena that involve social edification. Among the various topics covered during the lessons, one in particular remained with me: the tituli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dystopian Novel: &#34;Beyond Utopia&#34;!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dystopian novel developed during the 20th century when the reality of humanity’s volatile condition became evident after both the first and second world wars. The word, dystopia, refers to Utopia, the fictitious name of an ideal country, coined by Thomas More in his famous book Libellus &amp;hellip; de optimo reipublicae statu deque nova Insula &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/2130&#34;&gt;Utopia (1516)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was designed as a political, social and religious system which was not supposed to be reflected in reality, but proposed as an ideal model.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/8-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man stops to smile while playing cards in a town of northwestern Sichuan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Rajasthani man plays music on the street. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man who arranges camel safari tours rests on the desert in Rajasthan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man prepares for a photoshoot in a teahouse in Pengzhen town. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/2-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A woman celebrates New Year in the monastic town of Tongren. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Heritage Committee’s 44th session took place virtually from 16 to 31 July. It covered issues left outstanding since last year, when the annual meeting was postponed due to COVID-19. The extended session was chaired by Tian Xuejun, China’s Vice Minister for Education and Director of China’s National Commission for UNESCO. The session looked at 42 nominations to the World Heritage List (24 submitted for 2020 and 18 for 2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 books, movies and music UN-aligneders want you to dive in!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month we asked our readers to tell us about their favourite books, TV shows &amp;amp; music. This is a list of some their suggestions. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9k=&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;movie-parasite-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movie: Parasite (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gavinski from China says: “I have been meaning to watch this since well before it won the Oscar but never got round to it. Easily the best movie I have seen in years, loved the switch from black comedy to super tense, and its thought-provoking commentary on wealth, poverty and inequality.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfected Thought: Michelangelo Buonarroti</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-perfected-thought-michelangelo-buonarroti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 11:18:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-perfected-thought-michelangelo-buonarroti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The search for perfection, albeit in different ways and forms, has always accompanied man throughout his growth and impacted his socio-historical imprint . Starting from ideas for the improvement and evolution of the most basic aspects of life, such as the perfecting of agricultural or construction techniques, his ambition  stretched to the creation of increasingly perfect buildings and works of art. Although there is no universal concept of absolute perfection, because every judgment or perception of beauty is inevitably conditioned by its own yardstick, I find that everyone in art, in any form of art, can find or express their own idea of ​​perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Why are you talking like that?&#39;: How politicians use words to influence and mislead</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:56:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself agreeing with a politician for no apparent reason? Have you ever thought why many people support a certain politician even though they hold a ‘foolish’ standpoint? Have you ever thought of how language influences people’s decisions in a political environment? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While it is true that humans are complex creatures and clear linear relationships rarely apply in the real world, language usage and perception undoubtedly plays a significant role in the world of politics, especially today where social factors such as gender and ethnicity are gaining more attention. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitzgerald&#39;s Great Gatsby VS T. S. Eliot&#39;s Waste Land: Portraying a dusty vastness where nothing thrives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The situation that plagued the world after World War One was one of callous apathy and emotional aridity. My last article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/&#34;&gt;T. S. Eliot’s poetic portrayal of the early 20th century&lt;/a&gt; ended with the line, “The dehumanisation of the modern world is complete.” This ‘dehumanisation’, which Eliot portrayed as a waste land in his poetry, was also described very clearly in prose by F. S. Fitzgerald in his novel &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The freedom to choose</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following article is taken from a speech given by Carla Pietrobattista on Dante Day, March 25, which is traditionally held as the day the “divine poet” started his masterpiece, the &lt;em&gt;Divine Comedy&lt;/em&gt;. 2021 also marks the 700th anniversary of Dante’s death. The event was presided by the Mayor of Magliano dei Marsi, Pasqualino di Cristofano. Ms. Pietrobattista will also be collaborating on the new Art Section of &lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;, which will start next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the road: The story behind Santa Maria church in Valle Porclaneta</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 09:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The perfect balance and harmony that govern the elements present in the church of Santa Maria in the Porclaneta in Rosciolo, Abruzzo, Italy, tends to arouse one’s curiosity with regards to its origins and history. Although much has already been said by historians and art experts, I firmly believe there are still many secrets hidden in the iconography the church is steeped in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;unexplored-secrets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unexplored secrets&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until now the elements that have found greater exposure in the historical and stylistic examination are the sculptural ones. However, I believe that the paintings in the church of Santa Maria, despite the simplicity of execution of some of them, still have much to reveal. This is particularly true of the triptych placed at the end of the right nave of the church. Here, the Virgin and Child is flanked by St. Michael holding scales in his hands and a saint with a long liturgical robe grasping a chain: St. Leonard of Noblat (also known as San Leonardo de Noblac, from the Latin &amp;rsquo;nobiliacum&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your guide to T.S Eliot poems - April is the cruellest month</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:13:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;T.S Eliot is perhaps the best example of the modern metaphysical poet. Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/&#34;&gt;17th century poet, John Donne&lt;/a&gt;, Eliot veered from the ethereal world of romance and idealisation, to head directly towards a concrete reality through conceits and extended metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His work reflected the upheaval of the social order in the aftermath of World War I, and the failure of all of man’s social, political and philosophical aspirations. On the wake of death and destruction, all seemed to flounder on the crags of a festering humanity that had turned to superficial desires and material gain. Ethical and moral values were reduced to a vast expanse of ash and aridity; a waste land void of any humanity. Humankind had lost its soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Donne&#39;s No Man is an Island: Feeling a Oneness With Humanity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 08:38:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s world besieged by isolationism, America First, Britain First, white supremacy, cyber bullying, homophobia, racism, vaccine tug-of-war, colonialist withdrawal symptoms (… shall I go on?) and the like, never before have the words of John Donne been more relevant; “No man is an island…”. In the age of Brexit, the very notion that every man is part of a greater humanity is a powerful assertion. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the profound conviction that ‘every man is a piece of the continent, a part of the main’ has a far more universal metaphorical significance; a spiritual and existential significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming The Governing Strategies of Ongoing Socio-Economic Development by Way of G-Localization</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Domare-le-strategie-che-governano-lo-sviluppo-socio-economico-in-corso-attraverso-la-G-Localizzazione.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ultimate-goal-and-foregrounding&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimate goal and Foregrounding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this reflection is to create favourable conditions for progress by mobilizing the intellectual, spiritual and material forces with a sense of belonging to one and the same human community. This requires finding new ways of living in society and of facing the future together. Living organisms compete for resources, but collaborate for sustaining life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So You Have Been Called &#39;Laowai&#39;? Here&#39;s What it Means</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 08:56:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Chinese, foreigners are often referred to as &amp;rsquo;laowai&amp;rsquo;, a term that carries different meanings depending on context and perception. In this article, we shed light on the social and cultural aspects of language use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A single person may often be categorized and called in many different ways. I, for instance, may be categorized as ‘Iranian’, ‘Middle Eastern’, ‘brown’, etc. These separations and categorisations typically occur due to cultural differences between two or more groups. A common separation in China is that of a Chinese person and a foreigner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Greatest Metaphysical Poet&#34;: Your Full Guide to John Donne’s Life, Career &amp; Poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;family-background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John Donne was born in London in 1572 to a relatively wealthy family.  His father, who died when Donne was only four, was a successful tradesman and his mother, Elizabeth, was the daughter of the writer John Heywood.  Both parents were Roman Catholics and were in obvious difficulty to come to terms with the newly established Church of England.  Donne’s family, especially on his mother’s side, were persecuted for being Roman Catholics and for refusing to swear the Oath of Supremacy which acknowledged the English monarch as the Head of the Church of England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding conspiracy theories and its victims in the golden age of nonsense</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guarded by some 25 000 troops, Joe Biden successfully took the oath of office. Earlier Mr Ex-President had taken off for Mar-a-Lago. Hopes and dreams were shattered. I felt a rush of compassion for the QAnon believers who felt betrayed realising that nothing happened; no arrests, no intervention. It is bitter to realise that the firm ground below one’s feet has collapsed. The liberating, newly revealed truth turned out to be yet another lie. Yet, the question remains: What were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Pepys: A peep into the life of a gentleman in the Restoration period</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cannot speak of a literary career for Samuel Pepys (1633 -1703), since he wrote predominantly for his own private reading. He is known for his diary which was written in a special code (Shelton’s system of tachygraphy) and was not meant to have been deciphered and read by others.  This naturally makes his account of life during the Restoration period free from prejudice and all the more authentic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diary of Pepys is of paramount importance since it illustrates an informative and unique picture of Restoration life. It is a stunning self-portrait of the middle-class gentleman whose social position exemplifies the Restoration years of readjustment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misgendering people: Identity and Gender Pronouns</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:50:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article does not intend to offend or devalue anyone with a non-binary gender identity. It only tries to explain why fixing misgendering is a larger problem than most people think, and why there is no immediate solution to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-misgendering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is misgendering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Misgendering is the act of using language to describe or talk to a person in a manner that does not align with their affirmed gender, intentionally or unintentionally. This can be in the form of personal pronouns, such as referring to someone as a ‘he’ when they’re a woman or when they do not identify with the male gender, but also through the use of gender specific nouns such as ‘boy’ and ‘girl’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maurice and Sexual Awakening</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:55:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to start a short cycle on love with a work about the “love that dare not speak its name”; the love between two men. Maurice was written by E. M. Forster back in the Edwardian England of respectability and bigotry. Not that any other period in the last few centuries were any more progressive or open minded. As Forster put it, “England has always been disinclined to accept human nature.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Taylor Coleridge: The Supernatural Poet</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coleridge, like Wordsworth, loved nature and together they enjoyed walking in the Lake District, in the heart of the natural surroundings. However, Coleridge also loved the supernatural. His fantastic and mysterious imagination was an infinite source of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was this poetic process of creation that laid the foundations for the haunting scenes of &lt;em&gt;The Rime of The Ancient&lt;/em&gt; Mariner and the visionary surrealistic world of &lt;em&gt;Kubla Khan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Samuel-Taylor-Coleridge-KublaKhan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kubla Khan handwritten sketch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Appropriation: What is the Harm?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wimoweh / The Lion Sleeps Tonight, Memoirs of a Geisha, Karlie Kloss wearing a Native American inspired headdress at the Victoria’s Secret fashion show. Miley Cyrus twerking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The list could be filled with other, more ordinary affairs such as costume parties, authentic Chinese food, yoga, cornrows, ethnic fabrics or chopsticks as hair sticks. The list of examples of cultural appropriation is so long that it became an activity itself to google what kind of results are given for cultural appropriation combined to any non-Western element. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bluster of Arrogance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 12:40:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Popular leaders nowadays seem to owe their success to noise, aggression and self-aggrandisement. I call this the Cassius Clay syndrome. The louder they shout, the more they are respected. The more brazen they are, the more they gain trust. The more they blow their own trumpet, the more credible they appear. This is the leader of our 21st century populist culture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These loudmouths are distorted Machiavellian politicians. Distorted because the ends justified by their means are void of any political or social ideals. Their modus operandi is not based on any strategic acumen, it is improvised and opportunistic. It is sheer megalomania. They wallow in their own narcissism and arrogance, advocating an impoverished makeshift political agenda. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining modern American music: The story of Ruth Crawford Seeger</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:27:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From its early foundations, American music had a European character stamped on it by the American academic musical establishment, which itself was a product of the late 19th century. Before the 1870s, there was virtually no such thing as a music course at the universities; higher educational institutions were reserved for classes in science, history, and languages. Music was a pure extracurricular activity. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rivalry between European training and indigenous American folk sources has always resonated throughout America&amp;rsquo;s history&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women Composers in the Western Tradition</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 17:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The history of western classical music has traditionally been the province of male composers making music for the aristocracy. Rather than due to nonexistence, the absence of women in the standard music histories has been the result of the common practices of musicologists of the past. First of all, many musicologists focused more on the documents of music (manuscripts, prints and treatises) than on the sociology of music. Fewer documents of the music of women or of the lower classes have remained. Second, musicologists have focused on the development of musical styles and the progressive works that engendered new genres. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/&#34;&gt;Most women&lt;/a&gt; were excluded from professional musical positions, which at least partly led to them entering new styles “late”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Klaatu barada nikto”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 16:53:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These words are taken from the classic 1951 film directed by Robert Wise: The Day the Earth Stood Still. The film, based on a short story by Harry Bates, is about an alien, Klaatu, who comes to earth in order to warn humanity of its pending obliteration by an interplanetary police force, unless it mends its destructive ways. The words were uttered to Gort, the robot, after Klaatu was shot. They delivered a stay of execution. Nevertheless, the film ends with the ball in earth’s court; their decision still to be made. We are now in 2020 and it seems as though many of our leaders are still hellbent on pursuing a self-destructive agenda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
