<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wealth at Whistle&#39;s Blow: The Importance of Financial Planning for Athletes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/sports/the-importance-of-financial-planning-for-athletes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/sports/the-importance-of-financial-planning-for-athletes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would you do if you won a million dollars? How would you spend it? It is a hypothetical question often considered when dreaming of the luxuries that come with a large paycheck. Now, imagine being 21 and signing a $100 USD million contract. It is not a lottery prize, but a reality for some of the world’s top athletes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a select few athletes, this hypothetical becomes a reality. In the last decade of sports, contracts in all the major sports leagues have risen exponentially. In 2008, baseball star Alex Rodriguez &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firmex.com/resources/uncategorized/when-did-athletes-start-getting-rich/.&#34;&gt;signed&lt;/a&gt; a historic, 10-year, $275 million contract with the New York Yankees. His lucrative contract garnered attention as the largest contract ever to be signed in North American professional sports.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Table Tennis to the UN: How Kosovo Used Sports for Nation Building</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never before has the nexus between sport and international relations been more prominent than in the last 10 years. Even a cursory examination of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most publicised sporting events from the last decade reveals a clear link between the games and athletes we love to watch and money, power, and strategic international diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports-events-reflect-on-a-nations-best-and-worst&#34;&gt;Sports events reflect on a nations&amp;rsquo; best and worst&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Brazil hosted the FIFA World Cup, aiming to exhibit the beauty and rich culture of Brazil. However, the exciting football was overshadowed by extreme poverty; the inequality highlighted by the slums of Rio de Janeiro and the displacement of thousands to accommodate new stadiums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar 2022: A World Cup for Straight Men</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I wrote an article for The Gordian Magazine celebrating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/lifestyle/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/&#34;&gt;growth of women’s football&lt;/a&gt; in the UK, and hailing 2022 as a watershed year in women’s sport around the world. Now, just a few months later, nothing seems further from the truth. In choosing to host one of the world’s biggest sporting competitions in Qatar this year, a country run on Sharia law and plagued by inequalities, FIFA has let the world know that football remains the domain of straight men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Football: ‘Unsuitable for Women’ or were you just not brave enough to see the vision?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/sports/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:01:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/sports/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that football has a problem with sexism, which is why the Lioness’ (English Women’s football team) victory on Sunday 31st July 2022 at the Women’s European Championship means so much. I am a 23-year-old English woman who grew up playing football, and I had never even thought to dream that I might watch the England Women’s team win whilst 17.4 million people tuned in to watch. Very few did; it simply seemed impossible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
