<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Renewed for September! The free UN-aligned writing course</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join this practical and informative online workshop, which will culminate in a published article in The Gordian.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the space of just five lessons, starting on the first of July, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/adrian-liberto/&#34;&gt;Adrian Liberto&lt;/a&gt;, author, journalist, a former professor at the American University of Rome and current editor-in-chief of the Gordian Magazine, will teach you how to overcome your weaknesses in writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adrian will use his vast reserves of experience and enthusiasm to give you an overall assessment of your writing strengths and weaknesses and how to maximise the former and overcome the latter. This is an unmissable opportunity for anyone looking to sharpen their journalistic skills. After the course you will be offered the opportunity to send your piece for publication in the Gordian, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with UN-aligned&#39;s Language Courses</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 20:46:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally discovered UN-aligned through a post on Facebook and then joined the community as I found it quite interesting and inspiring. I also thought that reading articles of interest, such as those relating to climate change, could help me improve my English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was amazed about the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I desperately need to improve my English, I later also registered onto the English course. My tutor, Adrian, reached out to me soon after, and unexpectedly, this course turned out to be totally free! But what amazed me the most, was the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
