<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 09:50:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the road: The story behind Santa Maria church in Valle Porclaneta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 09:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>carlapietrobattista</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-santa-maria-church-in-valle-porclaneta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The perfect balance and harmony that govern the elements present in the church of Santa Maria in the Porclaneta in Rosciolo, Abruzzo, Italy, tends to arouse one’s curiosity with regards to its origins and history. Although much has already been said by historians and art experts, I firmly believe there are still many secrets hidden in the iconography the church is steeped in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unexplored-secrets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unexplored secrets&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now the elements that have found greater exposure in the historical and stylistic examination are the sculptural ones. However, I believe that the paintings in the church of Santa Maria, despite the simplicity of execution of some of them, still have much to reveal. This is particularly true of the triptych placed at the end of the right nave of the church. Here, the Virgin and Child is flanked by St. Michael holding scales in his hands and a saint with a long liturgical robe grasping a chain: St. Leonard of Noblat (also known as San Leonardo de Noblac, from the Latin &amp;rsquo;nobiliacum&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/Santa-Maria-in-Proclantea-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Times the Russian Orthodox Church Flouted Norms of Decency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the former communist regime, the Russian Orthodox Church (ROC) was suppressed, its properties confiscated and its followers harassed and imprisoned. This was until a Messiah came along. He promised the church fortune, a return to traditional values, a trip to simpler times when the state and church washed filth off each others’ backs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Putin and the Russian Orthodox Church walk hand-in-hand in so many ways. From the eyes of the church he is seen as a “miracle of God”, a humble Russian worshiper who wants to put the Church at the heart of Russia’s national identity. However, the Church is not the only one who has wet dreams; what the ROC knows too well is that they must return the favour. And we all know what the price of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/vlad-the-terrible/&#34;&gt;a deal with the devil&lt;/a&gt; is: selling your soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/John-Chrysostom-with-Basil-of-Caesarea-and-Gregory-of-Nazianzus-on-a-late-15th-century-icon-of-the-Three-Holy-Hierarchs-from-the-Cathedral-of-St-Sophia2C-Novgorod.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lingering Sins of Religion: When books weigh us down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 08:35:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;written-in-stone&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written in stone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of religions in the world today and many thousands more have come and gone. Many of these claim or have claimed a monopoly on truth relating to the divine and the moral, as well as to the rituals necessary to accompany a devout life. No doubt, much good has come from these religions in as much as they have contributed to unifying people around a set of values that have generally been beneficial to society and wellbeing. Often, they coalesce around scriptures that are professed to have been inspired or dictated by heaven itself. The Abrahamic religions, Judaism, Christianity and Islam are very much of this mould. There is only one problem: societies change, but books do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/6.jpg-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
