<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ariana Yekrangi on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/ariana-yekrangi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ariana Yekrangi on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/ariana-yekrangi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Zionist experiment has failed: it must be abolished</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some ideas are not up for debate. They are autopsies. You do not reason with a tumor; you remove it. Zionism, as a political project, is that malignancy, and the state of Israel its grotesque outgrowth. To advocate for a “two-state solution”—a partition of historic Palestine that enshrines an explicitly Jewish ethno-state—is no longer just a failure of imagination. It is moral idiocy: a mumbled incantation over a corpse, serving only to buy the murderers more time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Held Hostage No More’: Harris, Democrats and the Price of Betrayal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/harris-democrats-and-the-price-of-betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 08:47:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/harris-democrats-and-the-price-of-betrayal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First as tragedy, then as farce, and now—an endless cycle of farce, like a bad political rerun that won’t quit. America has rewarded its own worst instincts by returning to office an anti-women, climate-denying, xenophobic figure who has openly admired authoritarianism. This isn’t an anomaly; it’s déjà vu—again. Trump’s re-election isn’t an outlier but a pattern that shatters any pretence of America being better than this. It isn’t, and it’s high time we stopped pretending otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Reaping what you sow’: Why Trump’s assassination attempt is unworthy to steal headlines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/reaping-what-you-sow-why-trumps-assassination-attempt-is-unworthy-to-steal-headlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:14:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/reaping-what-you-sow-why-trumps-assassination-attempt-is-unworthy-to-steal-headlines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Karma often comes with a sting, as the old saying goes. After eight years of stoking division, Donald Trump almost got a taste of the chaos he helped create. He was on the verge of experiencing the kind of horror faced by 378,000 US students who &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/interactive/school-shootings-database/&#34;&gt;have died from guns&lt;/a&gt; since the Columbine High School massacre in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time, Trump nearly found himself in the same dire straits as over 37,000 Palestinians—who lost their lives as he &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-israel-gaza-finish-problem-rcna141905#&#34;&gt;cheered on Israel&lt;/a&gt; to “finish the problem” with bombs proudly stamped Made in the USA, and literally signed off by a Republican cheerleaders in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“We’ve seen this before”: Inside Israel’s war on truth, journalists and the free media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first casualty in any assault is invariably the truth. But what is it about journalists that tyrants find so terrifying? It is the fear of empowerment that comes with knowledge. Despots thrive in the shadows that ignorance casts, manipulating and controlling through a cocktail of misinformation and deceit. Yet, a journalist can spark a flame in our mind, capable of incinerating the very foundations of tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiding the truth is not merely the erratic behaviour of the paranoid or the despotically inclined; it is a clear indication of inherent weakness. A government that stands firm in its legitimacy and moral authority does not flinch at criticism nor recoil from dissent. It is the inherent brittleness of despotic rule that dreads the light of scrutiny, much like a rotten structure teetering on the verge of collapse at the merest prod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Embracing genocide’: How Iranian monarchists are championing Israel&#39;s deadly onslaught on Palestine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:55:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you encounter the rare sight of individuals rallying in support of Israel&amp;rsquo;s actions in Gaza, your attention might be drawn to an unexpected symbol: a variant of the Iranian flag. This particular flag, adorned with the Lion and Sun against a backdrop of green, white and red, harks back to Iran&amp;rsquo;s monarchical past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ensign, displayed alongside Israel&amp;rsquo;s, hails from a time when monarchs reigned over Iran, now seized upon by a diverse array within the Iranian diaspora, particularly those championing freedom in Iran, which includes the monarchists also known as Pahlavis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking away from Gaza will not assuage our conscience; only action will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 08:27:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently, amidst the clinking glasses and idle chatter of a social gathering, I ventured to pierce this bubble. I posed a question to my friends, seemingly simple yet laden with the weight of untold suffering, which asked for their thoughts on the current mass slaughter of Palestinians by Israel; an atrocity that enjoys, astonishingly, the tacit approval—if not outright support—of our governments. One friend, embodying the spirit of our age&amp;rsquo;s indifference, confessed to avoiding the subject altogether. The casual dismissal struck me—not for its rarity, but for its brazenness, as if the very act of engagement with such a grave matter was itself a burden too heavy to bear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone — The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:43:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/v2-issue-3-8-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the February issue of The Gordian Magazine. In this edition, we venture into the depths of a question that has, for centuries, puzzled and provoked: &amp;ldquo;To be or not to be European alone&amp;rdquo;. As we stand at the crossroads of history, the fabric of our collective identity is being stretched and tested by the forces of nationalism and globalisation, each tugging in its direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;No place for the politicisation of aid&#39;: Why the West&#39;s UNRWA fund cuts are nakedly political</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-the-wests-unrwa-fund-cuts-are-nakedly-political/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:38:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-the-wests-unrwa-fund-cuts-are-nakedly-political/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 27th of January, a day after Israel was ordered by the International Court of Justice to take all measures to prevent its genocidal acts in Gaza, Germany, Canada, the UK and six other Western nations joined the US in pausing funding for the UN Palestinian refugee agency (UNRWA). This decision followed Israel’s allegation that 12 UNRWA employees were involved in the October 7 Hamas terrorist attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNRWA, a UN agency founded in 1949 by the UN General Assembly, responded by terminating the employment of the accused individuals and initiating a thorough investigation. Secretary-General António Guterres expressed his horror at the allegations, stating that those found guilty would face criminal prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the backseat of a taxi, a simple chat took a jarring turn, plunging me into a story that is all too common yet often goes untold. My goal was straightforward: to land a full-time role at a publishing house. However, what unfolded was an unexpected confrontation with racial and sexist prejudices — an incident that, though personal, reflects a broader issue pervasive in our workspaces and media today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journey reached a pivotal moment at the end-of-year company dinner party, a gathering that marked the culmination of a challenging yet rewarding internship. Having broached the subject of future prospects with my immediate male supervisor during training and discussed my aspirations with colleagues, I felt cautiously optimistic. However, the evening took an unforeseen turn on the ride home, sharing a taxi with a female supervisor who was less often seen during office hours. Her reaction to my shared ambitions was not of encouragement or guidance but one of anger and insinuation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s 2023 Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:31:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event promises to be a pivotal moment for our organisation, providing a platform for valuable exchanges among our global membership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting is a vital opportunity for each of you to actively engage and contribute to the significant decisions that shape the organisation&amp;rsquo;s future. Your voice and input are crucial in steering UN-aligned towards our shared goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda-and-participation-details&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda and Participation Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date and Time:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The meeting is set for Thursday, December 14th, at 16:00 EET and will be conducted via Google Meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal&#39;s National Parks: A Conservation Success Shadowed by Local Struggles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Nepal, majestic national parks thrive as sanctuaries for wildlife, but for the local communities who are grappling with human rights abuses the path to harmonious coexistence remains fraught with challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The value of protected spaces like National Parks is undeniable. Nepal&amp;rsquo;s journey with these parks began in 1993, when the Forest Act recognised certain &amp;lsquo;protected forests&amp;rsquo; for their environmental, scientific and cultural value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the royal hunting grounds, these spaces have evolved into critical conservation centres, forming a key part of Nepal&amp;rsquo;s forest management strategy. Today, Nepal boasts about 20 such protected spaces. However, while these parks aim for conservation, they also pose challenges, particularly for local communities with restricted access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voices That Shape Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-2-8-Cover-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the gordian magazine cover issue 2 vol 8&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi/UN-aligned&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this issue of &lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;, titled &amp;ldquo;Voices That Shape Nations&amp;rdquo;. In this edition, we delve into the profound and often overlooked role that minorities play in the fabric of nation-building. Our world is a mosaic of cultures, each contributing uniquely to the narrative of history and the shaping of nations. This issue illuminates these diverse voices, offering insights into their struggles, triumphs and enduring spirit in the face of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing Civilian Areas &amp; Killing Children is Wrong. Even for Revenge, Especially for Revenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:54:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grief and fury brew a potent concoction for vengeance in the hearts of those who have lost all. The cycle of violence spirals, each rotation taking it to a ghastly new level. Israeli officials, under the banner of ‘self-defence’, have adopted a scorched earth policy towards Gaza. Yet, the international community&amp;rsquo;s reaction often diverges sharply into one of two markedly distinct viewpoints: unflinching support for Israel and utter condemnation for Hamas, or justifying Hamas&amp;rsquo;s targeted killings as acts of legitimate resistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Constitution: The New Social Contract Inside the October Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As October’s chill sets in, ‘The Gordian’ returns from its brief hiatus with a meticulously curated issue titled ‘Global Constitution: The New Social Contract.’ This edition seeks to weave together the intricate threads of geopolitics, art, culture, and science, presenting a cohesive narrative of our shared global destiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In ‘&lt;em&gt;The Imagined Unity&lt;/em&gt;: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock,’ Alexander Stoney offers an exploration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/&#34;&gt;nuanced concept of ‘Nation’.&lt;/a&gt; This sets the stage for Adrian Liberto’s discourse on the pressing need for a global constitution in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/&#34;&gt;‘&lt;em&gt;The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it&lt;/em&gt;.’&lt;/a&gt; Liberto subsequently scrutinises the UN’s role in the Palestinian crisis in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/&#34;&gt;‘Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Selective Outrage of the Tories: HS2 and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:14:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/the-selective-outrage-of-the-tories-hs2-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rishi Sunak&amp;rsquo;s decision to axe the Birmingham to Manchester segment, packaged as a pragmatic financial choice, has ruffled feathers, not least those of former prime ministers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/David_Cameron/status/1709579002220867922&#34;&gt;David Cameron&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tiktok.com/@dailymailuk/video/7284266548674563361&#34;&gt;Boris Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. Their collective critique, given their individual and joint legacies, is nothing short of ironic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunak, in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/liveblog/2023/10/4/uk-tory-conference-live-news-rishi-sunak-to-address-hs2-controversy&#34;&gt;address to the Conservative party&amp;rsquo;s annual rally&lt;/a&gt;, positioned himself as a radical reformer. His vision of axing HS2&amp;rsquo;s northern leg, introducing a broader Advanced British Standard to replace A-levels, and incrementally banning smoking are audacious moves. Yet, one cannot help but see these as emblematic of the Tories&amp;rsquo; recurring approach: prioritising headline-grabbing policies while seemingly neglecting dire issues such as child poverty, housing and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Armenia’s ICC Pivot: Defying Russia and Eyeing European and Iranian Ties</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unprecedented development, Armenian lawmakers have ratified the Rome Statute, thereby signifying the nation&amp;rsquo;s intent to join the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This development has sent ripples all the way to the Kremlin, which seems less than pleased. Given the earlier move by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;ICC to issue an arrest warrant for Russian President&lt;/a&gt; Vladimir Putin in March, Armenia now finds itself on a tightrope, precariously balancing its long-standing alliance with Russia. This recent gesture by Armenia has not only added a strain to its delicate camaraderie with Russia but also hints at a cautious pivot towards the West for a security umbrella. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: The New Social Contract</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:45:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-1-vol-8-cover-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Gordian Magazine cover reading the global constitution. &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As October&amp;rsquo;s chill sets in, &amp;lsquo;The Gordian&amp;rsquo; returns from its brief hiatus with a meticulously curated issue titled &amp;lsquo;Global Constitution: The New Social Contract.&amp;rsquo; This edition seeks to weave together the intricate threads of geopolitics, art, culture, and science, presenting a cohesive narrative of our shared global destiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;The Imagined Unity&lt;/em&gt;: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock,&amp;rsquo; Alexander Stoney offers a profound exploration of the nuanced concept of &amp;lsquo;Nation&amp;rsquo;. This sets the stage for Adrian Liberto’s discourse on the pressing need for a global constitution in &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rsquo; Liberto subsequently scrutinises the UN&amp;rsquo;s role in the Palestinian crisis in &amp;lsquo;Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contemporary Pottery From the Heart of Esfahan, Iran - In Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:35:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To fully appreciate the artistry presented in this gallery, don&amp;rsquo;t miss our &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/&#34;&gt;interview with the artists&lt;/a&gt; Samira Ghafori and Anahita Ahmadi. Their compelling narratives offer valuable insights that add depth and context to the pieces showcased here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Samira-Ghafori-pottry-7-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Samira Ghafori.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Anahita-Ahmadi-pottery-1-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi. &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Samira-Ghafori-pottery-6-1003x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Samira Ghafori.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Anahita-Ahmadi-pottery-4-892x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sculpting Change: Two Women Reshaping Iran&#39;s Pottery Scene</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whirling hum of the spinning wheel, the rhythm of skilled hands modelling shapeless clay and the mesmerising transformation in the kiln: the world of pottery is one of patience, resilience and creativity. And within this sphere in Iran, two exceptional women, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/samirghafori/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Samira Ghafori&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/anna_clayart/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Anahita Ahmadi,&lt;/a&gt; are shaping more than just clay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samira, an artist who started young, had her destiny intertwined with pottery before she even knew it. Her early fascination with the craft was born out of playful experimentation that evolved into a lifelong commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Pretender: Boris Johnson&#39;s Deceptive Finale to his Controversial Tenure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/boris-johnsons-deceptive-finale-to-his-controversial-tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Behold the curious tale of Boris Johnson, a leader whose exit from the political limelight has been less of a dignified adieu and more of a truculent retreat. Clad in the armour of self-pity, Johnson seems to have recast himself as a tragic hero, wronged by an ‘ungrateful nation’. However, as the curtains close, the audience sees through the artifice, observing a man who, in the throes of responsibility, chose subterfuge over substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In The Fume of Power: The Greed of Giants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-3-vol7-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: UN-aligned design team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the June issue of The Gordian. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since we last connected, and we have been eagerly preparing for our return. Our hiatus allowed us to refocus and recentre our commitment to bringing you insightful, provocative, and poignant articles that not only inform, but incite. We hope you&amp;rsquo;re ready for a feast of thoughtful content, as we are more than thrilled to serve it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love for Erdogan&#39;s Autocracy in the Heart of German Democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recep Tayyip Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s name echoes in Istanbul and Berlin alike. As Turkey&amp;rsquo;s President, he commands attention and drives conversation in both these distinct locales, exerting an influence that, to many observers, seems paradoxical. Despite being in the heart of Europe, where democracy is a foundational value, Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s autocratic approach finds a surprisingly receptive audience within a substantial German-Turkish community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s influence over this diaspora often equals, and at times even outstrips, his hold over his own nation, a conundrum that pushes against traditional ideas about the strength of democracy. But how can an autocratic leader secure such steadfast loyalty from a community residing in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most solid democracies?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Torke&#39;s &#39;Being&#39;: Dreadful Art Cover, Glorious Music</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/michael-torkes-being-dreadful-art-cover-glorious-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 17:24:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/michael-torkes-being-dreadful-art-cover-glorious-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;American composer Michael Torke has once again delivered an album that showcases his unique voice and style, drawing inspiration from jazz and minimalism to create a work that shimmers with vibrant timbrel palettes and infectious energy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finished in 2019, “Being” is a continuous 43-minute composition that consists of nine parts, each building on the previous and creating a hypnotic and immersive experience for the listener.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the music, we need to talk about the elephant in the room – that album cover. It looks like someone typed in “women holding coffee staring into the abyss” on a stock photo website and called it a day. But don&amp;rsquo;t let the questionable art direction deter you, the music inside is worth every quid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Peace Now Secure: Fugitive War Criminal Assumes UN Peacekeeping Chief Role</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:59:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the adage goes, “truth is stranger than fiction”. Case in point: Russia, the very nation embroiled in a relentless war in Ukraine, has assumed the presidency of the UN Security Council, an institution dedicated to preserving global peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add to the absurdity, Russia&amp;rsquo;s top dog, Vladimir Putin, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;slapped with an arrest warrant&lt;/a&gt; by the ICC for his role in abducting Ukrainian children. As we try to make sense of this bizarre twist of fate, one can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if this is an elaborate April Fools&amp;rsquo; ruse, leaving Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s UN mission and countless others befuddled and aghast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Pursues Putin: A Sprinkle of Justice in a World of Mischief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-reality-of-abducted-children-in-ukraine&#34;&gt;Chilling Reality of Abducted Children in Ukraine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Vladimir Putin, seemingly untouchable and unaccountable for countless transgressions, continues to cause havoc in Ukraine, a glimmer of hope emerges from the unlikeliest of origins: the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spark that ignited the fire was a public “thank you” from the Children&amp;rsquo;s Rights Commissioner, Maria Alekseyevna Lvova-Belova. She &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2023/02/16/putins-childrens-envoy-reveals-she-adopted-child-from-mariupol-a80249&#34;&gt;expressed gratitude to Putin&lt;/a&gt; for enabling the “adoption” of a young boy from Mariupol, unwittingly revealing the chilling reality of Ukrainian children torn from their homes and subjected to “re-education camps” or forced adoptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair&#39;s Fair: Entitlements Are Not Charity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-2-vol7-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Greetings, dear readers, and welcome to the newest edition of The Gordian Magazine. We are excited to present to you a collection of insightful and engaging articles that are sure to stimulate your mind and expand your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our cover story this month is penned by Adrian Liberto and titled &amp;ldquo;Bridging the Wealth Gap - A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication.&amp;rdquo; Through this piece, Liberto challenges the dominant economic system of the 21st century and offers a ray of hope for those who are trapped in the cycle of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diving Into the Enigmatic World of Deep Sea Creatures – A Photo Essay</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenging conditions of the deep sea, life thrives in this surreal world. The pressure can be unfathomable, temperatures can plummet to subzero, and darkness is all-consuming, yet a vast array of life forms, ranging from bioluminescent jellyfish to colossal squids, showcase exquisite diversity and beauty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deep sea is an enigmatic and mesmerising environment that never ceases to amaze us with its extraordinary inhabitants. Join us as we embark on an extraordinary expedition to the unfamiliar, as we unravel the wonders of the deep sea and the creatures that inhabit it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s views on strikes in England: Laying the blame where it should be</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government&amp;rsquo;s treatment of workers and Unions asking for a fair pay rise during a cost of living crisis has been shameful. Nurses, ambulance drivers, paramedics, and other frontline workers have been demonised and blamed for the country&amp;rsquo;s economic woes, despite their tireless efforts to keep the country running during a global crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, those who have actually caused the economic damage – such as the former prime minister who blew a £30 billion hole in the economy overnight, the shambolic execution of Brexit that is estimated to have cost the country over £40 billion, the Tory government’s botched test and trace programme which costed £37 billion, their wasteful procurement of PPE resulting in £8.7 billion being wasted and ending up in the pockets of Tory donors and Richie Sunak’s decision to spend £11 billion by overpaying interest on UK debt – are allowed to escape accountability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mick Lynch Named as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure to announce that Mick Lynch, the secretary-general of the RMT trade union, has been named the UN-aligned Person of the Year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This award recognises Lynch&amp;rsquo;s dedication to advancing the interests of working class people and fighting against issues of economic inequality and injustice. His efforts have earned him widespread admiration and attention, with many hailing him as a hero for our times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-mick-lynch&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is Mick Lynch?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mick Lynch is the current General Secretary of the British national Union of Rail, Maritime and Transport Workers (RMT), a labour union representing over 83,000 members across various sectors of the transport industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raising Utopia: Brick by Brick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-1-vol-7-1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;© UN-aligned Design team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ring in 2023! Even though it carries with it most of the serious problems associated with 2022, such as war, disease and climate disasters, we hope that at least some of these issues will be dealt with more competently in the next 12 months! We want to be able to report and write about happier stuff… ringing in a brighter and fairer world!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fight to Eliminate Jiggers Disease - In Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-fight-to-eliminate-jiggers-disease-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-fight-to-eliminate-jiggers-disease-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warning: Some of the photos in this gallery may be disturbing to some viewers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our photo gallery on Jiggers Disease in Marsabit, Kenya. Marsabit is a town located in a deprived part of Kenya, facing issues such as starvation, lack of water and disease.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amongst these issues is the devastating problem of Jiggers Disease, caused by tiny fleas known as jiggers that burrow into feet and lay eggs, multiplying until the feet and legs become swollen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Transcending the Moon, a Democratic Encounter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this story, we postulate an interview with the representative of a more advanced civilisation; and within this setting, novel visions are juxtaposed to some of our pressing problems. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/&#34;&gt;Learn more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could scarcely believe that I was about to embark on such a venture. The prospect of meeting an otherworldly being – a genuine extraterrestrial – was almost too fantastic to contemplate. And not just any alien, mind you, but the Dengilaun ambassador to our very own Moon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utopian Ideas from an Alien Society: Conversations with the Dengilauns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is excited to unveil a new series of short stories that will be featured in our upcoming volume, with a theme of Utopia. This series is an innovative and experimental form of storytelling that combines key utopian ideas with elements of science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our mission at the magazine is to promote the message of UN-aligned, which works towards creating a more effective and principled United Nations. This new series aligns with that mission by exploring the possibilities of a better world that upholds human rights, animal welfare, and environmental protection. These stories will take readers to imagined worlds where these values are prioritized and where current societal issues have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is citizen journalism and there is The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world that moves at a dizzying speed, UN-aligned and The Gordian have stayed true to their values, fighting for a better UN and bringing our readers the insights and information they need to stay informed and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the editor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian magazine,&lt;/a&gt; I reflect upon the past year with both gratitude and concern. On the one hand, I am grateful for the dedication and hard work of our team, whose members have produced high-quality, fact-based, impactful journalism that has provided clarity and imagination in an unprecedented year. On the other hand, I am concerned about the numerous challenges and crises that have impacted our world in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iranian Government: How is it structured?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the Assembly of Experts to the Guardian Council, learn about the complex process of electing the Supreme Leader of Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-supreme-leader&#34;&gt;The Supreme Leader&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the hierarchy stands the Supreme Leader of Iran. As this position is considered a life tenure post, there have only been two supreme leaders since the formation of the Islamic Republic of Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Muqtada-al-Sadr-and-khamenei-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Iranian supreme leader, Ali Khamenei&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iranian supreme leader, Ali Khamenei&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN votes on a fact-finding mission into Iran, but don’t look at it too closely</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the United Nations is not busy declaring French baguette a world cultural heritage or hosting awkward diplomatic cocktail parties where everyone pretends to like each other&amp;rsquo;s national dishes, it dedicates a small portion of its resources to protecting human rights across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in November, a fact-finding investigation into human rights violations in Iran, where hundreds have died and tens of thousands have been detained since protests started in September 2022, has been approved by the UN Human Rights Council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enough is Enough: Time to Enforce Justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/the-Gordian-Magazine-issue-6-vol6-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the December issue of the Gordian Magazine. In this edition, we have a range of thought-provoking and informative articles for our readers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main theme of this volume is still justice. In particular, we discuss how to effectively enforce it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As usual, the Gordian begins with our monthly recap containing news items you may have missed in November 2022. In a separate article, we also introduce the winners of this year’s Nobel Prize in physics, chemistry, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Leaked file uncovers how the Iranian Revolutionary Guards plan to quell protests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basij commander warns media organisations against talking about the recent unrest in Iran and advising them to refer to the rising opposition &lt;strong&gt;using terms such as &amp;ldquo;conspiracies&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;collusions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revolutionary Guards have &lt;strong&gt;received a list of Iranian football&lt;/strong&gt; fans who participated in World Cup from Qatari officials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IRGC has used the country&amp;rsquo;s participation in the 2022 World Cup as a &lt;strong&gt;distraction from the widespread protests.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hacking group named Black Reward has published the audio file of a confidential meeting between Basij commander Qasem Qoreyshi and media managers close to the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC) that took place on the 15th November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about ‘Utopia’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-the-new-lady-justicehttpsun-alignedorgthe-gordian-magazinegordian-may-issue-vol-6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet The New Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Meet-The-New-Lady-Justice-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine, issue 1, volume 6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In issue one, we critised the traditional image of lady justice. Her blindfold is supposed to symbolise impartiality, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world? We said no more and introduced our readers to a new Lady Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dismantling the war machine: Inside the October Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian rolls on with its messages of peace and light and respect, but notwithstanding, the world seems to be getting darker and more troubled. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate disasters are no longer the exception, while the threat of a nuclear apocalypse is more real than it ever has been. Giving in is not an option. On the contrary we must double our efforts to combat all that is a threat to the dignity and wellbeing of humanity and the survival of earth’s multifaceted manifestations of nature. Being marginally involved with organisations like UN-aligned is no longer enough. Each and every one of us needs to do more, both as individuals and as part of our communities, be they local, or global like UN-aligned. For want of a nail the shoe was lost… then the horse, the rider, the message, the battle and finally, the kingdom. We are that nail, but we have been led to believe that our input is insignificant. It isn’t. So The Gordian will continue to roll on with your support and inspiration: a platform for the sharing of ideas and information and a launchpad for exiting ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zahhak to the Islamic Republic of Iran: Has Ferdowsi prophesied the future of the republic?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:21:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zahhak was the evil king of Mesopotamia who conquered Iran and, together with his army and serpents that grew out of his two shoulders, terrorised the people of the land for thousands of years. It all started when in order to congratulate the new king on his new position, the embodiment of evil, known in the Book of Kings as Ahriman, disguises himself as the royal cook and asks to kiss the new king’s shoulders. Zahhak agrees and moments after Ahriman’s lips touch Zahhak’s shoulders two black snakes emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dismantling the war machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-5-vol6-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian rolls on with its messages of peace and light and respect, but notwithstanding, the world seems to be getting darker and more troubled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate disasters are no longer the exception, while the threat of a nuclear apocalypse is more real than it ever has been. Giving in is not an option. On the contrary we must double our efforts to combat all that is a threat to the dignity and wellbeing of humanity and the survival of earth’s multifaceted manifestations of nature. Being marginally involved with organisations like UN-aligned is no longer enough. Each and every one of us needs to do more, both as individuals and as part of our communities, be they local, or global like UN-aligned. For want of a nail the shoe was lost&amp;hellip; then the horse, the rider, the message, the battle and finally, the kingdom. We are that nail, but we have been led to believe that our input is insignificant. It isn’t. So The Gordian will continue to roll on with your support and inspiration: a platform for the sharing of ideas and information and a launchpad for exiting ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Annual General Meeting 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 19:46:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s 2022 Annual General Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is also an opportunity for you to express yourself and play an active role in the major decisions of the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below you will find the agenda and instructions on how to participate in this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off with the head! Getting Rid of Phoney Justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:20:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Executing a human being and punishments like solitary confinement are as coldblooded and premeditated as murder and torture can get. They are not in self-defence, because the danger has passed. It is not justice, because a person can always outweigh their deeds, and they can change, given the chance. The theme of this series is still justice and in this issue, we are looking at it from different angles, including those phoney ones imposed on the guilty with little or no respect for their welfare and human right. This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews and culture by UN-aligneders across the world, including Ruby Goldenberg, Carla Pietrobattista, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, Victoria Davila, Partho Chatterjee and Maya Bearyman, Cristina Mihailescu, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Atika Harba and Sonia Roopnarain. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU and Justice: Inside the July Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 10:09:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the July 2022 issue of The Gordian. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was obvious to most that civilisation shall have had to deal with far more than a war of aggression after one of Putin’s casual malign interferences around the world morphed into an unscrupulous war in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/ukraine/&#34;&gt;Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. A social and economic crisis was, perhaps, expected. Four months on, however it is clear that we are heading towards far worse: an orgy of human rights violations spearheaded by unsavoury governments and bureaucrats who are supposed to protect the rule of law and human dignity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-acquis-communautaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Acquis communautaire&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acquis Communautaire is the EU rule book that protects all member states&amp;rsquo; citizens under the rule of law. Fun fact, if you read two pages of this EU treaty an hour, without any breaks because duh, stuff your dinner plans, you’ll be through it in just 4.5 easy years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ginormous legal textbook, which consists of 35 chapters within &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2001:0645:FIN:EN:PDF&#34;&gt;80,000 pages&lt;/a&gt;, is a combination of all European legislation, including all treaties, directives and regulations established by the EU&amp;rsquo;s institutions, as well as all decisions rendered by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and Moldova&#39;s EU candidacy status… beneficial?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 08:52:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-ukraine-and-moldova-are-granted-candidacy-status-does-that-mean-they-are-members-now&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ukraine and Moldova are granted candidacy status, does that mean they are members now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If only it were that easy! Based on a recommendation from the European Commission, the European Council can grant Candidate Status to prospective members of the European Union. The right to join the block, however, is not one that is automatically granted to countries who receive a candidacy status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the European Council decides to begin accession negotiations with the candidate country, the Commission evaluates the application in light of the Copenhagen criteria, which we will talk more about below, and formulates an opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU&#39;s Struggle with Justice: Is the Cart Before the Horse?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:43:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the July issue of The Gordian. The European Union is a remarkable institution, but the callous exclusivity of the block has risked making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. The “Golden Curtain” of Europe is turning it into a fortress, a type of Noah’s Arc that cares little or nothing for the lives of others. In this issue, we will focus on justice across the European block.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland’s troubled history with Russia — A Story in Photos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:36:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-february-manifesto-and-the-russification-of-finland-1899&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The February Manifesto and the Russification of Finland (1899)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The February manifesto was part of the larger operation of the Russification of Finland during which Finnish territories were forced to align their cultures with that of the Russian empire. On the 5th of February 1899, Nicholas II of Russia, the Tsar of Russia, defined a new legislation order that asserted the imperial Russian government to rule over Finland without the consultation of the Finnish Senate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Is history repeating itself so soon?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:30:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/issue-2-vol6c-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another month and another warm welcome to a new issue of The Gordian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In keeping with our theme for this series on justice, we will be focusing on appeasement. Apart from the article about forfeiting somebody else’s justice that tackles appeasement head on, the issue is also highlighted in our articles in the UN in Focus section and alluded to elsewhere, including the campaign we have been working on over the last few months, namely, trying to bar countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from being given seats at the United Nations Human Rights Council. We can proudly announce that the letter has been sent to the UN to coincide with Pride Month and it has been supported by the many signatures of organisations and individuals alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three UN conventions on the laws of the sea and how they are failing to secure it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:50:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-convention-on-the-law-of-the-sea&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982, the third United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) was adopted after nearly 26 years of attempts to replace the archaic “freedom of the seas” concept, which dated all the way back to the 17th century. The convention came into force in 1994 and established rules governing the uses of the oceans and their resources. Essentially encapsulating traditional rules for ocean use in a single instrument while also introducing new legal concepts, as well as addressing new concerns that arose with modern times. Some notable developments ushered by the convention include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet The New Lady Justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Meet-The-New-Lady-Justice-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the May 2022 issue of The Gordian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is largely accepted that Lady Justice’s blindfold symbolises impartiality. Despite the accepted wisdom however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our cover article “The new Lady Justice with an eye on Ukraine”, Adrian Liberto addresses a failing world order and exchanges Lady Justice’s appearance for one that is more suitable to the needs of modern times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical: The Gordian Magazine enters Vol. 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 09:03:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having covered social topics in the last few issues of The Gordian, in May we will be moving on to a series that will focus on law and order. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics will range from international law and treaties to general crime and punishment. We will also be exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical, which are two very different animals. After all, most of the world’s problems today are caused by activities that are more or less legal everywhere, such as intensive animal farming, extraction and consumption of fossil fuels, suppression of human rights and exploitation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Square Holes For Square Pegs: Revamping The Education System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:29:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to April’s issue of The Gordian! This issue offers the usual mix of politics and culture, with our main focus this time being on education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adrian Liberto’s article, &lt;em&gt;Education’s Paradigm Shift,&lt;/em&gt; sets the scene with a revolutionary critique of traditional schooling and a vision of a more dynamic system for the future. Jihan Al-Assad’s article further highlights hurdles in education with a first-hand account of the specific problems Syrian refugee students face trying to learn in ill-equipped camps, where the situation has now been further exacerbated by the coronavirus. This article is complemented by another by Jihan that covers the hardships of refugee life in general. Our interview (Ruby Goldberg/Noor) also relates to education and describes the difficulties faced by pupils at the mercy of a system that is quite foreign to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on UN-aligned’s open letter to the United Nations Human Rights Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 11:11:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second half of 2021, we launched an &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;Open Letter&lt;/a&gt; to the United Nations Human Rights Commission requesting that countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights be barred from forming part of the commission. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, the letter has been signed by over a dozen LGBT+ organisations from around the globe, as well as individual activists. We originally planned to send the letter on 22 February 2022. However, owing to the latest developments in the United Nations and the ongoing war in Ukraine, we have decided to postpone the open letter as otherwise it would be sounded out by these tragic events. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At last, European Unity Prevails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 10:28:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We stood by and watched Putin help deliver both Brexit and Trump. We were quite happy letting him tear Syria apart. So what, he invaded Donbas? He is a cold-blooded murderer? “What then? poor beastie, thou maun live!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Putinism required diplomacy”, that’s what diplomats said anyway. It was obvious to most, at the time of each of these hammer blows, that Putin’s tentacles had penetrated through and influenced our democracy. Our response to this despot for his crimes? The occasional sanctions here are there. Don’t get me wrong; although they are increasingly becoming the bulwark of our international system, sanctions can work. But they won’t if we are too paralysed by indecision, or when we are at crossroads with ultra-complex choices: utilising green energy, on the one hand, or continuing importing Russian gas during a climate emergency, on the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crying Havoc: Putin unleashes the dogs of war</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the March 2022 issue of The Gordian Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“War is an unacceptable way of resolving differences, or crimes committed by one country against another. It should not be glorified with epithets like ‘just’ or ‘holy’; nor should it be legitimised with conventions aiming at damage limitation.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/in-english/#:~:text=and%20clearly%20stated.-,Article%206%3A%20War%20must%20be%20criminal%20offence.,-Reasoning%C2%A0&#34;&gt;Article 6&lt;/a&gt; of UN-aligned’s manifesto is unequivocal when it says that “war must be a criminal offence”. Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is a blatant breach of international law and UN-aligned strongly condemns it. Countries can no longer be allowed to use the term ‘soldier’ or ‘patriot’ to justify the deployment of people to commit crimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world stands up to Putin’s bloodthirsty antics — in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/London-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-%E2%80%94-in-pictures-1024x576.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London:&lt;/strong&gt; Russian Embassy London - Ukraine Anti-War Demonstration CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/London-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;London protests against war in Ukraine. Photo: Garry Knight/Flickr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Russia-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x813.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protests against war in Ukraine in Moscow. February 24th, Moscow. Tverskaya street. CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Berlin-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x684.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine solidarity protest Berlin Pariser Platz with lighted Brandenburg Gate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Wroclaw-Poland-2-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protests in Poznań - against Russian agression in Ukraine. Photo: Bohdan Bobrowski/Flickr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Wroclaw-Poland-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protest in Wrocław, Poland and solidarity with Ukraine on February 24, 2022 CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The painful history of Ukraine — A photo timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ukraine’s fate may be rooted in its heartbreaking past. In this photo timeline, which consists of more than 35 photos and 12 painful events, we’ll guide you through the county&amp;rsquo;s tragic history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukrainian-war-of-independence-1917-to-1921&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukrainian War of Independence (1917 to 1921)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 1917 to 1921, with the invasion of Bolsheviks, a series of conflicts and battles led to the establishment of the Ukrainian Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Ukrainian-War-of-Independence-1917-to-1921--1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A patriotic demonstration in Kyiv, Ukraine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;holodomor-1932-to-1933&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holodomor (1932 to 1933)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holodomor, meaning to kill by starvation, is another dark chapter in Ukraine’s history. It is widely believed that the famine was orchestrated by Joseph Stalin to impose collectivism and tamp down Ukrainian nationalism. Hunger was so common that the Soviet regime convicted more than 2,500 people for cannibalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Standing up for the planet&#39;: An interview with climate activist Partho Chatterjee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:46:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Partho Pratim Chatterjee, a citizen of India and a member of UN-aligned. I hail from the mineral rich eastern state of Jharkhand. I am an engineer by profession and working in the capacity of Co-Founder and Technical Advisor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adityabioinnovation.in/&#34;&gt;Aditya Bioinnovation&lt;/a&gt; Private Limited, Nagpur, India. I have a keen penchant for eco-friendly technologies which include clean nanofluids, clean energy and clean transportation. My hobbies include penning poems and biodiversity exploration. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity islands with the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/celebrity-islands-with-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/celebrity-islands-with-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many may not know, but the United Nations is the creator of some of the worst “&lt;a href=&#34;https://media.un.org/en/webtv&#34;&gt;reality TV&lt;/a&gt;” of all time. Whether they are shows about a climate convention where the organisers forget to invite representatives from countries that are literally drowning, as was the case with COP26, or an ongoing show about five thugs who think they have a monopoly on truth, sit at a horseshoe-shaped table and maintain international peace by telling everyone not to go to war without their permission, even though that’s exactly what every single of them has done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five benefits of legalising drugs that may change your perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-decriminalisation-of-drugs-mean-vs-what-does-it-mean-to-legalise-drugs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does decriminalisation of drugs mean VS&lt;/strong&gt; what does it mean to legalise drugs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about decriminalising all drugs, within a legal framework, we don’t necessarily refer to them being legalised. In other words, drug ownership and personal use would itself still be legally prohibited, but violations of those prohibitions are deemed to be exclusively administrative violations and are removed completely from the criminal realm. Ideally, we want the legalisation of all drugs, however, decriminalising them could also be an attractive short-term solution. Here are five arguments for legalising drugs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sex, Drugs and Rock &amp; Roll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to February’s The Gordian!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short month, but an issue brimming with provoking reads. As always, the title reflects the some of the themes we will be covering and it comes from a 1969 article in Life magazine by Edward Kern: “The counter culture” he wrote, “has its sacraments in sex, drugs and rock.” Of course, it was Ian Dury and the Blockheads who made the phrase famous with the 1977 song &lt;em&gt;Sex &amp;amp; Drugs &amp;amp; Rock &amp;amp; Roll&lt;/em&gt;. “Counter culture” sums it up really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council meeting on Ukraine Review: Abstaining Romance and Plenty of Hot Air</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tensions between Russia and Ukraine have been mounting for weeks now and for some reason, everyone expected that this particular Security Council session would narrow the wide divide between Russia and the so-called West. Of course, there’s nothing wrong with being pessimistic, but it is a fool who watches the same episode and expects a different ending. Here are three of the main sides of the argument presented during the Council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is circumcision abuse?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:43:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written: Adrian Liberto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Video: Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are in a position to help, please consider supporting The Gordian Magazine with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/thegordian&#34;&gt;Patreon subscription&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/&#34;&gt;Read the article published on the website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/register/&#34;&gt;Contribute to the Gordian by writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French and UK authorities are being sued, Merkel retires and Honduras gets its first female leader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcast/french-and-uk-authorities-are-being-sued-merkel-retires-and-honduras-gets-its-first-female-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcast/french-and-uk-authorities-are-being-sued-merkel-retires-and-honduras-gets-its-first-female-leader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thegordian/embed/episodes/French-and-UK-authorities-are-being-sued--Merkel-retires-and-Honduras-gets-its-first-female-leader--Monthly-Recap-e1ceajd&#34; height=&#34;102px&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border Bullies: Weaponising citizenship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;editorial&#34;&gt;Editorial&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;letter from the editors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last year was a cold bath for those who believed there were simple answers to complicated problems. Don’t be surprised if the new one is pretty much the same&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January 2022 issue of The Gordian Magazine! A new year and a new outlook: Like every month we gathered the best from UN-alignders from all across the world for you to read, 100% free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 17:43:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far we have managed to do without any financial support, however, as the organisation has grown our need for fundraising has become more and more crucial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in November — The Gordian Monthly Recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-november-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-november-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thegordian/embed/episodes/The-Gordian-Monthly-Recap-Everything-you-may-have-missed-in-November-e1bk6ej&#34; height=&#34;102px&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What have YOU done for Justice this year?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription&#34;&gt;Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/the-gordian-preview-1024x640.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can now now support the publication of the Gordian Magazine with a monthly subscription.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s first Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 11:19:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned’s first AGM was held on Wednesday, November 24th, 2021, at 19:30 - 20:30 (EET) on Google Meet. The proposals included in the agenda of UN-aligned’s AGM, together with this invitation, the NGO’s Financial Statement and the Auditor&amp;rsquo;s Report are all available on this page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s first Annual General Meeting. The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayesha Kajee Talks to UN-aligned About Her Poem &#34;Silence&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The second place was awarded to Ayesha Kajee for her poem Silence. The following interview was conducted on the 2nd of November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch the interview here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Read Ayesha&amp;rsquo;s poem “Silence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Terra Australis Incognita&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Dean Gessie Talks to UN-aligned about his “Terra Australis Incognita”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:40:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The first place was awarded to Dean Gessie for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”. The following interview was conducted on the 31st of October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Read Dean&amp;rsquo;s poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch our interview with Dean Gessie here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federalism &amp; Social Cohesion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/poetry-competition-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;terra-australis-incognita--silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition&#34;&gt;“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp;amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “Silence”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social ills equation... Minus inevitability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:55:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster… it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we cover various social issues ranging from rough sleeping to poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about “social issues”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month marks the last issue of the 4th Volume of the Gordian Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it may not seem like much, to date we have published more than 25 issues of the Gordian, all of which can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;accessed for free&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Words cannot express how grateful we are to the generous support of our writers, contributors and, you, our readers. Thank you for using this magazine as a platform to express your ideas for a better and fairer world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Heritage Committee’s 44th session took place virtually from 16 to 31 July. It covered issues left outstanding since last year, when the annual meeting was postponed due to COVID-19. The extended session was chaired by Tian Xuejun, China’s Vice Minister for Education and Director of China’s National Commission for UNESCO. The session looked at 42 nominations to the World Heritage List (24 submitted for 2020 and 18 for 2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 books, movies and music UN-aligneders want you to dive in!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month we asked our readers to tell us about their favourite books, TV shows &amp;amp; music. This is a list of some their suggestions. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9k=&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;movie-parasite-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movie: Parasite (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gavinski from China says: “I have been meaning to watch this since well before it won the Oscar but never got round to it. Easily the best movie I have seen in years, loved the switch from black comedy to super tense, and its thought-provoking commentary on wealth, poverty and inequality.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing up to The Dystopian Tide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-un-aligned-poetry-competition-2021&#34;&gt;The UN-aligned poetry competition 2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/poetry-competition-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition. Photo freepik&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the international literature day on the 8th of September, UN-aligned will be holding a poetry competition open to everyone. The application is open from 1.08.2021 and finishes on 08.09.2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applicants will be informed about the decision during the last week of September. The finalist(s) poems will be featured in the Gordian Magazine&amp;rsquo;s October issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this competition is to creatively portray the values which UN-aligned’s Manifesto campaigns for. The competition aims to highlight the importance of the creation of a different kind of a United Nations as well as the promotion of human rights, animal welfare and environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does Antonio Guterres&#39; re-selection mean for the United Nations? — Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcast/what-does-antonio-guterres-re-selection-mean-for-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcast/what-does-antonio-guterres-re-selection-mean-for-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/the-un-aligned-writing-course/&#34;&gt;Sign up to UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s free writing course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plunging into the ocean of UN communiques is like drowning in an alphabet soup. Often, the words are noble, the causes honourable. Occasionally they even make a difference&amp;hellip; and yet the members of this mighty club behave like undisciplined children who delight in doing just as they please.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this month&amp;rsquo;s episode of the Gordian in Audio we&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about António Guterres&amp;rsquo; ambitions and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 UN Secretariat Offices explained in 10 minutes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/8-un-secretariat-offices-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/8-un-secretariat-offices-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Secretariat consists of the personnel of the United Nations, with the Secretary-General as its head. It is estimated that as of 2021, more than 35,000 people are employed by the United Nations. Currently, the Secretariat consists of about 30 departments and offices. In this article, we will take a look at some of the most interesting ones (you can find a full list of them at the end of this article). &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edward Mortimer was wrong about the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/edward-mortimer-was-wrong-that-about-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 10:50:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/edward-mortimer-was-wrong-that-about-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Edward Mortimer, the chief speechwriter for Kofi Annan, passed away at the age of 77. He was described as “one of the lively minds surrounding the Secretary-General, given license to think and experiment at a time when the future of the United Nations was being written anew”. We wish his friends and family our deepest condolences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, however, we would like to point your attention towards a peculiar speech he made to the Oxford Union in 2017 defending why &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IZm5iBZkiT8&#34;&gt;the United Nations is not a failing institution.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Just Let Them Eat Fudge...&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fervid-summer-share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows--music-with-our-international-readers&#34;&gt;A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp;amp; music with our international readers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Share-your-favourite-books-TV-shows-music--1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by CandiceP/Pixabay&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More and more people are using their free time in summer to relax and enjoy a good book, movie, TV show or a piece of music.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligneders are from all across the world. We currently have members from over 24 countries, so we are certain that curating a list of your favorite entertainment will help inspire our international community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Pay no heed to the hippie”: Filippo Grandi, UNHCR chief, ignored once again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The globally displaced rose from 79.5 million in 2019 to 82.4 million by the end of 2020, a near 3 million increase. This is as the G7 decides to take no action whatsoever. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UNHCR says that the number of refugees around the world has hit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unhcr.org/refugee-statistics/&#34;&gt;a new high&lt;/a&gt;, this is in spite of the pandemic, a time in which over 160 countries closed their borders. More than a third of those who fled abroad came from just five countries: Syria (6.7 million); Venezuela (4 million); Afghanistan (2.6 million); South Sudan (2.2 million); Myanmar (1.1 million). Many more are expected to have been displaced within Africa due to conflicts in Mozambique, Ethiopia and the Central Sahel region. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Jean Arnault and what can he do about the Afghan peace talks?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Secretary General António Guterres appointed the Frenchman Jean Arnault as his envoy covering Afghanistan and regional issues. Mr Arnault is expected to support the negotiations and implementation of any agreements between the Taliban and Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jean Arnault is a former philosophy student with an extensive working background in United Nations missions in Asia, including Afghanistan, Europe, Latin America, and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No doubt his outstanding &lt;a href=&#34;https://cic.nyu.edu/content/jean-arnault&#34;&gt;experience&lt;/a&gt; in international diplomacy will bring a massive force behind the Afghan peace talks, and although we wish him all the best, it must be said that the UN&amp;rsquo;s political response to this conflict has been largely uninspiring. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 5 new non-permanent members of the UNSC for the term of 2022-2023?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/who-are-the-five-new-non-permanent-members-of-the-unsc-for-the-term-of-2022-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/who-are-the-five-new-non-permanent-members-of-the-unsc-for-the-term-of-2022-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Final tallies earlier this month showed that Albania, Brazil, Gabon, Ghana and the United Arab Emirates (UAE) were elected as the five new non-permanent members of the United Nations Security Council.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new members elected this year will be taking up their seats on 01.01.2022 and will serve for 1 year, until 31.12.2023. Four out of the Five new members have served on the council before: Brazil 10 times; Gabon and Ghana 2 times, while Albania has never served as a member. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help safeguard the access of Palestinian children to health services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/help-safeguard-the-access-of-palestinian-children-to-health-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/help-safeguard-the-access-of-palestinian-children-to-health-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Palestinian health authorities, during the recent clashes between Israel and Gaza, at least 254 Palestinians including 66 children were killed. This is while more than 1,900 are reported to be wounded. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 30 years, the Palestinian Children’s Relief Fund (PCRF), a nonpolitical humanitarian relief organisation, has provided the children of Gaza with free medical care. However, on the 17th of May, their main Gaza office was arbitrarily targeted by the Israeli military. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Led by extremists, bombed by extremists - Gaza in the midst of insanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your past is in front of your eyes, it’s 2014, 2012 and 2008 all over again. You cannot escape it, visual reminders are scattered all over the city. Being bombed back to the middle ages seems to be a recurring theme in Gaza. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history concerning the Israel and Palestine conflict is complicated. What is not at all complicated, however, is whether or not it is admissible to airstrike civilian areas, news buildings, health facilities or Covid labs. Whether or not it is acceptable to take away life should not be a controversial issue, one would hope. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Abandon all hope ye who enter here”: The shitshow that is the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-shitshow-that-is-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 11:49:57 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-shitshow-that-is-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-unsc-becoming-obsolete&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the UNSC becoming obsolete?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, it is not that the Security Council (UNSC) is no longer fit for purpose, it has never really been designed to fit its purpose. In 1946, after the League of Nations ceased its operations, the Security Council was invested with most of the power of the brand new organisation, the United Nations. The five winners, let’s face it bullies, of the war, none of whom possessed any moral authority, were tasked with one noble purpose: to advocate peace. What could possibly go wrong with tasking a group of warlords with the maintenance of international peace and security? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewed for September! The free UN-aligned writing course</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join this practical and informative online workshop, which will culminate in a published article in The Gordian.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the space of just five lessons, starting on the first of July, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/adrian-liberto/&#34;&gt;Adrian Liberto&lt;/a&gt;, author, journalist, a former professor at the American University of Rome and current editor-in-chief of the Gordian Magazine, will teach you how to overcome your weaknesses in writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adrian will use his vast reserves of experience and enthusiasm to give you an overall assessment of your writing strengths and weaknesses and how to maximise the former and overcome the latter. This is an unmissable opportunity for anyone looking to sharpen their journalistic skills. After the course you will be offered the opportunity to send your piece for publication in the Gordian, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law &amp; Disorder at The United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-in-focus---may-2021-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN in Focus - May 2021: The good, the bad and the ugly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/UNINFO1-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good-battling-for-universally-affordable-and-available-vaccines&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good: battling for universally affordable and available vaccines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://undocs.org/en/E/C.12/2021/1&#34;&gt;Statement&lt;/a&gt; on May 11 calling for COVID-19 vaccines to be universally affordable and accessible. The five-page document covered all the main issues comprehensively and with refreshing lucidity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Statement starts by highlighting the fact that everyone has the right “to enjoy the benefits of scientific progress and its applications” and proceeded to lament “the current unhealthy race among States for COVID-19 vaccines, which has created a sort of temporary monopoly by some developed States of the first vaccines to be produced.” This is underscored by the fact that current production capacity is at its limit in as much as stocks are already sold out through public procurement by such States. This has created an unacceptable situation of “health isolationism”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the ICJ and the ICC our answers to international justice? - Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/are-the-icj-and-the-icc-our-answers-to-international-justice-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/are-the-icj-and-the-icc-our-answers-to-international-justice-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN in Focus: Holding the United Nations Accountable to UN-aligned’s Standards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-in-focus-holding-the-united-nations-accountable-to-un-aligneds-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-in-focus-holding-the-united-nations-accountable-to-un-aligneds-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations is not just any organisation. It is meant to be the organisation par excellence, it is meant to represent humankind. However, the UN spreads itself so thinly it is no wonder that it struggles to meet many of its commitments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We would like to introduce you to a new feature in The Gordian Magazine. Every month an exclusive piece will highlight the good, bad and the ugly of the events in the UN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates to the UN-aligned manifesto that you need to review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 01:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We believe the flexible roadmap of UN-aligned’s manifesto presents a safe trajectory for a united world, so as UN-aligned grows we are always seeking to refine, clarify and improve our goals and missions. The following changes have been made to the UN-aligned manifesto as of May 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-regarding-our-mission-statement&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updates regarding our Mission statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We refined the language around our mission statement, namely regarding our vision to create an alternative to the United Nations. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whose Justice?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto-that-you-need-to-review&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updates to the UN-aligned manifesto that you need to review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Updates-to-the-UN-aligned-manifesto-that-you-need-to-review-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 2021, UN-aligned board decided to update the language around some of the items in its manifesto. You can review all the edits here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe the flexible roadmap of UN-aligned’s manifesto presents a safe trajectory for a united world, so as UN-aligned grows we are always seeking to refine, clarify and improve our goals and missions. The following changes have been made to the UN-aligned manifesto as of May 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Ways to Create a Healthy Economy with Kate Raworth - Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:36:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kate Raworth first introduced her visual representation of what a healthy economy could look like in a 2012 OXFAM discussion paper titled: &amp;ldquo;A safe and just space for humanity: can we live within the doughnut?&amp;rdquo; The doughnut represented the safe space where humanity could thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits, namely our social and planetary boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raworth’s 2017 book develops the idea further. The seven “ways” she explores are simple, well researched, grounded and achievable. Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/the-doughnut-economy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDP is an impostor, so why are we still using it to measure happiness?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-PIL-non-significa-nulla-di-concreto-quindi-perche-lo-utilizziamo-ancora-per-misurare-la-felicita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GDP is not a suitable measurement for happiness or welfare. It sucks. Assessing the economy using GDP is destroying our planet. The global community and the United Nation’s sustainable development solutions network (SDSN) need to find other suitable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, the SDSN, an initiative operating under the auspices of the United Nations, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/happiness-trust-and-deaths-under-covid-19/&#34;&gt;publishing a yearly report&lt;/a&gt; on how happy the world is. Embarking upon this fundamentally subjective and unquantifiable quest is no easy task and although the SDSN has significantly improved its methods to measure happiness throughout the years, it still has a long way to go before becoming perfect. This year the report used a host of different criteria to grade the happiness of a nation, these included: gross domestic product per capita (GDP), social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make your own life choices, generosity of the general population and perceptions of internal and external corruption levels. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easter doughnuts: reshaping the global economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-doughnut-economy-humanity-to-thrive-sandwiched-between-its-inner-and-outer-limits&#34;&gt;The Doughnut Economy: &amp;ldquo;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Doughnut-Economy-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Doughnut Economy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-LEconomia-della-Ciambella.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Sanction or Not to Sanction?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-you-listen-people-are-always-willing-to-talk---a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat&#34;&gt;“If you listen, people are always willing to talk” - A conversation with photographer Anwar Sadat&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/IMG_0228-copy-2-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 15th of February 2021, the 2020 UN-aligned photo competition winner, Anwar Sadat, tells us about the story behind his prize-winning photos and his love for photography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat&#34;&gt;Read the article →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-powerful-panacea-the-sanctions-dilemma&#34;&gt;A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/United-Nations-Security-Council-03.03-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Times the Russian Orthodox Church Flouted Norms of Decency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the former communist regime, the Russian Orthodox Church (ROC) was suppressed, its properties confiscated and its followers harassed and imprisoned. This was until a Messiah came along. He promised the church fortune, a return to traditional values, a trip to simpler times when the state and church washed filth off each others’ backs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, Putin and the Russian Orthodox Church walk hand-in-hand in so many ways. From the eyes of the church he is seen as a “miracle of God”, a humble Russian worshiper who wants to put the Church at the heart of Russia’s national identity. However, the Church is not the only one who has wet dreams; what the ROC knows too well is that they must return the favour. And we all know what the price of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/vlad-the-terrible/&#34;&gt;a deal with the devil&lt;/a&gt; is: selling your soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine New Series: Doughnut Economy, Davos Agenda and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-new-series-the-doughnut-economy-the-davos-agenda-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:57:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-new-series-the-doughnut-economy-the-davos-agenda-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Il-mese-prossimo.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Human Right Series of the Gordian comes to its eighth issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions. It is because of you that The Gordian Magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last eight issues we covered key human right topics. You can find all topics below. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Winners of the UN-aligned Photo Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/announcing-the-winners-of-the-un-aligned-photo-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/announcing-the-winners-of-the-un-aligned-photo-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to say thank you to everyone who took part in our Photo Competition! There were many fantastic entries with some awesome inspiring photography. As per rule of the contest, we have selected two winners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1st-prize-winner-anwar-sadat-swaka&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st Prize Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Anwar Sadat Swaka&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Anwar-Sadat-Swaka-2-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the streets of kibera, normal daily life goes on. Mama Maria as she is popularly known because of her daily religious attire, confidently makes her way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hijacking Religion to Down Human Rights...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed January 202&lt;/strong&gt;1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Africa-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Italian_-What-you-may-have-missed-in-Jan-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Scores of villagers were slaughtered by suspected Islamist terrorists in coordinated attacks on two villages near the border with Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. Incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadera was declared the winner of the presidential election that was held last month against a backdrop of unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05/06.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;DRC Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. A ferryboat carrying over 70 people capsized on Lake Kivu. About 50 people were rescued and the bodies a woman and two children found. Twenty or so people are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How cultivated meat can save the planet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animal agriculture is a major contributor to greenhouse gas emissions; it is driving up climate change, antibiotic resistance, deforestation and the resulting biodiversity loss. It is also an incredibly inefficient, as well as immoral, way to feed the planet. For example, in the United States alone, 56 million acres of land are used to grow feed for animals, while only 4 million acres are cultivated to produce plants for humans to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time for a change: Welcome Veganuary!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed December 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Featured-images-Jan-2021-1200x630-copy-1-1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. The top court rejected former President François Bozizé’s bid to run for president in the December 27 election against incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadéra. The former president failed to meet the ethical standards required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ghana&lt;/strong&gt;. Results of the presidential election held on Monday have confirmed a narrow victory for incumbent President Nana Akufo-Addo. His main rival was ex-President John Mahama. Supporters of both candidates took to the streets following delays in the announcement of the results and at least five people were killed in the unrest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy vs Anarchy: Which one is better?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 11:52:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winston Churchill once said: “Democracy is the worst form of government except for all others.” But was he right? This article about democracy vs anarchy offers different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years, democracy has become a defining characteristic of the West and its politics. This has even developed to a point where we are talking about &amp;ldquo;exporting&amp;rdquo; democracy to the non-Western world, falsely assuming, of course, that democracy is a perfect form of governance that enables societies to elect competent leaders through the votes of often uninformed citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – December Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 18:37:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-november-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.11.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 50 villagers, most of them women, children and elderly people were slaughtered in a rebel attack in the Oromia region at the weekend. The Oromo Liberation Army (OLA) is suspected of having carried out the barbaric attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.11.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ivory Coast&lt;/strong&gt;. The electoral commission confirmed President Alassane Ouattara won a disputed third term with an overwhelming majority. Most of the opposition, however, had boycotted the election. Anger at the elections spilled into the streets resulting in over 30 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to UN-aligned members: Ask your government to take immediate action against the looming hunger crisis affecting millions of people worldwide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/ask-your-government-to-take-immediate-action-against-hunger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 11:22:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/ask-your-government-to-take-immediate-action-against-hunger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/&#34;&gt;In a recent publication&lt;/a&gt;, UN-aligned joined the voices of organisations, like Oxfam and the WFP, in warning against a hunger catastrophe already targeting millions of children and adults in the world’s most vulnerable places. The good earth is rich and can provide for everyone and in our world of plenty, no one should have to suffer hunger or malnutrition.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solid frame-work the sustainable development goals provided during the last decade is threatened by an awful melange of disasters, such as Covid-19 and climate change. If no action is taken, many lives will be lost. Some estimates by Oxfam suggest up to 12,000 people could die every day as a result of hunger. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is the UN-aligned Person of the Year?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:50:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is excited to announce a new opportunity for its readers to nominate any individual or organisation whom they believe deserves more attention for championing their cause. Although the prize can go to literally anyone, we encourage you to think twice before nominating dictators, fascists or possibly your grandmother. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we have received the final results, we will shortlist your submitted names. An appointed executive committee, who will consist of UN-aligned staff and editors of the Gordian, will decide on the final winner. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to prevent the 2021 food crisis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 09:45:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many will face horrific hunger if relief efforts are not stepped up in a world heated by coal, infected with Covid-19 and separated by nationalists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, 193 countries lined up behind a comprehensive and ambitious set of targets – also known as the Sustainable Development Goals – to transform life and the planet by 2030. Contrary to most UN agreements that are ignored and unheeded by the member states, the project was more than a political platitude and successful on many fronts: extreme poverty fell dramatically and child deaths halved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – November Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:16:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-october-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EUROPE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;UK&lt;/strong&gt;. The EU has set in motion legal proceedings against the UK after it reneged on sections of its Brexit “divorce” deal. Talks, however, are set to continue. The UK was given until November to respond to EU concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;Greece&lt;/strong&gt;: The neofascist party Golden Dawn was declared a criminal organization for its role in a series of attacks on migrants and left-wing activists. &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; called it the “biggest trial of fascists since Nuremberg.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – October Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:40:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-photo-competition-announcement&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned Photo Competition Announcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1.-2-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is holding its first photo competition from today &lt;strong&gt;7th October 2020&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;15th of November 2020.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this competition is to visually and creatively portray UN-aligned’s Manifesto. The competition aims to highlight the crucial link between human rights, the environment, animal welfare and the health of our ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The jury, which is composed of professional photographers, will be looking in particular for creative photos that successfully illustrate the articles of the manifesto. You may look for inspiration in our Manifesto here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Zsuzsanna Jakab: Why is it so difficult for the WHO to take a non-political approach towards Taiwan?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:55:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Dr. Zsuzsanna Jakab, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that laid the foundations for an alternative United Nations, which aims to serve people, before nationstates. Although we regularly campaign for reforms to the United Nations, particularly with regards to its structure and principles, we are also involved with other issues, such as human rights, animal welfare and environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus pandemic has become the defining global health crisis of our time and the greatest challenge we have faced since the Second World War. Since its emergence last year, the virus has spread to every continent. UN-aligned greatly admires the tireless work of the WHO and its dedication to catalysing global and national responses to this and other serious health crises. However, this pandemic has become more than an unprecedented tragedy. Recently we have received questions from our members about the relevance of the WHO’s principles and its ability to serve everyone, regardless of their country’s membership status in the United Nations. On behalf of our members we would therefore like to ask you the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Future We Want and the UN We Need”: The UNGA Debates of 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-future-we-want-and-the-un-we-need-unga-debates-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:55:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-future-we-want-and-the-un-we-need-unga-debates-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-united-nations-general-assembly-debates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the United Nations General Assembly Debates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year, in September, all 193 Member States of the United Nations who are represented in the General Assembly come together to discuss a wide array of international issues covered by the Charter of the United Nations, such as development, peace, security and international law.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;un-aligned-will-be-watching-the-developments-of-this-event-closely&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned will be watching the developments of this event closely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the live blog from last year’s United Nations General Assembly (UNGA), Adrian Liberto and I summarised some of the most important speeches that unfolded during this four-day event. We even &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/united-nations-critic/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/&#34;&gt;awarded some of the speeches&lt;/a&gt; for their courage and relevance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – September Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-september-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 09:42:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-september-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed: August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Cameroon&lt;/strong&gt;. In a vicious grenade attack targeting a camp for displaced people, as they slept, suspected Boko Haram militants murdered over 16 people and wounded several others in the village of Nguetchewe, northern Cameroon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Tanzania&lt;/strong&gt;. Tundu Lissu, an opposition politician who survived being shot 16 times in an assassination attempt, will challenge President Magufuli in the October elections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mauritius&lt;/strong&gt;. A state of emergency has been announced after an oil spill from a damaged Japanese ship is contaminating vast tracts of water. Baby tortoises and rare plants from an island near the spill, Ile aux Aigrettes, are being taken to the mainland to protect them from the worsening situation. The ship had struck a reef on July 25.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I want UN-aligned to be a place where people can come together without being judged&#34;: Interview with Katharina Wüstnienhaus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/get-to-know-our-members-katha-from-germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This interview is part of an ongoing series about our members and how they wish to take charge of UN-aligned and use it as a beacon for hope and change. If you wish to participate in these interviews, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question: Tell us a little about yourself Katha. What is your background? Where do you live? What are some of your hobbies and things you are passionate about?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am from the westernmost part of Germany, only a bike ride away from the Netherlands. I have recently quitted my job in Berlin because I wanted to travel; unfortunately, this just happened when the Covid-19 pandemic hit us, so I decided to move back home and stay here instead. I enjoy music, being surrounded by nature, travelling and making friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hagia Sophia: National Sovereignty is not the Issue, Erdogan Likes to Play the Blaming Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:26:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cathedral first, then a mosque, and later a museum. Last week, Istanbul’s Hagia Sophia became a mosque once again; an insular act for Turkey’s Erdogan to flex his political mussels and to fuel his posture of indignation and grievance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The president knows casting cultural divides resonates with many of his support base, inside as well as outside of Turkey. He boosts his popularity and draws strength from his constant tussle with domestic and foreign foemen. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The OSCE Minsk Group is Unfit to Conciliate Between Azerbaijan &amp; Armenia over Nagorno-Karabakh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1992, two years before the war between the neighbouring Armenia and Azerbaijan ended, the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), met in Helsinki and decided to chair negotiations towards a peaceful political settlement for the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The body, also known as the Minsk group, is led and co-chaired by the US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt; and France with Belarus, Germany, Italy, Portugal, The Netherlands, Sweden, Finland, Turkey, Armenia and Azerbaijan as participating member states. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – August Issue, vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-august-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:46:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-august-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-to-ashin-wirathu&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter to Ashin Wirathu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2-1024x538.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhante Ashin Wirathu,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that focusses on the need to replace the United Nations with a more effective and principled organisation, although we also work to promote human and animal rights, as well as the welfare of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Institutionalised religion has had a sad history in a number of countries around the world owing to its bigotry and abuse of power. Many spiritual people, including some of our members, have therefore looked to Buddhism as a beacon of justice and openness. This image has been tainted over the last few years by portrayals of monks leading a crusade against the Rohingya inhabitants of Myanmar. The contradiction here reminds many people of the darkest periods of some of the leading world religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Become a Voluntary Ambassador</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/become-a-voluntary-ambassador/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:02:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/become-a-voluntary-ambassador/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All articles in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned manifesto&lt;/a&gt; are important, but it is only natural that we will feel more attached to some rather than to others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are particularly passionate about one of the articles in the manifesto, we would like you to consider becoming a voluntary Ambassador for that specific article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task will involve taking the standard and campaigning for that particular issue, with the full force of the organisation behind you. You will be giving guidance on how best to carry out this mission, as well as ongoing support. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protestors: When is it OK to Hit them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When is it OK to hit a protestor? Is protesting during a global pandemic a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has rarely been any positive social changes without some form of protest. Too often the establishment is seen grappling on to power by fostering a dominant discourse from which dissident and minority views are excluded. At best, protests today are characterised as a disruption and inconvenience and, at worst, a threat to a vaguely-defined national security. Political leaders and the majority they may represent, blame these warriors of justice for lack of character and accountability, even though, ironically, those are the very flaws &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; are being accused of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – July Issue, vol 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-july-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 18:38:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-july-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-starts-campaigning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned Starts Campaigning&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is proud to announce the launch of a series of campaigns in line with its manifesto. We will be covering a range of issues concerning human rights, the environment and United Nations reform, and we will be reporting on them in The Gordian, as well as on our website. Our campaigns will start by targeting blatant disregard to clearcut issues of social or environmental justice by powerful corporations, organisations or individuals. We will be highlighting their shortcomings and asking them to take positive steps in order to improve their undertakings in line with a fairer and safer world. For instance, we will be contacting the Arab League and holding it to account for blocking UN initiatives to protect LGBT rights and we will be challenging the Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu and asking him to consider how he can justify preaching hatred against the Rohingya, when this goes against every tenet of Buddhist belief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Appoints New Senior Administrator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-appoints-new-senior-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 13:02:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-appoints-new-senior-administrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ms-ruby-goldenberg-the-new-un-aligned-administrator&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Ruby Goldenberg: The new UN-aligned Administrator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Ruby Goldenberg has been appointed as the new Senior Administrator of UN-aligned with a mission to propel the NGO into the next stage of its evolution and to strengthen its activism and presence on the global stage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexia is a qualified lawyer with a history of working in the legal sector and financial services. She also has a  background in administration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am delighted to welcome Ruby Goldenberg to the UN-aligned management team. I had the privilege of working with Alexia in China, so I am well aware of the dedication she has for her duties and her determination to get things done thoroughly and efficiently. Alexia has an international outlook and is currently living in Moscow. She will be a great asset to UN-aligned and its mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Adrian Liberto, UN-aligned Coordinator&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Human Rights Series – There Must be no Monopoly on the Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-new-human-rights-series-there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-new-human-rights-series-there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the Environmental Priorities Series comes to its sixth and last issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions. It is because of you that The Gordian magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are incredibly proud of this achievement and will continue our efforts to improve this resource with the support of our members and contributors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – June Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-june-issue-vol-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 19:20:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-june-issue-vol-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-human-rights-series---there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Human Rights Series - There Must be no Monopoly on the Truth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Us-Versus-Them-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;The New Human Rights Series &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Environmental Priorities Series comes to its sixth and last issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions; it is because of you that The Gordian magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas. We are incredibly proud of this achievement and will continue our efforts to improve this resource with the support of our members and contributors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian - May Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-may-issue-vol-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 11:00:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-may-issue-vol-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned becomes one year old!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is one year old this month! The seed was sown some years ago in China and developed thanks to the dedication of like-minded people. We have gone from 22 Foundation Members to hundreds of followers from around the world: some are full members, others are subscribers, while many follow us on Facebook. To all our supporters, we wish to offer a big THANK YOU!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Become a Voice in UN-aligned and The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 10:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is a community-supported publication that aims to provide a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge on important issues such as human rights, animal welfare and environmental preservation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past year, we have &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/&#34;&gt;reached over 30,000&lt;/a&gt; readers and have worked to give a voice to diverse groups and shed light on important issues such as conversion therapy and abuses of power. We have also provided exclusive coverage of the United Nations, holding the organization accountable to its principles and working towards a more just, equitable, and sustainable future. In addition to our serious coverage, we have also provided some fun and joy to our readers through our coverage of culture and the arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian - April Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:07:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;facing-the-covid-19-together---letter-of-encouragement-to-gordian-readers&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facing the COVID-19 Together&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Letter of Encouragement to Gordian Readers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Gordian readers,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, we have found ourselves in extraordinary and unprecedented times. The COVID-19 pandemic has made our human interconnectedness clearer than ever before. While we know that no obvious solution lies ahead, we are certain that our best response relies on solidarity, bilateral collaboration and the very thing that makes us humans: compassion and respect for life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to the way our readers will be experiencing the Gordian magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/changes-to-the-way-our-readers-will-be-experiencing-the-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 15:40:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/changes-to-the-way-our-readers-will-be-experiencing-the-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far The Gordian magazine has been presented in a PDF format sent to your email on a monthly basis. While this may have been perfect for readers who printed our magazine on traditional paper or those who used computer devices with bigger screens, such as laptops or tablets, mobile users often had to pinch and zoom on a specific section of the page in order to see a paragraph of text. For this reason, we have decided to change the way The Gordian magazine is presented for a temporary period of time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – March Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-magazine-march-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:26:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-magazine-march-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-across-the-world-you-may-have-missed&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News across the world you may have missed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/image-9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MALAYSIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahathir Mohamad, Malaysia’s interim Prime Minister said that seeing as an agreement could not be reached on his replacement, parliament would vote to pick a new Prime Minister; failing that, a snap election will be called.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAMBODIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists are warning that millions of people who depend on the Mekong river for their sustenance are at risk. Dams being built by China are only part of the problem. Dredging the riverbed for sand to use in construction is causing the river to erode its banks and inhabited and cultivated areas with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An end to the “Fairytales of Eternal Economic Growth”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:35:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 27th February, a British appeals court ruled that a planned expansion of Heathrow airport is unconstitutional because the planning process was not in accordance with the government&amp;rsquo;s own climate policies set out in the Paris Agreement. Lords Justice Lindblom, Singh and Haddon-Cave ruled that when setting out their support for the measures in their National Policy Statement (NPS), the government did not take adequate account of its contribution to the Paris Agreement on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defining modern American music: The story of Ruth Crawford Seeger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:27:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From its early foundations, American music had a European character stamped on it by the American academic musical establishment, which itself was a product of the late 19th century. Before the 1870s, there was virtually no such thing as a music course at the universities; higher educational institutions were reserved for classes in science, history, and languages. Music was a pure extracurricular activity. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rivalry between European training and indigenous American folk sources has always resonated throughout America&amp;rsquo;s history&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Citizenship Amendment Bill: a Death Knell for Indian Secularism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2019 the Government of India, led by the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), secccesfully amended a bill to the Citizenship Act of 1955, offering amnesty to non-Muslim illegal immigrants, who arrived in India prior to 2004. These immigrants must be able to prove that they are citizens of one of the three neighbouring countries: Pakistan, Bangladesh or Afghanistan. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;half-the-truth-is-often-a-whole-lie&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half the truth is often a whole lie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spokespeople of the Indian Government have repeatedly claimed that the new law intends to give sanctuary to people fleeing religious persecution. While this is certainly the case, the dubious decision to exclude Muslim refugees from Myanmar, Sri Lanka, and China; or in fact, the Hindu Tamils from Sri Lanka, raises questions about the Government’s sincerity. The timing of the bill is also not inadvertent; In August, the Assam State, located in the North-East of the country, witnessed two million of its residents left off the Citizen Register; this essentially left thousands of people, suspected of being illegal residents, in temporary camps which are housed in the state&amp;rsquo;s prisons. Modi and his Home Minister, Amit Shah, the mastermind behind the Citizenship Amendment Bill (CAB), have been eroding and attacking the social identity of the Indian Muslim community from as early as 1992 and the CAB was undoubtedly brought forth with an intent to adversely affect the political identities of this community. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the recent conflicts in Syria could shape its future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:46:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although people are long used to the erratic twists and turns of Donald Trump, his decision to sell the Kurds down the river by withdrawing American troops from Syria caught everyone by surprise. Whether Trump was right to extricate his forces from Syria remains debatable, but just as there is rarely a good time to start international military interventions, so there is rarely a good time to discontinue them. One would have thought that Libya’s and Iraq’s ongoing atrocities would have made this clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Assembly that is stuck in time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:09:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year we took it upon ourselves to go through every speech of the United Nations General Assembly and brief you about the most important updates. In doing so, we got to hear some of the most bold and exciting statements from leaders around the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe that the President of El Salvador’s speech was courageous, effective and to the point and thus, deserves the prize of the best statement of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s view on the climate protests: the days of self-serving governments are over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:22:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;were-at-war-with-nature-if-we-win-were-lost-hubert-reeves&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re at war with nature. If we win, we&amp;rsquo;re lost&amp;rdquo; Hubert Reeves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the level of CO2 emissions reach their highest level in 10 million years, children and adults,  from an estimated of 185 countries, unite across continents and time-zones to demonstrate against politicians’ incompetence in dealing with this extraordinary challenge of our time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These protests come at a time when the Amazon forests are being burnt to ashes, a “biological annihilation” of wildlife is in sight and the consequences of melting ice in Greenland is about to give birth to a whole new group of internationally displaced people: climate refugees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing empties the top resorts of Biarritz like a shark attack; or a G7 summit - a guide to what happened at the 2019 summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:10:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of thorny topics were on the agenda this year. Some of the key issues included: foreign policy, trade and, of course, climate change. Let’s start with the last one shall we?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;climate-change-and-oceans&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change and oceans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While world leaders gather around the table to endorse a new charter on biodiversity and renew their commitments to the Paris Agreement, the climate-denier-in-chief, Trump, didn’t feel like attending these talks. He’d rather focus on trade, he says. The Metz Charter on Biodiversity attempts to boost efforts to stop biodiversity loss and sustain life on the planet. This is certainly welcomed, but we can, and should, do more in a much faster way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need your help</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/we-need-your-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:33:27 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/we-need-your-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is slowly, but surely, taking its place in the world arena of politics. We are also increasingly being criticised by different sides of the political spectrum. We love constructive criticism as this helps us develop and refine our mission. However, most objections simply imply that UN-aligned is “too idealistic.” This should fuel us all the more and encourage us to create stronger unity amongst ourselves. Together, there is nothing to stop us from creating the basis for a true United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Women are allowed to ride bikes – just not in public” Khamenei’s fatwa: another nail in the coffin of women rights in Iran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:19:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bike-campaign&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bike campaign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the autumn of 2015, a young environmentalist in Arak, a city with pollution levels as staggering as those in Tehran, started a “car-free Tuesday” campaign to encourage people to commute by bike. The campaign soon turned popular with municipal authorities across the country beginning to encourage residents to ride bikes and leave their cars at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Women cyclists, naturally, saw an opportunity to support a good cause that everybody in Iran could agree on: clean air. They thought they could cycle like other male citizens if they respected Iran&amp;rsquo;s strict dress code, which requires women to cover their hair and body in public. The campaign was soon aborted after a group of female cyclists were detained in the western city of Marivan following criticism from the city&amp;rsquo;s Friday Prayers leader. The women were released the same day, but only after they signed pledges not to cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Month in UN-aligned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/last-month-in-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 23:37:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/last-month-in-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the global political scene is beginning to look more and more like a Theatre of the Absurd, UN-aligned has become an alternative platform for many to turn to. This is not surprising; long lasting peace and prosperity can only be achieved with the kind of values and principles that UN-aligned advocates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last month, UN-aligned continued to grow, develop and change according to the needs of its members: we now have an exciting design for the user’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;dashboard&lt;/a&gt; interface, a brand new logo and, finally, we are starting the creation of our own UN-aligned App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Launched Successfully!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-launched-successfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:43:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-launched-successfully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday’s successful launch marks a new milestone in the world of politics, getting us ever closer to a world that works for and belongs to everyone. What makes this event so important is that UN-aligned doesn’t aim to make changes within our broken political systems, but aims to change the global framework itself as its primary goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;un-aligned-is-about-peace-prosperity-and-stability&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned is about peace, prosperity and stability&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is an organisation that aims to create long lasting peace, prosperity and stability among its member states, which is not based on the self-indulgent interests of superpowers and their wealth. Instead, the plan is to make our economies, politics and people so closely interconnected that nationalistic secessionist sentiments would become both impractical and unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
