<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anahitaahmadi on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/anahitaahmadi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anahitaahmadi on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:30:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/anahitaahmadi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where water is a gift: The outskirts of Nairobi in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7996-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A female tailor living in her one-roomed house made with corrugated metal sheets. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7787-2-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two girls from the Masai tribe. In this tribe, literacy for girls has no value and families consider it  just a waste of money. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_8019-1024x819.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A family in Gaucho, the suburbs of Nairobi. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7890-1024x682.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The containers that are used to carry water were used for storing fertilisers or oil. The water in basins and pumps is often contaminated. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portraits from Tanzania - In Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-from-tanzania-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 07:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-from-tanzania-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/A-girl-from-the-Maasai-tribe-7839-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A girl from the Maasai tribe. It is the duty of women and children to bring water and collect firewood. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/The-doctor-and-teacher-of-one-of-the-Maasai-tribes-in-Amboseli-7835-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The doctor and teacher of one of the Maasai tribes in Amboseli. Doctors and teachers are of special importance in Maasai tribes, both of whom will pass on their jobs to their children. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Maasai-man-using-a-natural-toothbrush-7780-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Maasai man using a natural toothbrush: Salvadora persica, also known as the toothbrush tree, is commonly used by the Maasai to whiten their teeth like Kilimanjaro&amp;rsquo;s snow. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in Iran: Inside The 17th Century Iranian-Armenian Monastery of St. Amenaprkich (Vank Church) — In Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/inside-vank-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/inside-vank-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vank Cathedral is one of the largest historical and religious attractions of Isfahan. It is located in the centre of Isfahan, in the New Jolfa neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The monastery has played a significant role as the first cultural communication link between Armenians and Iranians. Vank Cathedral has been inscribed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://whc.unesco.org/en/tentativelists/6385/&#34;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage sites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/18-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year around Christmas and New Year, local musicians play traditional music. (Instrument: Armenian bagpipe)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/13-1024x833.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look into the Iranian Turkmen Sahra - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An immigrant family from Sistan and Baluchestan living in one of the Turkmen villages. Their different culture and religion have prevented them from having friendly relationships with other residents of the village.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/7-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An old woman and her grandchildren in beautiful Turkmen dress wear. Even though Turkman in Iran make beautiful rugs and are wonderful artists, they still live in extreme poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/6-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Malik Banoo is an artist who enthusiastically invited me to take a picture of a wall rug that she had just finished weaving. Many Turkmen women weave carpets and Kilims, but very few agree to have their pictures taken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 40th day of winter: Kurdistan Celebrates Pir Shaliar - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The festival of Pir Shalyar is an old traditional ceremony in Kurdistan associated with the pre-Islamic, Zoroastrian times. It is held on the 40th day of winter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pir (also translated as saint), Shaliyar is believed to have cured the daughter of the king of Bukhara; the ceremony intends to mark their marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/&#34;&gt;Uraman Takht&lt;/a&gt;, the city hosting the festival, is located in the eastern part of Marivan, Kurdistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_6422-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kulla Ball is a vest that is made of fleece and does not require sewing. This vest dates back several thousand years in the history of Horaman. In Horaman, if a ruler was powerful yet just, the men wore kulla balls without ears (shoulder pads), but if the ruler deviated and did not serve the land and its people, the men wore kulla balls with earmuffs and demanded to overthrow the throne. Photo by Anahita Ahamdi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hormoz and its People - in picture</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Omid is a motorcyclist and his income comes from ferrying tourists around the island. He said that he was not too unhappy with the pandemic, explaining how he and his friends took advantage of the lack of tourists on the island. They bought a boat together and spent days fishing. He says, the joy of childhood days had returned to him. Photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/2-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man in need of a lighter, shouts his request towards another boat; the other boat quickly turns around to see what the passenger needs. Whether on land or at sea, people always seem happy to support each other here. Photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kathmandu: The Colorful Lands of Nepal - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 15:00:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in my life, I discovered a truthful and genuine smile in the poor areas of Nepal and India. From a distance you may only see men, women, and children who live in squatter areas or even on the streetsides, but when you get closer, you see a special kind of joy in the occasional smiles of these people. These smiles may not last forever, but when they appear, they&amp;rsquo;re as genuine as they can be. I call this the magic of Nepal and India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earning a Living in the Remote Areas of Baluchestan - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 11:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of Baluchi women holding a Shisha.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A woman Knitting ornaments on scarfs. The colorful shisha keeps her company during the long days. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man selling petrol in middle of a desert.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part of the country there is no gas station. This old man makes a living by selling small quantities of petrol to passing motorcycles and cars. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheep Shearing Amongst the Nomads of Kurdistan - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 09:36:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/4-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a boy shearing a sheep&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A young boy is shearing a sheep whose legs are tied. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/12-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of four young Kurdish children playing under a truck.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Children playing with their father’s cellular device under the shade of the pickup truck. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is photo of big Kurdish family in Iran.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A father and his children after a day of hard labour. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uraman Takht - a journey to the forgotten lands of Kurdistan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 05:51:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After publishing the August issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian&lt;/a&gt;, we received the kind message from an UN-aligned member, Anahita, saying the magazine had inspired her to travel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/MAGAZINE-ISSUE-3VOL.1-3.pdf&#34;&gt;Iranian Kurdistan&lt;/a&gt;. As a thank you we received beautiful pictures from her which we decided to publish as a bonus, showcasing Uraman Takht, a magnificent village in the west of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/iran/&#34;&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uraman Takht is indeed one of the wonders of what Iran has to offer. With a population of less than 3000, this village hosts the kindest and most hard-working people that I have yet seen throughout my journeys. This paradise is located in eastern part of Marivan city of Kurdistan and lies 1450 meters above sea level on the alluring heights of the Zagros mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
