<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Un Aligned News on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/un-aligned-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Un Aligned News on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 17:05:25 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/un-aligned-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/onward-and-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 17:05:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/onward-and-upwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Standing by, while destructive, self-serving oligarchs destroy our planet and the international order, is not an option. UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s warnings about the dangers of the United Nations, in particular its dominance by the Five Permanent Members of the Security Council, could have proved prophetic, had the writing not been on the wall from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite some well-functioning aspects of the organisation and some remarkable people, like the Secretary General himself and the Special Rapporteur for Palestine, Francesca Albanese, who is truly outstanding, the structure of the organisation does not allow it to meet the dire challenges the world is facing in these unpresented times. We, “the people”, need to mobilise; make sure our voices are heard; we need to stand up for every citizen of this planet and the planet itself. In order to achieve this more effectively we are looking for dedicated people to join our Board and bring our mission forward according to the urgency the time demands. So, whatever your skills, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:adrian.liberto@un-aligned.org&#34;&gt;adrian.liberto@un-aligned.org&lt;/a&gt; to see how you can take on a leading role in UN-aligned and be at the forefront of our action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>António Guterres Named as the UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-antónio-guterres&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why António Guterres?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considering UN-aligned is an organisation whose chief aim is to supplant the United Nations with a workable structure and agenda, António Guterres may seem one of the most unlikely choices for the UN-aligned Person of the Year. Nevertheless, all said and done, he too is striving for a better world order; the difference is that he is doing it from within: a losing battle, perhaps, but one that is not without its relevance and impact. He has proved to be brave and outspoken and unflinching in his support for the issues that matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Companion 2023: Your Stories from a Year on Edge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-companion-2023-your-stories-from-a-year-on-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:19:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-companion-2023-your-stories-from-a-year-on-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Step into the world of The Gordian Companion 2023 and experience a year of groundbreaking stories. This collection, consisting of the best reads from The Gordian Magazine, is not just a book; it is a revolution in citizen journalism. Edited by Ariana Yekrangi, every page challenges, inspires and awakens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Featuring a star-studded roster of writers such as Adrian Liberto, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Dinojah Patkunarajah, Elvira Ineza, Dawn Roy, Alex Liberto, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Alexander Stoney, Sunil Kumar Pariyar, Amy Church and Carla Pietrobattista, The Gordian Companion is where diverse perspectives ignite. Each voice in this anthology does not simply recount the year&amp;rsquo;s events; they redefine them, offering fresh, bold insights that break the mould.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s 2023 Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:31:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event promises to be a pivotal moment for our organisation, providing a platform for valuable exchanges among our global membership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting is a vital opportunity for each of you to actively engage and contribute to the significant decisions that shape the organisation&amp;rsquo;s future. Your voice and input are crucial in steering UN-aligned towards our shared goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;agenda-and-participation-details&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agenda and Participation Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date and Time:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The meeting is set for Thursday, December 14th, at 16:00 EET and will be conducted via Google Meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mick Lynch Named as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure to announce that Mick Lynch, the secretary-general of the RMT trade union, has been named the UN-aligned Person of the Year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This award recognises Lynch&amp;rsquo;s dedication to advancing the interests of working class people and fighting against issues of economic inequality and injustice. His efforts have earned him widespread admiration and attention, with many hailing him as a hero for our times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-mick-lynch&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is Mick Lynch?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mick Lynch is the current General Secretary of the British national Union of Rail, Maritime and Transport Workers (RMT), a labour union representing over 83,000 members across various sectors of the transport industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is citizen journalism and there is The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world that moves at a dizzying speed, UN-aligned and The Gordian have stayed true to their values, fighting for a better UN and bringing our readers the insights and information they need to stay informed and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the editor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian magazine,&lt;/a&gt; I reflect upon the past year with both gratitude and concern. On the one hand, I am grateful for the dedication and hard work of our team, whose members have produced high-quality, fact-based, impactful journalism that has provided clarity and imagination in an unprecedented year. On the other hand, I am concerned about the numerous challenges and crises that have impacted our world in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners of the 2022 Environmental Quiz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/winners-of-the-2022-environmental-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/winners-of-the-2022-environmental-quiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The UN-aligned Environmental Quiz has announced its winners, with 5 participants scoring a perfect score. A total of 279 people took part in the quiz, which was available for free on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unstop.com/quiz/environmental-quotient-test-un-aligned-488641&#34;&gt;unstop.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The winners, who scored perfectly in the competition are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gaurav Kumar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nitin Ranjan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aditya Ratnakar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rohit Wadhwa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rishabh Bansal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UN-aligned Environmental Quiz aimed to raise awareness about important environmental issues and promote sustainability. We congratulate the winners and thank all participants for their engagement and interest in these topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about ‘Utopia’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-the-new-lady-justicehttpsun-alignedorgthe-gordian-magazinegordian-may-issue-vol-6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet The New Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Meet-The-New-Lady-Justice-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine, issue 1, volume 6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In issue one, we critised the traditional image of lady justice. Her blindfold is supposed to symbolise impartiality, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world? We said no more and introduced our readers to a new Lady Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Annual General Meeting 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 19:46:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s 2022 Annual General Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is also an opportunity for you to express yourself and play an active role in the major decisions of the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below you will find the agenda and instructions on how to participate in this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“With a democratic world federation, humanity can address global problems”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:37:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The political movement to unite the world is nearly one hundred years old. Most identify the Campaign for World Government founded in 1937 by Lola Maverick Lloyd and Rosika Schwimmer as the genesis of the movement. Since then the world has transformed in ways unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, humanity is grappling with a growing pile of existential global challenges. Twentieth-century holdovers like poverty, inequality, human rights abuses, corruption, and the threat of nuclear war are now being complemented with an array of new challenges like the climate crisis, misinformation, and of course — the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical: The Gordian Magazine enters Vol. 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 09:03:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having covered social topics in the last few issues of The Gordian, in May we will be moving on to a series that will focus on law and order. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics will range from international law and treaties to general crime and punishment. We will also be exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical, which are two very different animals. After all, most of the world’s problems today are caused by activities that are more or less legal everywhere, such as intensive animal farming, extraction and consumption of fossil fuels, suppression of human rights and exploitation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on UN-aligned’s open letter to the United Nations Human Rights Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 11:11:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second half of 2021, we launched an &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;Open Letter&lt;/a&gt; to the United Nations Human Rights Commission requesting that countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights be barred from forming part of the commission. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, the letter has been signed by over a dozen LGBT+ organisations from around the globe, as well as individual activists. We originally planned to send the letter on 22 February 2022. However, owing to the latest developments in the United Nations and the ongoing war in Ukraine, we have decided to postpone the open letter as otherwise it would be sounded out by these tragic events. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity islands with the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/celebrity-islands-with-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/celebrity-islands-with-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many may not know, but the United Nations is the creator of some of the worst “&lt;a href=&#34;https://media.un.org/en/webtv&#34;&gt;reality TV&lt;/a&gt;” of all time. Whether they are shows about a climate convention where the organisers forget to invite representatives from countries that are literally drowning, as was the case with COP26, or an ongoing show about five thugs who think they have a monopoly on truth, sit at a horseshoe-shaped table and maintain international peace by telling everyone not to go to war without their permission, even though that’s exactly what every single of them has done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a PR Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/pr-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/pr-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you love writing a good pitch? Would your friends describe you as confident? Want to get involved with UN-aligned and help us with our media work?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We think you might be a great fit for our new open position: PR Manager&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes at UN-aligned we are writing and campaigning relentlessly for change. We celebrate the accomplishments but we’re just getting started and there is so much more to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a Puzzle Creator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 11:27:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you enjoy a good puzzle? Would your friends describe you as creative? Want to get involved with UN-aligned but don’t have too much spare time? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We think you might be a great fit for our new and unique open position: Puzzle Creator. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We at UN-aligned spread our message of fairness and equality through many platforms including our Newsletter, monthly publication ‘The Gordian’ and social media. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the United Nations may be in a sorry state, it’s not all doom and gloom and we like to drop in interactive quizzes to The Gordian for our readers. Until now we’ve been using multiple choice quizzes, you can see an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/category/quiz/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domenico Lucano declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 15:04:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned has chosen Domenico Lucano as its Person of the Year 2021. The ex-mayor of the Italian town of Riace has been chosen for his vision regarding the integration of refugees into their destination of choice, while at the same time revitalising a dying town.  Riace became a showcase of prosperity and integration and was hailed in 2016 by Fortune magazine as one of the world’s 50 greatest leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 30th September 2021, Lucano was sentenced to 13 years in prison for abetting illegal migration. His “crimes” included awarding waste collection contracts to companies that were set up to help migrants look for work and arranging a marriage of convenience to help a Nigerian woman escape prostitution and find legal work. The accusation that he enriched himself in the process, seems contrived, considering he does not even have the funds to pay for his legal fees. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 17:43:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far we have managed to do without any financial support, however, as the organisation has grown our need for fundraising has become more and more crucial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s first Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 11:19:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned’s first AGM was held on Wednesday, November 24th, 2021, at 19:30 - 20:30 (EET) on Google Meet. The proposals included in the agenda of UN-aligned’s AGM, together with this invitation, the NGO’s Financial Statement and the Auditor&amp;rsquo;s Report are all available on this page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s first Annual General Meeting. The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Terra Australis Incognita&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about “social issues”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month marks the last issue of the 4th Volume of the Gordian Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it may not seem like much, to date we have published more than 25 issues of the Gordian, all of which can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;accessed for free&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Words cannot express how grateful we are to the generous support of our writers, contributors and, you, our readers. Thank you for using this magazine as a platform to express your ideas for a better and fairer world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 books, movies and music UN-aligneders want you to dive in!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/10-books-movies-and-music-un-aligneders-want-you-to-dive-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month we asked our readers to tell us about their favourite books, TV shows &amp;amp; music. This is a list of some their suggestions. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9k=&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;movie-parasite-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movie: Parasite (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gavinski from China says: “I have been meaning to watch this since well before it won the Oscar but never got round to it. Easily the best movie I have seen in years, loved the switch from black comedy to super tense, and its thought-provoking commentary on wealth, poverty and inequality.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp; music with our international readers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 11:17:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more people are using their free time in summer to relax and enjoy a good book, movie, TV show or a piece of music. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligneders are from all across the world. We currently have members from over 24 countries, so we are certain that curating a list of your favorite entertainment will help inspire our international community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please fill out the form below and send us your suggestions; tell us also why enjoyed them and will publish your answers on The Gordian Magazine, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewed for September! The free UN-aligned writing course</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join this practical and informative online workshop, which will culminate in a published article in The Gordian.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the space of just five lessons, starting on the first of July, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/adrian-liberto/&#34;&gt;Adrian Liberto&lt;/a&gt;, author, journalist, a former professor at the American University of Rome and current editor-in-chief of the Gordian Magazine, will teach you how to overcome your weaknesses in writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adrian will use his vast reserves of experience and enthusiasm to give you an overall assessment of your writing strengths and weaknesses and how to maximise the former and overcome the latter. This is an unmissable opportunity for anyone looking to sharpen their journalistic skills. After the course you will be offered the opportunity to send your piece for publication in the Gordian, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN in Focus: Holding the United Nations Accountable to UN-aligned’s Standards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-in-focus-holding-the-united-nations-accountable-to-un-aligneds-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-in-focus-holding-the-united-nations-accountable-to-un-aligneds-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations is not just any organisation. It is meant to be the organisation par excellence, it is meant to represent humankind. However, the UN spreads itself so thinly it is no wonder that it struggles to meet many of its commitments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We would like to introduce you to a new feature in The Gordian Magazine. Every month an exclusive piece will highlight the good, bad and the ugly of the events in the UN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates to the UN-aligned manifesto that you need to review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 01:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We believe the flexible roadmap of UN-aligned’s manifesto presents a safe trajectory for a united world, so as UN-aligned grows we are always seeking to refine, clarify and improve our goals and missions. The following changes have been made to the UN-aligned manifesto as of May 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-regarding-our-mission-statement&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updates regarding our Mission statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We refined the language around our mission statement, namely regarding our vision to create an alternative to the United Nations. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine New Series: Doughnut Economy, Davos Agenda and more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-new-series-the-doughnut-economy-the-davos-agenda-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:57:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-new-series-the-doughnut-economy-the-davos-agenda-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Il-mese-prossimo.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Human Right Series of the Gordian comes to its eighth issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions. It is because of you that The Gordian Magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last eight issues we covered key human right topics. You can find all topics below. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the United Nations, Argead style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How exactly has the United Nations failed in its primary mission of securing world peace? What went wrong? Who or what is to blame? Can reform absolve the organisation of its monumental shortcomings and put it back on course with regards to meeting its obligations? These are just some questions this book aims to answer. And here is the spoiler: no, the United Nations cannot be salvaged. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the book presents an alternative vision: an organisation that can achieve the sacred mission without the shackles of obsolete structures and bullying superpowers. The organisation, UN-aligned, has already been founded and it is introduced in this groundbreaking work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Winners of the UN-aligned Photo Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/announcing-the-winners-of-the-un-aligned-photo-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/announcing-the-winners-of-the-un-aligned-photo-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We would like to say thank you to everyone who took part in our Photo Competition! There were many fantastic entries with some awesome inspiring photography. As per rule of the contest, we have selected two winners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1st-prize-winner-anwar-sadat-swaka&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st Prize Winner&lt;/strong&gt;: Anwar Sadat Swaka&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Anwar-Sadat-Swaka-2-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the streets of kibera, normal daily life goes on. Mama Maria as she is popularly known because of her daily religious attire, confidently makes her way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranian lawyer declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nasrin Sotoudeh is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nasrin_Sotoudeh&#34;&gt;Iranian human rights lawyer&lt;/a&gt; who has been in and out of prison since 2010 for no other reason than defending men, women and children who suffered under the oppressive Iranian regime. Her clients included opposition politicians, journalists, abused women and children, women who were arrested for not wearing the hijab and prisoners on death row for crimes they allegedly committed when they were minors. On several occasions she went on extended hunger strikes to protest against the severity of the prison regime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on the Ashin Wirathu Campaign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-the-afshin-wirathu-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-the-afshin-wirathu-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 27 July 2020, UN-aligned sent a &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/&#34;&gt;letter to the Burmese Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu&lt;/a&gt; asking him, amongst other things, how he could reconcile his hostility to the Rohingya with his Buddhist creed. The letter was sent registered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three months later, the letter is still sitting in a post office in Myanmar and the status of the letter is described as “in transit.” The address was of course correct; in fact, the monastery he resides in is the well-known and accessible New Masoyein Monastery in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;. So why on earth is the letter still stuck in Nowhere Land?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is the UN-aligned Person of the Year?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:50:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is excited to announce a new opportunity for its readers to nominate any individual or organisation whom they believe deserves more attention for championing their cause. Although the prize can go to literally anyone, we encourage you to think twice before nominating dictators, fascists or possibly your grandmother. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we have received the final results, we will shortlist your submitted names. An appointed executive committee, who will consist of UN-aligned staff and editors of the Gordian, will decide on the final winner. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Future We Want and the UN We Need”: The UNGA Debates of 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-future-we-want-and-the-un-we-need-unga-debates-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:55:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-future-we-want-and-the-un-we-need-unga-debates-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-the-united-nations-general-assembly-debates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the United Nations General Assembly Debates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year, in September, all 193 Member States of the United Nations who are represented in the General Assembly come together to discuss a wide array of international issues covered by the Charter of the United Nations, such as development, peace, security and international law.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;un-aligned-will-be-watching-the-developments-of-this-event-closely&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned will be watching the developments of this event closely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the live blog from last year’s United Nations General Assembly (UNGA), Adrian Liberto and I summarised some of the most important speeches that unfolded during this four-day event. We even &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/united-nations-critic/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/&#34;&gt;awarded some of the speeches&lt;/a&gt; for their courage and relevance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon: An Update on UN-alinged’s Campaign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-un-alingeds-amazon-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 10:45:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-un-alingeds-amazon-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When UN-aligned launched our series of campaigns, we knew that asking the big and uncomfortable questions would not lead to quick and straightforward answers. So far, we have campaigned against &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/&#34;&gt;anti-Muslim sentiment spearheaded by Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have campaigned against &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/&#34;&gt;the death penalty for three young Iranian protestors&lt;/a&gt; and are preparing campaigns against the discrimination of the LGBT+ community to religious and political leaders in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, our most dedicated readers may be able to recall the first campaign of UN-aligned, which was an open letter to Amazon to discuss their cardboard packaging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with UN-aligned&#39;s Language Courses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 20:46:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally discovered UN-aligned through a post on Facebook and then joined the community as I found it quite interesting and inspiring. I also thought that reading articles of interest, such as those relating to climate change, could help me improve my English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was amazed about the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I desperately need to improve my English, I later also registered onto the English course. My tutor, Adrian, reached out to me soon after, and unexpectedly, this course turned out to be totally free! But what amazed me the most, was the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New UN-aligned Campaigns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/un-aligned-campaigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 11:09:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/un-aligned-campaigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is proud to announce the launch of a series of campaigns in line with its manifesto. UN-aligned campaigns will cover a range of issues concerning human rights, the environment and United Nations reform, and we will be reporting on them in The Gordian, as well as on our website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our campaigns will start by targeting blatant disregard to clearcut issues of social or environmental justice by powerful corporations, organisations or individuals. We will be highlighting their shortcomings and asking them to take positive steps in order to improve their undertakings in line with a fairer and safer world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Appoints New Senior Administrator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-appoints-new-senior-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 13:02:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-appoints-new-senior-administrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ms-ruby-goldenberg-the-new-un-aligned-administrator&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms. Ruby Goldenberg: The new UN-aligned Administrator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Ruby Goldenberg has been appointed as the new Senior Administrator of UN-aligned with a mission to propel the NGO into the next stage of its evolution and to strengthen its activism and presence on the global stage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexia is a qualified lawyer with a history of working in the legal sector and financial services. She also has a  background in administration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am delighted to welcome Ruby Goldenberg to the UN-aligned management team. I had the privilege of working with Alexia in China, so I am well aware of the dedication she has for her duties and her determination to get things done thoroughly and efficiently. Alexia has an international outlook and is currently living in Moscow. She will be a great asset to UN-aligned and its mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Adrian Liberto, UN-aligned Coordinator&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Human Rights Series – There Must be no Monopoly on the Truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-new-human-rights-series-there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-new-human-rights-series-there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the Environmental Priorities Series comes to its sixth and last issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions. It is because of you that The Gordian magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are incredibly proud of this achievement and will continue our efforts to improve this resource with the support of our members and contributors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned becomes one year old!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 06:54:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is one year old this month! The seed was sown some years ago in China and developed thanks to the dedication of like-minded people. We have gone from 22 Foundation Members to hundreds of followers from around the world: some are full members, others are subscribers, while many follow us on Facebook. To all our supporters, we wish to offer a big THANK YOU!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike most organisations, UN-aligned is, primarily, its members. We are the New United Nations and though just a drop in the ocean, for now, we will carry on growing until we will become a force to be reckoned with! Our Mission Statement and Manifesto clearly indicate what we stand for, but they are not written in stone and with your help we hope to learn and evolve so that we can bring about the change that we know will make the world more sustainable and harmonious.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Become a Voice in UN-aligned and The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 10:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is a community-supported publication that aims to provide a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge on important issues such as human rights, animal welfare and environmental preservation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past year, we have &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/&#34;&gt;reached over 30,000&lt;/a&gt; readers and have worked to give a voice to diverse groups and shed light on important issues such as conversion therapy and abuses of power. We have also provided exclusive coverage of the United Nations, holding the organization accountable to its principles and working towards a more just, equitable, and sustainable future. In addition to our serious coverage, we have also provided some fun and joy to our readers through our coverage of culture and the arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to the way our readers will be experiencing the Gordian magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/changes-to-the-way-our-readers-will-be-experiencing-the-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 15:40:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/changes-to-the-way-our-readers-will-be-experiencing-the-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far The Gordian magazine has been presented in a PDF format sent to your email on a monthly basis. While this may have been perfect for readers who printed our magazine on traditional paper or those who used computer devices with bigger screens, such as laptops or tablets, mobile users often had to pinch and zoom on a specific section of the page in order to see a paragraph of text. For this reason, we have decided to change the way The Gordian magazine is presented for a temporary period of time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned in 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 22:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2019 was a momentous year for UN-aligned! The organisation was launched in May after years of preparation and it only took a few months to attract members from all over the world. The first months were focussed on perfecting and consolidating the website and communication structures, including the magazine and language options. We also worked on the services we provide to our members, such as the free English language courses to promote a lingua franca and the virtual library. Moreover, much energy was invested in the writing of a book that will challenge the structures and mechanisms of the United Nations; this should be ready for publication in Spring 2020. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need your help</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/we-need-your-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:33:27 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/we-need-your-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is slowly, but surely, taking its place in the world arena of politics. We are also increasingly being criticised by different sides of the political spectrum. We love constructive criticism as this helps us develop and refine our mission. However, most objections simply imply that UN-aligned is “too idealistic.” This should fuel us all the more and encourage us to create stronger unity amongst ourselves. Together, there is nothing to stop us from creating the basis for a true United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Month in UN-aligned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/last-month-in-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 23:37:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/last-month-in-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the global political scene is beginning to look more and more like a Theatre of the Absurd, UN-aligned has become an alternative platform for many to turn to. This is not surprising; long lasting peace and prosperity can only be achieved with the kind of values and principles that UN-aligned advocates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last month, UN-aligned continued to grow, develop and change according to the needs of its members: we now have an exciting design for the user’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;dashboard&lt;/a&gt; interface, a brand new logo and, finally, we are starting the creation of our own UN-aligned App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Launched Successfully!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-launched-successfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 14:43:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-launched-successfully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday’s successful launch marks a new milestone in the world of politics, getting us ever closer to a world that works for and belongs to everyone. What makes this event so important is that UN-aligned doesn’t aim to make changes within our broken political systems, but aims to change the global framework itself as its primary goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;un-aligned-is-about-peace-prosperity-and-stability&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned is about peace, prosperity and stability&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is an organisation that aims to create long lasting peace, prosperity and stability among its member states, which is not based on the self-indulgent interests of superpowers and their wealth. Instead, the plan is to make our economies, politics and people so closely interconnected that nationalistic secessionist sentiments would become both impractical and unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
