<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anonymous on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/authors/anonymous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anonymous on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/authors/anonymous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>As the Ukrainian invasion enters its third month, we explore the difference between Russian and Ukrainian language, which are often mistaken as the same.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Why-Russian-and-Ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language to Unite, Language to Separate: The Tale of Serbian &amp; Croatian</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:35:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Croatia and Serbia, once brothers united, have experienced many conflicts since the collapse of Yugoslavia in 1991. In fact, conflicts existed even prior to the demolition of Yugoslavia and can even be traced back as a cause for its collapse. Thus, it is worth looking at the role of language in this conflict. More specifically, how the classification of two languages can be utilized as a tool, sometimes even a weapon. We do this by answering the following question: “Are Serbian and Croatian two different languages, or simply two dialects of the same language”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Language-to-Unite-Language-to-Separate_-The-Tale-of-Serbian-Croatian--scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Why are you talking like that?&#39;: How politicians use words to influence and mislead</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:56:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself agreeing with a politician for no apparent reason? Have you ever thought why many people support a certain politician even though they hold a ‘foolish’ standpoint? Have you ever thought of how language influences people’s decisions in a political environment? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is true that humans are complex creatures and clear linear relationships rarely apply in the real world, language usage and perception undoubtedly plays a significant role in the world of politics, especially today where social factors such as gender and ethnicity are gaining more attention. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/how-politicians-use-language.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Have Been Called &#39;Laowai&#39;? Here&#39;s What it Means</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 08:56:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Chinese, foreigners are often referred to as &amp;rsquo;laowai&amp;rsquo;, a term that carries different meanings depending on context and perception. In this article, we shed light on the social and cultural aspects of language use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single person may often be categorized and called in many different ways. I, for instance, may be categorized as ‘Iranian’, ‘Middle Eastern’, ‘brown’, etc. These separations and categorisations typically occur due to cultural differences between two or more groups. A common separation in China is that of a Chinese person and a foreigner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Image-by-Collagist-from-pixabay.com_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Dilly-dallying Costs Lives</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year has been difficult for everyone. We have all had to adapt to new changes and the impact COVID-19 has had worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a classroom teacher based in a primary school in London. Since April, we have had to face many challenges due to the pandemic. Children have done an amazing job at adapting to necessary changes and staff have been very supportive of each other. We worked flexibly and creatively to help the school run as efficiently and effectively as possible. This last term, however, has been particularly draining for all of us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/people-wearing-diy-masks-3951623.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misgendering people: Identity and Gender Pronouns</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/misgendering-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:50:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/misgendering-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article does not intend to offend or devalue anyone with a non-binary gender identity. It only tries to explain why fixing misgendering is a larger problem than most people think, and why there is no immediate solution to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-misgendering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is misgendering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misgendering is the act of using language to describe or talk to a person in a manner that does not align with their affirmed gender, intentionally or unintentionally. This can be in the form of personal pronouns, such as referring to someone as a ‘he’ when they’re a woman or when they do not identify with the male gender, but also through the use of gender specific nouns such as ‘boy’ and ‘girl’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/3-1.jpg-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/7-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/9-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters: The Lives of Three Iranian Protestors are on the Line - Take Action Now</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:57:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, a spokesman for Iran&amp;rsquo;s judiciary confirmed the death sentence of three young men who were participants in the nationwide unrest that swept across the country in November 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “November protests” started with anger over the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to increase diesel prices, and soon developed into violent clashes between police and  protestors, with many chanting slogans against the Islamic Republic. Protests also echoed concerns over an increasing assault on individual liberties by the Iranian establishment, massive corruption scandals and a dying economy in which many struggle to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/113190050_f13a16a3-ba31-428e-b597-3418fd2b04dc.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Tear Gas in the 21st Century is Unacceptable.</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have come a long way since World War I and World War II, yet we still see police forces using dangerous chemical weapons, such as tear gas, against their own civilians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How dangerous are these chemical substances and should local police be permitted to use such weapons against people? How were these weapons used in WWI and WWII?  The following article aims to answer a few of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/WP-Photo-7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Use-of-Chinese-Medicine-in-Treating-Covid-19-1.png" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document no. 3 and what it reveals about the Chinese Communist Party</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:07:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is lying about the coronavirus, document no.3 reveals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-we-are&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we are&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic known as the coronavirus Pandemic started in December in Wuhan China, and as of 26th of April, 210 countries and territories have been affected by the virus, close to 3 million people have been diagnosed with the disease, and more than 200,000 people have tragically passed away of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late January Dr. Zhong Nanshan, one of the advisors in managing the crisis in China, was asked whether he thought that the virus outbreak would be as bad as the 2003 SARS pandemic. Dr. Zhong Nanshan replied with absolute certainty that this would not be the case. He attributed this to advancements in medical sciences and the experience gathered from the SARS pandemic. The SARS outbreak in 2003 only infected around 8000 people and killed a bit over 800. At this point approximately three months have passed since that initial interview and we must ask ourselves how things ended up like this…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge-1-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
