<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anonymous on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/anonymous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anonymous on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/anonymous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dante Alighieri&#39;s Vision for World Government: The Pathway to Abolishing War</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dante&amp;rsquo;s death 700 years ago marked the end of an era. But his lasting legacy may be his vision for a world government, outlined in his work De Monarchia. Written in 1313, this work may be the first literature to present a comprehensive solution to the problem of war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to imagine any sort of connection between the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, and something that occurred in an unremarkable bedroom in Italy almost exactly 700 years prior. It has nothing whatsoever to do with the deep historical connections between Russia and Ukraine, at many times one and the same state, during the preceding seven centuries. But last autumn marked the 700th anniversary of the death of the great Italian poet Dante Alighieri, from malaria, in Ravenna, on September 14, 1321. His bones lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Dilly-dallying Costs Lives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year has been difficult for everyone. We have all had to adapt to new changes and the impact COVID-19 has had worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a classroom teacher based in a primary school in London. Since April, we have had to face many challenges due to the pandemic. Children have done an amazing job at adapting to necessary changes and staff have been very supportive of each other. We worked flexibly and creatively to help the school run as efficiently and effectively as possible. This last term, however, has been particularly draining for all of us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters: The Lives of Three Iranian Protestors are on the Line - Take Action Now</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:57:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, a spokesman for Iran&amp;rsquo;s judiciary confirmed the death sentence of three young men who were participants in the nationwide unrest that swept across the country in November 2019. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “November protests” started with anger over the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to increase diesel prices, and soon developed into violent clashes between police and  protestors, with many chanting slogans against the Islamic Republic. Protests also echoed concerns over an increasing assault on individual liberties by the Iranian establishment, massive corruption scandals and a dying economy in which many struggle to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
