<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unhrc on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/unhrc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unhrc on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/unhrc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UN votes on a fact-finding mission into Iran, but don’t look at it too closely</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the United Nations is not busy declaring French baguette a world cultural heritage or hosting awkward diplomatic cocktail parties where everyone pretends to like each other&amp;rsquo;s national dishes, it dedicates a small portion of its resources to protecting human rights across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in November, a fact-finding investigation into human rights violations in Iran, where hundreds have died and tens of thousands have been detained since protests started in September 2022, has been approved by the UN Human Rights Council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia booted out of the UN Human Rights Council. What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to its charter, the UN was created to maintain international peace and security, protect human rights, deliver humanitarian aid, and support sustainable development. Each of these is an honourable goal that is sometimes brought to fruition in parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;193 countries around the globe are members of the United Nations and among those are the P5 (permanent Security Council Members) chosen because of their importance in the aftermath of WWII. Each one of these countries is part of the UN because they claim to believe in what this organisation stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th July, the Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. That’s no big deal, one would imagine, but sadly, for the United Nations, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is why a few months ago UN-aligned launched a campaign to bar countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from the Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the fact that our open letter to the United Nations was backed by several organisations and human rights activists, the letter was ignored.&lt;a href=&#34;https://documents-dds-ny.un.org/doc/UNDOC/GEN/G22/407/77/PDF/G2240777.pdf?OpenElement&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on UN-aligned’s open letter to the United Nations Human Rights Council</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 11:11:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second half of 2021, we launched an &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;Open Letter&lt;/a&gt; to the United Nations Human Rights Commission requesting that countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights be barred from forming part of the commission. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, the letter has been signed by over a dozen LGBT+ organisations from around the globe, as well as individual activists. We originally planned to send the letter on 22 February 2022. However, owing to the latest developments in the United Nations and the ongoing war in Ukraine, we have decided to postpone the open letter as otherwise it would be sounded out by these tragic events. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned calls on UNHRC to ban members that criminalise homosexuality</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the United Nations’ Declaration of Human Rights, we, the undersigned firmly believe in “the inherent dignity and the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family”. This is “the foundation of freedom, justice and peace in the world”, whereas “disregard” and “contempt” for these rights “have resulted in barbarous acts which have outraged the conscience of mankind.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst many member states flout human rights on a regular basis, certain states actually enshrine these abuses in law. This is very much the case with LGBT+ rights in as much as almost a third of United Nations’ member States criminalise homosexuality with penalties ranging from death and lengthy prison sentences to beatings and fines. This proportion does not include States that oppress the LGBT+ rights in other ways, such as Hungary and Poland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
