<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Turkey on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/tags/turkey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Turkey on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/turkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Love for Erdogan&#39;s Autocracy in the Heart of German Democracy</title>
      <link>/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</guid>
      <description>Cultural ties fuel German-Turkish diaspora&#39;s support for Erdogan&#39;s autocracy, a paradox threatening to stall Turkey&#39;s progress in the 21st century.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Erdogan-The-Love-for-Autocracy-in-the-Heart-of-German-Democracy-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new UN-peacekeeping budget: pun intended!</title>
      <link>/un-in-focus/un-peacekeeping-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/un-in-focus/un-peacekeeping-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of June, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://undocs.org/en/A/C.5/75/25&#34;&gt;budget for peacekeeping operations for the period from 1 July 2021 to 30 June 2022&lt;/a&gt; was approved by the United Nations. Eye-watering sums have been allocated in order to maintain buffers between hostilities that have been stewing for decades. This is not what peacekeeping should be about. Peacekeeping ought to be a temporary measure while every effort is put into resolving a conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, what is happening is that resources are being pumped into keeping the symptoms under control rather than removing the cause of the problem. As long as the wound is festering and the patient is alive, the doctor’s job is secured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Funding-and-Fiscal-Responsibility-of-the-United-Nations-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hagia Sophia: National Sovereignty is not the Issue, Erdogan Likes to Play the Blaming Game</title>
      <link>/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:26:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cathedral first, then a mosque, and later a museum. Last week, Istanbul’s Hagia Sophia became a mosque once again; an insular act for Turkey’s Erdogan to flex his political mussels and to fuel his posture of indignation and grievance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The president knows casting cultural divides resonates with many of his support base, inside as well as outside of Turkey. He boosts his popularity and draws strength from his constant tussle with domestic and foreign foemen. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/800px-President_Trump_at_the_G20_48144080071_cropped.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the recent conflicts in Syria could shape its future</title>
      <link>/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:46:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although people are long used to the erratic twists and turns of Donald Trump, his decision to sell the Kurds down the river by withdrawing American troops from Syria caught everyone by surprise. Whether Trump was right to extricate his forces from Syria remains debatable, but just as there is rarely a good time to start international military interventions, so there is rarely a good time to discontinue them. One would have thought that Libya’s and Iraq’s ongoing atrocities would have made this clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/image1170x530cropped-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
