<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Japan on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Japan on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan and its nuclear waste problem</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear leaks are probably among the most horrifying accidents possible due to their long-term detrimental damage to life and environment. Eight years after the nuclear leak from Japan’s Fukushima power plant, local residents, many of whom are fishermen, are still suffering the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dumping-the-radioactively-contaminated-water-directly-into-the-sea-in-order-to-dilute-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tragically, they now have to face another nightmare. However, rather than being triggered by a natural disaster, like the nuclear accident was, this time, it was all caused by their government’s proposal of dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it. So far, the plant’s operator, Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO), has already stored over 1 million tons of radioactive water used to cool destroyed reactors and the amount is still increasing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
