<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/immigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immigration on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary Cities: Shattering Myths, Protecting Human Rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received a parking ticket? Most are undoubtedly familiar with this feeling of intense frustration at the sight of a small fine tucked at the base of their windshield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, what if a minor parking ticket posed the threat of a much larger consequence? What if it meant your children would be taken out of school? What if it meant you and your family could be deported? This is the reality for thousands of illegal immigrant families living in North America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years immigration has been a controversial subject in the US. Some Americans call for harsher policies against immigration, others for a revision of immigration policies to allow for easier processing and more assistance to refugees. All in all, one after the other, governments have tried to revise these policies in hopes of appeasing the American population, but neither has been able to fully address this issue in a manner favourable to all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Curtain: Does the EU Stand on the Side of Justice?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many criticisms have been levied at the EU, a fair amount, as we shall see, may be justified, but most are part of that process that developing organisations with such a mighty mandate have to go through. All said and done, the benefits far outweigh the drawbacks, as Britain’s ever-increasing list of post-Brexit crises, on the one hand, and the eagerness of neighbouring nations to join, on the other, makes evidently clear. There is, however, one flaw that unless remedied as a priority, will risk making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. Rude language, but the reality is far ruder. I am referring to the EU’s callous exclusivity, which I will refer to as its Golden Curtain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I couldn&#39;t understand a word of it, but I loved choir singing”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:18:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;4th-october-1974&#34;&gt;4th October 1974&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in England, my first memory was walking through Heathrow Airport with my three sisters and one brother. I am the middle child of seven children, two of my siblings had already arrived in England before us. My mother was holding two of our hands, and the air hostesses were holding the rest of our little hands. My brother didn’t need his hand to be held and walked behind us as we approached Passport Control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate refugees in the modern world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 13:28:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A climate refugee is someone displaced from their home because of an extreme weather event caused by climate change. This particular category of refugees is coming from all over the world to various places that are not being affected as deeply by extreme weather. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate change is nothing new and neither is human migration. Migration has been a huge factor in international interactions since the dawn of written history. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Global climate change however, is a relatively recent occurrence. Climate change is defined as “the increasing changes in the measures of climate over a long period of time – including precipitation, temperature, and wind patterns”. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migrant-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The migrant problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied their history will know that migrations are what shaped the world as we know it today, both politically and ethnically. At times these migrations were peaceful. Often, they were predatory. At times they were gradual, spreading like an oil stain; often, they were sudden and quite alien, like a frenzied splash from a Jackson Pollock paintbrush. At times the end result was growth and a fusion of cultures; often, it was genocide. So we built walls of brick and paper to keep the undesirables out. Most of us belonged to those undesirables once, but that was a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domenico Lucano declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 15:04:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned has chosen Domenico Lucano as its Person of the Year 2021. The ex-mayor of the Italian town of Riace has been chosen for his vision regarding the integration of refugees into their destination of choice, while at the same time revitalising a dying town.  Riace became a showcase of prosperity and integration and was hailed in 2016 by Fortune magazine as one of the world’s 50 greatest leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 30th September 2021, Lucano was sentenced to 13 years in prison for abetting illegal migration. His “crimes” included awarding waste collection contracts to companies that were set up to help migrants look for work and arranging a marriage of convenience to help a Nigerian woman escape prostitution and find legal work. The accusation that he enriched himself in the process, seems contrived, considering he does not even have the funds to pay for his legal fees. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following interview was conducted in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-yourself-and-your-children&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself and your children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Amna; I am 33 years old. I live in Lebanon in a Syrian refugee camp. I have two children, a son and a daughter. My husband was lost in Syria, and I fled with my children from the war and came to Arsal to seek safety away from the difficult conditions of the war that destroyed our lives and the childhood of my children. I tried to work to meet the needs of my children, but I could not for fear of leaving them alone in the tent and I wanted to teach them and follow their school lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishing to stay above the ground: immigration and survival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is by Abdelkander, an UN-aligned member from Algeria who is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned English Language Programme&lt;/a&gt;. He is currently living and working in Turkey.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;immigration-and-survival&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immigration and survival&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Abdelkader, though I am also known as Faysal. I am from Algeria and I am 37-years-old. Like most young people, I want to have a decent life. Of course, I have dreams, but my main dream is simple: I just want an honest job. In my country, however, whether you studied or did not finish your studies, the matter will not be different, because in either case you will not get a job unless you have mediation, or you pay a bribe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking at migration in the face</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-has-not-been-a-good-week-for-refugees-but-then-again-it-never-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has not been a good week for refugees; but then again, it never is…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s The Guardian reports how the Lebanese government forced 5,000 refugee families to demolish their own home in order to induce them to return to Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the captain of rescue ship Sea-Watch 3, Carola Rackete, was arrested after she forcefully docked her ship in the Italian island of  Lampedusa. Having rescued 53 migrants drifting off the coast of Libya on June 12, the Sea-Watch 3 was left stranded while the Italian authorities kept refusing to let her dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonising Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 06:40:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-on-the-weakest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking on the weakest…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people just need a common enemy. Any group that can be easily picked on offers the perfect target. Minorities of every sort are often chosen because of their vulnerability. Bullying them makes weak or bigoted citizens feel superior. Some of these minorities have fought back and with time secured a certain level of safety, and the protection of their human rights. Still, immigrants are often the most threatened, because they are insecure. They do not know the ropes and cannot easily fight back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
