<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Federalism on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/federalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Federalism on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:53:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/federalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revitalising Global Engagement: The Case for a United Nations Peace Corps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-a-united-nations-peace-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:53:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-a-united-nations-peace-corps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations is as much an organisation of ironies as it is of stark contradictions. This is particularly true when comparing geopolitical power differentials between the global North and South. It is therefore unsurprising that the annual budgetary contributions of United Nations member states are calculated using strictly the US dollar. Based on details from the New York-based Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), an article on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/article/funding-united-nations-what-impact-do-us-contributions-have-un-agencies-and-programs&#34;&gt;American subsidisation of the United Nations&lt;/a&gt; revealed that one-fifth of the world&amp;rsquo;s premier supranational organisation is directly subsidised by the United States, to the tune of $12 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone: Horizons of EU expansion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe is a continent; a land mass. Politically, of course, Europe is much more. It is an entity. The history of its various nations interlaces intricately, more so than with other parts of the world, as does its culture. Its aspirations are also different, though many of these overlap with those of people all around the world. The EU encapsulates some of these hopes, such as a desire for peace, security, justice and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:27:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaac Newton famously said: “If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.” Sadly, society is where it is today because most people have stood on the shoulders of ogres. The past sticks to us like shit on a shoe and we have become so accustomed to the foul smell, that rather than scrape off the dung, we wallow in it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: planet earth in the 21st century, but one that had never witnessed the advent of humankind. Then, suddenly, it is discovered by an alien species much like our own. Before long, the planet is plundered, ravaged and abused. Life forms are enslaved, tortured and killed for entertainment, fashion and culinary delights, their habitats destroyed; forests are cut down; and rivers and seas polluted beyond recognition, as are the skies. Finally, having exhausted every possible resource, the alien species moves on, like a plague of locusts, to its next quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New International Man: Can World Federalism Overcome Nationalism?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an old millennial having experienced childhood in the nineties, my generation grew up with the quintessential strongmen movies personified in protagonists like Rocky Balboa, Ivan Drago and Apollo Creed, as seen in the Rocky franchise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Rocky 4, Dolph Lundgren portrayed a rather intimidating antihero; an opponent more machine than man. My generation remembers a world before it was possible to Google our curiosities away into the ether of the internet. Exposure to the world in terms of different cultures, languages and ways of life was primarily derived from movies like Rocky 4. Ivan Drago, Rocky&amp;rsquo;s deadly opponent having killed Apollo Creed in the boxing ring, seemingly revisited the literal definition of the New Soviet Man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the United Nations Parliamentary Assembly Address Failed State Realities?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What can the movement for a United Nations Parliamentary Assembly takeaway from the World Development Index? According to the United Nations Surviving on Pennies Global Awareness Initiative, 1 billion people live on $1.00 daily. We have been trained to localize the concept of gross domestic product by national classification, but on average, how widely considered as the world&amp;rsquo;s gross domestic product per capita?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of 2021, Macrotrends reported &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrotrends.net/countries/WLD/world/gdp-gross-domestic-product&#34;&gt;the world GDP&lt;/a&gt; at a meager $11,407 (per capita), less than what the United States Assistant Office of Planning &amp;amp; Evaluation identified as poverty for one person at $12,880 for the same year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dante Alighieri&#39;s Vision for World Government: The Pathway to Abolishing War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dante&amp;rsquo;s death 700 years ago marked the end of an era. But his lasting legacy may be his vision for a world government, outlined in his work De Monarchia. Written in 1313, this work may be the first literature to present a comprehensive solution to the problem of war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to imagine any sort of connection between the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, and something that occurred in an unremarkable bedroom in Italy almost exactly 700 years prior. It has nothing whatsoever to do with the deep historical connections between Russia and Ukraine, at many times one and the same state, during the preceding seven centuries. But last autumn marked the 700th anniversary of the death of the great Italian poet Dante Alighieri, from malaria, in Ravenna, on September 14, 1321. His bones lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“With a democratic world federation, humanity can address global problems”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:37:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The political movement to unite the world is nearly one hundred years old. Most identify the Campaign for World Government founded in 1937 by Lola Maverick Lloyd and Rosika Schwimmer as the genesis of the movement. Since then the world has transformed in ways unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, humanity is grappling with a growing pile of existential global challenges. Twentieth-century holdovers like poverty, inequality, human rights abuses, corruption, and the threat of nuclear war are now being complemented with an array of new challenges like the climate crisis, misinformation, and of course — the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Forging of an East African Federation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:37:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-shot-at-an-east-african-community&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Shot at an East African Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three countries of East Africa - Kenya, Tanzania (which is a union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar), and Uganda - were administered as one unit under the East African Common Services. When granting them independence, the British expected that these countries would eventually integrate into one political union, as had happened to Tanganyika and Zanzibar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of a political federation for East Africa emerged in the 1960s. The idea took shape in 1967 when the East African Community, a confederate government, was formed by the republics of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania. The heads of states of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania, by signing the treaty establishing the community, became its patron and hoped to use the community as a launching pad towards deeper political, economic, and socio-cultural integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-federalism-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation Earth: Why Youth are Necessary for Solving Global Problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;humanity-faces-immense-challenges&#34;&gt;Humanity faces immense challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many young people are global. Growing up online has predisposed a generation to a cosmopolitan perspective previously only accessible by the elite. Interacting with a culture different from your own has become a commonplace occurrence online, which has led many to retreat into safe, echo chambers with people of the value system. This retreat is exemplified by private chat groups which at best, provide a welcoming space for a niche community, and at worst, provide a space for terrorists to plan attacks. Yet, if you’ve grown up online, you’ll know that an echo chamber is far less fun than a debate space. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
