<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:05:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Defining Stories of May 2023</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/the-defining-stories-of-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/the-defining-stories-of-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-natural-disasters&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Natural Disasters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rwanda and Uganda Encounter Devastating Flash Floods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 130 people have tragically lost their lives in Rwanda due to flash floods and mudslides following torrential rains on May 3rd, 2023. A similar catastrophe struck neighbouring Uganda, where at least six people were reported dead. Climate change continues to wreak havoc across Africa, raising questions about preparedness and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Kivu Province in DR Congo Ravaged by Torrential Rains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, 2023, the South Kivu province of DR Congo was brought to its knees as torrential rains swept away villages and killed hundreds of people. The DR Congo government is grappling with disaster response and reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secret Visits, Insane Politics and Devastating Natural Disasters: February 2023 in One Look</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/february-2023-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/february-2023-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Burkina-Faso-army.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Burkina Faso army&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Burkina Faso army. Photo: Defence Visual Information Distribution Service © Public Domain&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.02.23: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. Suspected Islamist insurgents have killed 16 members of the security service in an ambush in the north of the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09/10.02.23: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 12 civilians were killed by militants on motorbikes in the village of Sanakadougou in the northwest of the country. Many were wounded, while the village itself was burned down. Al-Qaida-linked terrorists have been operating in the area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye United Nations: A Jolly Good Move!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/__trashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/__trashed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;American award-winning actress, film director, producer, and humanitarian, Angelina Jolie, has decided to quit her role as a Special Envoy to the United Nations refugee agency, the UNHCR, citing a desire to “work differently”. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Jolie has worked with the UNHCR since 2001, and has been a Special Envoy for the organisation since 2012. Her role involved building awareness and support for refugees and highlighting the need for urgent action to be taken in order to tackle issues relating to the serious events that force people to flee their homes, such as conflict and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Subtle Manipulation of News Media in the Age of Pseudo-Enlightenment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-the-sun-wot-won-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the Sun wot won it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The older generation may remember it well. It was 11 April, 1992. Neil Kinnock and his Labour Party were set to win the general election and the best the Conservatives could have hoped for was a hung parliament. Then, however, The Sun, one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s right wing tabloid newspapers owned by Australian-American media mogul Rupert Murdoch, launched an aggressive campaign to swing things around&amp;hellip; and sure enough it did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era: December 2022 in One Look</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/december-2022-in-one-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/december-2022-in-one-look/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Cyril-Ramaphosa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cyril Ramaphosa&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyril Ramaphosa. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/governmentza/&#34;&gt;GovernmentZA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13.12.22: &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt;. Scandal-engulfed President Cyril Ramaphosa, who is being investigated for serious violations and misconduct, survived a vote in parliament which could have set in motion impeachment proceedings that could have forced him out of office.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18.12.22: &lt;strong&gt;Tunisia&lt;/strong&gt;. The electorate has given President Kais Saied a clear message by boycotting yesterday’s elections, with less than 9% turning up to vote. The President had suspended parliament on March 30, 2022 and revised the constitution in the hope that he could cling to power, a prospect that has now become more unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 2022 Nobel Prize Winners?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:elviraineza5@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Nobel Prize is a prestigious international award that recognizes individuals who have made significant contributions to various fields, including physics, chemistry, physiology or medicine, literature, peace, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Established by Swedish inventor Alfred Nobel in 1895, the award is presented annually to individuals who have demonstrated exceptional achievements in their respective fields. The Nobel Prize is considered one of the highest honours that can be awarded, and recipients are often recognized as leaders in their fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madness in Israel, coup attempt in Sao Tome and Principe and earthquake in Indonesia: November 2022 in one look</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/november-2022-in-one-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/november-2022-in-one-look/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.11.22: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. After little more than a week of negotiations in South Africa, the parties in the conflict in the northern region of Tigray have agreed to cease hostilities permanently and work towards lasting peace and orderly disarmament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.11.22: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 22 people died when a minibus plunged into a canal in Cairo-Mansoura Road. Eight people were also injured in the accident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Trovoada-announces-the-successful-thwarting-of-a-coup-attempt-at-a-press-conference-on-November-25th..jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Patrice Trovoada&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Patrice Trovoada announces the successful thwarting of a coup attempt at a press conference on November 25th. © Creative Commons&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here are what your leaders had to say at the UN General Debate 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/here-are-what-you-leaders-had-to-say-at-the-un-general-debate-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/here-are-what-you-leaders-had-to-say-at-the-un-general-debate-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summaries and transcripts are available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gadebate.un.org/en&#34;&gt;General Debate pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10_Antonio_Guterres@0.5x-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;antónio-guterres-un-secretary-general&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;António Guterres, UN Secretary-General:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have a duty to act. And yet we are gridlocked in colossal global dysfunction. The international community is not ready or willing to tackle the big dramatic challenges of our age. These crises threaten the very future of humanity and the fate of our planet. Crises like the war in Ukraine and the multiplication of conflicts around the globe. Crises like the climate emergency and biodiversity loss&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women in power, nasty hurricanes and religious zealots — Monthly recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/september-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA  &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.09.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. The supreme court has upheld William Ruto’s victory in the presidential elections. The results had been challenged by long-time opposition leader Raila Odinga, who has now agreed to accept the court’s ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.09.22: &lt;strong&gt;Uganda&lt;/strong&gt;. The government has paid of $65m to the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) as the first instalment of the $325m Uganda was ordered to pay by the ICJ as compensation for its occupation of eastern areas of the DRC and for supporting other armed groups during the 1998-2003 conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th July, the Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. That’s no big deal, one would imagine, but sadly, for the United Nations, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is why a few months ago UN-aligned launched a campaign to bar countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from the Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the fact that our open letter to the United Nations was backed by several organisations and human rights activists, the letter was ignored.&lt;a href=&#34;https://documents-dds-ny.un.org/doc/UNDOC/GEN/G22/407/77/PDF/G2240777.pdf?OpenElement&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ukraine Recovery Conference: When Guterres (almost) told Russia to piss off</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres addressed the Ukraine Recovery Conference, which was held in Lugano Switzerland, on the 4th and 5th of July.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The event was attended by over 40 nations and nearly 20 international organisations who approved the Outcome Declaration, vowing support for Ukraine. It is estimated that the recovery plan is already worth $750 billion. The UN chief spoke boldly via a video link:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Russia’s war in Ukraine has taken thousands of lives and forcibly displaced millions of people. Millions of Ukrainians have lost their livelihoods and 90% risk of falling into poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WHO warns of pathogenic outbreaks  threatening Africa</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The WHO reported that zoonotic outbreaks on the African continent increased by 63% from 2012 to 2022 compared to the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global situation was also alarming with pathogens found in animals responsible for more than 60% of human infectious diseases, and more than 75% of emerging infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The WHO noted that these diseases sicken about one billion people every year, while killing millions of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Monkeypox, which was declared a Public Health Emergency of International Concern by the WHO Director-General on July 23, and other diseases whose names clearly indicate their animal origins, many like Aids and Ebola, do not; so for many people these diseases are just a natural hazard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Mexico suing the United Nations?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mexico has finally lost its patience with the United Nations and on August 22, President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador announced that he would be filing a formal complaint with the organisation regarding its failure to honour its commitment to supply the country with 10 million COVID-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The frustration only increased as the week went on, even as the World Health Organisation offered to ship over some of the owed vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isreal kills like it&#39;s no one&#39;s business and Asia becomes a new playground for super bullies - August 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/august-2022-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/august-2022-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Polling-station-in-Nairobi-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Polling station in Nairobi following Kenyan elections.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Polling station in Nairobi. Photo: Joewain Production&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15.08.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. Deputy President William Ruto has been declared the winner of the presidential election, narrowly defeating his rival, incumbent Raila Odinga. The announcement, which was only endorsed by three of seven members of the electoral commission, was delayed as violent scenes erupted in Parliament. Odinga has yet to concede defeat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Al-Shabaab-fighters.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An Al Shabaab fighter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America going bananas, new dinosaur and an independent Scotland: June 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:41:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;06.06.22**: Nigeria**. Over 50 people, including many children, were gunned down in a catholic church in Ondo State. So far, no group has claimed responsibility for the brutal attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/new-abelisaurid-dinosaur-Egypt-1024x409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A size comparison of five family members of the abelisaurids.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.06.22: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. A study published today in the journal Royal Society Open Science confirmed the discovery of a new abelisaurid dinosaur that lived more than 98 million years ago in the Bahariya Oasis depression of Egypt’s Western Desert. Studies on the fossil of the yet unnamed dinosaur took several years since its discovery in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Musk, new Nato members and the most expensive 20th-century art: May 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:52:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;Africa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;Western Sahara&lt;/strong&gt;. About 44 migrants trying to reach the Canary Islands have drowned off the coast of Moroccan-occupied Western Sahara after their boat capsized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. An overnight raid on a camp for displaced persons in the Ituri Province has left at least 14 people dead, including women and children. The attack follows a similar raid on a nearby mining site on Sunday that killed about 35 people. The CODECO militia is blamed for the brutal attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in April 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-april-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-april-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. As the United Nations confirmed hundreds of civilian deaths owing to the jihadist insurgency, the government announced that the army had killed 203 militants and arrested about 50 others in the Sahel region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. The Abuja-Kaduna train has been overrun by gunmen who have killed at least eight people and taken scores hostage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. About 90 people drowned over the weekend when their boat capsized as they were trying to migrate to Europe in hazardous conditions. &lt;strong&gt;18.04.22&lt;/strong&gt;: Another boat carrying migrants has capsized resulting in at least another 35 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in March 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 07:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Dozens of soldiers have been killed and many have been wounded when jihadists attacked a military camp in the centre of the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 60 volunteer vigilantes in the northwestern Kebbi State who were planning a raid on bandits operating in the area were killed by gunmen after their plans were leaked to the gang.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. About 13 gendarmes have been killed in an ambush in Taparko, a mining town that is often targeted by jihadists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in February 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:29:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;Guinea-Bissau&lt;/strong&gt;. President Umaro Sissoco Embalo survived a coup attempt that went on for five hours. Several people died during the assault, which the president blames on elements involved in corruption and drug trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 60 people have been confirmed dead, including 15 children, after an attack on a camp for displaced people in the eastern province of Ituri. CODECO, a militia that was originally a peaceful agricultural cooperative, is thought to be responsible for the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan calls on Russia to help quell its unrest, Rock star Meat Loaf dies and Prince Andrew gets stripped (out of his royal patronage)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/monthly-recap-feb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:37:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/monthly-recap-feb-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of the Gordian Monthly Recap Ruby Goldenberg, joins us from inside her messy closet, and Ariana Yekrangi from the freezing cold weather in Helsinki. If that isn’t commitment to this show, what is? Join them in catching up with everything that happened in January 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.un-aligned.org/register&#34;&gt;Become an UN-alignder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/thegordian&#34;&gt;Please our non-profit’s mission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thegordian/embed/episodes/Honduras-elects-its-first-female-president--Kazakhstan-calls-on-Russia-to-help-quell-the-unrest-and-Boris-Johnson-continues-to-make-a-fool-of-himself-e1dv7kh&#34; height=&#34;102px&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2022: What you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/february-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/february-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;Sudan&lt;/strong&gt;.  Prime Minister Abdalla Hamdok has resigned in the wake of continuing street protests. Despite having been restored to his position after the military coup in October last year, the move did little to restore confidence in the new military regime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. Ground-breaking palaeontologist, conservationist and politician Richard Leakey, who unearthed evidence suggesting humankind evolved in Africa, died aged of 77.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt;. A fire has been raging through the parliament building and has already destroyed the chamber of the National Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in December 2021</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-december-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 10:44:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-december-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. Ugandan troops have joined government forces in the DRC in order to coordinate attacks on the Allied Democratic Forces, an extremist group responsible for the slaughter of civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Jihadist militants open fire on a bus transporting civilians, including women and children, killing over 30 passengers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;The Gambia&lt;/strong&gt;. President Adama Barrow has won a second term with a comfortable margin of 53 percent; opponents, however, are disputing the results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in November 2021</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-november-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-november-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria.&lt;/strong&gt; A 21-story building collapsed in Lagos killing dozens of people. The exact toll will take several days to ascertain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;06.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Sierra Leone&lt;/strong&gt;. About a 100 people have died and many have been injured after an oil tanker exploded following a collision in the capital, Freetown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 26 kindergarten school children have been killed when their straw-hut classroom caught fire in the southern Maradi region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in November — The Gordian Monthly Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-november-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-november-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thegordian/embed/episodes/The-Gordian-Monthly-Recap-Everything-you-may-have-missed-in-November-e1bk6ej&#34; height=&#34;102px&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in October — The Gordian Monthly Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 12:28:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thegordian/embed/episodes/Heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-last-month-e19nade&#34; height=&#34;102px&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in October 2021 You May Have Missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 11:06:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/&#34;&gt;Listen to Ruby Goldenberg and Ariana Yekrangi help you catch up with everything that happened in October 2021.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. At least six refugees were shot dead by Libyan guards as they tried to leave a detention centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. In what had been described as a &amp;ldquo;first institutional return of its kind&amp;rdquo;, Jesus College, Cambridge, has agreed to return one of the Benin bronzes that had been looted from the area during colonial times. The National Commission for Museums and Monuments will receive a bronze cockerel later this year. France has also agreed to return many of the looted bronzes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;There is too much stupidity around&#34;: The UN&#39;s Climate Change Report</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sixth Assessment Report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change was published on August 9, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/&#34;&gt;The Report&lt;/a&gt; paints a grim picture of the planet’s health owing to human induced climate change and rising temperatures. These seem set to rise above the 1.5° threshold, which will signal a critical point of no return for those most exposed to the catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the report, UN Secretary-General António Guterres did not mince his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in August 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-august-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-august-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. Egyptian actress Dalal Abdel Aziz died aged 61 as a result of having contracted COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Algeria&lt;/strong&gt;. Wildfires in the north of the country have already claimed 65 lives and are continuing to threaten further death and destruction as firefighters struggle to bring them under control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Suspected Islamists on motorbikes killed 37 people including 14 children. This year alone, Islamist groups have killed at least 420 civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on Myanmar</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 29, the UN had a Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on the deteriorating situation in Myanmar. US ambassador and senior advisor for political affairs, Jeffrey DeLaurentis, summarised the dire situation, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Humanitarian aid workers inside Burma are sounding the alarm. As a direct result of the military’s brutality and administrative failures since its coup six months ago, Burma is reeling from a surge in COVID-19 cases. This burgeoning health catastrophe comes at a time when hundreds of thousands of people remain internally displaced by the recent violence, with the World Food Program projecting between 1.5 and 2.8 million additional people in the country could now be at risk of food insecurity.”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are reports of scores of doctors being rounded up and imprisoned because of the medical profession’s reaction to the coup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in July 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-july-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-july-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.07.21: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 10 people were killed in a terrorist raid on the city of Beni in the east of the country. Islamists are thought to be behind the attack, though as yet no group has claimed responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.07.21: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. Shortly after the government announced a unilateral ceasefire, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs announced that more than 400,000 have “crossed the threshold into famine in the Tigray region. Unless urgent action is taken to address the problems, the situation is likely to continue to deteriorate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Heritage Committee’s 44th session took place virtually from 16 to 31 July. It covered issues left outstanding since last year, when the annual meeting was postponed due to COVID-19. The extended session was chaired by Tian Xuejun, China’s Vice Minister for Education and Director of China’s National Commission for UNESCO. The session looked at 42 nominations to the World Heritage List (24 submitted for 2020 and 18 for 2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in June 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-june-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-june-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. The African Union has suspended Mali from the African Union over its second coup in nine months.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 160 villagers were slaughtered in a brutal onslaught that ended with the village being set on fire. Islamic militants are the likely perpetrators of the attack, though no group has as yet claimed responsibility for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. Another senseless killing spree has left 53 people dead in the north of the country.  The assailants hunted people down as they fled for their lives in a number of villages in northwest Nigeria’s Zamfara state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Pay no heed to the hippie”: Filippo Grandi, UNHCR chief, ignored once again</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The globally displaced rose from 79.5 million in 2019 to 82.4 million by the end of 2020, a near 3 million increase. This is as the G7 decides to take no action whatsoever. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UNHCR says that the number of refugees around the world has hit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unhcr.org/refugee-statistics/&#34;&gt;a new high&lt;/a&gt;, this is in spite of the pandemic, a time in which over 160 countries closed their borders. More than a third of those who fled abroad came from just five countries: Syria (6.7 million); Venezuela (4 million); Afghanistan (2.6 million); South Sudan (2.2 million); Myanmar (1.1 million). Many more are expected to have been displaced within Africa due to conflicts in Mozambique, Ethiopia and the Central Sahel region. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres publishes report about the lack of progress of UNSC Resolution 2334</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 23, the Secretary General, António Guterres, published a report on the progress (or rather lack of it) of Security Council &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/webcast/pdfs/SRES2334-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;Resolution 2334&lt;/a&gt; (2016) which “reaffirmed that the establishment by Israel of settlements in the Palestinian territory occupied since 1967, including East Jerusalem, had no legal validity and constituted a flagrant violation under international law and a major obstacle to the achievement of the two-State solution and a just, lasting and comprehensive peace.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eradicate colonialism by 2030? Unlikely.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 21st of June the United Nations General Assembly started publishing a number of draft resolutions calling on the colonial powers to relinquish their control on the few remaining colonies. The UN states that its target is to eradicate colonialism by 2030. To date, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/dppa/decolonization/en/nsgt&#34;&gt;17 non-self-governing territories&lt;/a&gt; remain. Of these, fifteen are governed by permanent members of the Security Council:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 by the UK,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 by the US and;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 by France.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list does not include occupied territories, such as Palestine, the Chagos Archipelago and Crimea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Jean Arnault and what can he do about the Afghan peace talks?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Secretary General António Guterres appointed the Frenchman Jean Arnault as his envoy covering Afghanistan and regional issues. Mr Arnault is expected to support the negotiations and implementation of any agreements between the Taliban and Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jean Arnault is a former philosophy student with an extensive working background in United Nations missions in Asia, including Afghanistan, Europe, Latin America, and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No doubt his outstanding &lt;a href=&#34;https://cic.nyu.edu/content/jean-arnault&#34;&gt;experience&lt;/a&gt; in international diplomacy will bring a massive force behind the Afghan peace talks, and although we wish him all the best, it must be said that the UN&amp;rsquo;s political response to this conflict has been largely uninspiring. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France halts its joint military operations in Mali as the G7 pledge 870 million doses of vaccine to the world</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/france-halts-joint-military-operations-in-mali-as-the-g7-pledge-870-million-doses-of-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 10:57:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/france-halts-joint-military-operations-in-mali-as-the-g7-pledge-870-million-doses-of-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlike-france-the-un-must-not-suspend-its-peacekeeping-operations-in-mali&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlike France, the UN must not suspend its peacekeeping operations&lt;/strong&gt; in Mali&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following Mali’s latest coup on May 24, France decided to stop joint military operations with Malian forces until it is convinced that a civilian government will be returning to power. Some may argue that the UN should also take a step back and suspend its peacekeeping operations rather than indirectly aid a regime that usurped power. This would be a mistake and fortunately one the UN is not prepared to make. After Colonel Assimi Goïta’s first coup of 18 August 2020, the UN spokesperson, Stéphane Dujarric stressed that the mission “must and will continue” and the situation is just as dire now as it was then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 5 new non-permanent members of the UNSC for the term of 2022-2023?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/who-are-the-five-new-non-permanent-members-of-the-unsc-for-the-term-of-2022-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/who-are-the-five-new-non-permanent-members-of-the-unsc-for-the-term-of-2022-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Final tallies earlier this month showed that Albania, Brazil, Gabon, Ghana and the United Arab Emirates (UAE) were elected as the five new non-permanent members of the United Nations Security Council.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new members elected this year will be taking up their seats on 01.01.2022 and will serve for 1 year, until 31.12.2023. Four out of the Five new members have served on the council before: Brazil 10 times; Gabon and Ghana 2 times, while Albania has never served as a member. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mladic revisited: An unremarkable news item, were it not for the absurdity of the process</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:04:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ratko Mladic, the former Bosnian Serb commander largely responsible for the Srebrenica Massacre in 1995 lost his appeal with the special UN tribunal set up to judge the case. He had been convicted on ten counts including genocide and crimes against humanity. This is an unremarkable news item really, were it not for the absurdity of the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuremberg_trials&#34;&gt;Nuremberg Trial&lt;/a&gt; (20 November 1945 - 1 October 1946) took less than a year to try 24 of the most prominent Nazis after World War II. Imagine if that trial had dragged on for as long: it would have been lingering on until the 1970’s. True, despite having been charged in July 1996, Mladic was not apprehended and extradited to the Hague for trial by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) until May 2011. Still, most of the ICTY’s cases had been dealt with by then. Nevertheless, the trial formally began a whole year later and he was not convicted until 22 November 2017, after which, the appeals process, that has only now been completed, was referred to the successor body, International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in May 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-may-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 09:19:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-may-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-Notizie-Aprile-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.04.21: &lt;strong&gt;Sudan&lt;/strong&gt;. An armed attack by militias in El Geneina, the capital of West Darfur State left at least 18 people dead and 54 others injured according to the Sudanese Doctors&amp;rsquo; Committee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.04.08: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. The United Nation has raised the alarm stating that the country is heading towards a famine with up to 27 million people, a third of the population, likely to experience acute hunger. The situation is exacerbated by ongoing conflicts and the rising COVID-19 cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in February 2021 You May Have Missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-february-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 08:50:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-february-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-notizie-nel-febbraio-2021-che-potresti-esserti-perso.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.02.21: &lt;strong&gt;Somalia.&lt;/strong&gt; Al-Shabab militants stormed the Afrik Hotel in the capital Mogadishu and started shooting at guests. At least nine people were killed including a former military general and four of the assailants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.02.21: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. UN-brokered peace talks held in Geneva have led to the formation of an interim unity government that will put an end to rival administrations. The government will work towards holding free elections in December. The country has been in turmoil since NATO-backed forces killed leader Muammar Gaddafi in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed January 2021</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:02:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Italian_-What-you-may-have-missed-in-Jan-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Scores of villagers were slaughtered by suspected Islamist terrorists in coordinated attacks on two villages near the border with Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. Incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadera was declared the winner of the presidential election that was held last month against a backdrop of unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05/06.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;DRC Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. A ferryboat carrying over 70 people capsized on Lake Kivu. About 50 people were rescued and the bodies a woman and two children found. Twenty or so people are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed December 2020</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. The top court rejected former President François Bozizé’s bid to run for president in the December 27 election against incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadéra. The former president failed to meet the ethical standards required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ghana&lt;/strong&gt;. Results of the presidential election held on Monday have confirmed a narrow victory for incumbent President Nana Akufo-Addo. His main rival was ex-President John Mahama. Supporters of both candidates took to the streets following delays in the announcement of the results and at least five people were killed in the unrest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution Gaming fires hundreds of employees as it buys NetEnt for $2.1 billion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/evolution-gaming-fires-hundreds-of-employees-as-it-buys-netent-for-2-1-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 14:38:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/evolution-gaming-fires-hundreds-of-employees-as-it-buys-netent-for-2-1-billion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following article, written by Alex Liberto, concerns one of our Maltese members who was a victim of a ruthless mass sacking following the takeover of one company by another.  Sadly, the coronavirus has already caused havoc in the jobs market around the world, but if anyone one can suggest what UN-aligned can do to support these people, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-ugly-side-to-capitalism&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another Ugly Side to Capitalism…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was the first day of December, the month of merriment and Christmas spirit. The staff at NetEnt were already planning Yuletide activities, trying to balance Covid restrictions with the desire to celebrate. They were unaware that this Christmas would be hijacked by something much more nefarious for them than Covid; the heartless stripping away of their livelihood. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in October 2020 you may have missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-october-2020-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:52:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/news-in-october-2020-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;europe&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Europe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;UK&lt;/strong&gt;. The EU has set in motion legal proceedings against the UK after it reneged on sections of its Brexit “divorce” deal. Talks, however, are set to continue. The UK was given until November to respond to EU concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;Greece&lt;/strong&gt;: The neofascist party Golden Dawn was declared a criminal organization for its role in a series of attacks on migrants and left-wing activists. &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; called it the “biggest trial of fascists since Nuremberg.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed: August 2020</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 17:00:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Cameroon&lt;/strong&gt;. In a vicious grenade attack targeting a camp for displaced people, as they slept, suspected Boko Haram militants murdered over 16 people and wounded several others in the village of Nguetchewe, northern Cameroon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Tanzania&lt;/strong&gt;. Tundu Lissu, an opposition politician who survived being shot 16 times in an assassination attempt, will challenge President Magufuli in the October elections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mauritius&lt;/strong&gt;. A state of emergency has been announced after an oil spill from a damaged Japanese ship is contaminating vast tracts of water. Baby tortoises and rare plants from an island near the spill, Ile aux Aigrettes, are being taken to the mainland to protect them from the worsening situation. The ship had struck a reef on July 25.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You May Have Missed: July 2020</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:27:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 30 farmers were slaughtered by armed jihadists on motorcycles while they were returning home from their fields in villages in the Mopti region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. The number of people killed in protests over the murder of popular political singer, Hachalu Hundessa, on June 29 rose to 156 according to a senior official.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ivory Coast&lt;/strong&gt;. Prime Minister Amadou Gon Coulibaly died aged 61 a few days after returning from France where he had undergone a medical check-up relating to a heart condition. He fell ill at a ministerial meeting and was rushed to hospital where he died shortly afterwards. He was the ruling party&amp;rsquo;s candidate for the October presidential election and was expected to replace the outgoing President Alassane Ouattara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you May Have Missed in June 2020</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 08:51:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VhGGrppQsg4&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/VhGGrppQsg4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O4.05.20: &lt;strong&gt;Burundi&lt;/strong&gt;. President Pierre Nkurunzizahas, who had been in power for 15 years, died aged 55 following a heart attack. He was due to step down in August. Riots following the start of his third term, five years ago, which many considered unconstitutional, resulted in 1,200 deaths and widespread violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5.06.20: &lt;strong&gt;Uganda&lt;/strong&gt;. The Buganda Kingdom and local communities were in shock over a fire that destroyed one of the sacred houses at the Tombs of Buganda Kings of Kasubi. The site is inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
