<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diaries From Refugee Camps on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/diaries-from-refugee-camps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diaries From Refugee Camps on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/diaries-from-refugee-camps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life on Repeat: Jihan&#39;s Diary from the Frontlines of a Refugee Camp&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life in a refugee camp seems stuck in an unending cycle of sameness. Days blur into one another, the only change being the unpredictable and often unforgiving weather conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is an attempt to document the individual days, but the repetition of the mundane is all too clear. Every harsh, cold morning feels identical, showing no mercy to the inhabitants. The only source of warmth is the resilience of the human spirit, akin to the skeletal structure of a body that refuses to succumb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My internship comes to an end, but my journey continues</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my internship at the UN-aligned, I did my best to convey the suffering of refugees and their lives in the camps through interviews and life in the camp. As a refugee myself, I now want to share one last story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I met a 23-year-old returning from work in the stone sawmills with his clothes covered in dust. He was the son of our neighbour and one of the brightest students at his university. He was forced to leave school due to forced majeure and ended up supporting his family by working in the mills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years immigration has been a controversial subject in the US. Some Americans call for harsher policies against immigration, others for a revision of immigration policies to allow for easier processing and more assistance to refugees. All in all, one after the other, governments have tried to revise these policies in hopes of appeasing the American population, but neither has been able to fully address this issue in a manner favourable to all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;We always hope for change, but we are powerless. We are just refugees&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to visit a friend of mine, it has been a while since I visited her and when we sat down and started chatting. She started telling me the story of a neighbour of hers in the camp who got very sick with corona and her children started running around to help her. She was then admitted to the hospital and put on an oxygen cylinder. The story filled me with sadness and thoughts filled my head. What is this epidemic that has taken over the whole world and claimed the lives of many friends and loved ones?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Almoallem Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One day, my little sister and I were studying for the high school exams, so we were all sitting very quietly. Suddenly we heard the sound of shooting near our camp; not only close, but actually in the camp. We started hearing the voices of children screaming and crying, and they all scrambled for their tents or perhaps entered a neighbour’s tent because of the fear and panic. We subconsciously put our heads to the ground and we started wondering what was going on. What are these sounds?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I entered the university and my heart is leaping with joy!” — An extracts from a refugee’s journal</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:31:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the days of the war in Syria, we lost our safety. We used to sleep to the sound of cannons and wake up to the sound of planes. One day, my mother asked me to go to the pharmacy near our house to buy a fever-reducing medicine for my little brother; while I was on the way back with my little sister, a shell fell in front of us. The people on the street started running to see what happened. We did not stop running until I got home, and we survived. This is one of the most difficult memories that stick in my memory and cannot be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education of Syrian Refugees During the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 09:59:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to the epidemic, the refugee child was twice as likely to leave school as a non-refugee child. In Lebanon, poverty-related changes have been driven largely by inflation and poverty has increased by about 33 percentage points among the Lebanese population; the increase among Syrian refugees here, however, has increased by 55 percent. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Children have not been able to continue their studies because of closures, but they are also constrained by a lack of educational opportunities at home and the digital divide.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a Syrian refugee?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 09:42:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Syrian; I think this phrase is enough to indicate that I may be in Sweden, Germany, Egypt or one of the many countries Syrians have resorted to in order to survive the tragedy inside Syria. This tragedy has left Syrians under the rubble, submerged in the Mediterranean Sea as they try to cross into Europe, or languishing in a prison under interrogation; perhaps eviscerated or eviscerating themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I Am A Syrian Refugee Who Lives In Lebanon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I still have hope that we will all return to our warm home and beautiful city” — Interview with Syrian refugee, Somaya</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-your-life-and-how-you-got-here&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your life and how you got here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am Somaya, a mother of three children, two daughters and a son. At the beginning of the war in my country, Syria, I lost my husband and did not know anything about what could have happened to him. When the battles intensified, I took my children and went to my father, as he lived alone in Damascus because my mother was dead. We lived with him for about a year, and then the war broke out in Damascus as well. One day we woke up to the sound of guns, bullets, and planes. I took my children and we went with my father to take refuge in the shelters. We stayed like this for three days until we finally decided to get away from this area. We actually made our way on foot, until we approached a car that was in a traffic jam on the way to the border with Lebanon. We accosted them and found that they too were leaving Syria for refuge in Lebanon. With them we eventually reached the Lebanese border and once in Lebanon, a tent was secured for us to live in. So after witnessing so much death, we finally found safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My religion is myself and my nationality is my heart”: Five days inside a refugee’s diary</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 10:22:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During her internship with UN-aligned, Jihan Al-Assad was asked to write about her life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Her experiences, along with those of other refugees are published in a new series titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/diaries-from-refugee-camps/&#34;&gt;Diaries from Refugee Camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-1122021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1/12/2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a new month and the end of a whole year. This does not feel like the beginning of a month or a day or anything new. I am afraid because I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what is coming to me, and this idea is a big horror for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disheartening revelations about the UNHCR in Lebanon — A refugee’s perspective</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 09:53:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary mission of the United Nations Refugee Agency, the UNHCR in Lebanon, is to provide emergency assistance to those forced to flee their homes. This is the first step towards long-term protection and rehabilitation, as well as a means to support in various sectors for refugees and asylum seekers. But how is this achieved in the current reality, especially in a country like Lebanon? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;positive-action-of-the-unhcr-in-lebanon&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive action of the UNHCR in Lebanon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the UNHCR include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following interview was conducted in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-yourself-and-your-children&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself and your children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Amna; I am 33 years old. I live in Lebanon in a Syrian refugee camp. I have two children, a son and a daughter. My husband was lost in Syria, and I fled with my children from the war and came to Arsal to seek safety away from the difficult conditions of the war that destroyed our lives and the childhood of my children. I tried to work to meet the needs of my children, but I could not for fear of leaving them alone in the tent and I wanted to teach them and follow their school lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Life Without Flowers: A Glimpse Into The Arsal Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I will talk about my place of residence in one of the camps in Lebanon, Arsal, and how I was able to adapt to this difficult life, which does not resemble life at all. It is only days that pass without taste. One of the most difficult days of my life was when I was fifteen years old. My family decided that we should live In a refugee camp. At that time, misfortune and sadness overtook me, and I went into a state of depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
