<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animal Rights on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/animal-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animal Rights on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/animal-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How CalAnimals is making a difference for animals in California</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people who love their companion animals, it may be surprising how so many animals wind up in shelters unclaimed, says Jill Tucker, CEO of California Animal Welfare Association&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tucker, who originally started her career in software, shifted into the animal sector in 2003, where she moved from California to Vermont to run an animal humane society organisation. From starting as a foster parent to making her way as the president of that same organisation, Tucker found herself as a leader in protecting animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WHO warns of pathogenic outbreaks  threatening Africa</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The WHO reported that zoonotic outbreaks on the African continent increased by 63% from 2012 to 2022 compared to the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global situation was also alarming with pathogens found in animals responsible for more than 60% of human infectious diseases, and more than 75% of emerging infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The WHO noted that these diseases sicken about one billion people every year, while killing millions of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Monkeypox, which was declared a Public Health Emergency of International Concern by the WHO Director-General on July 23, and other diseases whose names clearly indicate their animal origins, many like Aids and Ebola, do not; so for many people these diseases are just a natural hazard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the campaign to save cruelty-free cosmetics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EU&amp;rsquo;s ban on animal testing for cosmetics is under threath as new analysis (link) finds that cosmetics sold in the EU and UK contain chemicals tested on animals. Furthermore, the European Chemicals Agency (ECHA) is requesting new animal tests on ingredients that have been used in cosmetics safely for years. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than 400 animal rights organizations and companies, including PETA, The Body Shop, Dove and it´s parent company Unilever have signed and sent an open letter to the Presidents of the European Commission, the Parliament and the Council to fully commit to the EU-regulation and continue with its course for a global ban by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How cultivated meat can save the planet</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animal agriculture is a major contributor to greenhouse gas emissions; it is driving up climate change, antibiotic resistance, deforestation and the resulting biodiversity loss. It is also an incredibly inefficient, as well as immoral, way to feed the planet. For example, in the United States alone, 56 million acres of land are used to grow feed for animals, while only 4 million acres are cultivated to produce plants for humans to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accidentally Vegan Feature?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve pondered veganism but haven’t yet followed through, it may be that you are put off by the myth of the diet being restricted. As with any lifestyle change, slow and steady tends to lead to longevity. It is much better to gradually cut animal products from your diet permanently than trying to be a strict vegan for a month, falling off the wagon, and being put off enough to never try it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving voice to the the voiceless: Animal Equality’s Global Fight for Farmed Animals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/animal-equality-14-years-of-supporting-those-on-the-brink-animals-reared-for-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/animal-equality-14-years-of-supporting-those-on-the-brink-animals-reared-for-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animal Equality is an international organisation that was founded in Spain in 2006 by Sharon Nuñez, Jose Valle and Javier Moreno; their one objective: to protect animals. From that moment on, a growing enthusiasm and commitment ensured the organisation’s global reach. It has expanded to such an extent, that it is now one of the most successful forces for the defence of farmed animals.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animal Equality’s vision is that of a world where all animals are respected and protected. Our core values are compassion, determination, and effectiveness; these guide us in our daily operations, which are designed to end cruelty to farmed animals. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annus Horribilis? Looking on the brighter side of 2020</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:25:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has certainly been an Annus Horribilis, with plagues, floods, fires, terrorist attacks and wars, but it wasn’t all bad&amp;hellip; In the sciences for instance, vaccines to fight the coronavirus were created in record time. In business, SpaceX ferried astronauts to the International Space Station in the first commercial flight of its kind. Here are some of the success stories from 2020 with regards to human rights and animal welfare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
