<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russia on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/russia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russia on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/russia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Armenia’s ICC Pivot: Defying Russia and Eyeing European and Iranian Ties</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unprecedented development, Armenian lawmakers have ratified the Rome Statute, thereby signifying the nation&amp;rsquo;s intent to join the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This development has sent ripples all the way to the Kremlin, which seems less than pleased. Given the earlier move by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;ICC to issue an arrest warrant for Russian President&lt;/a&gt; Vladimir Putin in March, Armenia now finds itself on a tightrope, precariously balancing its long-standing alliance with Russia. This recent gesture by Armenia has not only added a strain to its delicate camaraderie with Russia but also hints at a cautious pivot towards the West for a security umbrella. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Peace Now Secure: Fugitive War Criminal Assumes UN Peacekeeping Chief Role</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:59:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the adage goes, “truth is stranger than fiction”. Case in point: Russia, the very nation embroiled in a relentless war in Ukraine, has assumed the presidency of the UN Security Council, an institution dedicated to preserving global peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add to the absurdity, Russia&amp;rsquo;s top dog, Vladimir Putin, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;slapped with an arrest warrant&lt;/a&gt; by the ICC for his role in abducting Ukrainian children. As we try to make sense of this bizarre twist of fate, one can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if this is an elaborate April Fools&amp;rsquo; ruse, leaving Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s UN mission and countless others befuddled and aghast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Pursues Putin: A Sprinkle of Justice in a World of Mischief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-reality-of-abducted-children-in-ukraine&#34;&gt;Chilling Reality of Abducted Children in Ukraine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Vladimir Putin, seemingly untouchable and unaccountable for countless transgressions, continues to cause havoc in Ukraine, a glimmer of hope emerges from the unlikeliest of origins: the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spark that ignited the fire was a public “thank you” from the Children&amp;rsquo;s Rights Commissioner, Maria Alekseyevna Lvova-Belova. She &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2023/02/16/putins-childrens-envoy-reveals-she-adopted-child-from-mariupol-a80249&#34;&gt;expressed gratitude to Putin&lt;/a&gt; for enabling the “adoption” of a young boy from Mariupol, unwittingly revealing the chilling reality of Ukrainian children torn from their homes and subjected to “re-education camps” or forced adoptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Scenarios of Russia’s Removal from the UN Security Council: A Bleak Future or a Chance for a Fresh Start?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 08:23:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia’s permanent seat on the UN Security Council is under scrutiny like never. What would happen if the UN decided to expel this rogue state from the Security Council? Will it lead to war, polarisation, or perhaps a new beginning for the UN?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About a year ago now, on 7 April 2022, the UN General Assembly adopted a resolution triggering the suspension of Russia from the Human Rights Council. Oh, would it not be lovely if it could also be suspended from its status as a permanent member of the Security Council! But first things first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia booted out of the UN Human Rights Council. What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to its charter, the UN was created to maintain international peace and security, protect human rights, deliver humanitarian aid, and support sustainable development. Each of these is an honourable goal that is sometimes brought to fruition in parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;193 countries around the globe are members of the United Nations and among those are the P5 (permanent Security Council Members) chosen because of their importance in the aftermath of WWII. Each one of these countries is part of the UN because they claim to believe in what this organisation stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When I see all my kingsmen, Krishna, who have come here on this field of battle, life goes from my limbs and they sink, and my mouth is sear and dry; a trembling overcomes my body, and my hair shudders in horror. My great bow, Gandiva, falls from my hands and the skin of my flesh is burning; I am no longer able to stand, because my mind is whirling and wondering. And I see forebodings of evil, Krishna. I cannot foresee any glory if I kill my own kinsmen in the sacrifice of battle. Because I have no wish for victory, Krishna, nor for kingdom, nor for its pleasures. How can we want a kingdom, Govinda, or its pleasures or even life, when those for whom we want a kingdom and its pleasures, and the joys of life are here in this field of battle, giving up their wealth and their life?” (Translation by Juan Mascaró)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t the UN expel Russia like the League of Nations did in 1939?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 10:32:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via a video address to the UN security Council on April 5, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky urged the Council to expel Russia “so it cannot block decisions about its own war”, which he emphasised was responsible for “the most terrible war crimes”. Some days ago, on June 28, he went further and called for a complete expulsion, adding that an international tribunal should investigate &amp;ldquo;the actions of Russian occupiers on Ukrainian soil&amp;rdquo; so that the Kremlin could be “brought to justice”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finland’s troubled history with Russia — A Story in Photos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:36:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-february-manifesto-and-the-russification-of-finland-1899&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The February Manifesto and the Russification of Finland (1899)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The February manifesto was part of the larger operation of the Russification of Finland during which Finnish territories were forced to align their cultures with that of the Russian empire. On the 5th of February 1899, Nicholas II of Russia, the Tsar of Russia, defined a new legislation order that asserted the imperial Russian government to rule over Finland without the consultation of the Finnish Senate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council of Europe and the struggle to uphold human rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:01:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe is an organization that was founded in 1949 after the conclusion of the second World War. The council is composed of 47 member states with 27 of those states also being members of the European Union. The council operates on the mission of protecting and preserving human rights throughout its domain. This council was formed so that no atrocities such as those seen during World War II, would ever occur again. Since its inception, the Council of Europe has expanded to include six smaller councils and assemblies that actively work towards achieving goals such as abolitioning the death penalty, supporting children’s rights, ensuring fair and equal elections, and fighting for equal access to healthcare. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russian and Ukrainian are often mistaken as the same language, especially by people who have no prior exposure to Slavic languages. This confusion is justified considering that both Russian and Ukrainian use the Cyrillic alphabet, and they both belong to the language family of East Slavic (Slavonic languages). In fact, the only other East Slavic language is Belarusian. Many sources estimate Old East Slavic to have diverged into these three sub-languages as early as the fifth century. This left a large window of time for these languages to develop independently. Historical and geographical aspects have also influenced the development of these languages. This article compares Russian and Ukrainian from a number of linguistic aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Putin: “You are a serial killer, but there is one thing I must thank you for…”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Putin,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not mean to be rude by not gracing your name with a salutation or title; quite the contrary; if I had done so, only obscenities would have been appropriate under the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation I am referring to is, of course, your ever-increasing list of crimes: yours, plus the many your soldiers are sanctioned to carry out in your name, such as murdering innocent men, women and children, rape and pillaging. “Kill one man, and you are a murderer. Kill millions of men, and you are a conqueror. Kill them all, and you are a god.”  I see that a god is what you are aspiring to become; a sinister god of the underworld, no doubt, but don’t delude yourself! Jean Rostand was referring to the perception in the minds of fools. You are no god. You are just a serial killer, a rapist, a bully and a thief. You will join the ranks of other sadists, who like you, abused their power to bring death and destruction into the world. However, in some ways you are worse than they are. They operated in darker times, when Truth was still struggling to climb out of her well. You have not got the luxury of mitigating circumstances. Truth is easily accessible now. The fanaticism of the past had been shown up for what it is, but you embrace it and with cynical irony you justify your onslaught on Ukraine as a Nazi-clensing operation, when in fact, it is your evil that is the closest thing to Nazism the world has known since Hitler’s demise. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t be NATO, it should be the United Nations: The Poetry of Appeasement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-the-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We the people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the list of governments I hate grows longer by the day, I cannot help but wonder about all the people who elected them into power in the first place. True, sometimes the system is rigged against the people, either because of the iron grip of despotic regimes or through a flawed system that only provides an illusion of choice. What Julius Nyerere said about America, applies to many democracies: “The United States is also a one-party state but, with typical American extravagance, they have two of them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At last, European Unity Prevails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 10:28:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We stood by and watched Putin help deliver both Brexit and Trump. We were quite happy letting him tear Syria apart. So what, he invaded Donbas? He is a cold-blooded murderer? “What then? poor beastie, thou maun live!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Putinism required diplomacy”, that’s what diplomats said anyway. It was obvious to most, at the time of each of these hammer blows, that Putin’s tentacles had penetrated through and influenced our democracy. Our response to this despot for his crimes? The occasional sanctions here are there. Don’t get me wrong; although they are increasingly becoming the bulwark of our international system, sanctions can work. But they won’t if we are too paralysed by indecision, or when we are at crossroads with ultra-complex choices: utilising green energy, on the one hand, or continuing importing Russian gas during a climate emergency, on the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We support Ukraine because it represents the sacrosanct right to build one&#39;s own future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After appealing to the Russian President, Volodymyr Zelenskyy only received silence in return. He therefore decided to deliver a speech to the people of Russia and to the people of the world; not as the President of Ukraine, but as he put it, as a citizen of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy spoke about the shared 2000km border with Russia that is today breached by almost 200,000 soldiers and thousands of military units. This situation could trigger a widespread war on the European continent. The area is now a smouldering keg that could potentially burst into a catastrophic conflagration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is a death knell for the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ould you entrust a child you love to the care of a school or nursery if you knew that not only many of its teachers, but the school board itself, consisted of child abusers, rapists and murderers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course not! And yet that is exactly what we are doing when we entrust world peace and human rights to the United Nations. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Nations, in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. By ‘integral’ I am particularly referring to the five permanent members (P5) of the UN Security Council. In fact, most of the world problems since WWII stem directly or indirectly from one or more of these five permanent members. The Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine is just one of the many instances of a crisis that has been caused or exacerbated by one of these powers. I have discussed the flaws of the UN at length in my recent book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/&#34;&gt;Unravelling the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, so I will not dwell on its lack of structural integrity or its monumental failures here. Instead, I wish to focus on the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vlady Hell: Putin Strikes Again!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:05:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the August 2020 issue of The Gordian titled Russian Roulette: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity&lt;/a&gt; we published an article cheekily called Vlad the Terrible. It listed a range of crimes committed by Putin ranging from mass murder to mass deceit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vlad-the-terrible&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vlad the Terrible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You play with fire and you risk getting burned; play with the devil and you end up screwed. Sadly, this is exactly what is happening to Europe and beyond now that the demon is waving his devil’s fork and even threatening nuclear destruction. The good news is not only that we have learned a lesson, but even more remarkably, that we are prepared to suffer the consequences of our mistakes and send this devil to hell!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Kamchatka in pictures: A visual tour of this stunning region&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kamchatka sits in the far east of Russia with one arm brushing past Alaska and another reaching down to Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A region famous for active volcanoes and a huge population of Brown bears.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although Kamchatka has stunning nature, the territory can be hostile and dangerous for unprepared tourists, and those who are not local should travel with a guide for their own safety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1.-Tolbachik-volcano-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arriving to the vicinity of the Tolbachik volcano, a black desert with volcanic sand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Church of Putin: Inside The Cathedral of Russian Armed Forces - in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces1-502x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has long been a link between Russian banks and the Russian Orthodox Church, so for many it came as no surprise to learn that an extraordinary new cathedral was being built in the outskirts of Moscow costing allegedly 82 Million USD. Photo by Alexia James.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces10-498x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about the mixture of military and religious imagery. Some may consider it distasteful, while other patriots may view it as complimentary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Times the Russian Orthodox Church Flouted Norms of Decency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the former communist regime, the Russian Orthodox Church (ROC) was suppressed, its properties confiscated and its followers harassed and imprisoned. This was until a Messiah came along. He promised the church fortune, a return to traditional values, a trip to simpler times when the state and church washed filth off each others’ backs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, Putin and the Russian Orthodox Church walk hand-in-hand in so many ways. From the eyes of the church he is seen as a “miracle of God”, a humble Russian worshiper who wants to put the Church at the heart of Russia’s national identity. However, the Church is not the only one who has wet dreams; what the ROC knows too well is that they must return the favour. And we all know what the price of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/vlad-the-terrible/&#34;&gt;a deal with the devil&lt;/a&gt; is: selling your soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian Roulette: Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-grim-trend&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Grim Trend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July seems to have accelerated the grim trend that has been eroding civility and security over the last few years. The month dawned with Hong Kong finding itself stripped of many of its civil liberties. A few days later, on the 6th, President Trump formally notified the World Health Organisation that the US would be withdrawing from the organisation once the required twelve-month’s period of notice was over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of accessible tourist visas to balance our perception of Russia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2020, Russia announced that it would soon be offering a simplified and cheaper online visa application for tourists from EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you were asked to describe Russia, your immediate thoughts may be of snow, bears and vodka. Unsurprisingly, Russia does contain all of those things. Think a little more and you might settle on political tension, corruption and the mafia. Unless you had visited, you probably would not envision the long summers in a cottage surrounded by countryside, LGBT activists, or a local taxi driver cracking jokes in elementary English. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
