<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ukraine on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ukraine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ukraine on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ukraine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Odessa&#39;s Cultural Heritage Threatened by Ongoing Conflict in Ukraine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 25, UNESCO inscribed the historical Ukrainian city of Odessa on the World Heritage List and the World Heritage in Danger List. “Odessa, a free city, a world city, a legendary port that has left its mark on cinema, literature and the arts, is thus placed under the reinforced protection of the international community,” said Audrey Azoulay, Director-General of UNESCO. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The people of the port city were delighted as was its mayor, Gennady Trukhanov. He pointed out, however, that the task would not be an easy one:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When I see all my kingsmen, Krishna, who have come here on this field of battle, life goes from my limbs and they sink, and my mouth is sear and dry; a trembling overcomes my body, and my hair shudders in horror. My great bow, Gandiva, falls from my hands and the skin of my flesh is burning; I am no longer able to stand, because my mind is whirling and wondering. And I see forebodings of evil, Krishna. I cannot foresee any glory if I kill my own kinsmen in the sacrifice of battle. Because I have no wish for victory, Krishna, nor for kingdom, nor for its pleasures. How can we want a kingdom, Govinda, or its pleasures or even life, when those for whom we want a kingdom and its pleasures, and the joys of life are here in this field of battle, giving up their wealth and their life?” (Translation by Juan Mascaró)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ukraine Recovery Conference: When Guterres (almost) told Russia to piss off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres addressed the Ukraine Recovery Conference, which was held in Lugano Switzerland, on the 4th and 5th of July.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The event was attended by over 40 nations and nearly 20 international organisations who approved the Outcome Declaration, vowing support for Ukraine. It is estimated that the recovery plan is already worth $750 billion. The UN chief spoke boldly via a video link:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Russia’s war in Ukraine has taken thousands of lives and forcibly displaced millions of people. Millions of Ukrainians have lost their livelihoods and 90% risk of falling into poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t the UN expel Russia like the League of Nations did in 1939?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 10:32:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via a video address to the UN security Council on April 5, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky urged the Council to expel Russia “so it cannot block decisions about its own war”, which he emphasised was responsible for “the most terrible war crimes”. Some days ago, on June 28, he went further and called for a complete expulsion, adding that an international tribunal should investigate &amp;ldquo;the actions of Russian occupiers on Ukrainian soil&amp;rdquo; so that the Kremlin could be “brought to justice”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and Moldova&#39;s EU candidacy status… beneficial?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 08:52:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-ukraine-and-moldova-are-granted-candidacy-status-does-that-mean-they-are-members-now&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ukraine and Moldova are granted candidacy status, does that mean they are members now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If only it were that easy! Based on a recommendation from the European Commission, the European Council can grant Candidate Status to prospective members of the European Union. The right to join the block, however, is not one that is automatically granted to countries who receive a candidacy status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the European Council decides to begin accession negotiations with the candidate country, the Commission evaluates the application in light of the Copenhagen criteria, which we will talk more about below, and formulates an opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media in an Era of Invasion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From February 24th until now, nearly tens of thousands of people have been either injured or killed by the Russian invasion of Ukraine. This is an unfortunate number of people, especially so when considering the number of refugees fleeing Ukraine; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/conflict-ukraine&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;with more than five million leaving Ukraine in search of safety. The people of Ukraine have been pushed from their homes, forced to leave behind their lives, families, friends, and pets; but they are resilient people and have given the world personal insights to life in Ukraine post-invasion. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council of Europe and the struggle to uphold human rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:01:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe is an organization that was founded in 1949 after the conclusion of the second World War. The council is composed of 47 member states with 27 of those states also being members of the European Union. The council operates on the mission of protecting and preserving human rights throughout its domain. This council was formed so that no atrocities such as those seen during World War II, would ever occur again. Since its inception, the Council of Europe has expanded to include six smaller councils and assemblies that actively work towards achieving goals such as abolitioning the death penalty, supporting children’s rights, ensuring fair and equal elections, and fighting for equal access to healthcare. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russian and Ukrainian are often mistaken as the same language, especially by people who have no prior exposure to Slavic languages. This confusion is justified considering that both Russian and Ukrainian use the Cyrillic alphabet, and they both belong to the language family of East Slavic (Slavonic languages). In fact, the only other East Slavic language is Belarusian. Many sources estimate Old East Slavic to have diverged into these three sub-languages as early as the fifth century. This left a large window of time for these languages to develop independently. Historical and geographical aspects have also influenced the development of these languages. This article compares Russian and Ukrainian from a number of linguistic aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rehauling Lady Justice: Is the United Nations guilty in Ukraine?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long as international justice is left in the hands of nation states at the UN nothing will ever improve because self-interest will always win the day. This needs to change. Meet the new lady justice!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lady-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why representations of Lady Justice depict her in a blindfold? The accepted explanation is that the blindfold symbolises impartiality. Lady Justice is supposed to be oblivious to power, status, wealth or any other privilege. She also sports scales, which represent fairness through the weighing up of the facts, and a sword, which represents swift and thorough retribution. Although the scales date back to her earliest manifestations as the Egyptian goddess Maat, the blindfold probably originated with Hans Gieng’s 1543 Gerechtigkeitsbrunnen (Fountain of Justice) in the Old City of Bern. Despite the accepted wisdom, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems For a Better World: This War of MMXXII</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:54:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Invasion for pure greed and gratification.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else can this be?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Civilians, soldiers, casualties dying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In their blood lying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lives are meaningless,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The soul is downcast and sighing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is the battlefield, blood, brutality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Politicians lacking  rationality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aggression, destruction, death and ravished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers and innocent lying on the streets.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Surely logic has perished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The cold carnage continues …&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Unleashed on humanity.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mourning for innocent lives.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who will stop the insanity?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can people not see such torment and tragedy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is only depravity and brutality…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Putin: “You are a serial killer, but there is one thing I must thank you for…”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Putin,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not mean to be rude by not gracing your name with a salutation or title; quite the contrary; if I had done so, only obscenities would have been appropriate under the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation I am referring to is, of course, your ever-increasing list of crimes: yours, plus the many your soldiers are sanctioned to carry out in your name, such as murdering innocent men, women and children, rape and pillaging. “Kill one man, and you are a murderer. Kill millions of men, and you are a conqueror. Kill them all, and you are a god.”  I see that a god is what you are aspiring to become; a sinister god of the underworld, no doubt, but don’t delude yourself! Jean Rostand was referring to the perception in the minds of fools. You are no god. You are just a serial killer, a rapist, a bully and a thief. You will join the ranks of other sadists, who like you, abused their power to bring death and destruction into the world. However, in some ways you are worse than they are. They operated in darker times, when Truth was still struggling to climb out of her well. You have not got the luxury of mitigating circumstances. Truth is easily accessible now. The fanaticism of the past had been shown up for what it is, but you embrace it and with cynical irony you justify your onslaught on Ukraine as a Nazi-clensing operation, when in fact, it is your evil that is the closest thing to Nazism the world has known since Hitler’s demise. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romania Always Welcomes Ukrainian Refugees: Support and Opportunities Await</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 10:06:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few days since Romanians stopped wearing masks. Literally speaking, we have finally been told that such protection is no longer necessary, even though the hospitals are still full of sick people. The pandemic is not over, but a greater evil has appeared at the borders of our country, an evil we would hopefully never meet face to face: war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrible as it sounds and can be felt in the images broadcast 24 hours a day on all the TV stations, the war in the neighbouring country has produced an unprecedented, totally unexpected outcome: Romanians stopped wearing masks in their daily lives and started showing their true colours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t be NATO, it should be the United Nations: The Poetry of Appeasement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-the-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We the people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the list of governments I hate grows longer by the day, I cannot help but wonder about all the people who elected them into power in the first place. True, sometimes the system is rigged against the people, either because of the iron grip of despotic regimes or through a flawed system that only provides an illusion of choice. What Julius Nyerere said about America, applies to many democracies: “The United States is also a one-party state but, with typical American extravagance, they have two of them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We support Ukraine because it represents the sacrosanct right to build one&#39;s own future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After appealing to the Russian President, Volodymyr Zelenskyy only received silence in return. He therefore decided to deliver a speech to the people of Russia and to the people of the world; not as the President of Ukraine, but as he put it, as a citizen of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy spoke about the shared 2000km border with Russia that is today breached by almost 200,000 soldiers and thousands of military units. This situation could trigger a widespread war on the European continent. The area is now a smouldering keg that could potentially burst into a catastrophic conflagration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is a death knell for the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ould you entrust a child you love to the care of a school or nursery if you knew that not only many of its teachers, but the school board itself, consisted of child abusers, rapists and murderers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course not! And yet that is exactly what we are doing when we entrust world peace and human rights to the United Nations. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Nations, in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. By ‘integral’ I am particularly referring to the five permanent members (P5) of the UN Security Council. In fact, most of the world problems since WWII stem directly or indirectly from one or more of these five permanent members. The Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine is just one of the many instances of a crisis that has been caused or exacerbated by one of these powers. I have discussed the flaws of the UN at length in my recent book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/&#34;&gt;Unravelling the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, so I will not dwell on its lack of structural integrity or its monumental failures here. Instead, I wish to focus on the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2021: UN-Ukraine Timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 09:33:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-30-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyiv has urged Moscow to pull back its troops from Ukraine’s border and continue dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-31-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;US and Russia spar over the Ukraine crisis at a special closed session of the &lt;strong&gt;UN Security Council&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s UN envoy Vasily Nebenzya accused Washington and its allies of drumming up the threat of war despite Moscow’s repeated denials of a planned invasion. “The discussions about a threat of war is provocative in and of itself. You are almost calling for this. You want it to happen”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world stands up to Putin’s bloodthirsty antics — in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/London-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-%E2%80%94-in-pictures-1024x576.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London:&lt;/strong&gt; Russian Embassy London - Ukraine Anti-War Demonstration CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/London-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;London protests against war in Ukraine. Photo: Garry Knight/Flickr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Russia-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x813.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protests against war in Ukraine in Moscow. February 24th, Moscow. Tverskaya street. CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Berlin-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x684.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine solidarity protest Berlin Pariser Platz with lighted Brandenburg Gate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Wroclaw-Poland-2-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protests in Poznań - against Russian agression in Ukraine. Photo: Bohdan Bobrowski/Flickr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Wroclaw-Poland-%E2%80%94-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Protest in Wrocław, Poland and solidarity with Ukraine on February 24, 2022 CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The painful history of Ukraine — A photo timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ukraine’s fate may be rooted in its heartbreaking past. In this photo timeline, which consists of more than 35 photos and 12 painful events, we’ll guide you through the county&amp;rsquo;s tragic history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukrainian-war-of-independence-1917-to-1921&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukrainian War of Independence (1917 to 1921)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 1917 to 1921, with the invasion of Bolsheviks, a series of conflicts and battles led to the establishment of the Ukrainian Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Ukrainian-War-of-Independence-1917-to-1921--1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A patriotic demonstration in Kyiv, Ukraine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;holodomor-1932-to-1933&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holodomor (1932 to 1933)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holodomor, meaning to kill by starvation, is another dark chapter in Ukraine’s history. It is widely believed that the famine was orchestrated by Joseph Stalin to impose collectivism and tamp down Ukrainian nationalism. Hunger was so common that the Soviet regime convicted more than 2,500 people for cannibalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
