<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinojah.Patkunarajah on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/dinojah.patkunarajah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dinojah.Patkunarajah on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/dinojah.patkunarajah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More Than a Mere Copycat? The Rise of AI-Generated Art and its Implications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/artificial-intelligence/more-than-a-mere-copycat-the-rise-of-ai-generated-art-and-its-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/artificial-intelligence/more-than-a-mere-copycat-the-rise-of-ai-generated-art-and-its-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you scrolled through Instagram recently, did you stumble across pieces of digital artwork that looked like it was custom-made for the user? The chances are, it was generated by an AI using a trendy new app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lensa is just one of many apps that have recently gained popularity, allowing users to generate portraits, illustrations and other types of artwork at the click of a button. But while these AI-powered tools can produce impressive results, they have also sparked a debate about the implications of using AI to create art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Solutions to Overhaul the United Nations Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/6-solutions-to-overhaul-the-united-nations-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/6-solutions-to-overhaul-the-united-nations-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Security Council (UNSC) is in desperate need of reform. Its current structure and its voting system have failed to effectively address global conflicts and address the needs of its member states.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The council, made up of 15 members, including the five permanent members or P5 (China, France, Russia, the United Kingdom and the United States) who hold unbridled veto power, has remained largely unchanged since its creation in 1945.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are Sri Lanka’s Missing Children?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Remember when you and Akka [older sister in Tamil] used to skip dance class by hiding in the storage shed in the backyard?”, reminisces my Aunt. “We would spend ages looking for you, thinking you both had gone missing.” It’s been 13 years since the end of the Sri Lankan civil war and my cousin went missing. My aunt, like many mothers in Sri Lanka, is still searching for her daughter or at least answers as to what happened to her. Answers she is unlikely to ever find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran&#39;s Removal from the Commission on the Status of Women: Change in Membership Standards?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/irans-removal-from-the-commission-on-the-status-of-women-change-in-membership-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/irans-removal-from-the-commission-on-the-status-of-women-change-in-membership-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a decision that is being celebrated as a victory for women’s rights, the UN’s Economic and Social Council has removed Iran from the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW). The country’s tenure, meant to last until 2026, was cut short in response to Iran’s repeated violations against the rights of women, including the violent suppression of protests demanding justice for the death of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/&#34;&gt;Mahsa Amini&lt;/a&gt;, a young woman who died in police custody last September.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
