<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aryan.yekrangi on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/authors/aryan.yekrangi/</link><description>Recent content in Aryan.yekrangi on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/authors/aryan.yekrangi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate><author>aryan.yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Use-of-Chinese-Medicine-in-Treating-Covid-19-1.png" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Document no. 3 and what it reveals about the Chinese Communist Party</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:07:40 +0300</pubDate><author>aryan.yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</guid><description>&lt;p>China is lying about the coronavirus, document no.3 reveals&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="where-we-are">&lt;strong>Where we are&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The global pandemic known as the coronavirus Pandemic started in December in Wuhan China, and as of 26th of April, 210 countries and territories have been affected by the virus, close to 3 million people have been diagnosed with the disease, and more than 200,000 people have tragically passed away of the virus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In late January Dr. Zhong Nanshan, one of the advisors in managing the crisis in China, was asked whether he thought that the virus outbreak would be as bad as the 2003 SARS pandemic. Dr. Zhong Nanshan replied with absolute certainty that this would not be the case. He attributed this to advancements in medical sciences and the experience gathered from the SARS pandemic. The SARS outbreak in 2003 only infected around 8000 people and killed a bit over 800. At this point approximately three months have passed since that initial interview and we must ask ourselves how things ended up like this…&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge-1-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>