<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Un Aligned on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/un-aligned/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Un Aligned on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/un-aligned/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There is citizen journalism and there is The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world that moves at a dizzying speed, UN-aligned and The Gordian have stayed true to their values, fighting for a better UN and bringing our readers the insights and information they need to stay informed and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the editor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian magazine,&lt;/a&gt; I reflect upon the past year with both gratitude and concern. On the one hand, I am grateful for the dedication and hard work of our team, whose members have produced high-quality, fact-based, impactful journalism that has provided clarity and imagination in an unprecedented year. On the other hand, I am concerned about the numerous challenges and crises that have impacted our world in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners of the 2022 Environmental Quiz</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/winners-of-the-2022-environmental-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/winners-of-the-2022-environmental-quiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The UN-aligned Environmental Quiz has announced its winners, with 5 participants scoring a perfect score. A total of 279 people took part in the quiz, which was available for free on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unstop.com/quiz/environmental-quotient-test-un-aligned-488641&#34;&gt;unstop.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The winners, who scored perfectly in the competition are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gaurav Kumar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nitin Ranjan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aditya Ratnakar&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rohit Wadhwa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rishabh Bansal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UN-aligned Environmental Quiz aimed to raise awareness about important environmental issues and promote sustainability. We congratulate the winners and thank all participants for their engagement and interest in these topics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about ‘Utopia’</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-the-new-lady-justicehttpsun-alignedorgthe-gordian-magazinegordian-may-issue-vol-6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet The New Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Meet-The-New-Lady-Justice-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine, issue 1, volume 6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In issue one, we critised the traditional image of lady justice. Her blindfold is supposed to symbolise impartiality, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world? We said no more and introduced our readers to a new Lady Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical: The Gordian Magazine enters Vol. 6</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 09:03:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-magazine-enters-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having covered social topics in the last few issues of The Gordian, in May we will be moving on to a series that will focus on law and order. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics will range from international law and treaties to general crime and punishment. We will also be exploring the difference between what is legal and what is ethical, which are two very different animals. After all, most of the world’s problems today are caused by activities that are more or less legal everywhere, such as intensive animal farming, extraction and consumption of fossil fuels, suppression of human rights and exploitation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 17:43:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far we have managed to do without any financial support, however, as the organisation has grown our need for fundraising has become more and more crucial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
