<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Justice on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/global-justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Justice on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/global-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ICC Pursues Putin: A Sprinkle of Justice in a World of Mischief</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-reality-of-abducted-children-in-ukraine&#34;&gt;Chilling Reality of Abducted Children in Ukraine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Vladimir Putin, seemingly untouchable and unaccountable for countless transgressions, continues to cause havoc in Ukraine, a glimmer of hope emerges from the unlikeliest of origins: the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spark that ignited the fire was a public “thank you” from the Children&amp;rsquo;s Rights Commissioner, Maria Alekseyevna Lvova-Belova. She &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2023/02/16/putins-childrens-envoy-reveals-she-adopted-child-from-mariupol-a80249&#34;&gt;expressed gratitude to Putin&lt;/a&gt; for enabling the “adoption” of a young boy from Mariupol, unwittingly revealing the chilling reality of Ukrainian children torn from their homes and subjected to “re-education camps” or forced adoptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Key Points to Consider for Effective Law Enforcement and Justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few issues of The Gordian, we have covered various aspects of justice, from the definition of justice itself to specific instances regarding the assaults it is often subject to. In order to understand justice from a legal perspective, however, it is important to bear in mind the various aspects that are involved in law enforcement. Here are some important points to bear in mind:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ensuring ethical, global, flexible and measured definitions of criminal acts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When I see all my kingsmen, Krishna, who have come here on this field of battle, life goes from my limbs and they sink, and my mouth is sear and dry; a trembling overcomes my body, and my hair shudders in horror. My great bow, Gandiva, falls from my hands and the skin of my flesh is burning; I am no longer able to stand, because my mind is whirling and wondering. And I see forebodings of evil, Krishna. I cannot foresee any glory if I kill my own kinsmen in the sacrifice of battle. Because I have no wish for victory, Krishna, nor for kingdom, nor for its pleasures. How can we want a kingdom, Govinda, or its pleasures or even life, when those for whom we want a kingdom and its pleasures, and the joys of life are here in this field of battle, giving up their wealth and their life?” (Translation by Juan Mascaró)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The need for an International Anti-Corruption Court (IACC) is greater than ever before</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the law of the jungle, kleptocracies are shielded by plutocracies. The latter keeps the former in power. A reality all too familiar in a world dominated by the black and white absolutisms of realpolitik. It is for this reason that geopolitical power alliances currently assume complete precedence over the rule of international law. Dictatorial regimes almost always double up as localised kleptocracies. They serve as the ultimate fodder for competing foreign policy interests allowing world powers to act unilaterally outside the purview of international law. Such exchanges are all too typical of fledgling geopolitical arenas in the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solitary confinement is cruel and amounts to torture</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solitary confinement often achieves fewer goals than keeping prisoners under control more quickly and satisfying a perverse need to see pain inflicted on those deemed criminally responsible, with little regard for the consequences. In doing so, the prolonged use of solitary confinement contravenes many national statutes. These include the 8th Amendment to the US Constitution, the Nelson Mandela Rules put forth by the UN, China’s Prison Law and European Prison Laws. In 2011, UN Special Rapporteur for Torture Juan E Mendez claimed that in many cases, it breaks international law, and he has called for a ban.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s barbaric and repulsive: Let&#39;s Axe the Death Penalty</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the death penalty involves legally killing an alleged criminal. “Alleged”, not only because the person may not have committed the crime in the first place, but equally because the crime may have been labelled as such only due to the distorted perspective of the lawmakers. At times, this perspective is biassed in favour of jealousy, bigotry, the acquisition of wealth and power; or the neutralising of a rival or critic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-acquis-communautaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Acquis communautaire&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acquis Communautaire is the EU rule book that protects all member states&amp;rsquo; citizens under the rule of law. Fun fact, if you read two pages of this EU treaty an hour, without any breaks because duh, stuff your dinner plans, you’ll be through it in just 4.5 easy years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ginormous legal textbook, which consists of 35 chapters within &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2001:0645:FIN:EN:PDF&#34;&gt;80,000 pages&lt;/a&gt;, is a combination of all European legislation, including all treaties, directives and regulations established by the EU&amp;rsquo;s institutions, as well as all decisions rendered by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three UN conventions on the laws of the sea and how they are failing to secure it</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:50:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-convention-on-the-law-of-the-sea&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982, the third United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) was adopted after nearly 26 years of attempts to replace the archaic “freedom of the seas” concept, which dated all the way back to the 17th century. The convention came into force in 1994 and established rules governing the uses of the oceans and their resources. Essentially encapsulating traditional rules for ocean use in a single instrument while also introducing new legal concepts, as well as addressing new concerns that arose with modern times. Some notable developments ushered by the convention include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rehauling Lady Justice: Is the United Nations guilty in Ukraine?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long as international justice is left in the hands of nation states at the UN nothing will ever improve because self-interest will always win the day. This needs to change. Meet the new lady justice!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lady-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why representations of Lady Justice depict her in a blindfold? The accepted explanation is that the blindfold symbolises impartiality. Lady Justice is supposed to be oblivious to power, status, wealth or any other privilege. She also sports scales, which represent fairness through the weighing up of the facts, and a sword, which represents swift and thorough retribution. Although the scales date back to her earliest manifestations as the Egyptian goddess Maat, the blindfold probably originated with Hans Gieng’s 1543 Gerechtigkeitsbrunnen (Fountain of Justice) in the Old City of Bern. Despite the accepted wisdom, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mladic revisited: An unremarkable news item, were it not for the absurdity of the process</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:04:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ratko Mladic, the former Bosnian Serb commander largely responsible for the Srebrenica Massacre in 1995 lost his appeal with the special UN tribunal set up to judge the case. He had been convicted on ten counts including genocide and crimes against humanity. This is an unremarkable news item really, were it not for the absurdity of the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuremberg_trials&#34;&gt;Nuremberg Trial&lt;/a&gt; (20 November 1945 - 1 October 1946) took less than a year to try 24 of the most prominent Nazis after World War II. Imagine if that trial had dragged on for as long: it would have been lingering on until the 1970’s. True, despite having been charged in July 1996, Mladic was not apprehended and extradited to the Hague for trial by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) until May 2011. Still, most of the ICTY’s cases had been dealt with by then. Nevertheless, the trial formally began a whole year later and he was not convicted until 22 November 2017, after which, the appeals process, that has only now been completed, was referred to the successor body, International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve a robust legal system? Solutions towards comprehensive global justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in last month’s issue of The Gordian, I highlighted some of the weaknesses of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and the International Criminal Court (ICC). Whilst these bodies are merely a part of a wider international legal system that is also governed by various treaties, conventions and accords, they are pivotal in as much as their focus is on safeguarding human life and world peace. My conclusion was that these two institutions were flawed, compromised and generally ineffective. In this issue, therefore, I intend to offer some concrete ideas for a robust legal system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-La-giustizia-di-chi.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
