<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Justice on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/global-justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Justice on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/global-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ICC Pursues Putin: A Sprinkle of Justice in a World of Mischief</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</guid>
      <description>The International Criminal Court&#39;s arrest warrant for Putin may be a small, symbolic step towards justice, but in a world where accountability is as dead as the dodo, it&#39;s a tune worth dancing to.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Vladimir-Putin-and-Maria-Lvova-Belova.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Key Points to Consider for Effective Law Enforcement and Justice</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</guid>
      <description>Ethical values should guide the definition of crimes and the creation of an international peace and police forces is key to effective law enforcement.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/10-Key-Points-to-Consider-for-Effective-Law-Enforcement-and-Justice-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>People and nations may disagree, they may commit crimes, but these antagonisms can be resolved in countless ways. Why war?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/making-war-illegal.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The need for an International Anti-Corruption Court (IACC) is greater than ever before</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Omar Alansari-Kreger</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</guid>
      <description>While the ICC is busy with sanctimonious show trials in the Global South, the need for a supranational criminal court that prosecutes corruption without fear and favour is rising.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-need-for-an-International-Anti-Corruption-Court-IACC-is-greater-than-ever-before-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solitary confinement is cruel and amounts to torture</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>mayabearyman</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</guid>
      <description>The UN defines torture as cruel, inhumane and degrading treatment. Solitary confinement clearly reaches this bar, stripping prisoners of their rights to socialisation at the cost of their mental health.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture-copy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s barbaric and repulsive: Let&#39;s Axe the Death Penalty</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</guid>
      <description>Executing a human being is as coldblooded and premeditated as murder can get, writes Adrian Liberto</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Barbaric-and-Repulsive-Lets-Axe-the-Death-Penalty-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a look over the five key judicial branches of the European Union and how they are safeguarding justice across the block.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/How-Justice-is-ensured-in-the-European-Union-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>Appeasement is giving the school bully your lunch money in order to avoid being beaten up. In politics, however, it is more like giving the school bully someone else’s lunch money, to stop them from being picked on.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Appeasement-Forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three UN conventions on the laws of the sea and how they are failing to secure it</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:50:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will explore the three UN conventions that are designed to protect the laws of our seas: the UNCLOS, the ITLOS  and ISA.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-three-UN-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehauling Lady Justice: Is the United Nations guilty in Ukraine?</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long as international justice is left in the hands of nation states at the UN nothing will ever improve because self-interest will always win the day. This needs to change. Meet the new lady justice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lady-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why representations of Lady Justice depict her in a blindfold? The accepted explanation is that the blindfold symbolises impartiality. Lady Justice is supposed to be oblivious to power, status, wealth or any other privilege. She also sports scales, which represent fairness through the weighing up of the facts, and a sword, which represents swift and thorough retribution. Although the scales date back to her earliest manifestations as the Egyptian goddess Maat, the blindfold probably originated with Hans Gieng’s 1543 Gerechtigkeitsbrunnen (Fountain of Justice) in the Old City of Bern. Despite the accepted wisdom, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-new-lady-justice.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Selective-Justice_-Nine-Rings-of-Moral-Tunnel-Vision.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mladic revisited: An unremarkable news item, were it not for the absurdity of the process</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/news/mladic-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:04:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/news/mladic-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ratko Mladic, the former Bosnian Serb commander largely responsible for the Srebrenica Massacre in 1995 lost his appeal with the special UN tribunal set up to judge the case. He had been convicted on ten counts including genocide and crimes against humanity. This is an unremarkable news item really, were it not for the absurdity of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuremberg_trials&#34;&gt;Nuremberg Trial&lt;/a&gt; (20 November 1945 - 1 October 1946) took less than a year to try 24 of the most prominent Nazis after World War II. Imagine if that trial had dragged on for as long: it would have been lingering on until the 1970’s. True, despite having been charged in July 1996, Mladic was not apprehended and extradited to the Hague for trial by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) until May 2011. Still, most of the ICTY’s cases had been dealt with by then. Nevertheless, the trial formally began a whole year later and he was not convicted until 22 November 2017, after which, the appeals process, that has only now been completed, was referred to the successor body, International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Mladic-at-the-start-of-the-ICC-Trial-in-May-2012-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve a robust legal system? Solutions towards comprehensive global justice</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in last month’s issue of The Gordian, I highlighted some of the weaknesses of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and the International Criminal Court (ICC). Whilst these bodies are merely a part of a wider international legal system that is also governed by various treaties, conventions and accords, they are pivotal in as much as their focus is on safeguarding human life and world peace. My conclusion was that these two institutions were flawed, compromised and generally ineffective. In this issue, therefore, I intend to offer some concrete ideas for a robust legal system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Towards-Comprehensive-Global-Justice.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-ICJ-the-ICC-A-closer-look-at-the-justice-doppelganger.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
