<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Afghanistan on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/afghanistan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Afghanistan on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/afghanistan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘No Girl Left Behind’: How Taliban&#39;s Ban on Girls&#39; Education Imperils Afghanistan&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>amyc</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</guid>
      <description>The empty chairs in Afghanistan&#39;s classrooms don&#39;t just signify a local crisis; they mark a global failure that jeopardises the future of an entire generation and country.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Afghan-girl-education-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edward Mortimer was wrong about the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/un-in-focus/edward-mortimer-was-wrong-that-about-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 10:50:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/un-in-focus/edward-mortimer-was-wrong-that-about-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Edward Mortimer, the chief speechwriter for Kofi Annan, passed away at the age of 77. He was described as “one of the lively minds surrounding the Secretary-General, given license to think and experiment at a time when the future of the United Nations was being written anew”. We wish his friends and family our deepest condolences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, however, we would like to point your attention towards a peculiar speech he made to the Oxford Union in 2017 defending why &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IZm5iBZkiT8&#34;&gt;the United Nations is not a failing institution.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Edward-Mortimer.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is Jean Arnault and what can he do about the Afghan peace talks?</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/news/who-is-jean-arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-afghan-peace-talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Secretary General António Guterres appointed the Frenchman Jean Arnault as his envoy covering Afghanistan and regional issues. Mr Arnault is expected to support the negotiations and implementation of any agreements between the Taliban and Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jean Arnault is a former philosophy student with an extensive working background in United Nations missions in Asia, including Afghanistan, Europe, Latin America, and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt his outstanding &lt;a href=&#34;https://cic.nyu.edu/content/jean-arnault&#34;&gt;experience&lt;/a&gt; in international diplomacy will bring a massive force behind the Afghan peace talks, and although we wish him all the best, it must be said that the UN&amp;rsquo;s political response to this conflict has been largely uninspiring. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Who-is-Jean-Arnault-and-what-can-he-do-about-the-Afghan-peace-talks_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
