<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iran on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/iran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iran on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:55:03 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/iran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Embracing genocide’: How Iranian monarchists are championing Israel&#39;s deadly onslaught on Palestine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:55:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you encounter the rare sight of individuals rallying in support of Israel&amp;rsquo;s actions in Gaza, your attention might be drawn to an unexpected symbol: a variant of the Iranian flag. This particular flag, adorned with the Lion and Sun against a backdrop of green, white and red, harks back to Iran&amp;rsquo;s monarchical past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ensign, displayed alongside Israel&amp;rsquo;s, hails from a time when monarchs reigned over Iran, now seized upon by a diverse array within the Iranian diaspora, particularly those championing freedom in Iran, which includes the monarchists also known as Pahlavis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contemporary Pottery From the Heart of Esfahan, Iran - In Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:35:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To fully appreciate the artistry presented in this gallery, don&amp;rsquo;t miss our &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/&#34;&gt;interview with the artists&lt;/a&gt; Samira Ghafori and Anahita Ahmadi. Their compelling narratives offer valuable insights that add depth and context to the pieces showcased here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Samira-Ghafori-pottry-7-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Samira Ghafori.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Anahita-Ahmadi-pottery-1-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi. &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Samira-Ghafori-pottery-6-1003x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Samira Ghafori.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Anahita-Ahmadi-pottery-4-892x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pottery and photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sculpting Change: Two Women Reshaping Iran&#39;s Pottery Scene</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/women-reshaping-iran-pottery-scene/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whirling hum of the spinning wheel, the rhythm of skilled hands modelling shapeless clay and the mesmerising transformation in the kiln: the world of pottery is one of patience, resilience and creativity. And within this sphere in Iran, two exceptional women, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/samirghafori/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Samira Ghafori&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/anna_clayart/?img_index=1&#34;&gt;Anahita Ahmadi,&lt;/a&gt; are shaping more than just clay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samira, an artist who started young, had her destiny intertwined with pottery before she even knew it. Her early fascination with the craft was born out of playful experimentation that evolved into a lifelong commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iranian Government: How is it structured?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the Assembly of Experts to the Guardian Council, learn about the complex process of electing the Supreme Leader of Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-supreme-leader&#34;&gt;The Supreme Leader&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the top of the hierarchy stands the Supreme Leader of Iran. As this position is considered a life tenure post, there have only been two supreme leaders since the formation of the Islamic Republic of Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Muqtada-al-Sadr-and-khamenei-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Iranian supreme leader, Ali Khamenei&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iranian supreme leader, Ali Khamenei&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN votes on a fact-finding mission into Iran, but don’t look at it too closely</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the United Nations is not busy declaring French baguette a world cultural heritage or hosting awkward diplomatic cocktail parties where everyone pretends to like each other&amp;rsquo;s national dishes, it dedicates a small portion of its resources to protecting human rights across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in November, a fact-finding investigation into human rights violations in Iran, where hundreds have died and tens of thousands have been detained since protests started in September 2022, has been approved by the UN Human Rights Council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Leaked file uncovers how the Iranian Revolutionary Guards plan to quell protests</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basij commander warns media organisations against talking about the recent unrest in Iran and advising them to refer to the rising opposition &lt;strong&gt;using terms such as &amp;ldquo;conspiracies&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;collusions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revolutionary Guards have &lt;strong&gt;received a list of Iranian football&lt;/strong&gt; fans who participated in World Cup from Qatari officials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IRGC has used the country&amp;rsquo;s participation in the 2022 World Cup as a &lt;strong&gt;distraction from the widespread protests.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hacking group named Black Reward has published the audio file of a confidential meeting between Basij commander Qasem Qoreyshi and media managers close to the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC) that took place on the 15th November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zahhak to the Islamic Republic of Iran: Has Ferdowsi prophesied the future of the republic?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:21:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zahhak was the evil king of Mesopotamia who conquered Iran and, together with his army and serpents that grew out of his two shoulders, terrorised the people of the land for thousands of years. It all started when in order to congratulate the new king on his new position, the embodiment of evil, known in the Book of Kings as Ahriman, disguises himself as the royal cook and asks to kiss the new king’s shoulders. Zahhak agrees and moments after Ahriman’s lips touch Zahhak’s shoulders two black snakes emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in Iran: Inside The 17th Century Iranian-Armenian Monastery of St. Amenaprkich (Vank Church) — In Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/inside-vank-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/inside-vank-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vank Cathedral is one of the largest historical and religious attractions of Isfahan. It is located in the centre of Isfahan, in the New Jolfa neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The monastery has played a significant role as the first cultural communication link between Armenians and Iranians. Vank Cathedral has been inscribed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://whc.unesco.org/en/tentativelists/6385/&#34;&gt;UNESCO World Heritage sites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/18-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year around Christmas and New Year, local musicians play traditional music. (Instrument: Armenian bagpipe)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/13-1024x833.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look into the Iranian Turkmen Sahra - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An immigrant family from Sistan and Baluchestan living in one of the Turkmen villages. Their different culture and religion have prevented them from having friendly relationships with other residents of the village.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/7-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An old woman and her grandchildren in beautiful Turkmen dress wear. Even though Turkman in Iran make beautiful rugs and are wonderful artists, they still live in extreme poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/6-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Malik Banoo is an artist who enthusiastically invited me to take a picture of a wall rug that she had just finished weaving. Many Turkmen women weave carpets and Kilims, but very few agree to have their pictures taken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 40th day of winter: Kurdistan Celebrates Pir Shaliar - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The festival of Pir Shalyar is an old traditional ceremony in Kurdistan associated with the pre-Islamic, Zoroastrian times. It is held on the 40th day of winter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pir (also translated as saint), Shaliyar is believed to have cured the daughter of the king of Bukhara; the ceremony intends to mark their marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/&#34;&gt;Uraman Takht&lt;/a&gt;, the city hosting the festival, is located in the eastern part of Marivan, Kurdistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_6422-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kulla Ball is a vest that is made of fleece and does not require sewing. This vest dates back several thousand years in the history of Horaman. In Horaman, if a ruler was powerful yet just, the men wore kulla balls without ears (shoulder pads), but if the ruler deviated and did not serve the land and its people, the men wore kulla balls with earmuffs and demanded to overthrow the throne. Photo by Anahita Ahamdi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranian lawyer declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nasrin Sotoudeh is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nasrin_Sotoudeh&#34;&gt;Iranian human rights lawyer&lt;/a&gt; who has been in and out of prison since 2010 for no other reason than defending men, women and children who suffered under the oppressive Iranian regime. Her clients included opposition politicians, journalists, abused women and children, women who were arrested for not wearing the hijab and prisoners on death row for crimes they allegedly committed when they were minors. On several occasions she went on extended hunger strikes to protest against the severity of the prison regime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hormoz and its People - in picture</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Omid is a motorcyclist and his income comes from ferrying tourists around the island. He said that he was not too unhappy with the pandemic, explaining how he and his friends took advantage of the lack of tourists on the island. They bought a boat together and spent days fishing. He says, the joy of childhood days had returned to him. Photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/2-1-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man in need of a lighter, shouts his request towards another boat; the other boat quickly turns around to see what the passenger needs. Whether on land or at sea, people always seem happy to support each other here. Photo by Anahita Ahmadi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earning a Living in the Remote Areas of Baluchestan - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 11:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/10-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of Baluchi women holding a Shisha.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A woman Knitting ornaments on scarfs. The colorful shisha keeps her company during the long days. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man selling petrol in middle of a desert.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part of the country there is no gas station. This old man makes a living by selling small quantities of petrol to passing motorcycles and cars. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheep Shearing Amongst the Nomads of Kurdistan - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 09:36:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/4-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a boy shearing a sheep&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A young boy is shearing a sheep whose legs are tied. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/12-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of four young Kurdish children playing under a truck.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Children playing with their father’s cellular device under the shade of the pickup truck. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/9-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is photo of big Kurdish family in Iran.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A father and his children after a day of hard labour. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uraman Takht - a journey to the forgotten lands of Kurdistan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 05:51:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After publishing the August issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian&lt;/a&gt;, we received the kind message from an UN-aligned member, Anahita, saying the magazine had inspired her to travel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/MAGAZINE-ISSUE-3VOL.1-3.pdf&#34;&gt;Iranian Kurdistan&lt;/a&gt;. As a thank you we received beautiful pictures from her which we decided to publish as a bonus, showcasing Uraman Takht, a magnificent village in the west of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/iran/&#34;&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uraman Takht is indeed one of the wonders of what Iran has to offer. With a population of less than 3000, this village hosts the kindest and most hard-working people that I have yet seen throughout my journeys. This paradise is located in eastern part of Marivan city of Kurdistan and lies 1450 meters above sea level on the alluring heights of the Zagros mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Women are allowed to ride bikes – just not in public” Khamenei’s fatwa: another nail in the coffin of women rights in Iran</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:19:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bike-campaign&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bike campaign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the autumn of 2015, a young environmentalist in Arak, a city with pollution levels as staggering as those in Tehran, started a “car-free Tuesday” campaign to encourage people to commute by bike. The campaign soon turned popular with municipal authorities across the country beginning to encourage residents to ride bikes and leave their cars at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Women cyclists, naturally, saw an opportunity to support a good cause that everybody in Iran could agree on: clean air. They thought they could cycle like other male citizens if they respected Iran&amp;rsquo;s strict dress code, which requires women to cover their hair and body in public. The campaign was soon aborted after a group of female cyclists were detained in the western city of Marivan following criticism from the city&amp;rsquo;s Friday Prayers leader. The women were released the same day, but only after they signed pledges not to cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
