<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jay.davis on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/authors/jay.davis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jay.davis on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 15:39:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/authors/jay.davis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SDG 16: &#34;People who live in glass houses shouldn’t throw stones&#34;</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/sdg-16-people-who-live-in-glass-houses-shouldnt-throw-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 15:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>jay.davis</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/sdg-16-people-who-live-in-glass-houses-shouldnt-throw-stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peace, Justice and Strong Institutions are three fundamental facets of any progressive civil society in the 21st century. Therefore, as the UN is in many senses the world’s guardian, one of its utmost duties is to promote, instil and maintain these components globally to ensure collective harmony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015 – and since the UN’s conception – promoting peace, justice and strong institutions has been at the forefront of the UN’s agenda. This is evident with UN member states dedicating an entire Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) towards this pledge, which will see these beliefs transformed into formal and legitimate processes worldwide by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/a.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UN is failing to eradicate poverty</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>jay.davis</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty, to put it simply, is one of humankind’s greatest ills and despite various ways to quantify, analyse or measure it, the problem remains unsolved. With the world finding itself in unprecedented straits owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, which has not only claimed the lives of 4,000,000, but has revealed ominous and record-breaking poverty worldwide, humanity more than ever needs its leaders to come together and work towards effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/%E2%80%98Unanimous-Verdict_-the-UN-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN is failing to combat Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>jay.davis</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change is the world’s biggest collective enemy, which threatens to destroy the very planet that we all live on. Whether it be rising sea levels, global warming, record-breaking temperatures, melting ice caps or an overall shift in severity of natural disasters, we as humankind need to strategise together for immediate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the UN’s response, it can be commended for shining light upon the escalating emergency; with, for example, setting up the annual COP meetings since 1995 to assess progress in dealing with climate change. Also, at COP 21, the UN established the landmark 2016 Paris Agreement, which was signed by 196 parties worldwide and is based upon limiting a global temperature increase to below 2 degrees. Other exposure includes promoting sustainable lifestyle changes, working with climate activists, and dedicating an entire Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) to combating climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/%E2%80%98Unanimous-verdict_-UN-is-failing-to-combat-Climate-Change.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
