<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Issues on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/global-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Issues on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:54:35 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/global-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Kakistocracy Sanctions Humanity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-kakistocracy-sanctions-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:54:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-kakistocracy-sanctions-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday July 9, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio announced the imposition of sanctions by the United States under a Presidential Executive Order targeting Francesca Albanese, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Palestine. Her crime? Speaking the truth about the Gaza genocide and those who profit from it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;United Nations representatives of Human Rights Council lost no time in expressing their objections, but of course in the customary UN watered-down sort of way. Meanwhile, on the same day, Wednesday 10, Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu left Washington after two days of meetings with Trump and more US protection and support for his country’s genocide against Gaza.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The last straw for the genocidaires was Albanese’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ohchr.org/sites/default/files/documents/hrbodies/hrcouncil/sessions-regular/session59/advance-version/a-hrc-59-23-aev.pdf&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt; published on June 16 that unequivocally exposed their heinous crimes, their accomplices and the heartless greed that motivates them. The Summary sets the scene nicely:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua’s War on the Press: New Report Highlights Escalating Repression</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:52:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned recently partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fled.ong/&#34;&gt;FLED Nicaragua&lt;/a&gt; to translate their annual report from Spanish into English, highlighting the grave state of press freedom in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assassination of retired Nicaraguan army officer and outspoken critic of President Daniel Ortega, Roberto Samcam, on June 19 while in exile in Costa Rica, underscores the urgency of the crisis and the critical need to raise international awareness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Press-Freedom-Report-January%E2%80%93March-2025-%E2%80%93-Copy.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read full report -&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky-Born Infernos: How Pyrocumulonimbus Clouds Supercharge Wildfires</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sky-born-infernos-the-deadly-feedback-loop-of-pyrocumulonimbus-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 21:33:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sky-born-infernos-the-deadly-feedback-loop-of-pyrocumulonimbus-clouds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pyrocumulonimbus clouds—towering thunderclouds born from wildfire heat—are becoming an increasingly dangerous force in today’s fire-prone world. Unlike typical storm clouds, these massive systems form when the intense heat from large wildfires creates powerful updrafts, carrying smoke, ash, and moisture high into the atmosphere. As the rising air cools and condenses, it forms thunderclouds that do far more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Far from offering relief, pyrocumulonimbus clouds often worsen fire conditions. They generate lightning capable of sparking new fires miles away from the original blaze, while their strong winds can fan existing flames, pushing wildfires across vast stretches of land with alarming speed. Despite their storm-like appearance, these clouds rarely produce significant rainfall—leaving the fires beneath them undoused and free to spread.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confronting a Genocide</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/confronting-a-genocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:28:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/confronting-a-genocide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the “business as usual” attitude of most of the world’s politicians and the people the media like to keep in the spotlight, the genocidaires are hurting. The protests, the immolations, the hunger strikes, the courageous acts of defiance… They are slowly taking their toll. The genocidaires know that even if they managed to kill every single Palestinian living in Gaza and the West Bank, they will always be branded as mass-murderers. And now, on the first day of June, another remarkable challenge: Greta Thunberg and other 11 activists have set sail towards Gaza on the Madleen, a small ship operated the Freedom Flotilla, to dent the siege and raise “international awareness” to the atrocities that are being committed by Israel. Speaking before her departure, the brave activist acknowledged the dangers involved, but equally the more insidious risks of doing nothing: “Because the moment we stop trying is when we lose our humanity. And no matter how dangerous this mission is, it’s not even near as dangerous as the silence of the entire world in the face of the live-streamed genocide.” Activists on board include “Game of Thrones” actor Liam Cunningham and French member of the European Parliament Rima Hassan. They are expected to reach Gaza in about a week’s time. Unsurprisingly, haughty critics soon attacked from their Pro- Zionist ivory towers. Republican senator Lindsey Graham, sneered: “Hope Greta and her friends can swim!”; while Brendan&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Trumpian Flirtations with Total Denuclearization</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 18:11:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Donald Trump to be taken seriously when openly speaking of denuclearization? The Center for Public Integrity reported in an article from 2020 on the future of warfare that the nuclear weapons industry under Trump&amp;rsquo;s first term flourished to heights not seen since before the end of the Cold War. He effectively catapulted an aggressive nuclear rearming of America at an estimated 1.7 trillion-dollar cost to the American taxpayer. Despite the massive cost, politicians like Republican Senator Deb Fischer argued that the nuclear rearming of America in a multipolar world is to be considered an essential but not sufficient national security imperative, implying the 1.7 trillion-dollar price tag for the nuclear rearming of America is substantively insufficient. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of a charade: Israel&#39;s collapse under global condemnation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel is as good as finished. It has lost all credibility as a responsible nation in-the-making. From the onset its creation has depended on abusing superpowers, injustice and crime. It has been those three forces that have kept it enduring and spreading until now, while skilfully dodging every attempt to hold it to account, often by playing the victim. Despite the numerous massacres perpetrated along the way, something very different has happened now that has shaken its very foundations; mortally so: Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone: Horizons of EU expansion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe is a continent; a land mass. Politically, of course, Europe is much more. It is an entity. The history of its various nations interlaces intricately, more so than with other parts of the world, as does its culture. Its aspirations are also different, though many of these overlap with those of people all around the world. The EU encapsulates some of these hopes, such as a desire for peace, security, justice and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation-Building and Indigenous Struggles: Histories, Rights and Representation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where borders are drawn and redrawn, the quest for a homeland remains fraught with strife for many. Nation-building, the process of constructing a national identity and establishing political and social structures, is pivotal in this quest. It is not just about hotly-debated independence stories or drawing lines on a map; it involves acknowledging diverse histories, cultures and rights to create a cohesive and inclusive society. This is crucial for ensuring peace, stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Table Tennis to the UN: How Kosovo Used Sports for Nation Building</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never before has the nexus between sport and international relations been more prominent than in the last 10 years. Even a cursory examination of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most publicised sporting events from the last decade reveals a clear link between the games and athletes we love to watch and money, power, and strategic international diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports-events-reflect-on-a-nations-best-and-worst&#34;&gt;Sports events reflect on a nations&amp;rsquo; best and worst&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Brazil hosted the FIFA World Cup, aiming to exhibit the beauty and rich culture of Brazil. However, the exciting football was overshadowed by extreme poverty; the inequality highlighted by the slums of Rio de Janeiro and the displacement of thousands to accommodate new stadiums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Nuclear Deterrence: Geopolitical Bravado or Our Obligation Towards Peace?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:38:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuclear-threats-past-and-present&#34;&gt;Nuclear Threats: Past and Present&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every historical curiosity is borne out of a rhetorical question that challenges the accepted narratives of the past. The history we are taught is often presented as simplified stories with humanity at the existential core. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, history is actually moulded by successive generations. With Vladimir Putin ordering Russia&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Rocket Forces to perform battle readiness drills with live nuclear weapons on Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s border, the spectre of nuclear war has returned in a starkly real manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Imagined Unity’: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:15:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few terms in political science hold as complex a definition as “Nation”. As UN-aligned launches its new volume of The Gordian, exploring Nation Building, it becomes crucial to establish a clear understanding of the term and its multilayered complexities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-nation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a nation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nation is defined as “a group of people who share a history, traditions, culture and, often, language – even if the group does not have a country of its own”, writes National Geographic. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:27:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaac Newton famously said: “If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.” Sadly, society is where it is today because most people have stood on the shoulders of ogres. The past sticks to us like shit on a shoe and we have become so accustomed to the foul smell, that rather than scrape off the dung, we wallow in it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: planet earth in the 21st century, but one that had never witnessed the advent of humankind. Then, suddenly, it is discovered by an alien species much like our own. Before long, the planet is plundered, ravaged and abused. Life forms are enslaved, tortured and killed for entertainment, fashion and culinary delights, their habitats destroyed; forests are cut down; and rivers and seas polluted beyond recognition, as are the skies. Finally, having exhausted every possible resource, the alien species moves on, like a plague of locusts, to its next quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Corrupt to the Bone’: The Pursuit of Transparency in a Corrupt World</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-pursuit-of-transparency-in-a-corrupt-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-pursuit-of-transparency-in-a-corrupt-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Corruption is paid by the poor,&amp;rdquo; warns Pope Francis, highlighting an unsettling reality: those least able to afford it, endure corruption&amp;rsquo;s harshest consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The publication of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transparency.org/en/cpi/2022&#34;&gt;Corruption Perceptions Index&lt;/a&gt; 2022 (CPI), which uses a scale from 0 (highly corrupt) to 100 (very clean), has shed light on the efforts taken by policymakers to combat corruption in different countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The report indicates that out of the 180 countries assessed, 124 have made no progress in fighting corruption across any levels. This staggering statistic underscores the severity and pervasiveness of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Infernal Gates: Confronting the Oil Industry&#39;s Greed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:24:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beneath the surface of our greedy economy lies a lurking danger, driven by the relentless greed of giant oil companies. Like the ominous entrance to Dante&amp;rsquo;s Inferno, their self-serving position and inaction threaten to unleash chaos and destruction. However, before shedding light on hidden environmental and ethical transgressions across scattered timelines, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the lethal nature of the oil giants&amp;rsquo; self-serving stance and their culpability for inaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;barring-the-gates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barring the gates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All art aficionados would be familiar with Rodin’s The Thinker, or representations of it, some may have even been lucky enough to see the pensive figure in his intended setting sitting atop of The Gates of Hell. Whatever was he thinking? My guess is that he was contemplating what Sartre put into words decades later: &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;enfer, c&amp;rsquo;est les autres&amp;rdquo; (Hell is other people).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conversion of St. Paul by Caravaggio: A Masterpiece of Dramatic Intensity and Transformative Power</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-conversion-and-its-relevance-to-the-painting&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meaning of ‘Conversion’ and Its Relevance to the Painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;lsquo;conversion&amp;rsquo; is derived from the Latin word &amp;lsquo;conversio&amp;rsquo;, which denotes a movement from one place to another, a turning towards something or someone, or a change of direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the word itself does not necessarily connote any religious or moral significance, it presents boundless possibilities for internal and external transformation. Change can happen by deliberate choice or can be brought about unexpectedly by life&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable events, which often add new shades and dimensions to our existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New International Man: Can World Federalism Overcome Nationalism?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an old millennial having experienced childhood in the nineties, my generation grew up with the quintessential strongmen movies personified in protagonists like Rocky Balboa, Ivan Drago and Apollo Creed, as seen in the Rocky franchise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Rocky 4, Dolph Lundgren portrayed a rather intimidating antihero; an opponent more machine than man. My generation remembers a world before it was possible to Google our curiosities away into the ether of the internet. Exposure to the world in terms of different cultures, languages and ways of life was primarily derived from movies like Rocky 4. Ivan Drago, Rocky&amp;rsquo;s deadly opponent having killed Apollo Creed in the boxing ring, seemingly revisited the literal definition of the New Soviet Man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Combat the Negative Impacts of Global Warming on Biodiversity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The contemporary phenomena of global warming has created a &amp;ldquo;Hothouse Earth&amp;rdquo; and has wreaked havoc on pristine ecosystems. The melting of glaciers exposes vast swathes of marine water to atmospheric carbon dioxide, lowering pH from alkaline values and threatening the survival of corals and other marine organisms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the indiscriminate felling of certain species of flora and the poaching of certain species of animals for medicinal purposes exacerbates their extinction. Clearing tropical rainforests for agriculture also strips the planet of its carbon sinks and lungs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are Sri Lanka’s Missing Children?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Remember when you and Akka [older sister in Tamil] used to skip dance class by hiding in the storage shed in the backyard?”, reminisces my Aunt. “We would spend ages looking for you, thinking you both had gone missing.” It’s been 13 years since the end of the Sri Lankan civil war and my cousin went missing. My aunt, like many mothers in Sri Lanka, is still searching for her daughter or at least answers as to what happened to her. Answers she is unlikely to ever find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Subtle Manipulation of News Media in the Age of Pseudo-Enlightenment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-the-sun-wot-won-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the Sun wot won it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The older generation may remember it well. It was 11 April, 1992. Neil Kinnock and his Labour Party were set to win the general election and the best the Conservatives could have hoped for was a hung parliament. Then, however, The Sun, one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s right wing tabloid newspapers owned by Australian-American media mogul Rupert Murdoch, launched an aggressive campaign to swing things around&amp;hellip; and sure enough it did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Key Points to Consider for Effective Law Enforcement and Justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few issues of The Gordian, we have covered various aspects of justice, from the definition of justice itself to specific instances regarding the assaults it is often subject to. In order to understand justice from a legal perspective, however, it is important to bear in mind the various aspects that are involved in law enforcement. Here are some important points to bear in mind:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ensuring ethical, global, flexible and measured definitions of criminal acts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 2022 Nobel Prize Winners?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:elviraineza5@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Nobel Prize is a prestigious international award that recognizes individuals who have made significant contributions to various fields, including physics, chemistry, physiology or medicine, literature, peace, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Established by Swedish inventor Alfred Nobel in 1895, the award is presented annually to individuals who have demonstrated exceptional achievements in their respective fields. The Nobel Prize is considered one of the highest honours that can be awarded, and recipients are often recognized as leaders in their fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demilitarising the Manipulable Atom</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When World War One broke out, one of the founding fathers of modern science fiction, H.G. Wells, popularised the &amp;ldquo;war to end all wars&amp;rdquo; antiwar euphemism while trenches were dug on the Western front as British, French and German militaries mobilised for war. That same euphemism is often adopted and overused by aggressive unilateralists bent on justifying wanton militarism in pursuit of lopsided geopolitical objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Wells juxtaposed as the seminal foundation for a future liberated from the scourge of war, the Serbian American inventor Nikola Tesla fashioned in the form of a &amp;ldquo;death ray&amp;rdquo; to deny the possibility of war by vaporising invading militaries with &amp;ldquo;national energy shields&amp;rdquo; powered by alternating current. If history has proved anything, it is that war is one of man&amp;rsquo;s seminal preoccupations. War colleges churning out young military officers would have us believe wars are justifiable if waged to restore order to a Westphalian international balance of power system to make world peace possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When I see all my kingsmen, Krishna, who have come here on this field of battle, life goes from my limbs and they sink, and my mouth is sear and dry; a trembling overcomes my body, and my hair shudders in horror. My great bow, Gandiva, falls from my hands and the skin of my flesh is burning; I am no longer able to stand, because my mind is whirling and wondering. And I see forebodings of evil, Krishna. I cannot foresee any glory if I kill my own kinsmen in the sacrifice of battle. Because I have no wish for victory, Krishna, nor for kingdom, nor for its pleasures. How can we want a kingdom, Govinda, or its pleasures or even life, when those for whom we want a kingdom and its pleasures, and the joys of life are here in this field of battle, giving up their wealth and their life?” (Translation by Juan Mascaró)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The need for an International Anti-Corruption Court (IACC) is greater than ever before</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the law of the jungle, kleptocracies are shielded by plutocracies. The latter keeps the former in power. A reality all too familiar in a world dominated by the black and white absolutisms of realpolitik. It is for this reason that geopolitical power alliances currently assume complete precedence over the rule of international law. Dictatorial regimes almost always double up as localised kleptocracies. They serve as the ultimate fodder for competing foreign policy interests allowing world powers to act unilaterally outside the purview of international law. Such exchanges are all too typical of fledgling geopolitical arenas in the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia Needs to Legalise Drugs</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/australia-needs-to-legalise-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 12:00:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/australia-needs-to-legalise-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many drugs taken for pleasure in Australia are illegal. Examples include cannabis (cannabis can be grown and consumed legally, but not sold, in the Australian Capital Territory), heroin, ice (crystal meth) and many others. Some drugs taken for pleasure are legal, such as nicotine, with tobacco smoked by 2.5 million Australians, and alcohol, drunk at least once per week by 8 million. In addition, about 800 prescription drugs are subsidised under the pharmaceutical benefits scheme. Prescription drugs are reported to be misused by around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2017/dec/19/prescription-drugs-misused-by-one-million-australians-in-year-report-shows&#34;&gt;1 million Australians&lt;/a&gt;. Cannabis can be taken legally for medicinal purposes in all Australian states by people with certain limited classes of health problems. The obvious question is – why are some drugs legal and others illegal?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lobbyland: The Story of American Lobbying and Campaign Donations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:07:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States, although a mighty country, has its flaws. One of its flaws is how some lobbying groups hold immensely more significant sway than others, thus unfairly eliciting beneficial results for a minority group. Another such flaw is the restriction of representatives to be solely those who may afford to run. These systemic flaws, among others not mentioned, when compounded together, erode democratic representation and must be viewed as an existential threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America going bananas, new dinosaur and an independent Scotland: June 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:41:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;06.06.22**: Nigeria**. Over 50 people, including many children, were gunned down in a catholic church in Ondo State. So far, no group has claimed responsibility for the brutal attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/new-abelisaurid-dinosaur-Egypt-1024x409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A size comparison of five family members of the abelisaurids.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.06.22: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. A study published today in the journal Royal Society Open Science confirmed the discovery of a new abelisaurid dinosaur that lived more than 98 million years ago in the Bahariya Oasis depression of Egypt’s Western Desert. Studies on the fossil of the yet unnamed dinosaur took several years since its discovery in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“With a democratic world federation, humanity can address global problems”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:37:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The political movement to unite the world is nearly one hundred years old. Most identify the Campaign for World Government founded in 1937 by Lola Maverick Lloyd and Rosika Schwimmer as the genesis of the movement. Since then the world has transformed in ways unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, humanity is grappling with a growing pile of existential global challenges. Twentieth-century holdovers like poverty, inequality, human rights abuses, corruption, and the threat of nuclear war are now being complemented with an array of new challenges like the climate crisis, misinformation, and of course — the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media in an Era of Invasion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/social-media-in-an-era-of-invasion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From February 24th until now, nearly tens of thousands of people have been either injured or killed by the Russian invasion of Ukraine. This is an unfortunate number of people, especially so when considering the number of refugees fleeing Ukraine; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/conflict-ukraine&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;with more than five million leaving Ukraine in search of safety. The people of Ukraine have been pushed from their homes, forced to leave behind their lives, families, friends, and pets; but they are resilient people and have given the world personal insights to life in Ukraine post-invasion. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Almoallem Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One day, my little sister and I were studying for the high school exams, so we were all sitting very quietly. Suddenly we heard the sound of shooting near our camp; not only close, but actually in the camp. We started hearing the voices of children screaming and crying, and they all scrambled for their tents or perhaps entered a neighbour’s tent because of the fear and panic. We subconsciously put our heads to the ground and we started wondering what was going on. What are these sounds?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Musk, new Nato members and the most expensive 20th-century art: May 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:52:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;Africa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;Western Sahara&lt;/strong&gt;. About 44 migrants trying to reach the Canary Islands have drowned off the coast of Moroccan-occupied Western Sahara after their boat capsized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. An overnight raid on a camp for displaced persons in the Ituri Province has left at least 14 people dead, including women and children. The attack follows a similar raid on a nearby mining site on Sunday that killed about 35 people. The CODECO militia is blamed for the brutal attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Glass Ceiling: Women in India are not Behind</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:47:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glass-ceiling-effect-in-the-west&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Ceiling Effect in the West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th century, women in other parts of the industrialised world had also experienced what is popularly known as the &amp;lsquo;glass ceiling&amp;rsquo; phenomenon, which meant that women found they could only rise to a certain level in corporations and no further. This raises two immediate questions. What were the reasons that could have led to such a thought? And, were men keeping women away from the top?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three UN conventions on the laws of the sea and how they are failing to secure it</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:50:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-convention-on-the-law-of-the-sea&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982, the third United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) was adopted after nearly 26 years of attempts to replace the archaic “freedom of the seas” concept, which dated all the way back to the 17th century. The convention came into force in 1994 and established rules governing the uses of the oceans and their resources. Essentially encapsulating traditional rules for ocean use in a single instrument while also introducing new legal concepts, as well as addressing new concerns that arose with modern times. Some notable developments ushered by the convention include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russian and Ukrainian are often mistaken as the same language, especially by people who have no prior exposure to Slavic languages. This confusion is justified considering that both Russian and Ukrainian use the Cyrillic alphabet, and they both belong to the language family of East Slavic (Slavonic languages). In fact, the only other East Slavic language is Belarusian. Many sources estimate Old East Slavic to have diverged into these three sub-languages as early as the fifth century. This left a large window of time for these languages to develop independently. Historical and geographical aspects have also influenced the development of these languages. This article compares Russian and Ukrainian from a number of linguistic aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Putin: “You are a serial killer, but there is one thing I must thank you for…”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Putin,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not mean to be rude by not gracing your name with a salutation or title; quite the contrary; if I had done so, only obscenities would have been appropriate under the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation I am referring to is, of course, your ever-increasing list of crimes: yours, plus the many your soldiers are sanctioned to carry out in your name, such as murdering innocent men, women and children, rape and pillaging. “Kill one man, and you are a murderer. Kill millions of men, and you are a conqueror. Kill them all, and you are a god.”  I see that a god is what you are aspiring to become; a sinister god of the underworld, no doubt, but don’t delude yourself! Jean Rostand was referring to the perception in the minds of fools. You are no god. You are just a serial killer, a rapist, a bully and a thief. You will join the ranks of other sadists, who like you, abused their power to bring death and destruction into the world. However, in some ways you are worse than they are. They operated in darker times, when Truth was still struggling to climb out of her well. You have not got the luxury of mitigating circumstances. Truth is easily accessible now. The fanaticism of the past had been shown up for what it is, but you embrace it and with cynical irony you justify your onslaught on Ukraine as a Nazi-clensing operation, when in fact, it is your evil that is the closest thing to Nazism the world has known since Hitler’s demise. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t be NATO, it should be the United Nations: The Poetry of Appeasement</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-the-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We the people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the list of governments I hate grows longer by the day, I cannot help but wonder about all the people who elected them into power in the first place. True, sometimes the system is rigged against the people, either because of the iron grip of despotic regimes or through a flawed system that only provides an illusion of choice. What Julius Nyerere said about America, applies to many democracies: “The United States is also a one-party state but, with typical American extravagance, they have two of them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We support Ukraine because it represents the sacrosanct right to build one&#39;s own future</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After appealing to the Russian President, Volodymyr Zelenskyy only received silence in return. He therefore decided to deliver a speech to the people of Russia and to the people of the world; not as the President of Ukraine, but as he put it, as a citizen of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy spoke about the shared 2000km border with Russia that is today breached by almost 200,000 soldiers and thousands of military units. This situation could trigger a widespread war on the European continent. The area is now a smouldering keg that could potentially burst into a catastrophic conflagration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is a death knell for the United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ould you entrust a child you love to the care of a school or nursery if you knew that not only many of its teachers, but the school board itself, consisted of child abusers, rapists and murderers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course not! And yet that is exactly what we are doing when we entrust world peace and human rights to the United Nations. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Nations, in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. By ‘integral’ I am particularly referring to the five permanent members (P5) of the UN Security Council. In fact, most of the world problems since WWII stem directly or indirectly from one or more of these five permanent members. The Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine is just one of the many instances of a crisis that has been caused or exacerbated by one of these powers. I have discussed the flaws of the UN at length in my recent book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/&#34;&gt;Unravelling the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, so I will not dwell on its lack of structural integrity or its monumental failures here. Instead, I wish to focus on the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2021: UN-Ukraine Timeline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 09:33:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-30-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyiv has urged Moscow to pull back its troops from Ukraine’s border and continue dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-31-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;US and Russia spar over the Ukraine crisis at a special closed session of the &lt;strong&gt;UN Security Council&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s UN envoy Vasily Nebenzya accused Washington and its allies of drumming up the threat of war despite Moscow’s repeated denials of a planned invasion. “The discussions about a threat of war is provocative in and of itself. You are almost calling for this. You want it to happen”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in February 2022</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:29:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;Guinea-Bissau&lt;/strong&gt;. President Umaro Sissoco Embalo survived a coup attempt that went on for five hours. Several people died during the assault, which the president blames on elements involved in corruption and drug trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 60 people have been confirmed dead, including 15 children, after an attack on a camp for displaced people in the eastern province of Ituri. CODECO, a militia that was originally a peaceful agricultural cooperative, is thought to be responsible for the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Forging of an East African Federation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:37:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-shot-at-an-east-african-community&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Shot at an East African Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three countries of East Africa - Kenya, Tanzania (which is a union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar), and Uganda - were administered as one unit under the East African Common Services. When granting them independence, the British expected that these countries would eventually integrate into one political union, as had happened to Tanganyika and Zanzibar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of a political federation for East Africa emerged in the 1960s. The idea took shape in 1967 when the East African Community, a confederate government, was formed by the republics of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania. The heads of states of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania, by signing the treaty establishing the community, became its patron and hoped to use the community as a launching pad towards deeper political, economic, and socio-cultural integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five benefits of legalising drugs that may change your perspective</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-decriminalisation-of-drugs-mean-vs-what-does-it-mean-to-legalise-drugs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does decriminalisation of drugs mean VS&lt;/strong&gt; what does it mean to legalise drugs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about decriminalising all drugs, within a legal framework, we don’t necessarily refer to them being legalised. In other words, drug ownership and personal use would itself still be legally prohibited, but violations of those prohibitions are deemed to be exclusively administrative violations and are removed completely from the criminal realm. Ideally, we want the legalisation of all drugs, however, decriminalising them could also be an attractive short-term solution. Here are five arguments for legalising drugs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My religion is myself and my nationality is my heart”: Five days inside a refugee’s diary</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 10:22:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During her internship with UN-aligned, Jihan Al-Assad was asked to write about her life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Her experiences, along with those of other refugees are published in a new series titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/diaries-from-refugee-camps/&#34;&gt;Diaries from Refugee Camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-1122021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1/12/2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a new month and the end of a whole year. This does not feel like the beginning of a month or a day or anything new. I am afraid because I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what is coming to me, and this idea is a big horror for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstaining in the face of war</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-un-security-council-not-prepared-to-put-up-with-moscows-bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UN Security Council not prepared to put up with Moscow’s bullshit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Following weeks of heightened tensions around Ukraine, with reports that Russia has been deploying more than 100,000 troops and heavy weapons close to its border, the United Nations’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/securitycouncil/&#34;&gt;Security Council&lt;/a&gt; held its first meeting to discuss ways of de-escalating the crisis on Monday.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/01/1110912&#34;&gt;United Nations News Page&lt;/a&gt;, 31 January 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For an organisation that was founded primarily to promote world peace, the United Nations is a sad joke. The crisis in Ukraine has been intensifying for weeks and yet the Security Council waited until January 31 to convene in order to have a discussion on the issue and it did so only because it was urged to by the US. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the microscopic world: 10 stunning photos</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Sand.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Sand&lt;/strong&gt;: Composed of finely divided rock and mineral particles, sand looks surprisingly beautiful under a microscope. This image shows the star-shaped sand in Hatoma Island. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:2085f_Japon_Hatoma.jpg&#34;&gt;Alain Couette/CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Butterfly-wing-1024x782.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Butterfly wing&lt;/strong&gt;: Thousands of pigmented scales cover butterfly wings, giving the insect its magnificent colourful appearance. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/zeissmicro/8271132283&#34;&gt;Zeiss Microscopy/CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Sea-water-1024x716.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Sea water&lt;/strong&gt;: This image shows a range of marine microplankton found in sea water. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Marine_microplankton.jpg&#34;&gt;David Liittschwager/CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council meeting on Ukraine Review: Abstaining Romance and Plenty of Hot Air</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tensions between Russia and Ukraine have been mounting for weeks now and for some reason, everyone expected that this particular Security Council session would narrow the wide divide between Russia and the so-called West. Of course, there’s nothing wrong with being pessimistic, but it is a fool who watches the same episode and expects a different ending. Here are three of the main sides of the argument presented during the Council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migrant-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The migrant problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied their history will know that migrations are what shaped the world as we know it today, both politically and ethnically. At times these migrations were peaceful. Often, they were predatory. At times they were gradual, spreading like an oil stain; often, they were sudden and quite alien, like a frenzied splash from a Jackson Pollock paintbrush. At times the end result was growth and a fusion of cultures; often, it was genocide. So we built walls of brick and paper to keep the undesirables out. Most of us belonged to those undesirables once, but that was a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following interview was conducted in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-yourself-and-your-children&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself and your children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Amna; I am 33 years old. I live in Lebanon in a Syrian refugee camp. I have two children, a son and a daughter. My husband was lost in Syria, and I fled with my children from the war and came to Arsal to seek safety away from the difficult conditions of the war that destroyed our lives and the childhood of my children. I tried to work to meet the needs of my children, but I could not for fear of leaving them alone in the tent and I wanted to teach them and follow their school lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Life Without Flowers: A Glimpse Into The Arsal Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I will talk about my place of residence in one of the camps in Lebanon, Arsal, and how I was able to adapt to this difficult life, which does not resemble life at all. It is only days that pass without taste. One of the most difficult days of my life was when I was fifteen years old. My family decided that we should live In a refugee camp. At that time, misfortune and sadness overtook me, and I went into a state of depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-federalism-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation Earth: Why Youth are Necessary for Solving Global Problems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;humanity-faces-immense-challenges&#34;&gt;Humanity faces immense challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many young people are global. Growing up online has predisposed a generation to a cosmopolitan perspective previously only accessible by the elite. Interacting with a culture different from your own has become a commonplace occurrence online, which has led many to retreat into safe, echo chambers with people of the value system. This retreat is exemplified by private chat groups which at best, provide a welcoming space for a niche community, and at worst, provide a space for terrorists to plan attacks. Yet, if you’ve grown up online, you’ll know that an echo chamber is far less fun than a debate space. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SDG 16: &#34;People who live in glass houses shouldn’t throw stones&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/sdg-16-people-who-live-in-glass-houses-shouldnt-throw-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 15:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/sdg-16-people-who-live-in-glass-houses-shouldnt-throw-stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peace, Justice and Strong Institutions are three fundamental facets of any progressive civil society in the 21st century. Therefore, as the UN is in many senses the world’s guardian, one of its utmost duties is to promote, instil and maintain these components globally to ensure collective harmony.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2015 – and since the UN’s conception – promoting peace, justice and strong institutions has been at the forefront of the UN’s agenda. This is evident with UN member states dedicating an entire Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) towards this pledge, which will see these beliefs transformed into formal and legitimate processes worldwide by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in October 2021 You May Have Missed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 11:06:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/&#34;&gt;Listen to Ruby Goldenberg and Ariana Yekrangi help you catch up with everything that happened in October 2021.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. At least six refugees were shot dead by Libyan guards as they tried to leave a detention centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. In what had been described as a &amp;ldquo;first institutional return of its kind&amp;rdquo;, Jesus College, Cambridge, has agreed to return one of the Benin bronzes that had been looted from the area during colonial times. The National Commission for Museums and Monuments will receive a bronze cockerel later this year. France has also agreed to return many of the looted bronzes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;There is too much stupidity around&#34;: The UN&#39;s Climate Change Report</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sixth Assessment Report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change was published on August 9, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/&#34;&gt;The Report&lt;/a&gt; paints a grim picture of the planet’s health owing to human induced climate change and rising temperatures. These seem set to rise above the 1.5° threshold, which will signal a critical point of no return for those most exposed to the catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the report, UN Secretary-General António Guterres did not mince his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Titulus as a safe haven: Case Romane del Celio</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-titulus-as-a-safe-haven-case-romane-del-celio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-titulus-as-a-safe-haven-case-romane-del-celio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If talking about what you don&amp;rsquo;t know well is frightening, trying to convey to others what you have studied for a long time with enthusiasm and passion is disorienting, because you proceed with the constant feeling of not saying everything or at least not saying enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Years ago, when I was still a university student, I was deeply impressed by Christian archeology not only as a matter of faith, but because when art is placed at the service of any kind of religion or religious thought, it generates artistic phenomena that involve social edification. Among the various topics covered during the lessons, one in particular remained with me: the tituli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dystopian Novel: &#34;Beyond Utopia&#34;!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dystopian novel developed during the 20th century when the reality of humanity’s volatile condition became evident after both the first and second world wars. The word, dystopia, refers to Utopia, the fictitious name of an ideal country, coined by Thomas More in his famous book Libellus &amp;hellip; de optimo reipublicae statu deque nova Insula &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/2130&#34;&gt;Utopia (1516)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was designed as a political, social and religious system which was not supposed to be reflected in reality, but proposed as an ideal model.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN is failing to combat Climate Change</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change is the world’s biggest collective enemy, which threatens to destroy the very planet that we all live on. Whether it be rising sea levels, global warming, record-breaking temperatures, melting ice caps or an overall shift in severity of natural disasters, we as humankind need to strategise together for immediate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the UN’s response, it can be commended for shining light upon the escalating emergency; with, for example, setting up the annual COP meetings since 1995 to assess progress in dealing with climate change. Also, at COP 21, the UN established the landmark 2016 Paris Agreement, which was signed by 196 parties worldwide and is based upon limiting a global temperature increase to below 2 degrees. Other exposure includes promoting sustainable lifestyle changes, working with climate activists, and dedicating an entire Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) to combating climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Not Trust The United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-the-devil-you-know&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations: the devil you know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met someone from a peculiar land with a completely messed up political system yielding a society that was plagued with poverty, oppression, corruption and strife. I commiserated until I found out that there actually was an alternative party that, given the chance, would put things right, yet nobody seemed to care about it. “Hey! What’s wrong with you people?” I asked my new acquaintance, pointing this out. “Many do not know; many do not care&amp;hellip;” “And what about you?”  I petitioned. “Ah, better the devil you know!” They replied smugly, as a demon dragged them to hell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Why are you talking like that?&#39;: How politicians use words to influence and mislead</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:56:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself agreeing with a politician for no apparent reason? Have you ever thought why many people support a certain politician even though they hold a ‘foolish’ standpoint? Have you ever thought of how language influences people’s decisions in a political environment? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While it is true that humans are complex creatures and clear linear relationships rarely apply in the real world, language usage and perception undoubtedly plays a significant role in the world of politics, especially today where social factors such as gender and ethnicity are gaining more attention. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>António Guterres: The Power Under The Throne</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/antonio-guterres-the-power-under-the-throne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 13:21:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/antonio-guterres-the-power-under-the-throne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The feeling I experience when plunging into the ocean of communiques from the United Nations is always the same: drowning in an alphabet soup. Often, the words are noble, the causes honourable. Occasionally they even make a difference. Report after report; document after document; resolution after resolution&amp;hellip; and yet the members of this mighty club behave like undisciplined children who delight in doing just as they please. The world of politics rolls on like a combined harvester devoid of breaks, macerating anyone unfortunate enough to get in its way. They only serve to create one grim statistic after another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the ICJ and the ICC our answers to international justice? - Podcast</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/are-the-icj-and-the-icc-our-answers-to-international-justice-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/are-the-icj-and-the-icc-our-answers-to-international-justice-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human Anthropological Transmutation: Bridging thoughts and new concepts</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-human-anthropological-transmutation-bridging-thoughts-and-new-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-human-anthropological-transmutation-bridging-thoughts-and-new-concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italian_-La-trasmutazione-antropologica-umana.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Palaeozoic era, an order of molluscs with red shells, called ammonites, had spread through all the sea since they had the ability not just to live underwater, but also to expel water from their shell and thus rise and descend. Their success with respect to other forms of life led them to reproduce until they saturated their environment and became extinct. The reason is the uncontainable growth of the species.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-La-giustizia-di-chi.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Growth Dilemma</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 11:08:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-della-crescita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcending-simplistic-assumptions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transcending simplistic assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Society is faced with a profound dilemma. To reject growth is to risk economic and social collapse. To pursue it relentlessly is to endanger the ecosystems on which we depend for long term survival. This delusional strategy has reached its limits. Simplistic assumptions that capitalism’s propensity for efficiency will stabilise the climate and solve the problems of resource scarcity are almost literally bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding and Fiscal Responsibility of the United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Unravelling-United-Nations-Argead-style/dp/B08T7J1QX4/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1612176186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;UN-aligned’s new publication&lt;/a&gt; that highlights the shortcomings of the United Nations with details that cover its foundation, structure and monumental failures. You may be surprised at the murky facts that this book will bring to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thorough critique of the UN finances would therefore involve a massive amount of time and investigation, which exceeds the remit of this work. Nevertheless, even without specific details regarding UN spending, some of its weaknesses in this regard have been manifestly exposed from within the organisation. The two main criticisms concern the manifold overlaps in UN operations and the inflated salaries of UN personnel. These issues go hand in hand and can be summed up in one word: bureaucracy. They give rise to an unnecessary multiplying of well-paid personnel and a replication of resources, which means that while employees and their administrative needs receive the lion’s share of the allocated funds, identified problems are left with the crumbs. Of course, decision-making is also impaired, which in turn affects efficiency in general. Speaking at a UN Reform Event in September 2017, Secretary General António Guterres summed up the situation without mincing his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDP is an impostor, so why are we still using it to measure happiness?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-PIL-non-significa-nulla-di-concreto-quindi-perche-lo-utilizziamo-ancora-per-misurare-la-felicita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GDP is not a suitable measurement for happiness or welfare. It sucks. Assessing the economy using GDP is destroying our planet. The global community and the United Nation’s sustainable development solutions network (SDSN) need to find other suitable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, the SDSN, an initiative operating under the auspices of the United Nations, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/happiness-trust-and-deaths-under-covid-19/&#34;&gt;publishing a yearly report&lt;/a&gt; on how happy the world is. Embarking upon this fundamentally subjective and unquantifiable quest is no easy task and although the SDSN has significantly improved its methods to measure happiness throughout the years, it still has a long way to go before becoming perfect. This year the report used a host of different criteria to grade the happiness of a nation, these included: gross domestic product per capita (GDP), social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make your own life choices, generosity of the general population and perceptions of internal and external corruption levels. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming The Governing Strategies of Ongoing Socio-Economic Development by Way of G-Localization</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Domare-le-strategie-che-governano-lo-sviluppo-socio-economico-in-corso-attraverso-la-G-Localizzazione.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ultimate-goal-and-foregrounding&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimate goal and Foregrounding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this reflection is to create favourable conditions for progress by mobilizing the intellectual, spiritual and material forces with a sense of belonging to one and the same human community. This requires finding new ways of living in society and of facing the future together. Living organisms compete for resources, but collaborate for sustaining life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yesterday, upon the stair,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I met a man who wasn&amp;rsquo;t there!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t there again today,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh how I wish he&amp;rsquo;d go away!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from Hughes Mearns’ poem, &lt;em&gt;Antigonish&lt;/em&gt;, could so easily allude to sanctions. They are full of sound and fury, and yet, they signify nothing concrete, but rather an absence of something. Of course, sometimes, a lack of something can have devastating effects: if you stop my air supply, for instance, I am dead. Sanctions, however, are very limited in what they can stop, because what comes from outside one’s borders was not there in the first place, like the man upon the stair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religion that unites...</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/religion-that-unites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 09:59:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/religion-that-unites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Le-religioni-che-uniscono.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People with bigotted or selfish agendas have always tried to hijack religion, but there have always been spiritual adherents who have understood that kindness is paramount and they have highlighted the essence that unites us rather than the dross that divides us. Here are some inspirational quotes from a range of religious thinkers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanskrit-hymn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanskrit Hymn&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As different streams having their sources in different places all mingle their waters in the sea, so, Oh Lord, the different paths which men take through different tendencies, various though they appear, crooked or straight, all lead to Thee.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding conspiracy theories and its victims in the golden age of nonsense</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guarded by some 25 000 troops, Joe Biden successfully took the oath of office. Earlier Mr Ex-President had taken off for Mar-a-Lago. Hopes and dreams were shattered. I felt a rush of compassion for the QAnon believers who felt betrayed realising that nothing happened; no arrests, no intervention. It is bitter to realise that the firm ground below one’s feet has collapsed. The liberating, newly revealed truth turned out to be yet another lie. Yet, the question remains: What were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Dilly-dallying Costs Lives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/when-dilly-dallying-costs-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year has been difficult for everyone. We have all had to adapt to new changes and the impact COVID-19 has had worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a classroom teacher based in a primary school in London. Since April, we have had to face many challenges due to the pandemic. Children have done an amazing job at adapting to necessary changes and staff have been very supportive of each other. We worked flexibly and creatively to help the school run as efficiently and effectively as possible. This last term, however, has been particularly draining for all of us!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy vs Anarchy: Which one is better?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 11:52:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winston Churchill once said: “Democracy is the worst form of government except for all others.” But was he right? This article about democracy vs anarchy offers different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years, democracy has become a defining characteristic of the West and its politics. This has even developed to a point where we are talking about &amp;ldquo;exporting&amp;rdquo; democracy to the non-Western world, falsely assuming, of course, that democracy is a perfect form of governance that enables societies to elect competent leaders through the votes of often uninformed citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to prevent the 2021 food crisis</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 09:45:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many will face horrific hunger if relief efforts are not stepped up in a world heated by coal, infected with Covid-19 and separated by nationalists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, 193 countries lined up behind a comprehensive and ambitious set of targets – also known as the Sustainable Development Goals – to transform life and the planet by 2030. Contrary to most UN agreements that are ignored and unheeded by the member states, the project was more than a political platitude and successful on many fronts: extreme poverty fell dramatically and child deaths halved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blame Game: Blame Breeds Blame in a Never Ending Game of Hate</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-blame-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-blame-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I blame my bed&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my bad back&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I blame my shoes&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my flat feet&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I blame my wife&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Our daily strife&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I blame the heat&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my fatigue&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I blame the cold&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my clogged nose&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I blame them all&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my bad traits&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It’s all their fault&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I live in hate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And when I die&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I’ll blame my God&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For a hateful life&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A painful death&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We live in a culture of litigation. We sue Starbucks if their coffee is too hot and scalds us. We sue our hosts if we get involved in an alcohol-related accident after drinking at their home. We sue teachers if our children fall and hurt themselves at school. We would sue God if we could, for making us sick, for making us unhappy, for not preventing the death of a loved one. This is the blame game. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misgendering people: Identity and Gender Pronouns</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:50:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article does not intend to offend or devalue anyone with a non-binary gender identity. It only tries to explain why fixing misgendering is a larger problem than most people think, and why there is no immediate solution to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-misgendering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is misgendering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Misgendering is the act of using language to describe or talk to a person in a manner that does not align with their affirmed gender, intentionally or unintentionally. This can be in the form of personal pronouns, such as referring to someone as a ‘he’ when they’re a woman or when they do not identify with the male gender, but also through the use of gender specific nouns such as ‘boy’ and ‘girl’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving against the odds: life in an overlooked Bangladeshi locality</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/life-in-an-overlooked-bangladeshi-locality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 10:55:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/life-in-an-overlooked-bangladeshi-locality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I live in a southernmost Upazila (administrative district) of Bangladesh called Gabura. Bangladesh is an underdeveloped country and my village is typical of the struggling communities of the delta region. Many people here do not have access to basic education and the village does not even have electricity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three distinct seasons in Bangladesh: a hot, humid summer from March to June; a cool rainy monsoon season from June to October; and a cool dry winter from October to March. Life in Gabura changes dramatically with each season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Wedlock</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:26:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-slow-pace-of-same-sex-marriage&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slow pace of same-sex marriage…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same-sex marriage is now legal in almost thirty countries in the world. Considering same-sex unions date back over 12,000 years and that there are almost 200 countries in the world, this is not much of an achievement. In recent times, the first country to legalise same-sex marriage was the Netherlands. That law was passed in December 2000 and came into effect in April 1, 2001. So, even in the last few decades, progress has been slow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hagia Sophia: National Sovereignty is not the Issue, Erdogan Likes to Play the Blaming Game</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 09:26:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/erdogan-plays-blaming-games-over-hagia-sophia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cathedral first, then a mosque, and later a museum. Last week, Istanbul’s Hagia Sophia became a mosque once again; an insular act for Turkey’s Erdogan to flex his political mussels and to fuel his posture of indignation and grievance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The president knows casting cultural divides resonates with many of his support base, inside as well as outside of Turkey. He boosts his popularity and draws strength from his constant tussle with domestic and foreign foemen. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Appropriation: What is the Harm?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wimoweh / The Lion Sleeps Tonight, Memoirs of a Geisha, Karlie Kloss wearing a Native American inspired headdress at the Victoria’s Secret fashion show. Miley Cyrus twerking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The list could be filled with other, more ordinary affairs such as costume parties, authentic Chinese food, yoga, cornrows, ethnic fabrics or chopsticks as hair sticks. The list of examples of cultural appropriation is so long that it became an activity itself to google what kind of results are given for cultural appropriation combined to any non-Western element. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compassion fatigue: How to turn your compassion into positive action</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:03:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;symptoms-of-compassion-fatigue&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms&lt;/strong&gt; of Compassion Fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever catch yourself feeling really moved by something quite trivial when reading the news, as you skimmed past some tragedy in Yemen or Syria without even paying the slightest bit of attention? Or are you prone to add a like or comment to a Facebook GIF about a silly animal situation, for instance, while ignoring a poignant post about social injustice or an environmental emergency?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Tear Gas in the 21st Century is Unacceptable.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have come a long way since World War I and World War II, yet we still see police forces using dangerous chemical weapons, such as tear gas, against their own civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How dangerous are these chemical substances and should local police be permitted to use such weapons against people? How were these weapons used in WWI and WWII?  The following article aims to answer a few of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protestors: When is it OK to Hit them?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When is it OK to hit a protestor? Is protesting during a global pandemic a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has rarely been any positive social changes without some form of protest. Too often the establishment is seen grappling on to power by fostering a dominant discourse from which dissident and minority views are excluded. At best, protests today are characterised as a disruption and inconvenience and, at worst, a threat to a vaguely-defined national security. Political leaders and the majority they may represent, blame these warriors of justice for lack of character and accountability, even though, ironically, those are the very flaws &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; are being accused of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document no. 3 and what it reveals about the Chinese Communist Party</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:07:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is lying about the coronavirus, document no.3 reveals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-we-are&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we are&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic known as the coronavirus Pandemic started in December in Wuhan China, and as of 26th of April, 210 countries and territories have been affected by the virus, close to 3 million people have been diagnosed with the disease, and more than 200,000 people have tragically passed away of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In late January Dr. Zhong Nanshan, one of the advisors in managing the crisis in China, was asked whether he thought that the virus outbreak would be as bad as the 2003 SARS pandemic. Dr. Zhong Nanshan replied with absolute certainty that this would not be the case. He attributed this to advancements in medical sciences and the experience gathered from the SARS pandemic. The SARS outbreak in 2003 only infected around 8000 people and killed a bit over 800. At this point approximately three months have passed since that initial interview and we must ask ourselves how things ended up like this…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:56:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why some of us choose to set up life in a new country. The prospect offers numerous benefits, such as satisfying a yearning for exploration, self-improvement or a higher standard of living.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Living abroad is undoubtedly a highly enriching experience, it broadens your mind and provides exposure to different ways of life; it offers a more immersive language learning opportunity and your self-sufficiency will come to know no bounds as a result of having to jump through strange and complex bureaucratic hoops in a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of accessible tourist visas to balance our perception of Russia</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2020, Russia announced that it would soon be offering a simplified and cheaper online visa application for tourists from EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you were asked to describe Russia, your immediate thoughts may be of snow, bears and vodka. Unsurprisingly, Russia does contain all of those things. Think a little more and you might settle on political tension, corruption and the mafia. Unless you had visited, you probably would not envision the long summers in a cottage surrounded by countryside, LGBT activists, or a local taxi driver cracking jokes in elementary English. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Citizenship Amendment Bill: a Death Knell for Indian Secularism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2019 the Government of India, led by the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), secccesfully amended a bill to the Citizenship Act of 1955, offering amnesty to non-Muslim illegal immigrants, who arrived in India prior to 2004. These immigrants must be able to prove that they are citizens of one of the three neighbouring countries: Pakistan, Bangladesh or Afghanistan. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;half-the-truth-is-often-a-whole-lie&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half the truth is often a whole lie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spokespeople of the Indian Government have repeatedly claimed that the new law intends to give sanctuary to people fleeing religious persecution. While this is certainly the case, the dubious decision to exclude Muslim refugees from Myanmar, Sri Lanka, and China; or in fact, the Hindu Tamils from Sri Lanka, raises questions about the Government’s sincerity. The timing of the bill is also not inadvertent; In August, the Assam State, located in the North-East of the country, witnessed two million of its residents left off the Citizen Register; this essentially left thousands of people, suspected of being illegal residents, in temporary camps which are housed in the state&amp;rsquo;s prisons. Modi and his Home Minister, Amit Shah, the mastermind behind the Citizenship Amendment Bill (CAB), have been eroding and attacking the social identity of the Indian Muslim community from as early as 1992 and the CAB was undoubtedly brought forth with an intent to adversely affect the political identities of this community. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India on the Brink</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:48:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-enemy-within&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Martin Luther King Jr. visited India in 1959, he paid the homage to the venerable land with these powerful words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“To other countries I may go as a tourist, but to India I come as a pilgrim.” Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Would Mr. King think differently of India if he were alive today? Probably not. The narrowminded fanaticism that is trying to drag India down is not a new phenomenon. Even if one cannot ignore it, one can always look beyond it. However, the world is not what it was 60 years ago. It is a much more dangerous place. Our efficiency in depleting the earth’s life and resources is only matched by the relentlessness of nature’s means of revenge, such as climate change or the smog that has recently been chocking Delhi.  Moreover, if we should end up fighting for whatever is left, we would be able to do so with much more devastating results. Finally, mass media have altered the way in which we communicate. Just as the Internet, for instance, helps the wise become wiser, it often has the opposite effect with fools, who become easy prey to those who would exploit them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan and its nuclear waste problem</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear leaks are probably among the most horrifying accidents possible due to their long-term detrimental damage to life and environment. Eight years after the nuclear leak from Japan’s Fukushima power plant, local residents, many of whom are fishermen, are still suffering the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dumping-the-radioactively-contaminated-water-directly-into-the-sea-in-order-to-dilute-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tragically, they now have to face another nightmare. However, rather than being triggered by a natural disaster, like the nuclear accident was, this time, it was all caused by their government’s proposal of dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it. So far, the plant’s operator, Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO), has already stored over 1 million tons of radioactive water used to cool destroyed reactors and the amount is still increasing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separatism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/separatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/separatism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;national-identity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Villages and towns, built on cooperation, existed long before nations did. With time, however, the need for security threaded them together like a string of pearls. Sometimes, the unification was voluntary, sometimes it was not. The necklaces became kingdoms and empires; republics even. Polities and economies began to evolve, as did religion, language and culture. The process continues to this day. Nevertheless, threats to national borders remain. These threats come from abroad, as in the case of Georgia and Ukraine, or from within, as is happening in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the recent conflicts in Syria could shape its future</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:46:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although people are long used to the erratic twists and turns of Donald Trump, his decision to sell the Kurds down the river by withdrawing American troops from Syria caught everyone by surprise. Whether Trump was right to extricate his forces from Syria remains debatable, but just as there is rarely a good time to start international military interventions, so there is rarely a good time to discontinue them. One would have thought that Libya’s and Iraq’s ongoing atrocities would have made this clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Culture of Subterfuge - Lest We Forget</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-culture-of-subterfuge-lest-we-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:27:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-culture-of-subterfuge-lest-we-forget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lies, half truths, deceit and hypocrisy are so embedded in our society that people have become immune to them, accept them and often believe that subterfuge is a way of life. Some, indeed, revel in fake news, willingly spreading fictitious slander in jest. Others use fabricated tales of deception for more malevolent objectives, knowing too well that the pseudo facts will filter down into our social fabric. Whatever the reasons, the real fact is that we are living in an era of “alternative facts”, to quote the paradoxical claim by U.S. Counselor to President Trump, Kellyanne Conway. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing empties the top resorts of Biarritz like a shark attack; or a G7 summit - a guide to what happened at the 2019 summit</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:10:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A number of thorny topics were on the agenda this year. Some of the key issues included: foreign policy, trade and, of course, climate change. Let’s start with the last one shall we?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;climate-change-and-oceans&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Climate change and oceans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While world leaders gather around the table to endorse a new charter on biodiversity and renew their commitments to the Paris Agreement, the climate-denier-in-chief, Trump, didn’t feel like attending these talks. He’d rather focus on trade, he says. The Metz Charter on Biodiversity attempts to boost efforts to stop biodiversity loss and sustain life on the planet. This is certainly welcomed, but we can, and should, do more in a much faster way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s shopping list!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/trumps-shopping-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:05:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/trumps-shopping-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, President Trump now wants to buy Greenland! An uninhabited Greek island is one thing, but the largest island in the world that is also an autonomous territory… Well! Although Greenland has been a part of Denmark for over 200 years, it has been increasingly self-governing since 1979, with only foreign affairs and defence still controlled by Denmark. The suggestion just highlights how callous and clueless the American President is. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uraman Takht - a journey to the forgotten lands of Kurdistan</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 05:51:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After publishing the August issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian&lt;/a&gt;, we received the kind message from an UN-aligned member, Anahita, saying the magazine had inspired her to travel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/MAGAZINE-ISSUE-3VOL.1-3.pdf&#34;&gt;Iranian Kurdistan&lt;/a&gt;. As a thank you we received beautiful pictures from her which we decided to publish as a bonus, showcasing Uraman Takht, a magnificent village in the west of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/iran/&#34;&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uraman Takht is indeed one of the wonders of what Iran has to offer. With a population of less than 3000, this village hosts the kindest and most hard-working people that I have yet seen throughout my journeys. This paradise is located in eastern part of Marivan city of Kurdistan and lies 1450 meters above sea level on the alluring heights of the Zagros mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Women are allowed to ride bikes – just not in public” Khamenei’s fatwa: another nail in the coffin of women rights in Iran</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:19:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bike-campaign&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bike campaign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the autumn of 2015, a young environmentalist in Arak, a city with pollution levels as staggering as those in Tehran, started a “car-free Tuesday” campaign to encourage people to commute by bike. The campaign soon turned popular with municipal authorities across the country beginning to encourage residents to ride bikes and leave their cars at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Women cyclists, naturally, saw an opportunity to support a good cause that everybody in Iran could agree on: clean air. They thought they could cycle like other male citizens if they respected Iran&amp;rsquo;s strict dress code, which requires women to cover their hair and body in public. The campaign was soon aborted after a group of female cyclists were detained in the western city of Marivan following criticism from the city&amp;rsquo;s Friday Prayers leader. The women were released the same day, but only after they signed pledges not to cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking at migration in the face</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-has-not-been-a-good-week-for-refugees-but-then-again-it-never-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has not been a good week for refugees; but then again, it never is…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s The Guardian reports how the Lebanese government forced 5,000 refugee families to demolish their own home in order to induce them to return to Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the captain of rescue ship Sea-Watch 3, Carola Rackete, was arrested after she forcefully docked her ship in the Italian island of  Lampedusa. Having rescued 53 migrants drifting off the coast of Libya on June 12, the Sea-Watch 3 was left stranded while the Italian authorities kept refusing to let her dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>150 Lives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/150-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:28:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/150-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-thoughts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second thoughts…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After ordering an attack on Iran last week, president Trump had an after thought. How many human lives would it cost? One wonders: what amount of casualties would have made his strike acceptable? Fifty? A hundred? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Iranian problem is of Trump’s making. He pulled out of the 2015 Iran nuclear deal, started a war of words and began imposing harsh sanctions. On top of that, Trump bullied all other nations to follow suit. A legally binding deal became powerless in the face of Trump’s financial blackmail. Of course that did not have to be the case, but few countries had the backbone to stand up to Trump’s threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan gives the world a lesson in democracy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:15:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-a-thing-or-two-from-taiwan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning a thing or two from Taiwan…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan gave the world a lesson in real democracy last month when same-sex marriage was legalised in the “country“. In a referendum last November, 72% of the population had voted against allowing same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two years earlier, however, Taiwan’s supreme court had ruled that limiting the definition of marriage to couples of the opposite sex was unconstitutional. Legislators therefore backed the Government Bill, putting justice before numbers. This is real democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonising Immigrants</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 06:40:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-on-the-weakest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking on the weakest…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people just need a common enemy. Any group that can be easily picked on offers the perfect target. Minorities of every sort are often chosen because of their vulnerability. Bullying them makes weak or bigoted citizens feel superior. Some of these minorities have fought back and with time secured a certain level of safety, and the protection of their human rights. Still, immigrants are often the most threatened, because they are insecure. They do not know the ropes and cannot easily fight back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Sri Lanka bombings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 08:15:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bloody-motives&#34;&gt;Bloody motives!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an angel came and told me that all the world problems would be solved if I just put a few bombs around killing innocent people in mosques, synagogues, churches, market places or hotels… would I do it? Of course not. Firstly, because I do not even have the right to insult an innocent person, let alone take their life. Secondly, because it would be like asking me to believe that good is founded on evil, or harmony on hatred. Rather obvious, you would say… Then why, oh why, does it keep happening again and again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
