<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/the-gordian-magazine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:43:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/the-gordian-magazine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone — The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:43:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/v2-issue-3-8-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the February issue of The Gordian Magazine. In this edition, we venture into the depths of a question that has, for centuries, puzzled and provoked: &amp;ldquo;To be or not to be European alone&amp;rdquo;. As we stand at the crossroads of history, the fabric of our collective identity is being stretched and tested by the forces of nationalism and globalisation, each tugging in its direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voices That Shape Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-2-8-Cover-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the gordian magazine cover issue 2 vol 8&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: Ariana Yekrangi/UN-aligned&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this issue of &lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;, titled &amp;ldquo;Voices That Shape Nations&amp;rdquo;. In this edition, we delve into the profound and often overlooked role that minorities play in the fabric of nation-building. Our world is a mosaic of cultures, each contributing uniquely to the narrative of history and the shaping of nations. This issue illuminates these diverse voices, offering insights into their struggles, triumphs and enduring spirit in the face of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: The New Social Contract</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:45:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-1-vol-8-cover-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Gordian Magazine cover reading the global constitution. &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As October&amp;rsquo;s chill sets in, &amp;lsquo;The Gordian&amp;rsquo; returns from its brief hiatus with a meticulously curated issue titled &amp;lsquo;Global Constitution: The New Social Contract.&amp;rsquo; This edition seeks to weave together the intricate threads of geopolitics, art, culture, and science, presenting a cohesive narrative of our shared global destiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;The Imagined Unity&lt;/em&gt;: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock,&amp;rsquo; Alexander Stoney offers a profound exploration of the nuanced concept of &amp;lsquo;Nation&amp;rsquo;. This sets the stage for Adrian Liberto’s discourse on the pressing need for a global constitution in &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rsquo; Liberto subsequently scrutinises the UN&amp;rsquo;s role in the Palestinian crisis in &amp;lsquo;Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In The Fume of Power: The Greed of Giants</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-3-vol7-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphic: UN-aligned design team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the June issue of The Gordian. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since we last connected, and we have been eagerly preparing for our return. Our hiatus allowed us to refocus and recentre our commitment to bringing you insightful, provocative, and poignant articles that not only inform, but incite. We hope you&amp;rsquo;re ready for a feast of thoughtful content, as we are more than thrilled to serve it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair&#39;s Fair: Entitlements Are Not Charity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-2-vol7-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Greetings, dear readers, and welcome to the newest edition of The Gordian Magazine. We are excited to present to you a collection of insightful and engaging articles that are sure to stimulate your mind and expand your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our cover story this month is penned by Adrian Liberto and titled &amp;ldquo;Bridging the Wealth Gap - A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication.&amp;rdquo; Through this piece, Liberto challenges the dominant economic system of the 21st century and offers a ray of hope for those who are trapped in the cycle of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raising Utopia: Brick by Brick</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-1-vol-7-1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;© UN-aligned Design team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ring in 2023! Even though it carries with it most of the serious problems associated with 2022, such as war, disease and climate disasters, we hope that at least some of these issues will be dealt with more competently in the next 12 months! We want to be able to report and write about happier stuff… ringing in a brighter and fairer world!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enough is Enough: Time to Enforce Justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter From the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/the-Gordian-Magazine-issue-6-vol6-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the December issue of the Gordian Magazine. In this edition, we have a range of thought-provoking and informative articles for our readers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main theme of this volume is still justice. In particular, we discuss how to effectively enforce it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As usual, the Gordian begins with our monthly recap containing news items you may have missed in November 2022. In a separate article, we also introduce the winners of this year’s Nobel Prize in physics, chemistry, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dismantling the war machine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-5-vol6-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian rolls on with its messages of peace and light and respect, but notwithstanding, the world seems to be getting darker and more troubled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate disasters are no longer the exception, while the threat of a nuclear apocalypse is more real than it ever has been. Giving in is not an option. On the contrary we must double our efforts to combat all that is a threat to the dignity and wellbeing of humanity and the survival of earth’s multifaceted manifestations of nature. Being marginally involved with organisations like UN-aligned is no longer enough. Each and every one of us needs to do more, both as individuals and as part of our communities, be they local, or global like UN-aligned. For want of a nail the shoe was lost&amp;hellip; then the horse, the rider, the message, the battle and finally, the kingdom. We are that nail, but we have been led to believe that our input is insignificant. It isn’t. So The Gordian will continue to roll on with your support and inspiration: a platform for the sharing of ideas and information and a launchpad for exiting ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off with the head! Getting Rid of Phoney Justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:20:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Executing a human being and punishments like solitary confinement are as coldblooded and premeditated as murder and torture can get. They are not in self-defence, because the danger has passed. It is not justice, because a person can always outweigh their deeds, and they can change, given the chance. The theme of this series is still justice and in this issue, we are looking at it from different angles, including those phoney ones imposed on the guilty with little or no respect for their welfare and human right. This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews and culture by UN-aligneders across the world, including Ruby Goldenberg, Carla Pietrobattista, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, Victoria Davila, Partho Chatterjee and Maya Bearyman, Cristina Mihailescu, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Atika Harba and Sonia Roopnarain. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU&#39;s Struggle with Justice: Is the Cart Before the Horse?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:43:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the July issue of The Gordian. The European Union is a remarkable institution, but the callous exclusivity of the block has risked making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. The “Golden Curtain” of Europe is turning it into a fortress, a type of Noah’s Arc that cares little or nothing for the lives of others. In this issue, we will focus on justice across the European block.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Is history repeating itself so soon?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:30:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/issue-2-vol6c-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by the UN-aligned design team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another month and another warm welcome to a new issue of The Gordian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In keeping with our theme for this series on justice, we will be focusing on appeasement. Apart from the article about forfeiting somebody else’s justice that tackles appeasement head on, the issue is also highlighted in our articles in the UN in Focus section and alluded to elsewhere, including the campaign we have been working on over the last few months, namely, trying to bar countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from being given seats at the United Nations Human Rights Council. We can proudly announce that the letter has been sent to the UN to coincide with Pride Month and it has been supported by the many signatures of organisations and individuals alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet The New Lady Justice</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Meet-The-New-Lady-Justice-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the May 2022 issue of The Gordian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is largely accepted that Lady Justice’s blindfold symbolises impartiality. Despite the accepted wisdom however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our cover article “The new Lady Justice with an eye on Ukraine”, Adrian Liberto addresses a failing world order and exchanges Lady Justice’s appearance for one that is more suitable to the needs of modern times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Square Holes For Square Pegs: Revamping The Education System</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:29:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to April’s issue of The Gordian! This issue offers the usual mix of politics and culture, with our main focus this time being on education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adrian Liberto’s article, &lt;em&gt;Education’s Paradigm Shift,&lt;/em&gt; sets the scene with a revolutionary critique of traditional schooling and a vision of a more dynamic system for the future. Jihan Al-Assad’s article further highlights hurdles in education with a first-hand account of the specific problems Syrian refugee students face trying to learn in ill-equipped camps, where the situation has now been further exacerbated by the coronavirus. This article is complemented by another by Jihan that covers the hardships of refugee life in general. Our interview (Ruby Goldberg/Noor) also relates to education and describes the difficulties faced by pupils at the mercy of a system that is quite foreign to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crying Havoc: Putin unleashes the dogs of war</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the March 2022 issue of The Gordian Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“War is an unacceptable way of resolving differences, or crimes committed by one country against another. It should not be glorified with epithets like ‘just’ or ‘holy’; nor should it be legitimised with conventions aiming at damage limitation.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/in-english/#:~:text=and%20clearly%20stated.-,Article%206%3A%20War%20must%20be%20criminal%20offence.,-Reasoning%C2%A0&#34;&gt;Article 6&lt;/a&gt; of UN-aligned’s manifesto is unequivocal when it says that “war must be a criminal offence”. Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is a blatant breach of international law and UN-aligned strongly condemns it. Countries can no longer be allowed to use the term ‘soldier’ or ‘patriot’ to justify the deployment of people to commit crimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sex, Drugs and Rock &amp; Roll</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-from-the-editors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter from the Editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to February’s The Gordian!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short month, but an issue brimming with provoking reads. As always, the title reflects the some of the themes we will be covering and it comes from a 1969 article in Life magazine by Edward Kern: “The counter culture” he wrote, “has its sacraments in sex, drugs and rock.” Of course, it was Ian Dury and the Blockheads who made the phrase famous with the 1977 song &lt;em&gt;Sex &amp;amp; Drugs &amp;amp; Rock &amp;amp; Roll&lt;/em&gt;. “Counter culture” sums it up really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border Bullies: Weaponising citizenship</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:36:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;editorial&#34;&gt;Editorial&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;letter from the editors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last year was a cold bath for those who believed there were simple answers to complicated problems. Don’t be surprised if the new one is pretty much the same&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January 2022 issue of The Gordian Magazine! A new year and a new outlook: Like every month we gathered the best from UN-alignders from all across the world for you to read, 100% free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What have YOU done for Justice this year?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription&#34;&gt;Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/the-gordian-preview-1024x640.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can now now support the publication of the Gordian Magazine with a monthly subscription.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federalism &amp; Social Cohesion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/poetry-competition-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;terra-australis-incognita--silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition&#34;&gt;“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp;amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “Silence”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social ills equation... Minus inevitability</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:55:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster… it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we cover various social issues ranging from rough sleeping to poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing up to The Dystopian Tide</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-un-aligned-poetry-competition-2021&#34;&gt;The UN-aligned poetry competition 2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/poetry-competition-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition. Photo freepik&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the international literature day on the 8th of September, UN-aligned will be holding a poetry competition open to everyone. The application is open from 1.08.2021 and finishes on 08.09.2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applicants will be informed about the decision during the last week of September. The finalist(s) poems will be featured in the Gordian Magazine&amp;rsquo;s October issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this competition is to creatively portray the values which UN-aligned’s Manifesto campaigns for. The competition aims to highlight the importance of the creation of a different kind of a United Nations as well as the promotion of human rights, animal welfare and environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Just Let Them Eat Fudge...&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fervid-summer-share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows--music-with-our-international-readers&#34;&gt;A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp;amp; music with our international readers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Share-your-favourite-books-TV-shows-music--1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photo by CandiceP/Pixabay&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More and more people are using their free time in summer to relax and enjoy a good book, movie, TV show or a piece of music.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligneders are from all across the world. We currently have members from over 24 countries, so we are certain that curating a list of your favorite entertainment will help inspire our international community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law &amp; Disorder at The United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-in-focus---may-2021-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN in Focus - May 2021: The good, the bad and the ugly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/UNINFO1-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good-battling-for-universally-affordable-and-available-vaccines&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good: battling for universally affordable and available vaccines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://undocs.org/en/E/C.12/2021/1&#34;&gt;Statement&lt;/a&gt; on May 11 calling for COVID-19 vaccines to be universally affordable and accessible. The five-page document covered all the main issues comprehensively and with refreshing lucidity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Statement starts by highlighting the fact that everyone has the right “to enjoy the benefits of scientific progress and its applications” and proceeded to lament “the current unhealthy race among States for COVID-19 vaccines, which has created a sort of temporary monopoly by some developed States of the first vaccines to be produced.” This is underscored by the fact that current production capacity is at its limit in as much as stocks are already sold out through public procurement by such States. This has created an unacceptable situation of “health isolationism”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whose Justice?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-to-the-un-aligned-manifesto-that-you-need-to-review&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updates to the UN-aligned manifesto that you need to review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Updates-to-the-UN-aligned-manifesto-that-you-need-to-review-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 2021, UN-aligned board decided to update the language around some of the items in its manifesto. You can review all the edits here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe the flexible roadmap of UN-aligned’s manifesto presents a safe trajectory for a united world, so as UN-aligned grows we are always seeking to refine, clarify and improve our goals and missions. The following changes have been made to the UN-aligned manifesto as of May 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easter doughnuts: reshaping the global economy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-doughnut-economy-humanity-to-thrive-sandwiched-between-its-inner-and-outer-limits&#34;&gt;The Doughnut Economy: &amp;ldquo;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Doughnut-Economy-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Doughnut Economy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-LEconomia-della-Ciambella.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Sanction or Not to Sanction?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-you-listen-people-are-always-willing-to-talk---a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat&#34;&gt;“If you listen, people are always willing to talk” - A conversation with photographer Anwar Sadat&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_0228-copy-2-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 15th of February 2021, the 2020 UN-aligned photo competition winner, Anwar Sadat, tells us about the story behind his prize-winning photos and his love for photography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat&#34;&gt;Read the article →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-powerful-panacea-the-sanctions-dilemma&#34;&gt;A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Adrian Liberto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/United-Nations-Security-Council-03.03-1024x614.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hijacking Religion to Down Human Rights...</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed January 202&lt;/strong&gt;1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Africa-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Italian_-What-you-may-have-missed-in-Jan-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Scores of villagers were slaughtered by suspected Islamist terrorists in coordinated attacks on two villages near the border with Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. Incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadera was declared the winner of the presidential election that was held last month against a backdrop of unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05/06.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;DRC Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. A ferryboat carrying over 70 people capsized on Lake Kivu. About 50 people were rescued and the bodies a woman and two children found. Twenty or so people are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time for a change: Welcome Veganuary!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed December 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Featured-images-Jan-2021-1200x630-copy-1-1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. The top court rejected former President François Bozizé’s bid to run for president in the December 27 election against incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadéra. The former president failed to meet the ethical standards required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ghana&lt;/strong&gt;. Results of the presidential election held on Monday have confirmed a narrow victory for incumbent President Nana Akufo-Addo. His main rival was ex-President John Mahama. Supporters of both candidates took to the streets following delays in the announcement of the results and at least five people were killed in the unrest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – December Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 18:37:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-november-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.11.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 50 villagers, most of them women, children and elderly people were slaughtered in a rebel attack in the Oromia region at the weekend. The Oromo Liberation Army (OLA) is suspected of having carried out the barbaric attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.11.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ivory Coast&lt;/strong&gt;. The electoral commission confirmed President Alassane Ouattara won a disputed third term with an overwhelming majority. Most of the opposition, however, had boycotted the election. Anger at the elections spilled into the streets resulting in over 30 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – November Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:16:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-october-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed October 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EUROPE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;UK&lt;/strong&gt;. The EU has set in motion legal proceedings against the UK after it reneged on sections of its Brexit “divorce” deal. Talks, however, are set to continue. The UK was given until November to respond to EU concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;Greece&lt;/strong&gt;: The neofascist party Golden Dawn was declared a criminal organization for its role in a series of attacks on migrants and left-wing activists. &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; called it the “biggest trial of fascists since Nuremberg.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – October Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:40:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-photo-competition-announcement&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned Photo Competition Announcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1.-2-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is holding its first photo competition from today &lt;strong&gt;7th October 2020&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;15th of November 2020.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this competition is to visually and creatively portray UN-aligned’s Manifesto. The competition aims to highlight the crucial link between human rights, the environment, animal welfare and the health of our ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The jury, which is composed of professional photographers, will be looking in particular for creative photos that successfully illustrate the articles of the manifesto. You may look for inspiration in our Manifesto here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – September Issue, Vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-september-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 09:42:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-september-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you may have missed: August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1-1024x538.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Cameroon&lt;/strong&gt;. In a vicious grenade attack targeting a camp for displaced people, as they slept, suspected Boko Haram militants murdered over 16 people and wounded several others in the village of Nguetchewe, northern Cameroon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Tanzania&lt;/strong&gt;. Tundu Lissu, an opposition politician who survived being shot 16 times in an assassination attempt, will challenge President Magufuli in the October elections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mauritius&lt;/strong&gt;. A state of emergency has been announced after an oil spill from a damaged Japanese ship is contaminating vast tracts of water. Baby tortoises and rare plants from an island near the spill, Ile aux Aigrettes, are being taken to the mainland to protect them from the worsening situation. The ship had struck a reef on July 25.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – August Issue, vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-august-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:46:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-august-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;letter-to-ashin-wirathu&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letter to Ashin Wirathu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/2-1024x538.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhante Ashin Wirathu,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that focusses on the need to replace the United Nations with a more effective and principled organisation, although we also work to promote human and animal rights, as well as the welfare of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Institutionalised religion has had a sad history in a number of countries around the world owing to its bigotry and abuse of power. Many spiritual people, including some of our members, have therefore looked to Buddhism as a beacon of justice and openness. This image has been tainted over the last few years by portrayals of monks leading a crusade against the Rohingya inhabitants of Myanmar. The contradiction here reminds many people of the darkest periods of some of the leading world religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – July Issue, vol 3</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-july-issue-vol-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 18:38:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-july-issue-vol-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-starts-campaigning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned Starts Campaigning&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is proud to announce the launch of a series of campaigns in line with its manifesto. We will be covering a range of issues concerning human rights, the environment and United Nations reform, and we will be reporting on them in The Gordian, as well as on our website. Our campaigns will start by targeting blatant disregard to clearcut issues of social or environmental justice by powerful corporations, organisations or individuals. We will be highlighting their shortcomings and asking them to take positive steps in order to improve their undertakings in line with a fairer and safer world. For instance, we will be contacting the Arab League and holding it to account for blocking UN initiatives to protect LGBT rights and we will be challenging the Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu and asking him to consider how he can justify preaching hatred against the Rohingya, when this goes against every tenet of Buddhist belief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – June Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-june-issue-vol-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 19:20:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-june-issue-vol-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-human-rights-series---there-must-be-no-monopoly-on-the-truth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Human Rights Series - There Must be no Monopoly on the Truth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Us-Versus-Them-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;The New Human Rights Series &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Environmental Priorities Series comes to its sixth and last issue, we sincerely thank all of our readers and authors for their generous support and contributions; it is because of you that The Gordian magazine has developed into its current form and has become a platform for members to express their thoughts and ideas. We are incredibly proud of this achievement and will continue our efforts to improve this resource with the support of our members and contributors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian - May Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-may-issue-vol-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 11:00:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-may-issue-vol-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN-aligned becomes one year old!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is one year old this month! The seed was sown some years ago in China and developed thanks to the dedication of like-minded people. We have gone from 22 Foundation Members to hundreds of followers from around the world: some are full members, others are subscribers, while many follow us on Facebook. To all our supporters, we wish to offer a big THANK YOU!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian - April Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 18:07:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;facing-the-covid-19-together---letter-of-encouragement-to-gordian-readers&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facing the COVID-19 Together&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Letter of Encouragement to Gordian Readers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Gordian readers,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, we have found ourselves in extraordinary and unprecedented times. The COVID-19 pandemic has made our human interconnectedness clearer than ever before. While we know that no obvious solution lies ahead, we are certain that our best response relies on solidarity, bilateral collaboration and the very thing that makes us humans: compassion and respect for life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian – March Issue, vol 2</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-magazine-march-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 18:26:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-magazine-march-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-across-the-world-you-may-have-missed&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News across the world you may have missed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/image-9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MALAYSIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahathir Mohamad, Malaysia’s interim Prime Minister said that seeing as an agreement could not be reached on his replacement, parliament would vote to pick a new Prime Minister; failing that, a snap election will be called.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAMBODIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists are warning that millions of people who depend on the Mekong river for their sustenance are at risk. Dams being built by China are only part of the problem. Dredging the riverbed for sand to use in construction is causing the river to erode its banks and inhabited and cultivated areas with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
