<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/categories/the-gordian-magazine/</link><description>Recent content in The Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:43:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/categories/the-gordian-magazine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>To be or not to be European alone — The Gordian Magazine</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 13:43:31 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-8/</guid><description>Welcome to the February issue of The Gordian Magazine. In this edition, we venture into the depths of a question that has, for centuries, puzzled and provoked: "To be or not to be European alone". As we stand at the crossroads of history, the fabric of our collective identity is being stretched and tested by the forces of nationalism and globalisation, each tugging in its direction.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-3-vol-8-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Voices That Shape Nations</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:05:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-november-issue-vol-8/</guid><description>Voices that shape us are all around us. In this issue of The Gordian magazine, we delve into the profound influence of diverse cultures and communities in the process of nation-building. From the tranquil mountains of Tibet to the vibrant streets of India, each article illuminates the unique contributions and challenges faced by these distinct groups in shaping the tapestry of our global society. This issue features articles by Alexander Stoney, Amy Church, Sunil Kumar Pariyar, Ellen Jones, Omar Alansari-Kreger and Carla Pietrobattista. The Editors are Ariana Yekrangi and Adrian Liberto.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-gordian-issue-2-vol-8-cover-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Global Constitution: The New Social Contract</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:45:51 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-8/</guid><description>The dream of a united global constitution is closer than we think. As nationalism rises, can a unified code be the anchor we need? Dive into our October issue titled 'Global Constitution: The New Social Contract'. Join us as we navigate through the intricacies of geopolitics, art, culture, and more. This issue boasts thought-provoking pieces by Alexander Stoney, Adrian Liberto, Sunil Kumar Pariyar, Samira Ghafori, Anahita Ahmadi, Dawn Roy, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Carla Pietrobattista and Partho Pratim Chatterjee. The editors are Ariana Yekrangi and Adrian Liberto.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-1-vol-8-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>In The Fume of Power: The Greed of Giants</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:10:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-7/</guid><description>No one needs to be consumed by the fumes of power. There is space for equity, even in the face of giant greed! This is not mere utopian thought; this is an urgent call to action. In this re-emerging June issue of The Gordian, titled "In The Fume of Power: The Greed of Giants", we confront the unchecked power of industry giants and the inherent dangers they pose. Of course, our explorations do not end here. The June issue presents a plethora of compelling articles penned by an array of thoughtful minds, including Dawn Roy, Alexander Stoney, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Jihan Al-Assad, Carla Pietrobattista and Alex Liberto. Overseeing this issue are editors Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-3-vol-7-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Fair's Fair: Entitlements Are Not Charity</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-7/</guid><description>No one needs to be poor. There is plenty for all of us! This is not utopia; this is a fact. In this second issue of our new Utopia series, we will be focusing on poverty and its elimination. Of course, our coverage does not end here. The March issue offers a wide range of insightful pieces by Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Pradeep Kumar Chatterjee, Elvira Ineza, Atika Harba, Carla Pietrobattista, Alex Liberto, Dinojah Patkunarajah, Dawn Roy, and Omar Alansari-Kreger. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-2-vol-7-copy-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Raising Utopia: Brick by Brick</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-7/</guid><description>In this first issue of our new Utopia series, we will be focusing on world peace and democracy. Our main article is a quirky piece which postulates an interview with the representative of a more advanced civilisation; and within this setting, novel visions are juxtaposed to some of our pressing problems. Of course, our coverage does not end here. The January issue offers a wide number of insightful articles by Lukas Pfluger, Dinojah Patkunarajah, Partho and Pradeep Chatteree, Elvira Ineza, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Joe Wain as well as our literary article by Alex Liberto and our art piece by Carla Pietrobattista. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-1-vol-7-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Enough is Enough: Time to Enforce Justice</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:50:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Welcome to last issue of volume 6 of The Gordian. The main theme of this volume is still justice, but we will also focus on a fight for justice that is unfolding in front of our eyes. Despite the brutality of the security forces in Iran, protests continue to thrive and grow. The courage and defiance of women is inspiring, and their determination to stand up for their rights is a testament to their strength and resilience. This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews and culture by UN-aligneders across the world, including Carla Pietrobattista, Elvira Ineza, Partho Chatterjee, Ted Daley, Ayesha Dawood, Aryan Yekrangi and Omar Alansari-Kreger. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Gordian-Cover-issue-6-vol-6-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Dismantling the war machine</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:28:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Welcome to the September issue of The Gordian. In this issue we are focussing on war. I was going to add “and the futility of it”, but ‘futility’ is far from the right word. No, war is not futile. It too is a nail, and allowed to be, it may well be the last nail in our collective coffin. This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews and culture by UN-aligneders across the world, including Ruby Goldenberg, Carla Pietrobattista, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, Victoria Davila, Partho Chatterjee and Nick Hautamaki, Usha Roopnarain and Omar Alansari-Kreger The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-5-vol-6-copy-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Off with the head! Getting Rid of Phoney Justice</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:20:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Executing a human being and punishments like solitary confinement are as coldblooded and premeditated as murder and torture can get.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-4-vol-6-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>EU's Struggle with Justice: Is the Cart Before the Horse?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:43:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Criticising the European Union as a callous and exclusive gentlemen's club that has created a Golden Curtain against outsiders, the July issue of The Gordian focuses on the state of justice across the bloc.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-3-vol-6-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Appeasement: Is history repeating itself so soon?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:30:02 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Welcome to this issue of The Gordian Magazine. Appeasement is like giving the school bully your lunch money to avoid being beaten up. In political terms, however, it is more like giving the school bully someone else’s lunch money, to stop them from being picked on, because we just cannot be bothered to deal with the confrontation. The term often brings to mind the prelude to WWII, a time when, in the name of peace, Hitler was being allowed to threaten, intimidate and torment. We all know how that story ended. However, is history repeating itself so soon again? This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews, culture, and galleries by our UN-aligneders across the world, including Ruby Goldenberg, Carla Pietrobattista, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, Atika Harba, Kaitlyn Rivera, Partho Pratim Chatterjee and Eston McKeague. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-2-vol-6c-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Meet The New Lady Justice</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-6/</guid><description>Welcome to the first issue of the 6 volume of The Gordian. It is largely accepted that Lady Justice’s blindfold symbolises impartiality, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world? We say no more: Meet our new Lady Justice. This issue offers the usual mix of politics, interviews, culture, and galleries by our UN-aligneders across the world, including Ruby Goldenberg, Carla Pietrobattista, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, Atika Harba, Kaitlyn Rivera, Anahita Ahmadi, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Sailaja S.P and Aryan Yekrangi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-1-vol-6-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Square Holes For Square Pegs: Revamping The Education System</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 06:29:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-april-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>Welcome this special issue of the Gordian Magazine. This issue offers the usual mix of politics and culture, with our main focus this time being on education. This issue contains many more exclusive reports, galleries and interviews by senior administrator, Ruby Goldenberg, our art editor, Carla Pietrobatistta, our puzzles creator, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, our interns, Jihane Al-assad and Kaitlyn Rivera and other UN-aligneders, namely, Usha Roopnarain, Cristina Mihailescu, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Pradeep Kumar Chatterjee and Anahita Ahmadi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/issue-7-vol-5-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Crying Havoc: Putin unleashes the dogs of war</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-march-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>Welcome this special issue of the Gordian Magazine. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Naitons, but in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. This month, we take a closer look at the United Nations' part in the Ukrainian invasion. This issue contains many more exclusive reports, galleries and timelines by our literary editor, Alex Liberto, our puzzles creator, Katharina Wüstnienhaus, our interns, Atika Harba and Kaitlyn Rivera and other UN-aligneders, namely, The Young World Federalists, Usha Roopnarain and Ashkan. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Issue-6-Vol.-6-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Sex, Drugs and Rock &amp; Roll</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-february-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>A short month, but an issue brimming with provoking reads. In this issue of The Gordian, we invite you to look at events from a different perspective, whether it is a step away from our rigid notions regarding sex, or challenging our unquestioning reverence to the United Nations. This issue contains more exclusive reports by, our Art Editor, Carla Pietrobattista, our literary editor, Alex Liberto, our ex-virtual intern Jihan Al-Assad; and other UN-aligneders, namely, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Jonna Lappalainen, Ruby Goldenberg and Kennedy Karanja. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Issue-5-Vol.-5-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Border Bullies: Weaponising citizenship</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 02:36:37 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-january-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>In this issue of The Gordian, we talk about the concept of citizenship and why our primary duty should be to humankind and not the state. This issue contains more exclusive reports by, our Art Editor, Carla Pietrobattista; our virtual interns, Atika Harba and Jihan Al-Assad; and other UN-aligned members, namely, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Anahita Ahmadi, Ruby Goldenberg and Pouyan Jaberi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Issue-4-Vol.-5.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>What have YOU done for Justice this year?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-december-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>In this issue of The Gordian, we take a look at all the serious issues relating to justice that we may be oblivious to. This issue contains exclusive reports by, our literary editor, Alex Liberto; our virtual interns, Atika Harba and Jihan Al-Assadother; and other UN-aligned members, namely Carla Pietrobattista. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-3VOL.5.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Federalism &amp; Social Cohesion</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:56 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-october-and-november-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>In this issue of The Gordian, we take a closer look at the Balkan Peninsula and the fall of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia.  This issue contains exclusive reports by, our literary editor, Alex Liberto, and other UN-aligned members, namely Jay Davis and Carla Pietrobattista, Eston McKeague, Jonna Lappalainen and Aryan Yekrangi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-2VOL.5-copy-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The social ills equation... Minus inevitability</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:55:34 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-september-issue-vol-5/</guid><description>Exploring our tendency to view personal disaster as a distant, parallel universe, this issue of *The Gordian* delves into pressing social issues from rough sleeping to poverty, featuring exclusive reports from its editorial team.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-1VOL.5-copy.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Standing up to The Dystopian Tide</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-august-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>The United Nations is the devil. It has had the top job of securing world peace for over three quarters of a century and for a host of reasons it has made an absolute mess of it. And yet, most of us are happy to be represented by this organisation. We say enough is enough. In this issue of The Gordian, we talk about why the UN cannot be trusted to represent, let alone advance, humanity’s ideals and aspirations and why simple reform will not resolve its inherent problems. This issue contains more exclusive reports by, our literary editor, Alex Liberto, and other UN-aligned members, namely Jay Davis, Jonna Lappalainen and Carla Pietrobattista. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-6VOL.4.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>"Just Let Them Eat Fudge..."</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-july-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>Plunging into the ocean of UN communiques is like drowning in an alphabet soup. Often, the words are noble, the causes honourable. Occasionally they even make a difference... and yet the members of this mighty club behave like undisciplined children who delight in doing just as they please. In this issue of The Gordian, following the re-election of the Secretary-General, Antonio Guterres, we will be discussing everything relating to his post and office. This issue contains more exclusive reports by, our literary editor, Alex Liberto, and other UN-aligned members, namely Jonna Lappalainen, Carla Pietrobattista and Aryan Yekrangi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-5VOL.4.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Law &amp; Disorder at The United Nations</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-june-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>War is an unacceptable way of resolving differences, or crimes committed by one country against another. In this issue of The Gordian, we discuss a solutions towards comprehensive global justice. We also take a closer look at the crimes committed by Israel and the UN Security Council. This issue contains exclusive reports by our Administrator, Ruby Goldenberg, our literary editor, Alex Liberto, our treasurer, Jonna Lappalainen and other UN-aligned members, namely Carla Pietrobattista and Anahita Ahmadi. The editors are Adrian Liberto and Ariana Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-4VOL.4-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Whose Justice?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/gordian-may-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. Human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. In this issue of The Gordian, we discuss the differences between the International Court of Justice and the International Criminal Court and test their fairness, validity and integrity. We will also introduce you to a new series within magazine titled "UN in Focus". This issue contains exclusive reports by Jonna Lappalainen, Ayten Aydin and Carla Pietrobattista.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Gordian-Cover-ISSUE-3VOL.4.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Easter doughnuts: reshaping the global economy</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-april-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. In this issue of The Gordian, we present to you the basics of modern economic theory including topics like, the Doughnut Economy, the dilemma of growth and the relationship between GDP and happiness. This issue contains exclusive reports by our literary editor, Alex Liberto and other contributors namely, Carla Pietrobattista and Ruby Goldenberg.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Gordian-Cover-ISSUE-2VOL.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>To Sanction or Not to Sanction?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:48 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-march-issue-vol-4/</guid><description>"Yesterday, upon the stair; I met a man who wasn't there! He wasn't there again today; Oh how I wish he'd go away!" The following quote from Hughes Mearns’ poem, Antigonish, could so easily allude to sanctions. They are full of sound and fury, and yet, they signify nothing concrete, but rather an absence of something. In this issue of The Gordian we talk about sanctions, what they aim to achieve and whether they are successful or not. This issue contains exclusive reports by Alex Liberto, Anahita Ahmadi and Ayten Aydin. To read this issue free of charge, click on the link below.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-1VOL.4-22.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Hijacking Religion to Down Human Rights...</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-february-issue-vol-3/</guid><description>People with bigotted or selfish agendas have always tried to hijack religion. Many of them claim a monopoly on truth relating to the divine and the moral. Today however, we know that religion cannot be used as an excuse for indifference, oppression or injustice of any kind, whether it be to fellow humans, to animals or to the planet itself. In this issue of The Gordian we highlight why it is important to put human rights before religious rights. This issue contains exclusive reports by Alex Liberto, Jonna Lappalainen and Aryan Yekrangi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-8-VOL.3.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>It's time for a change: Welcome Veganuary!</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-january-issue-vol-3/</guid><description>Factory farming causes animals to live and die in great pain each year. So far, our response has been almost total indifference and inaction. For this reason, we have decided to dedicate this issue to animal rights and animal welfare. In the spirit of Veganuary, we have a number of articles dedicated to the topic, including: reports, interviews, poetry and even food recipes. We will also discuss UN-aligned's achievements in 2020 and how we plan to take the leap to 2021. This issue contains exclusive reports by Animal Equality Italia, Andrea Piccinelli, Anahita Ahmadi, Jonna Lappalainen and other UN-aligned members.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-7VOL.3-2-copy.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Gordian – December Issue, Vol 3</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 18:37:24 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-december-issue-vol-3/</guid><description>People rave about democracy, but democracy is not the panacea it is made out to be. It has been described as “two wolves and a sheep deciding what to have for dinner” and in many cases it appears to be just that: a dictatorship of the majority. In this issue of the Gordian we take closer look at serious weaknesses of the US democratic system. This issue also contains a peep into the life of Samuel Pepys, a photo gallery from Uzbekistan and a dangerously hot quiz that should challenge everything you know about democracy.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Copy-of-ISSUE-6VOL.3.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Gordian – November Issue, Vol 3</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:16:13 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-november-issue-vol-3/</guid><description>This year the World Food Programme was awarded the prestigious Nobel Peace Prize. But should branches of the United Nations be beneficiaries of such awards for simply doing their job? Wasn't this a missed opportunity? "This was a coward and political move" argues Adrian Liberto in his piece: Five Reasons why this Year’s Nobel Peace Prize was Misplaced. In this publication, author Ariana Yekrangi also takes a closer look at a looming food crisis predicted to be unlike anything we've seen before. This issue also contains an exclusive photo reportage by UN-aligned Administrator, Ruby Goldenberg.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/ISSUE-5VOL.3-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Gordian – October Issue, Vol 3</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:40:02 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian-magazine/the-gordian-october-issue-vol-3/</guid><description>Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy...” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government...”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.” In this month's Gordian we discuss LGBTQ+ rights. This issue contain more exclusive reports by Alex Liberto, Aryan Yekrangi and Anahita Ahmadi.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Copy-of-ISSUE-4VOL.3.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>