<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unesco on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/unesco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unesco on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/unesco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Odessa&#39;s Cultural Heritage Threatened by Ongoing Conflict in Ukraine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 25, UNESCO inscribed the historical Ukrainian city of Odessa on the World Heritage List and the World Heritage in Danger List. “Odessa, a free city, a world city, a legendary port that has left its mark on cinema, literature and the arts, is thus placed under the reinforced protection of the international community,” said Audrey Azoulay, Director-General of UNESCO. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The people of the port city were delighted as was its mayor, Gennady Trukhanov. He pointed out, however, that the task would not be an easy one:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Heritage Committee’s 44th session took place virtually from 16 to 31 July. It covered issues left outstanding since last year, when the annual meeting was postponed due to COVID-19. The extended session was chaired by Tian Xuejun, China’s Vice Minister for Education and Director of China’s National Commission for UNESCO. The session looked at 42 nominations to the World Heritage List (24 submitted for 2020 and 18 for 2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
