<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human Rights on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/human-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Human Rights on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/human-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Zionist experiment has failed: it must be abolished</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some ideas are not up for debate. They are autopsies. You do not reason with a tumor; you remove it. Zionism, as a political project, is that malignancy, and the state of Israel its grotesque outgrowth. To advocate for a “two-state solution”—a partition of historic Palestine that enshrines an explicitly Jewish ethno-state—is no longer just a failure of imagination. It is moral idiocy: a mumbled incantation over a corpse, serving only to buy the murderers more time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua’s War on the Press: New Report Highlights Escalating Repression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:52:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned recently partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fled.ong/&#34;&gt;FLED Nicaragua&lt;/a&gt; to translate their annual report from Spanish into English, highlighting the grave state of press freedom in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assassination of retired Nicaraguan army officer and outspoken critic of President Daniel Ortega, Roberto Samcam, on June 19 while in exile in Costa Rica, underscores the urgency of the crisis and the critical need to raise international awareness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Press-Freedom-Report-January%E2%80%93March-2025-%E2%80%93-Copy.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read full report -&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Held Hostage No More’: Harris, Democrats and the Price of Betrayal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/harris-democrats-and-the-price-of-betrayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 08:47:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/harris-democrats-and-the-price-of-betrayal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First as tragedy, then as farce, and now—an endless cycle of farce, like a bad political rerun that won’t quit. America has rewarded its own worst instincts by returning to office an anti-women, climate-denying, xenophobic figure who has openly admired authoritarianism. This isn’t an anomaly; it’s déjà vu—again. Trump’s re-election isn’t an outlier but a pattern that shatters any pretence of America being better than this. It isn’t, and it’s high time we stopped pretending otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Reaping what you sow’: Why Trump’s assassination attempt is unworthy to steal headlines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/reaping-what-you-sow-why-trumps-assassination-attempt-is-unworthy-to-steal-headlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:14:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/reaping-what-you-sow-why-trumps-assassination-attempt-is-unworthy-to-steal-headlines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Karma often comes with a sting, as the old saying goes. After eight years of stoking division, Donald Trump almost got a taste of the chaos he helped create. He was on the verge of experiencing the kind of horror faced by 378,000 US students who &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/interactive/school-shootings-database/&#34;&gt;have died from guns&lt;/a&gt; since the Columbine High School massacre in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time, Trump nearly found himself in the same dire straits as over 37,000 Palestinians—who lost their lives as he &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-israel-gaza-finish-problem-rcna141905#&#34;&gt;cheered on Israel&lt;/a&gt; to “finish the problem” with bombs proudly stamped Made in the USA, and literally signed off by a Republican cheerleaders in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘If it ain’t broke... break it’: How the US betrayed  free speech and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;loving-guns-hating-free-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loving guns, hating free speech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely amazing how the US government bows with such unquestioning fervour and reverence to the Second Amendment, while comfortably sticking its middle finger up to the First.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Second Amendment, ratified in 1791, in the heyday of the Wild West and almost 100 years before the iconic gunfight at the O.K. Corral (1881), stipulates “the right of the people to keep and bear Arms”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“We’ve seen this before”: Inside Israel’s war on truth, journalists and the free media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first casualty in any assault is invariably the truth. But what is it about journalists that tyrants find so terrifying? It is the fear of empowerment that comes with knowledge. Despots thrive in the shadows that ignorance casts, manipulating and controlling through a cocktail of misinformation and deceit. Yet, a journalist can spark a flame in our mind, capable of incinerating the very foundations of tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiding the truth is not merely the erratic behaviour of the paranoid or the despotically inclined; it is a clear indication of inherent weakness. A government that stands firm in its legitimacy and moral authority does not flinch at criticism nor recoil from dissent. It is the inherent brittleness of despotic rule that dreads the light of scrutiny, much like a rotten structure teetering on the verge of collapse at the merest prod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Embracing genocide’: How Iranian monarchists are championing Israel&#39;s deadly onslaught on Palestine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:55:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you encounter the rare sight of individuals rallying in support of Israel&amp;rsquo;s actions in Gaza, your attention might be drawn to an unexpected symbol: a variant of the Iranian flag. This particular flag, adorned with the Lion and Sun against a backdrop of green, white and red, harks back to Iran&amp;rsquo;s monarchical past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ensign, displayed alongside Israel&amp;rsquo;s, hails from a time when monarchs reigned over Iran, now seized upon by a diverse array within the Iranian diaspora, particularly those championing freedom in Iran, which includes the monarchists also known as Pahlavis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking away from Gaza will not assuage our conscience; only action will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 08:27:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently, amidst the clinking glasses and idle chatter of a social gathering, I ventured to pierce this bubble. I posed a question to my friends, seemingly simple yet laden with the weight of untold suffering, which asked for their thoughts on the current mass slaughter of Palestinians by Israel; an atrocity that enjoys, astonishingly, the tacit approval—if not outright support—of our governments. One friend, embodying the spirit of our age&amp;rsquo;s indifference, confessed to avoiding the subject altogether. The casual dismissal struck me—not for its rarity, but for its brazenness, as if the very act of engagement with such a grave matter was itself a burden too heavy to bear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of a charade: Israel&#39;s collapse under global condemnation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel is as good as finished. It has lost all credibility as a responsible nation in-the-making. From the onset its creation has depended on abusing superpowers, injustice and crime. It has been those three forces that have kept it enduring and spreading until now, while skilfully dodging every attempt to hold it to account, often by playing the victim. Despite the numerous massacres perpetrated along the way, something very different has happened now that has shaken its very foundations; mortally so: Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>António Guterres Named as the UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-antónio-guterres&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why António Guterres?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considering UN-aligned is an organisation whose chief aim is to supplant the United Nations with a workable structure and agenda, António Guterres may seem one of the most unlikely choices for the UN-aligned Person of the Year. Nevertheless, all said and done, he too is striving for a better world order; the difference is that he is doing it from within: a losing battle, perhaps, but one that is not without its relevance and impact. He has proved to be brave and outspoken and unflinching in his support for the issues that matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation-Building and Indigenous Struggles: Histories, Rights and Representation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where borders are drawn and redrawn, the quest for a homeland remains fraught with strife for many. Nation-building, the process of constructing a national identity and establishing political and social structures, is pivotal in this quest. It is not just about hotly-debated independence stories or drawing lines on a map; it involves acknowledging diverse histories, cultures and rights to create a cohesive and inclusive society. This is crucial for ensuring peace, stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘No Girl Left Behind’: How Taliban&#39;s Ban on Girls&#39; Education Imperils Afghanistan&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-historical-context-afghanistans-education-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The historical context: Afghanistan&amp;rsquo;s education system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan is currently the only country in the world where girls are forbidden to go to school. The decision to stop women being able to access school and university by the Taliban in August 2021, has consequently denied millions of girls their fundamental right to education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan has a complex and turbulent history and this has had undeniable consequences on its education system. The department of education was established in Afghanistan in 1913, with the goal of a national education system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal&#39;s National Parks: A Conservation Success Shadowed by Local Struggles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Nepal, majestic national parks thrive as sanctuaries for wildlife, but for the local communities who are grappling with human rights abuses the path to harmonious coexistence remains fraught with challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The value of protected spaces like National Parks is undeniable. Nepal&amp;rsquo;s journey with these parks began in 1993, when the Forest Act recognised certain &amp;lsquo;protected forests&amp;rsquo; for their environmental, scientific and cultural value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the royal hunting grounds, these spaces have evolved into critical conservation centres, forming a key part of Nepal&amp;rsquo;s forest management strategy. Today, Nepal boasts about 20 such protected spaces. However, while these parks aim for conservation, they also pose challenges, particularly for local communities with restricted access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India has certainly been in the spotlight these last few months and anyone not looking too closely would be justified in thinking that the country was rising, phoenix-like, from its post-colonial ashes to virtual super power status. In April 2023 it overtook China as the most populous nation on Earth with well over 1.4 billion people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 4, Rahul Gandhi, champion of the Congress Party and heir to the Nehru-Gandhi dynasty, had his two-year prison sentence for disparaging comments made against Modi, suspended by India’s supreme court, suggesting a robust democratic rule of law. Also in August (23rd), India’s Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft landed on the lunar surface. This was all the more spectacular coming so soon after Russia’s failed moon mission. Moreover, it was the very first successful landing on the dark side of the moon. Then, in September, with much pomp and circumstance, India hosted the 2023 G20 Summit. Its presidency may not have been a roaring success, but it was a success nonetheless. Though Russia’s President Vladimir Putin and China’s Xi Jinping did not attend, and organisers had to forego the traditional “family” photo owing to disagreements over Ukraine, the overall outcome was positive, with the African Union’s addition to the block being one of this G20’s notable achievements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing Civilian Areas &amp; Killing Children is Wrong. Even for Revenge, Especially for Revenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:54:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grief and fury brew a potent concoction for vengeance in the hearts of those who have lost all. The cycle of violence spirals, each rotation taking it to a ghastly new level. Israeli officials, under the banner of ‘self-defence’, have adopted a scorched earth policy towards Gaza. Yet, the international community&amp;rsquo;s reaction often diverges sharply into one of two markedly distinct viewpoints: unflinching support for Israel and utter condemnation for Hamas, or justifying Hamas&amp;rsquo;s targeted killings as acts of legitimate resistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could Uganda&#39;s Anti-Gay Law Alter the Lives of All Ugandans, Straight or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/could-ugandas-anti-gay-law-alter-the-lives-of-all-ugandans-straight-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:11:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/could-ugandas-anti-gay-law-alter-the-lives-of-all-ugandans-straight-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The President of Uganda, Yoweri Museveni, has signed an Anti-Homosexuality Act (AHA), outlawing homosexuality in the country. Uganda&amp;rsquo;s penal code already prohibits same-sex conduct, but the new bill, signed on the 26th of May, introduced the death penalty for acts classified as “aggravated homosexuality”, which includes spreading HIV, rape and serial offending. Moreover, it raised the imprisonment term for same-sex conduct to 10 years, while a 20-year sentence could be handed to anyone promoting homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life on Repeat: Jihan&#39;s Diary from the Frontlines of a Refugee Camp&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life in a refugee camp seems stuck in an unending cycle of sameness. Days blur into one another, the only change being the unpredictable and often unforgiving weather conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is an attempt to document the individual days, but the repetition of the mundane is all too clear. Every harsh, cold morning feels identical, showing no mercy to the inhabitants. The only source of warmth is the resilience of the human spirit, akin to the skeletal structure of a body that refuses to succumb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bots for a Demining Peace Initiative: The Path Towards a World Free of Landmines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bots-for-a-demining-peace-initiative-the-path-towards-a-world-free-of-landmines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bots-for-a-demining-peace-initiative-the-path-towards-a-world-free-of-landmines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Could the development of robots capable of demining, ensure that peace is within reach for regions recovering from or living through conflict?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest escapes for children growing up against the backdrop of war and famine is in their creative imaginations. The power of pretend is brilliantly articulated by children in games where they explore and adventure in the unforgiving rubble and debris of their war-torn communities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine, a child wanders to the outskirts of town kicking stone pebbles in between barbed wiring, intermittingly dispersed in a seemingly unsuspecting demarcation area alluding to some kind of Neverland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary Cities: Shattering Myths, Protecting Human Rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received a parking ticket? Most are undoubtedly familiar with this feeling of intense frustration at the sight of a small fine tucked at the base of their windshield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, what if a minor parking ticket posed the threat of a much larger consequence? What if it meant your children would be taken out of school? What if it meant you and your family could be deported? This is the reality for thousands of illegal immigrant families living in North America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love for Erdogan&#39;s Autocracy in the Heart of German Democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recep Tayyip Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s name echoes in Istanbul and Berlin alike. As Turkey&amp;rsquo;s President, he commands attention and drives conversation in both these distinct locales, exerting an influence that, to many observers, seems paradoxical. Despite being in the heart of Europe, where democracy is a foundational value, Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s autocratic approach finds a surprisingly receptive audience within a substantial German-Turkish community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s influence over this diaspora often equals, and at times even outstrips, his hold over his own nation, a conundrum that pushes against traditional ideas about the strength of democracy. But how can an autocratic leader secure such steadfast loyalty from a community residing in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most solid democracies?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICC Pursues Putin: A Sprinkle of Justice in a World of Mischief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:09:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-reality-of-abducted-children-in-ukraine&#34;&gt;Chilling Reality of Abducted Children in Ukraine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Vladimir Putin, seemingly untouchable and unaccountable for countless transgressions, continues to cause havoc in Ukraine, a glimmer of hope emerges from the unlikeliest of origins: the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spark that ignited the fire was a public “thank you” from the Children&amp;rsquo;s Rights Commissioner, Maria Alekseyevna Lvova-Belova. She &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2023/02/16/putins-childrens-envoy-reveals-she-adopted-child-from-mariupol-a80249&#34;&gt;expressed gratitude to Putin&lt;/a&gt; for enabling the “adoption” of a young boy from Mariupol, unwittingly revealing the chilling reality of Ukrainian children torn from their homes and subjected to “re-education camps” or forced adoptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My internship comes to an end, but my journey continues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my internship at the UN-aligned, I did my best to convey the suffering of refugees and their lives in the camps through interviews and life in the camp. As a refugee myself, I now want to share one last story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I met a 23-year-old returning from work in the stone sawmills with his clothes covered in dust. He was the son of our neighbour and one of the brightest students at his university. He was forced to leave school due to forced majeure and ended up supporting his family by working in the mills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Arizona&#39;s Hostile Stance Towards Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state of Arizona has been a hotspot for immigrants for many years. The US state, which shares about 600 km of border with Mexico, has become a popular destination for refugees and migrants who escape their homes searching for a better and safer life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While some advocate for mass deportations of these ‘illegal immigrants’, others argue for faster processing and greater protections for those seeking asylum or other forms of humanitarian assistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are Sri Lanka’s Missing Children?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/where-are-sri-lankas-missing-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Remember when you and Akka [older sister in Tamil] used to skip dance class by hiding in the storage shed in the backyard?”, reminisces my Aunt. “We would spend ages looking for you, thinking you both had gone missing.” It’s been 13 years since the end of the Sri Lankan civil war and my cousin went missing. My aunt, like many mothers in Sri Lanka, is still searching for her daughter or at least answers as to what happened to her. Answers she is unlikely to ever find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Subtle Manipulation of News Media in the Age of Pseudo-Enlightenment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-the-sun-wot-won-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the Sun wot won it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The older generation may remember it well. It was 11 April, 1992. Neil Kinnock and his Labour Party were set to win the general election and the best the Conservatives could have hoped for was a hung parliament. Then, however, The Sun, one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s right wing tabloid newspapers owned by Australian-American media mogul Rupert Murdoch, launched an aggressive campaign to swing things around&amp;hellip; and sure enough it did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mick Lynch Named as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mick-lynch-named-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is our pleasure to announce that Mick Lynch, the secretary-general of the RMT trade union, has been named the UN-aligned Person of the Year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This award recognises Lynch&amp;rsquo;s dedication to advancing the interests of working class people and fighting against issues of economic inequality and injustice. His efforts have earned him widespread admiration and attention, with many hailing him as a hero for our times.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-mick-lynch&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is Mick Lynch?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mick Lynch is the current General Secretary of the British national Union of Rail, Maritime and Transport Workers (RMT), a labour union representing over 83,000 members across various sectors of the transport industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN votes on a fact-finding mission into Iran, but don’t look at it too closely</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhrc-fact-finding-mission-into-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the United Nations is not busy declaring French baguette a world cultural heritage or hosting awkward diplomatic cocktail parties where everyone pretends to like each other&amp;rsquo;s national dishes, it dedicates a small portion of its resources to protecting human rights across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in November, a fact-finding investigation into human rights violations in Iran, where hundreds have died and tens of thousands have been detained since protests started in September 2022, has been approved by the UN Human Rights Council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar 2022: A World Cup for Straight Men</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I wrote an article for The Gordian Magazine celebrating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/lifestyle/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/&#34;&gt;growth of women’s football&lt;/a&gt; in the UK, and hailing 2022 as a watershed year in women’s sport around the world. Now, just a few months later, nothing seems further from the truth. In choosing to host one of the world’s biggest sporting competitions in Qatar this year, a country run on Sharia law and plagued by inequalities, FIFA has let the world know that football remains the domain of straight men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealed: Leaked file uncovers how the Iranian Revolutionary Guards plan to quell protests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/iranian-irgc-secret-meeting-leaked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basij commander warns media organisations against talking about the recent unrest in Iran and advising them to refer to the rising opposition &lt;strong&gt;using terms such as &amp;ldquo;conspiracies&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;collusions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revolutionary Guards have &lt;strong&gt;received a list of Iranian football&lt;/strong&gt; fans who participated in World Cup from Qatari officials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IRGC has used the country&amp;rsquo;s participation in the 2022 World Cup as a &lt;strong&gt;distraction from the widespread protests.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hacking group named Black Reward has published the audio file of a confidential meeting between Basij commander Qasem Qoreyshi and media managers close to the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC) that took place on the 15th November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zahhak to the Islamic Republic of Iran: Has Ferdowsi prophesied the future of the republic?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:21:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zahhak was the evil king of Mesopotamia who conquered Iran and, together with his army and serpents that grew out of his two shoulders, terrorised the people of the land for thousands of years. It all started when in order to congratulate the new king on his new position, the embodiment of evil, known in the Book of Kings as Ahriman, disguises himself as the royal cook and asks to kiss the new king’s shoulders. Zahhak agrees and moments after Ahriman’s lips touch Zahhak’s shoulders two black snakes emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USA vs Canada: A history of residential schools in North America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/residential-schools-in-canada-and-the-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/residential-schools-in-canada-and-the-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uncovering-of-mass-graves-in-canada-and-the-united-states&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Uncovering of Mass Graves in Canada and the United States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/The-Uncovering-of-Mass-Graves-in-Canada-and-the-United-States-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kamloops Indian Residential School classroom building&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A classroom building of Kamloops Indian Residential School, Kamloops, British Columbia during the 1950. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;© CC 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May 2021, 215 bodies of children were found buried on Kamloops Indian Residential School grounds in Kamloops, British Columbia, Canada. Following the incident, the US Interior Department began their investigation of US schools and uncovered over nine graves of indigenous children at the Carlisle Indian Industrial school in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, United States. What followed since has brought forth to the colonist public’s attention the systemic destruction of indigenous communities, cultures, and peoples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th July, the Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. That’s no big deal, one would imagine, but sadly, for the United Nations, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is why a few months ago UN-aligned launched a campaign to bar countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from the Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the fact that our open letter to the United Nations was backed by several organisations and human rights activists, the letter was ignored.&lt;a href=&#34;https://documents-dds-ny.un.org/doc/UNDOC/GEN/G22/407/77/PDF/G2240777.pdf?OpenElement&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;We always hope for change, but we are powerless. We are just refugees&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to visit a friend of mine, it has been a while since I visited her and when we sat down and started chatting. She started telling me the story of a neighbour of hers in the camp who got very sick with corona and her children started running around to help her. She was then admitted to the hospital and put on an oxygen cylinder. The story filled me with sadness and thoughts filled my head. What is this epidemic that has taken over the whole world and claimed the lives of many friends and loved ones?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solitary confinement is cruel and amounts to torture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/solitary-confinement-is-cruel-and-amounts-to-torture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solitary confinement often achieves fewer goals than keeping prisoners under control more quickly and satisfying a perverse need to see pain inflicted on those deemed criminally responsible, with little regard for the consequences. In doing so, the prolonged use of solitary confinement contravenes many national statutes. These include the 8th Amendment to the US Constitution, the Nelson Mandela Rules put forth by the UN, China’s Prison Law and European Prison Laws. In 2011, UN Special Rapporteur for Torture Juan E Mendez claimed that in many cases, it breaks international law, and he has called for a ban.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s barbaric and repulsive: Let&#39;s Axe the Death Penalty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the death penalty involves legally killing an alleged criminal. “Alleged”, not only because the person may not have committed the crime in the first place, but equally because the crime may have been labelled as such only due to the distorted perspective of the lawmakers. At times, this perspective is biassed in favour of jealousy, bigotry, the acquisition of wealth and power; or the neutralising of a rival or critic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mridul Wadhwa on Conversion Therapy and Edinburgh Rape Crisis Centre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mridul Wadhwa, and I am originally from India, and I’ve lived in Scotland since 2004. I started working in the violence against women or gender-based violence sector in 2005. With a small break in between, I’ve worked in that sector since then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I primarily worked with minority ethnic women, immigrant women, and women from communities of colour living in Scotland. For most of that time, my job was to work with the white majority community, primarily service providers, to help them develop an understanding of what kind of barriers minority ethnic women in Scotland face when experiencing and leaving abusive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OHCHR: Take action to ban harmful conversion practices against LGBTQIA&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Michelle Bachelet Jeria, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, a Finland-based NGO whose mission is to create a better and fairer United Nations that promotes ethical principles of human rights, animal welfare, environmental well-being, and world peace. Pertaining to human rights and global justice, I request that the OHCHR address and take action to eliminate harmful conversion practices that promote violence and invalidate the LGBTQIA+ community worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-acquis-communautaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Acquis communautaire&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acquis Communautaire is the EU rule book that protects all member states&amp;rsquo; citizens under the rule of law. Fun fact, if you read two pages of this EU treaty an hour, without any breaks because duh, stuff your dinner plans, you’ll be through it in just 4.5 easy years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ginormous legal textbook, which consists of 35 chapters within &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2001:0645:FIN:EN:PDF&#34;&gt;80,000 pages&lt;/a&gt;, is a combination of all European legislation, including all treaties, directives and regulations established by the EU&amp;rsquo;s institutions, as well as all decisions rendered by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Curtain: Does the EU Stand on the Side of Justice?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many criticisms have been levied at the EU, a fair amount, as we shall see, may be justified, but most are part of that process that developing organisations with such a mighty mandate have to go through. All said and done, the benefits far outweigh the drawbacks, as Britain’s ever-increasing list of post-Brexit crises, on the one hand, and the eagerness of neighbouring nations to join, on the other, makes evidently clear. There is, however, one flaw that unless remedied as a priority, will risk making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. Rude language, but the reality is far ruder. I am referring to the EU’s callous exclusivity, which I will refer to as its Golden Curtain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Overturning of Roe v. Wade: Here’s what this will mean</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/the-overturning-of-roe-v-wade-heres-what-this-will-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 10:18:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/the-overturning-of-roe-v-wade-heres-what-this-will-mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States Supreme Court ruled on January 22, 1973, that under the Due Process Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment, a person’s choice on whether or not to have an abortion was protected in the United States and could not be criminalized. This constitutional right would stand for nearly 50 years and result in safer abortion procedures and reproductive healthcare that saved lives across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the developing decision was leaked prior to its final release, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.loc.gov/item/usrep410113/&#34;&gt;Roe v. Wade&lt;/a&gt; was officially overturned by the U.S. Supreme Court on June 24, 2022, marking the erasure of progress for human reproductive rights in the U.S. and leaving the decision of legalizing abortion up to the states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Almoallem Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One day, my little sister and I were studying for the high school exams, so we were all sitting very quietly. Suddenly we heard the sound of shooting near our camp; not only close, but actually in the camp. We started hearing the voices of children screaming and crying, and they all scrambled for their tents or perhaps entered a neighbour’s tent because of the fear and panic. We subconsciously put our heads to the ground and we started wondering what was going on. What are these sounds?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council of Europe and the struggle to uphold human rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:01:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe is an organization that was founded in 1949 after the conclusion of the second World War. The council is composed of 47 member states with 27 of those states also being members of the European Union. The council operates on the mission of protecting and preserving human rights throughout its domain. This council was formed so that no atrocities such as those seen during World War II, would ever occur again. Since its inception, the Council of Europe has expanded to include six smaller councils and assemblies that actively work towards achieving goals such as abolitioning the death penalty, supporting children’s rights, ensuring fair and equal elections, and fighting for equal access to healthcare. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I entered the university and my heart is leaping with joy!” — An extracts from a refugee’s journal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:31:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the days of the war in Syria, we lost our safety. We used to sleep to the sound of cannons and wake up to the sound of planes. One day, my mother asked me to go to the pharmacy near our house to buy a fever-reducing medicine for my little brother; while I was on the way back with my little sister, a shell fell in front of us. The people on the street started running to see what happened. We did not stop running until I got home, and we survived. This is one of the most difficult memories that stick in my memory and cannot be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rehauling Lady Justice: Is the United Nations guilty in Ukraine?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long as international justice is left in the hands of nation states at the UN nothing will ever improve because self-interest will always win the day. This needs to change. Meet the new lady justice!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lady-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why representations of Lady Justice depict her in a blindfold? The accepted explanation is that the blindfold symbolises impartiality. Lady Justice is supposed to be oblivious to power, status, wealth or any other privilege. She also sports scales, which represent fairness through the weighing up of the facts, and a sword, which represents swift and thorough retribution. Although the scales date back to her earliest manifestations as the Egyptian goddess Maat, the blindfold probably originated with Hans Gieng’s 1543 Gerechtigkeitsbrunnen (Fountain of Justice) in the Old City of Bern. Despite the accepted wisdom, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a Syrian refugee?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 09:42:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Syrian; I think this phrase is enough to indicate that I may be in Sweden, Germany, Egypt or one of the many countries Syrians have resorted to in order to survive the tragedy inside Syria. This tragedy has left Syrians under the rubble, submerged in the Mediterranean Sea as they try to cross into Europe, or languishing in a prison under interrogation; perhaps eviscerated or eviscerating themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I Am A Syrian Refugee Who Lives In Lebanon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate refugees in the modern world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 13:28:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A climate refugee is someone displaced from their home because of an extreme weather event caused by climate change. This particular category of refugees is coming from all over the world to various places that are not being affected as deeply by extreme weather. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate change is nothing new and neither is human migration. Migration has been a huge factor in international interactions since the dawn of written history. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Global climate change however, is a relatively recent occurrence. Climate change is defined as “the increasing changes in the measures of climate over a long period of time – including precipitation, temperature, and wind patterns”. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romania Always Welcomes Ukrainian Refugees: Support and Opportunities Await</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 10:06:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few days since Romanians stopped wearing masks. Literally speaking, we have finally been told that such protection is no longer necessary, even though the hospitals are still full of sick people. The pandemic is not over, but a greater evil has appeared at the borders of our country, an evil we would hopefully never meet face to face: war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrible as it sounds and can be felt in the images broadcast 24 hours a day on all the TV stations, the war in the neighbouring country has produced an unprecedented, totally unexpected outcome: Romanians stopped wearing masks in their daily lives and started showing their true colours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At last, European Unity Prevails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 10:28:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We stood by and watched Putin help deliver both Brexit and Trump. We were quite happy letting him tear Syria apart. So what, he invaded Donbas? He is a cold-blooded murderer? “What then? poor beastie, thou maun live!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Putinism required diplomacy”, that’s what diplomats said anyway. It was obvious to most, at the time of each of these hammer blows, that Putin’s tentacles had penetrated through and influenced our democracy. Our response to this despot for his crimes? The occasional sanctions here are there. Don’t get me wrong; although they are increasingly becoming the bulwark of our international system, sanctions can work. But they won’t if we are too paralysed by indecision, or when we are at crossroads with ultra-complex choices: utilising green energy, on the one hand, or continuing importing Russian gas during a climate emergency, on the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We support Ukraine because it represents the sacrosanct right to build one&#39;s own future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/why-we-support-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After appealing to the Russian President, Volodymyr Zelenskyy only received silence in return. He therefore decided to deliver a speech to the people of Russia and to the people of the world; not as the President of Ukraine, but as he put it, as a citizen of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy spoke about the shared 2000km border with Russia that is today breached by almost 200,000 soldiers and thousands of military units. This situation could trigger a widespread war on the European continent. The area is now a smouldering keg that could potentially burst into a catastrophic conflagration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I still have hope that we will all return to our warm home and beautiful city” — Interview with Syrian refugee, Somaya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-your-life-and-how-you-got-here&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about your life and how you got here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am Somaya, a mother of three children, two daughters and a son. At the beginning of the war in my country, Syria, I lost my husband and did not know anything about what could have happened to him. When the battles intensified, I took my children and went to my father, as he lived alone in Damascus because my mother was dead. We lived with him for about a year, and then the war broke out in Damascus as well. One day we woke up to the sound of guns, bullets, and planes. I took my children and we went with my father to take refuge in the shelters. We stayed like this for three days until we finally decided to get away from this area. We actually made our way on foot, until we approached a car that was in a traffic jam on the way to the border with Lebanon. We accosted them and found that they too were leaving Syria for refuge in Lebanon. With them we eventually reached the Lebanese border and once in Lebanon, a tent was secured for us to live in. So after witnessing so much death, we finally found safety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vlady Hell: Putin Strikes Again!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:05:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the August 2020 issue of The Gordian titled Russian Roulette: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity&lt;/a&gt; we published an article cheekily called Vlad the Terrible. It listed a range of crimes committed by Putin ranging from mass murder to mass deceit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vlad-the-terrible&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vlad the Terrible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You play with fire and you risk getting burned; play with the devil and you end up screwed. Sadly, this is exactly what is happening to Europe and beyond now that the demon is waving his devil’s fork and even threatening nuclear destruction. The good news is not only that we have learned a lesson, but even more remarkably, that we are prepared to suffer the consequences of our mistakes and send this devil to hell!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five benefits of legalising drugs that may change your perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-benefits-of-legalising-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-decriminalisation-of-drugs-mean-vs-what-does-it-mean-to-legalise-drugs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does decriminalisation of drugs mean VS&lt;/strong&gt; what does it mean to legalise drugs&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we talk about decriminalising all drugs, within a legal framework, we don’t necessarily refer to them being legalised. In other words, drug ownership and personal use would itself still be legally prohibited, but violations of those prohibitions are deemed to be exclusively administrative violations and are removed completely from the criminal realm. Ideally, we want the legalisation of all drugs, however, decriminalising them could also be an attractive short-term solution. Here are five arguments for legalising drugs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My religion is myself and my nationality is my heart”: Five days inside a refugee’s diary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 10:22:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During her internship with UN-aligned, Jihan Al-Assad was asked to write about her life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Her experiences, along with those of other refugees are published in a new series titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/diaries-from-refugee-camps/&#34;&gt;Diaries from Refugee Camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-1122021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1/12/2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a new month and the end of a whole year. This does not feel like the beginning of a month or a day or anything new. I am afraid because I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what is coming to me, and this idea is a big horror for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeking Behind the Fig Leaf: Our Journey to Sexual Liberation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Society is a raft made from the wreckage of our dreams and fears. Space is limited and we struggle to keep aboard, scrambling for the middle ground so we do not have to witness those sacrificed at the rim: pushed, or slipping, or just unable to grab a hold. Smug, we pretend that they are not there or that they are so out of reach that we are quite exonerated from any obligation to assist them from their demise. Some would rather swim. Others choose to drown. Reality, as we perceive it, as we live it, is a fragile thing, so we cling on to the raft despite its many flaws. We ignore them. We justify them. We acknowledge and accept them. Often, religions sanction them. And so we paddle on, tossed by abysmal waves, never quite certain where we are heading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is circumcision abuse?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:43:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written: Adrian Liberto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Video: Ariana Yekrangi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are in a position to help, please consider supporting The Gordian Magazine with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/thegordian&#34;&gt;Patreon subscription&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/&#34;&gt;Read the article published on the website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/register/&#34;&gt;Contribute to the Gordian by writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: When People Gather</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 10:37:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-people-gather&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When People Gather&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news is published everywhere&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It tells us the world is in disrepair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you turn and pretend it&amp;rsquo;s not there&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you consume the news in despair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you say that you&amp;rsquo;re not political&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What a privilege you have, that&amp;rsquo;s not typical!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Things only seem to get worse by the day&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods and plagues, corruption, decay&lt;br&gt;&#xA;While thoughts and prayers might be a gesture&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Stand up, be proactive or the problems fester&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These are man-made issues and ours to undo&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where do we start? You haven&amp;rsquo;t a clue.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Well there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just I can do&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But what if your neighbour thought that too?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And their neighbour thought they didn&amp;rsquo;t matter&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Changes happen when people gather &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/in-english/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s message&lt;/a&gt; is loud and clear&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The earth is for sharing, all welcome here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disheartening revelations about the UNHCR in Lebanon — A refugee’s perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 09:53:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary mission of the United Nations Refugee Agency, the UNHCR in Lebanon, is to provide emergency assistance to those forced to flee their homes. This is the first step towards long-term protection and rehabilitation, as well as a means to support in various sectors for refugees and asylum seekers. But how is this achieved in the current reality, especially in a country like Lebanon? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;positive-action-of-the-unhcr-in-lebanon&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive action of the UNHCR in Lebanon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the UNHCR include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migrant-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The migrant problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied their history will know that migrations are what shaped the world as we know it today, both politically and ethnically. At times these migrations were peaceful. Often, they were predatory. At times they were gradual, spreading like an oil stain; often, they were sudden and quite alien, like a frenzied splash from a Jackson Pollock paintbrush. At times the end result was growth and a fusion of cultures; often, it was genocide. So we built walls of brick and paper to keep the undesirables out. Most of us belonged to those undesirables once, but that was a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domenico Lucano declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 15:04:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned has chosen Domenico Lucano as its Person of the Year 2021. The ex-mayor of the Italian town of Riace has been chosen for his vision regarding the integration of refugees into their destination of choice, while at the same time revitalising a dying town.  Riace became a showcase of prosperity and integration and was hailed in 2016 by Fortune magazine as one of the world’s 50 greatest leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 30th September 2021, Lucano was sentenced to 13 years in prison for abetting illegal migration. His “crimes” included awarding waste collection contracts to companies that were set up to help migrants look for work and arranging a marriage of convenience to help a Nigerian woman escape prostitution and find legal work. The accusation that he enriched himself in the process, seems contrived, considering he does not even have the funds to pay for his legal fees. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following interview was conducted in November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tell-me-about-yourself-and-your-children&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about yourself and your children?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Amna; I am 33 years old. I live in Lebanon in a Syrian refugee camp. I have two children, a son and a daughter. My husband was lost in Syria, and I fled with my children from the war and came to Arsal to seek safety away from the difficult conditions of the war that destroyed our lives and the childhood of my children. I tried to work to meet the needs of my children, but I could not for fear of leaving them alone in the tent and I wanted to teach them and follow their school lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still Life Without Flowers: A Glimpse Into The Arsal Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I will talk about my place of residence in one of the camps in Lebanon, Arsal, and how I was able to adapt to this difficult life, which does not resemble life at all. It is only days that pass without taste. One of the most difficult days of my life was when I was fifteen years old. My family decided that we should live In a refugee camp. At that time, misfortune and sadness overtook me, and I went into a state of depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;i&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silence is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Silence is complicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Complicity is violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So in the violence of our silence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let us take stock of our complicity &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;ii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our complicity silences truth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muffles honour, rapes innocence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The same innocence we plead&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Confronted by shattered delusion&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“We didn’t know” &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;iii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wished to not know&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Blinded, deafened, deadened&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We turned away Bedecked ourselves in laurel&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Which now turns to rue &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;iv&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our silence - yours and mine - is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is complicit It is violent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And in its complicit explicit violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We too have bloodied our souls&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Terra Australis Incognita</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;and those black fellas believed these white fellas spirits of their ancestors (pale time travellers of everywhen) and those black fellas received venereal, opium, rum and pox and they returned witchetty grubs, honey ants and fruit bats and the white fellas killed no one with their guns because the new land was called &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (land belonging to no one) and it was fair to say that these white fellas did not include themselves nor irony in their census taking and the captain struck the collarbone of the elder (he that had helped himself to the white fellas shovel) and the aborigine elder embraced the captain and spread his arm to indicate everything he could see and the captain surrendered his shovel of wrought iron just as black fellas shared their axes of polished greenstone and so it was with ropes and stakes and sacred land; these white fellas pushed the black fellas further from the sea, scattered burial totems of coral, red basket and seagull feather and there was bile and spleen between the groups and dead black fellas (females and young, too) and the aborigine elder pushed the collarbone of the captain and the captain knew it was wrong to survey and deed what wasn’t theirs and he was ashamed and he agreed that his voice was no greater than the magpie or the blue winged kookaburra and he negotiated to settle the interior space of &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (that ground that was less hospitable like them) and handcuffs and leg irons fell from the poors and politicals and these made a mountain of metal where everyone was free to piss and the captain cast off his blue jacket and white waistcoat and humbled himself to learn yellomundi (or storyteller) and butbut (or heart) and he was granted initiation by they that met and decided he was ten years old and he was painted with red clay and fat of the wallroo and wombat and he received cuts to his chest arms shoulders and buttocks and sand in each produced voluminous scars and the penis of this white fella was split with a stone knife and a front tooth was knocked out to mark him as community and he danced the tree lion climbing ripping and pulling but laying in peace with brother and sister alike and he sang the songlines that trek creation and he blew didjerry didjerry through termite eucalyptus, pressed his lips to beeswax and shook out grins and guffaws and the black fellas did not call him apostle but he returned his blind eye seeing to the white sails of sirius of the orion and he stayed the cannons and six-pounder guns and his voice was dreamtime and ancestral beings and why it is that men and women walk upright and those that saw and heard were ashamed and they pushed the collarbone one of the other and they agreed against greed to call this place “must be there somewhere land” and it remains so to this day&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 29, the UN had a Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on the deteriorating situation in Myanmar. US ambassador and senior advisor for political affairs, Jeffrey DeLaurentis, summarised the dire situation, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Humanitarian aid workers inside Burma are sounding the alarm. As a direct result of the military’s brutality and administrative failures since its coup six months ago, Burma is reeling from a surge in COVID-19 cases. This burgeoning health catastrophe comes at a time when hundreds of thousands of people remain internally displaced by the recent violence, with the World Food Program projecting between 1.5 and 2.8 million additional people in the country could now be at risk of food insecurity.”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are reports of scores of doctors being rounded up and imprisoned because of the medical profession’s reaction to the coup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Not Trust The United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-the-devil-you-know&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations: the devil you know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met someone from a peculiar land with a completely messed up political system yielding a society that was plagued with poverty, oppression, corruption and strife. I commiserated until I found out that there actually was an alternative party that, given the chance, would put things right, yet nobody seemed to care about it. “Hey! What’s wrong with you people?” I asked my new acquaintance, pointing this out. “Many do not know; many do not care&amp;hellip;” “And what about you?”  I petitioned. “Ah, better the devil you know!” They replied smugly, as a demon dragged them to hell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Led by extremists, bombed by extremists - Gaza in the midst of insanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your past is in front of your eyes, it’s 2014, 2012 and 2008 all over again. You cannot escape it, visual reminders are scattered all over the city. Being bombed back to the middle ages seems to be a recurring theme in Gaza. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history concerning the Israel and Palestine conflict is complicated. What is not at all complicated, however, is whether or not it is admissible to airstrike civilian areas, news buildings, health facilities or Covid labs. Whether or not it is acceptable to take away life should not be a controversial issue, one would hope. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve a robust legal system? Solutions towards comprehensive global justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in last month’s issue of The Gordian, I highlighted some of the weaknesses of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and the International Criminal Court (ICC). Whilst these bodies are merely a part of a wider international legal system that is also governed by various treaties, conventions and accords, they are pivotal in as much as their focus is on safeguarding human life and world peace. My conclusion was that these two institutions were flawed, compromised and generally ineffective. In this issue, therefore, I intend to offer some concrete ideas for a robust legal system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-La-giustizia-di-chi.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taming The Governing Strategies of Ongoing Socio-Economic Development by Way of G-Localization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/taming-the-governing-strategies-of-ongoing-socio-economic-development-by-way-of-g-localization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Domare-le-strategie-che-governano-lo-sviluppo-socio-economico-in-corso-attraverso-la-G-Localizzazione.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ultimate-goal-and-foregrounding&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimate goal and Foregrounding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this reflection is to create favourable conditions for progress by mobilizing the intellectual, spiritual and material forces with a sense of belonging to one and the same human community. This requires finding new ways of living in society and of facing the future together. Living organisms compete for resources, but collaborate for sustaining life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yesterday, upon the stair,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I met a man who wasn&amp;rsquo;t there!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t there again today,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh how I wish he&amp;rsquo;d go away!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from Hughes Mearns’ poem, &lt;em&gt;Antigonish&lt;/em&gt;, could so easily allude to sanctions. They are full of sound and fury, and yet, they signify nothing concrete, but rather an absence of something. Of course, sometimes, a lack of something can have devastating effects: if you stop my air supply, for instance, I am dead. Sanctions, however, are very limited in what they can stop, because what comes from outside one’s borders was not there in the first place, like the man upon the stair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;No, it&#39;s not just a snip&#34;: Why Circumcision is Legalised Child Abuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:56:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mutilating the sexual organs of a child (circumcision) in the name of culture, religion or dubious preventative medical claims is outrageous and a blatant breach of the child’s human rights. Female genital mutilation is thankfully on the decline and relatively rare in developed countries. The cutting of little boys, however, is not. Approximately one third of males are circumcised worldwide. In this article I intend to highlight the futility and barbarity of the practice. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Times the Russian Orthodox Church Flouted Norms of Decency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 08:19:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/5-times-the-russian-orthodox-church-flouted-norms-of-decency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the former communist regime, the Russian Orthodox Church (ROC) was suppressed, its properties confiscated and its followers harassed and imprisoned. This was until a Messiah came along. He promised the church fortune, a return to traditional values, a trip to simpler times when the state and church washed filth off each others’ backs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, Putin and the Russian Orthodox Church walk hand-in-hand in so many ways. From the eyes of the church he is seen as a “miracle of God”, a humble Russian worshiper who wants to put the Church at the heart of Russia’s national identity. However, the Church is not the only one who has wet dreams; what the ROC knows too well is that they must return the favour. And we all know what the price of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/vlad-the-terrible/&#34;&gt;a deal with the devil&lt;/a&gt; is: selling your soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lingering Sins of Religion: When books weigh us down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 08:35:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;written-in-stone&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written in stone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of religions in the world today and many thousands more have come and gone. Many of these claim or have claimed a monopoly on truth relating to the divine and the moral, as well as to the rituals necessary to accompany a devout life. No doubt, much good has come from these religions in as much as they have contributed to unifying people around a set of values that have generally been beneficial to society and wellbeing. Often, they coalesce around scriptures that are professed to have been inspired or dictated by heaven itself. The Abrahamic religions, Judaism, Christianity and Islam are very much of this mould. There is only one problem: societies change, but books do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranian lawyer declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nasrin Sotoudeh is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nasrin_Sotoudeh&#34;&gt;Iranian human rights lawyer&lt;/a&gt; who has been in and out of prison since 2010 for no other reason than defending men, women and children who suffered under the oppressive Iranian regime. Her clients included opposition politicians, journalists, abused women and children, women who were arrested for not wearing the hijab and prisoners on death row for crimes they allegedly committed when they were minors. On several occasions she went on extended hunger strikes to protest against the severity of the prison regime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annus Horribilis? Looking on the brighter side of 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:25:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has certainly been an Annus Horribilis, with plagues, floods, fires, terrorist attacks and wars, but it wasn’t all bad&amp;hellip; In the sciences for instance, vaccines to fight the coronavirus were created in record time. In business, SpaceX ferried astronauts to the International Space Station in the first commercial flight of its kind. Here are some of the success stories from 2020 with regards to human rights and animal welfare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy vs Anarchy: Which one is better?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 11:52:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/democracy-vs-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winston Churchill once said: “Democracy is the worst form of government except for all others.” But was he right? This article about democracy vs anarchy offers different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years, democracy has become a defining characteristic of the West and its politics. This has even developed to a point where we are talking about &amp;ldquo;exporting&amp;rdquo; democracy to the non-Western world, falsely assuming, of course, that democracy is a perfect form of governance that enables societies to elect competent leaders through the votes of often uninformed citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to prevent the 2021 food crisis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 09:45:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many will face horrific hunger if relief efforts are not stepped up in a world heated by coal, infected with Covid-19 and separated by nationalists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, 193 countries lined up behind a comprehensive and ambitious set of targets – also known as the Sustainable Development Goals – to transform life and the planet by 2030. Contrary to most UN agreements that are ignored and unheeded by the member states, the project was more than a political platitude and successful on many fronts: extreme poverty fell dramatically and child deaths halved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Wedlock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:26:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-slow-pace-of-same-sex-marriage&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slow pace of same-sex marriage…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same-sex marriage is now legal in almost thirty countries in the world. Considering same-sex unions date back over 12,000 years and that there are almost 200 countries in the world, this is not much of an achievement. In recent times, the first country to legalise same-sex marriage was the Netherlands. That law was passed in December 2000 and came into effect in April 1, 2001. So, even in the last few decades, progress has been slow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wishing to stay above the ground: immigration and survival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is by Abdelkander, an UN-aligned member from Algeria who is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned English Language Programme&lt;/a&gt;. He is currently living and working in Turkey.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;immigration-and-survival&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immigration and survival&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My name is Abdelkader, though I am also known as Faysal. I am from Algeria and I am 37-years-old. Like most young people, I want to have a decent life. Of course, I have dreams, but my main dream is simple: I just want an honest job. In my country, however, whether you studied or did not finish your studies, the matter will not be different, because in either case you will not get a job unless you have mediation, or you pay a bribe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When grandmama fell off the boat… Very nearly taking note of migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:50:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A raft full of migrants who are fleeing war and famine are awaiting at the bay. What would &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: you have five buttons in front of you. They are all linked to a raft full of migrants trying to get into your country. Many are fleeing war and famine, some may be simply looking for a better life, while a few may be nasty characters out for what they can get. Button 1: Destroy. Button 2: Ignore. Button 3: Repatriate. Button 4: Assist. Which would you press? Buttons one and two are more or less as deadly, while the consequences of button 3 are often not much better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The OSCE Minsk Group is Unfit to Conciliate Between Azerbaijan &amp; Armenia over Nagorno-Karabakh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1992, two years before the war between the neighbouring Armenia and Azerbaijan ended, the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), met in Helsinki and decided to chair negotiations towards a peaceful political settlement for the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The body, also known as the Minsk group, is led and co-chaired by the US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt; and France with Belarus, Germany, Italy, Portugal, The Netherlands, Sweden, Finland, Turkey, Armenia and Azerbaijan as participating member states. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian Roulette: Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-grim-trend&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Grim Trend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July seems to have accelerated the grim trend that has been eroding civility and security over the last few years. The month dawned with Hong Kong finding itself stripped of many of its civil liberties. A few days later, on the 6th, President Trump formally notified the World Health Organisation that the US would be withdrawing from the organisation once the required twelve-month’s period of notice was over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compassion fatigue: How to turn your compassion into positive action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:03:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;symptoms-of-compassion-fatigue&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms&lt;/strong&gt; of Compassion Fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever catch yourself feeling really moved by something quite trivial when reading the news, as you skimmed past some tragedy in Yemen or Syria without even paying the slightest bit of attention? Or are you prone to add a like or comment to a Facebook GIF about a silly animal situation, for instance, while ignoring a poignant post about social injustice or an environmental emergency?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Tear Gas in the 21st Century is Unacceptable.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have come a long way since World War I and World War II, yet we still see police forces using dangerous chemical weapons, such as tear gas, against their own civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How dangerous are these chemical substances and should local police be permitted to use such weapons against people? How were these weapons used in WWI and WWII?  The following article aims to answer a few of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protestors: When is it OK to Hit them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/hitting-a-protestor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When is it OK to hit a protestor? Is protesting during a global pandemic a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There has rarely been any positive social changes without some form of protest. Too often the establishment is seen grappling on to power by fostering a dominant discourse from which dissident and minority views are excluded. At best, protests today are characterised as a disruption and inconvenience and, at worst, a threat to a vaguely-defined national security. Political leaders and the majority they may represent, blame these warriors of justice for lack of character and accountability, even though, ironically, those are the very flaws &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; are being accused of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here is What Social Psychology Say About Prejudice &amp; Discrimination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 08:49:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rotests and clashes have spread across the US after the death of African-American George Floyd on May 25th 2020, in police custody. Frustration over the deaths of African-Americans at the hands of police was already rising over the recent deaths of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52623151&#34;&gt;Ahmaud Arbery&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/article/breonna-taylor-police.html&#34;&gt;Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;. These terrible events are only a few examples among the many of conflicts rooted in false judgement, prejudice and discrimination.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article presents prejudice and discrimination from the perspective of social psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:56:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why some of us choose to set up life in a new country. The prospect offers numerous benefits, such as satisfying a yearning for exploration, self-improvement or a higher standard of living.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Living abroad is undoubtedly a highly enriching experience, it broadens your mind and provides exposure to different ways of life; it offers a more immersive language learning opportunity and your self-sufficiency will come to know no bounds as a result of having to jump through strange and complex bureaucratic hoops in a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Citizenship Amendment Bill: a Death Knell for Indian Secularism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2019 the Government of India, led by the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), secccesfully amended a bill to the Citizenship Act of 1955, offering amnesty to non-Muslim illegal immigrants, who arrived in India prior to 2004. These immigrants must be able to prove that they are citizens of one of the three neighbouring countries: Pakistan, Bangladesh or Afghanistan. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;half-the-truth-is-often-a-whole-lie&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half the truth is often a whole lie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spokespeople of the Indian Government have repeatedly claimed that the new law intends to give sanctuary to people fleeing religious persecution. While this is certainly the case, the dubious decision to exclude Muslim refugees from Myanmar, Sri Lanka, and China; or in fact, the Hindu Tamils from Sri Lanka, raises questions about the Government’s sincerity. The timing of the bill is also not inadvertent; In August, the Assam State, located in the North-East of the country, witnessed two million of its residents left off the Citizen Register; this essentially left thousands of people, suspected of being illegal residents, in temporary camps which are housed in the state&amp;rsquo;s prisons. Modi and his Home Minister, Amit Shah, the mastermind behind the Citizenship Amendment Bill (CAB), have been eroding and attacking the social identity of the Indian Muslim community from as early as 1992 and the CAB was undoubtedly brought forth with an intent to adversely affect the political identities of this community. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India on the Brink</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:48:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-enemy-within&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Martin Luther King Jr. visited India in 1959, he paid the homage to the venerable land with these powerful words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“To other countries I may go as a tourist, but to India I come as a pilgrim.” Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Would Mr. King think differently of India if he were alive today? Probably not. The narrowminded fanaticism that is trying to drag India down is not a new phenomenon. Even if one cannot ignore it, one can always look beyond it. However, the world is not what it was 60 years ago. It is a much more dangerous place. Our efficiency in depleting the earth’s life and resources is only matched by the relentlessness of nature’s means of revenge, such as climate change or the smog that has recently been chocking Delhi.  Moreover, if we should end up fighting for whatever is left, we would be able to do so with much more devastating results. Finally, mass media have altered the way in which we communicate. Just as the Internet, for instance, helps the wise become wiser, it often has the opposite effect with fools, who become easy prey to those who would exploit them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Women are allowed to ride bikes – just not in public” Khamenei’s fatwa: another nail in the coffin of women rights in Iran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:19:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/women-are-allowed-to-ride-bikes-just-not-in-public-khameneis-fatwa-another-nail-in-the-coffin-of-women-rights-in-iran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bike-campaign&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A bike campaign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the autumn of 2015, a young environmentalist in Arak, a city with pollution levels as staggering as those in Tehran, started a “car-free Tuesday” campaign to encourage people to commute by bike. The campaign soon turned popular with municipal authorities across the country beginning to encourage residents to ride bikes and leave their cars at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Women cyclists, naturally, saw an opportunity to support a good cause that everybody in Iran could agree on: clean air. They thought they could cycle like other male citizens if they respected Iran&amp;rsquo;s strict dress code, which requires women to cover their hair and body in public. The campaign was soon aborted after a group of female cyclists were detained in the western city of Marivan following criticism from the city&amp;rsquo;s Friday Prayers leader. The women were released the same day, but only after they signed pledges not to cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking at migration in the face</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-has-not-been-a-good-week-for-refugees-but-then-again-it-never-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has not been a good week for refugees; but then again, it never is…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s The Guardian reports how the Lebanese government forced 5,000 refugee families to demolish their own home in order to induce them to return to Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the captain of rescue ship Sea-Watch 3, Carola Rackete, was arrested after she forcefully docked her ship in the Italian island of  Lampedusa. Having rescued 53 migrants drifting off the coast of Libya on June 12, the Sea-Watch 3 was left stranded while the Italian authorities kept refusing to let her dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan gives the world a lesson in democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:15:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-a-thing-or-two-from-taiwan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning a thing or two from Taiwan…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan gave the world a lesson in real democracy last month when same-sex marriage was legalised in the “country“. In a referendum last November, 72% of the population had voted against allowing same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two years earlier, however, Taiwan’s supreme court had ruled that limiting the definition of marriage to couples of the opposite sex was unconstitutional. Legislators therefore backed the Government Bill, putting justice before numbers. This is real democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonising Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 06:40:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-on-the-weakest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking on the weakest…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people just need a common enemy. Any group that can be easily picked on offers the perfect target. Minorities of every sort are often chosen because of their vulnerability. Bullying them makes weak or bigoted citizens feel superior. Some of these minorities have fought back and with time secured a certain level of safety, and the protection of their human rights. Still, immigrants are often the most threatened, because they are insecure. They do not know the ropes and cannot easily fight back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
