<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>European Union on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/european-union/</link>
    <description>Recent content in European Union on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/european-union/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone: Horizons of EU expansion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe is a continent; a land mass. Politically, of course, Europe is much more. It is an entity. The history of its various nations interlaces intricately, more so than with other parts of the world, as does its culture. Its aspirations are also different, though many of these overlap with those of people all around the world. The EU encapsulates some of these hopes, such as a desire for peace, security, justice and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU and Justice: Inside the July Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 10:09:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the July 2022 issue of The Gordian. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was obvious to most that civilisation shall have had to deal with far more than a war of aggression after one of Putin’s casual malign interferences around the world morphed into an unscrupulous war in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/ukraine/&#34;&gt;Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. A social and economic crisis was, perhaps, expected. Four months on, however it is clear that we are heading towards far worse: an orgy of human rights violations spearheaded by unsavoury governments and bureaucrats who are supposed to protect the rule of law and human dignity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-acquis-communautaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Acquis communautaire&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acquis Communautaire is the EU rule book that protects all member states&amp;rsquo; citizens under the rule of law. Fun fact, if you read two pages of this EU treaty an hour, without any breaks because duh, stuff your dinner plans, you’ll be through it in just 4.5 easy years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ginormous legal textbook, which consists of 35 chapters within &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2001:0645:FIN:EN:PDF&#34;&gt;80,000 pages&lt;/a&gt;, is a combination of all European legislation, including all treaties, directives and regulations established by the EU&amp;rsquo;s institutions, as well as all decisions rendered by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Curtain: Does the EU Stand on the Side of Justice?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many criticisms have been levied at the EU, a fair amount, as we shall see, may be justified, but most are part of that process that developing organisations with such a mighty mandate have to go through. All said and done, the benefits far outweigh the drawbacks, as Britain’s ever-increasing list of post-Brexit crises, on the one hand, and the eagerness of neighbouring nations to join, on the other, makes evidently clear. There is, however, one flaw that unless remedied as a priority, will risk making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. Rude language, but the reality is far ruder. I am referring to the EU’s callous exclusivity, which I will refer to as its Golden Curtain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and Moldova&#39;s EU candidacy status… beneficial?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 08:52:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-ukraine-and-moldova-are-granted-candidacy-status-does-that-mean-they-are-members-now&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ukraine and Moldova are granted candidacy status, does that mean they are members now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If only it were that easy! Based on a recommendation from the European Commission, the European Council can grant Candidate Status to prospective members of the European Union. The right to join the block, however, is not one that is automatically granted to countries who receive a candidacy status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the European Council decides to begin accession negotiations with the candidate country, the Commission evaluates the application in light of the Copenhagen criteria, which we will talk more about below, and formulates an opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Council of Europe and the struggle to uphold human rights</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:01:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-council-of-europe-and-the-struggle-to-uphold-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe is an organization that was founded in 1949 after the conclusion of the second World War. The council is composed of 47 member states with 27 of those states also being members of the European Union. The council operates on the mission of protecting and preserving human rights throughout its domain. This council was formed so that no atrocities such as those seen during World War II, would ever occur again. Since its inception, the Council of Europe has expanded to include six smaller councils and assemblies that actively work towards achieving goals such as abolitioning the death penalty, supporting children’s rights, ensuring fair and equal elections, and fighting for equal access to healthcare. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At last, European Unity Prevails</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 10:28:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We stood by and watched Putin help deliver both Brexit and Trump. We were quite happy letting him tear Syria apart. So what, he invaded Donbas? He is a cold-blooded murderer? “What then? poor beastie, thou maun live!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Putinism required diplomacy”, that’s what diplomats said anyway. It was obvious to most, at the time of each of these hammer blows, that Putin’s tentacles had penetrated through and influenced our democracy. Our response to this despot for his crimes? The occasional sanctions here are there. Don’t get me wrong; although they are increasingly becoming the bulwark of our international system, sanctions can work. But they won’t if we are too paralysed by indecision, or when we are at crossroads with ultra-complex choices: utilising green energy, on the one hand, or continuing importing Russian gas during a climate emergency, on the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the campaign to save cruelty-free cosmetics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EU&amp;rsquo;s ban on animal testing for cosmetics is under threath as new analysis (link) finds that cosmetics sold in the EU and UK contain chemicals tested on animals. Furthermore, the European Chemicals Agency (ECHA) is requesting new animal tests on ingredients that have been used in cosmetics safely for years. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than 400 animal rights organizations and companies, including PETA, The Body Shop, Dove and it´s parent company Unilever have signed and sent an open letter to the Presidents of the European Commission, the Parliament and the Council to fully commit to the EU-regulation and continue with its course for a global ban by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
