<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editorial on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/editorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editorial on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:54:16 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/editorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bombing Civilian Areas &amp; Killing Children is Wrong. Even for Revenge, Especially for Revenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:54:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grief and fury brew a potent concoction for vengeance in the hearts of those who have lost all. The cycle of violence spirals, each rotation taking it to a ghastly new level. Israeli officials, under the banner of ‘self-defence’, have adopted a scorched earth policy towards Gaza. Yet, the international community&amp;rsquo;s reaction often diverges sharply into one of two markedly distinct viewpoints: unflinching support for Israel and utter condemnation for Hamas, or justifying Hamas&amp;rsquo;s targeted killings as acts of legitimate resistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s views on strikes in England: Laying the blame where it should be</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/un-aligneds-views-on-strikes-in-england-laying-the-blame-where-it-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The government&amp;rsquo;s treatment of workers and Unions asking for a fair pay rise during a cost of living crisis has been shameful. Nurses, ambulance drivers, paramedics, and other frontline workers have been demonised and blamed for the country&amp;rsquo;s economic woes, despite their tireless efforts to keep the country running during a global crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, those who have actually caused the economic damage – such as the former prime minister who blew a £30 billion hole in the economy overnight, the shambolic execution of Brexit that is estimated to have cost the country over £40 billion, the Tory government’s botched test and trace programme which costed £37 billion, their wasteful procurement of PPE resulting in £8.7 billion being wasted and ending up in the pockets of Tory donors and Richie Sunak’s decision to spend £11 billion by overpaying interest on UK debt – are allowed to escape accountability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is citizen journalism and there is The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 14:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/there-is-citizen-journalism-and-there-is-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world that moves at a dizzying speed, UN-aligned and The Gordian have stayed true to their values, fighting for a better UN and bringing our readers the insights and information they need to stay informed and engaged.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the editor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian magazine,&lt;/a&gt; I reflect upon the past year with both gratitude and concern. On the one hand, I am grateful for the dedication and hard work of our team, whose members have produced high-quality, fact-based, impactful journalism that has provided clarity and imagination in an unprecedented year. On the other hand, I am concerned about the numerous challenges and crises that have impacted our world in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s view on the climate protests: the days of self-serving governments are over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:22:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;were-at-war-with-nature-if-we-win-were-lost-hubert-reeves&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re at war with nature. If we win, we&amp;rsquo;re lost&amp;rdquo; Hubert Reeves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the level of CO2 emissions reach their highest level in 10 million years, children and adults,  from an estimated of 185 countries, unite across continents and time-zones to demonstrate against politicians’ incompetence in dealing with this extraordinary challenge of our time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These protests come at a time when the Amazon forests are being burnt to ashes, a “biological annihilation” of wildlife is in sight and the consequences of melting ice in Greenland is about to give birth to a whole new group of internationally displaced people: climate refugees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
