<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rubygoldenberg on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/rubygoldenberg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rubygoldenberg on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:10:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/rubygoldenberg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can we overcome the nuclear threat? | Ask Ruby</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/can-we-overcome-the-nuclear-threat-ask-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/can-we-overcome-the-nuclear-threat-ask-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for your great and timely question. Antonio Guterres recently called for “sending to the past” nuclear weapons and has said that the “world must abandon them forever”. You’ll notice such statements are without actionable steps but that’s besides the point…</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Can-we-overcome-the-nuclear-threat_-_-Ask-Ruby.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do you write so much about the Ukrainian war, what about other wars? | AskRuby</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/why-do-you-write-so-much-about-the-ukrainian-war-what-about-other-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:13:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/why-do-you-write-so-much-about-the-ukrainian-war-what-about-other-wars/</guid>
      <description>Indeed it may feel like the conflict in Ukraine is dominating many column inches now, but fear not. I’m confident that...</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Why-do-you-write-so-much-about-the-Ukrainian-war-what-about-other-wars_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are train workers on strike? They earn more than teachers and nurses anyway... | Ask Ruby</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/why-are-train-workers-on-strike-they-earn-more-than-teachers-and-nurses-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:34:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/lifestyle/why-are-train-workers-on-strike-they-earn-more-than-teachers-and-nurses-anyway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi. Why are train workers on strike? They earn more than teachers and nurses anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✏️ &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ruby’s answer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
Dear reader,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations and many thanks for pointing out that train workers are not the only overworked and underpaid sector in the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RMT union coordinated a strike - which includes not just those “greedy, overpaid” drivers who I’m sure are buzzing about inconveniencing the public, but a whole host of workers key to the British rail infrastructure, from the train cleaner to the railway lubricator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Unlikely-Agony-Aunt-Letters.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;All of the anger poured out of me like a volcano and I saw red&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:44:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School. This is the third and final part of Noor&#39;s story.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/All-of-the-anger-poured-out-of-me-like-a-volcano-and-I-saw-red-%E2%80%94-My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England-Part-3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“No, I wasn’t somebody just to be picked on”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 10:24:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/no-i-wasnt-somebody-just-to-be-picked-on/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of Noor’s story. Noor is sharing her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, Noor was still grappling with the English language and finding her place in High School.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I couldn&#39;t understand a word of it, but I loved choir singing”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:18:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/i-couldnt-understand-a-word-of-it-but-i-loved-choir-singing-my-life-as-a-moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-england/</guid>
      <description>Noor shares her experience as an immigrant child who came to England in the 70s from Morocco. At the time, she didn’t speak a word of English and was thrust into the British Primary School education system.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/My-life-as-a-Moroccan-child-immigrant-in-70s-England.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a PR Manager</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/opportunities/pr-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/opportunities/pr-manager/</guid>
      <description>Do you love writing a good pitch? Would your friends describe you as confident? Want to get involved with UN-aligned and help us with our media work? We think you might be a great fit for our new open position: PR Manager. Apply now!</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/PR-Manager-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a Puzzle Creator</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 11:27:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you enjoy a good puzzle? Would your friends describe you as creative? Want to get involved with UN-aligned but don’t have too much spare time? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think you might be a great fit for our new and unique open position: Puzzle Creator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at UN-aligned spread our message of fairness and equality through many platforms including our Newsletter, monthly publication ‘The Gordian’ and social media. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the United Nations may be in a sorry state, it’s not all doom and gloom and we like to drop in interactive quizzes to The Gordian for our readers. Until now we’ve been using multiple choice quizzes, you can see an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/category/quiz/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Puzzle-Creator-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan calls on Russia to help quell its unrest, Rock star Meat Loaf dies and Prince Andrew gets stripped (out of his royal patronage)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/monthly-recap-feb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:37:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/monthly-recap-feb-2022/</guid>
      <description>From a messy closet to the freezing cold of Helsinki, hosts Ruby Goldenberg and Ariana Yekrangi show their commitment as they recap the events of January 2022 for the Gordian Monthly Recap.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Kazakhstan-calls-on-Russia-to-help-quell-its-unrest-Rock-star-Meat-Loaf-dies-and-Prince-Andrew-gets-stripped-out-of-his-royal-patronage-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: When People Gather</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 10:37:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</guid>
      <description>Where do we start? You haven&#39;t a clue. &#34;Well there&#39;s nothing that just I can do&#34;. But what if your neighbour thought that too? And their neighbour thought they didn&#39;t matter. Changes happen when people gather...</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/When-People-Gather@2x-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in October — The Gordian Monthly Recap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 12:28:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of Gordian Monthly Recap, Ruby Goldenberg and Ariana Yekrangi help you catch up with everything that happened in October 2021.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-October-%E2%80%94-The-Gordian-Monthly-recap-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Kamchatka in pictures: A visual tour of this stunning region&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Famous for its active volcanoes and brown bears, Russia&#39;s remote Kamchatka peninsula offers stunning yet hostile terrain where unprepared tourists are advised to travel with a guide for safety.</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/2.-camp-where-Lunar-Rover-was-tested-during-soviet-times.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“A preventable tragedy”: How dementia became the catalyst that eroded Noor’s family</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine visiting your mother or father in their home. When you arrive, you discover that they are in distress in front of the television. They look at you with fear in their eyes; you look at them and then to the ordinary television screen, not understanding the problem. Your mother or father imagines that the people on the television are home intruders, and they ask you how those people got into the house. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/A-story-of-Dementia_-How-a-vivacious-and-vibrant-lady-fell-victim-to-her-own-lack-of-planning.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Church of Putin: Inside The Cathedral of Russian Armed Forces - in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces1-502x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has long been a link between Russian banks and the Russian Orthodox Church, so for many it came as no surprise to learn that an extraordinary new cathedral was being built in the outskirts of Moscow costing allegedly 82 Million USD. Photo by Alexia James.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces10-498x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about the mixture of military and religious imagery. Some may consider it distasteful, while other patriots may view it as complimentary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidentally Vegan Feature?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve pondered veganism but haven’t yet followed through, it may be that you are put off by the myth of the diet being restricted. As with any lifestyle change, slow and steady tends to lead to longevity. It is much better to gradually cut animal products from your diet permanently than trying to be a strict vegan for a month, falling off the wagon, and being put off enough to never try it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Featured-images-Jan-2021-1200x630-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon: An Update on UN-alinged’s Campaign</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-un-alingeds-amazon-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 10:45:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-un-alingeds-amazon-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When UN-aligned launched our series of campaigns, we knew that asking the big and uncomfortable questions would not lead to quick and straightforward answers. So far, we have campaigned against &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/&#34;&gt;anti-Muslim sentiment spearheaded by Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have campaigned against &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/&#34;&gt;the death penalty for three young Iranian protestors&lt;/a&gt; and are preparing campaigns against the discrimination of the LGBT+ community to religious and political leaders in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our most dedicated readers may be able to recall the first campaign of UN-aligned, which was an open letter to Amazon to discuss their cardboard packaging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/3-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Amazon: Feedback &amp; suggestions for a more  effective &amp; environmentally friendly practices</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-amazon-about-a-more-effective-packaging-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 18:45:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-amazon-about-a-more-effective-packaging-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Amazon,I am writing on behalf of UN-aligned. An alternative United Nations organization that seeks to put humanity before nationality and planet before greed. We consider topics ranging from the current United Nations, Human Rights, Environment, Economy and Trade. Today I am writing to you in relation to our commitment to the environment. In particular, our members are interested in schemes to limit the need for packaging and on this topic, we reach out to you for answers. Naturally, the scope of this is limitless, but I’d like to address to you some concerns regarding Amazons conscious effort towards sustainable packaging materials in your orders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/unnamed.png" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of accessible tourist visas to balance our perception of Russia</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:45:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/accessible-russian-tourist-visas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2020, Russia announced that it would soon be offering a simplified and cheaper online visa application for tourists from EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were asked to describe Russia, your immediate thoughts may be of snow, bears and vodka. Unsurprisingly, Russia does contain all of those things. Think a little more and you might settle on political tension, corruption and the mafia. Unless you had visited, you probably would not envision the long summers in a cottage surrounded by countryside, LGBT activists, or a local taxi driver cracking jokes in elementary English. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/A-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-Kurdistan-2-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
