<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>India ascends on the world stage, projecting power and prosperity, yet within its borders, the stark reality of disparity and unfulfilled promises persists. What are the steps forward?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Behind-the-Headlines-Indias-Rising-Power-Lingering-Poverty-and-the-Quest-for-Balance-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Glass Ceiling: Women in India are not Behind</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:47:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>unregisteredauthor</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</guid>
      <description>In the late 20th century, women in other parts of the industrialised world had also experienced what is popularly known as the &#39;glass ceiling&#39; phenomenon, which meant that women found they could only rise to a certain level in corporations and no further. This raises two immediate questions. What were the reasons that could have led to such a thought? And, were men keeping women away from the top?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Women-in-India-are-not-Behind.-photo_-Anahita-ahmadi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India’s Citizenship Amendment Bill: a Death Knell for Indian Secularism</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/indias-citizenship-amendment-bill-a-death-knell-for-indian-secularism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2019 the Government of India, led by the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), secccesfully amended a bill to the Citizenship Act of 1955, offering amnesty to non-Muslim illegal immigrants, who arrived in India prior to 2004. These immigrants must be able to prove that they are citizens of one of the three neighbouring countries: Pakistan, Bangladesh or Afghanistan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;half-the-truth-is-often-a-whole-lie&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half the truth is often a whole lie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokespeople of the Indian Government have repeatedly claimed that the new law intends to give sanctuary to people fleeing religious persecution. While this is certainly the case, the dubious decision to exclude Muslim refugees from Myanmar, Sri Lanka, and China; or in fact, the Hindu Tamils from Sri Lanka, raises questions about the Government’s sincerity. The timing of the bill is also not inadvertent; In August, the Assam State, located in the North-East of the country, witnessed two million of its residents left off the Citizen Register; this essentially left thousands of people, suspected of being illegal residents, in temporary camps which are housed in the state&amp;rsquo;s prisons. Modi and his Home Minister, Amit Shah, the mastermind behind the Citizenship Amendment Bill (CAB), have been eroding and attacking the social identity of the Indian Muslim community from as early as 1992 and the CAB was undoubtedly brought forth with an intent to adversely affect the political identities of this community. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/8ac5d214508c4f918d03ff04492a63a0_18.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India on the Brink</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:48:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-enemy-within&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Martin Luther King Jr. visited India in 1959, he paid the homage to the venerable land with these powerful words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To other countries I may go as a tourist, but to India I come as a pilgrim.” Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would Mr. King think differently of India if he were alive today? Probably not. The narrowminded fanaticism that is trying to drag India down is not a new phenomenon. Even if one cannot ignore it, one can always look beyond it. However, the world is not what it was 60 years ago. It is a much more dangerous place. Our efficiency in depleting the earth’s life and resources is only matched by the relentlessness of nature’s means of revenge, such as climate change or the smog that has recently been chocking Delhi.  Moreover, if we should end up fighting for whatever is left, we would be able to do so with much more devastating results. Finally, mass media have altered the way in which we communicate. Just as the Internet, for instance, helps the wise become wiser, it often has the opposite effect with fools, who become easy prey to those who would exploit them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/1529427239324.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
