<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security Council on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/security-council/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security Council on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:59:33 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/security-council/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>World Peace Now Secure: Fugitive War Criminal Assumes UN Peacekeeping Chief Role</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 15:59:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/world-peace-now-secure-fugitive-war-criminal-assumes-un-peacekeeping-chief-role/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the adage goes, “truth is stranger than fiction”. Case in point: Russia, the very nation embroiled in a relentless war in Ukraine, has assumed the presidency of the UN Security Council, an institution dedicated to preserving global peace and security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add to the absurdity, Russia&amp;rsquo;s top dog, Vladimir Putin, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;slapped with an arrest warrant&lt;/a&gt; by the ICC for his role in abducting Ukrainian children. As we try to make sense of this bizarre twist of fate, one can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if this is an elaborate April Fools&amp;rsquo; ruse, leaving Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s UN mission and countless others befuddled and aghast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t the UN expel Russia like the League of Nations did in 1939?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 10:32:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via a video address to the UN security Council on April 5, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky urged the Council to expel Russia “so it cannot block decisions about its own war”, which he emphasised was responsible for “the most terrible war crimes”. Some days ago, on June 28, he went further and called for a complete expulsion, adding that an international tribunal should investigate &amp;ldquo;the actions of Russian occupiers on Ukrainian soil&amp;rdquo; so that the Kremlin could be “brought to justice”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is a death knell for the United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ould you entrust a child you love to the care of a school or nursery if you knew that not only many of its teachers, but the school board itself, consisted of child abusers, rapists and murderers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course not! And yet that is exactly what we are doing when we entrust world peace and human rights to the United Nations. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Nations, in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. By ‘integral’ I am particularly referring to the five permanent members (P5) of the UN Security Council. In fact, most of the world problems since WWII stem directly or indirectly from one or more of these five permanent members. The Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine is just one of the many instances of a crisis that has been caused or exacerbated by one of these powers. I have discussed the flaws of the UN at length in my recent book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/&#34;&gt;Unravelling the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, so I will not dwell on its lack of structural integrity or its monumental failures here. Instead, I wish to focus on the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstaining in the face of war</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-un-security-council-not-prepared-to-put-up-with-moscows-bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UN Security Council not prepared to put up with Moscow’s bullshit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Following weeks of heightened tensions around Ukraine, with reports that Russia has been deploying more than 100,000 troops and heavy weapons close to its border, the United Nations’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/securitycouncil/&#34;&gt;Security Council&lt;/a&gt; held its first meeting to discuss ways of de-escalating the crisis on Monday.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/01/1110912&#34;&gt;United Nations News Page&lt;/a&gt;, 31 January 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For an organisation that was founded primarily to promote world peace, the United Nations is a sad joke. The crisis in Ukraine has been intensifying for weeks and yet the Security Council waited until January 31 to convene in order to have a discussion on the issue and it did so only because it was urged to by the US. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council meeting on Ukraine Review: Abstaining Romance and Plenty of Hot Air</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/unsc-meeting-on-ukraine-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tensions between Russia and Ukraine have been mounting for weeks now and for some reason, everyone expected that this particular Security Council session would narrow the wide divide between Russia and the so-called West. Of course, there’s nothing wrong with being pessimistic, but it is a fool who watches the same episode and expects a different ending. Here are three of the main sides of the argument presented during the Council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on Myanmar</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 29, the UN had a Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on the deteriorating situation in Myanmar. US ambassador and senior advisor for political affairs, Jeffrey DeLaurentis, summarised the dire situation, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Humanitarian aid workers inside Burma are sounding the alarm. As a direct result of the military’s brutality and administrative failures since its coup six months ago, Burma is reeling from a surge in COVID-19 cases. This burgeoning health catastrophe comes at a time when hundreds of thousands of people remain internally displaced by the recent violence, with the World Food Program projecting between 1.5 and 2.8 million additional people in the country could now be at risk of food insecurity.”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are reports of scores of doctors being rounded up and imprisoned because of the medical profession’s reaction to the coup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
