<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurdistan on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/kurdistan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kurdistan on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/kurdistan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 40th day of winter: Kurdistan Celebrates Pir Shaliar - in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The festival of Pir Shalyar is an old traditional ceremony in Kurdistan associated with the pre-Islamic, Zoroastrian times. It is held on the 40th day of winter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pir (also translated as saint), Shaliyar is believed to have cured the daughter of the king of Bukhara; the ceremony intends to mark their marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/&#34;&gt;Uraman Takht&lt;/a&gt;, the city hosting the festival, is located in the eastern part of Marivan, Kurdistan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/IMG_6422-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kulla Ball is a vest that is made of fleece and does not require sewing. This vest dates back several thousand years in the history of Horaman. In Horaman, if a ruler was powerful yet just, the men wore kulla balls without ears (shoulder pads), but if the ruler deviated and did not serve the land and its people, the men wore kulla balls with earmuffs and demanded to overthrow the throne. Photo by Anahita Ahamdi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the recent conflicts in Syria could shape its future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:46:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although people are long used to the erratic twists and turns of Donald Trump, his decision to sell the Kurds down the river by withdrawing American troops from Syria caught everyone by surprise. Whether Trump was right to extricate his forces from Syria remains debatable, but just as there is rarely a good time to start international military interventions, so there is rarely a good time to discontinue them. One would have thought that Libya’s and Iraq’s ongoing atrocities would have made this clear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uraman Takht - a journey to the forgotten lands of Kurdistan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 05:51:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After publishing the August issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/&#34;&gt;The Gordian&lt;/a&gt;, we received the kind message from an UN-aligned member, Anahita, saying the magazine had inspired her to travel to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/MAGAZINE-ISSUE-3VOL.1-3.pdf&#34;&gt;Iranian Kurdistan&lt;/a&gt;. As a thank you we received beautiful pictures from her which we decided to publish as a bonus, showcasing Uraman Takht, a magnificent village in the west of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/iran/&#34;&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uraman Takht is indeed one of the wonders of what Iran has to offer. With a population of less than 3000, this village hosts the kindest and most hard-working people that I have yet seen throughout my journeys. This paradise is located in eastern part of Marivan city of Kurdistan and lies 1450 meters above sea level on the alluring heights of the Zagros mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
