<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World Peace on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/world-peace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in World Peace on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/world-peace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Zionist experiment has failed: it must be abolished</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:29:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-zionist-experiment-has-failed-it-must-be-abolished/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some ideas are not up for debate. They are autopsies. You do not reason with a tumor; you remove it. Zionism, as a political project, is that malignancy, and the state of Israel its grotesque outgrowth. To advocate for a “two-state solution”—a partition of historic Palestine that enshrines an explicitly Jewish ethno-state—is no longer just a failure of imagination. It is moral idiocy: a mumbled incantation over a corpse, serving only to buy the murderers more time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another US Condemns Gaza to Further Genocide </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/another-us-veto-supporting-genocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 22:09:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/another-us-veto-supporting-genocide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Trump and Netanyahu cosy up in Washington again with fresh talks on Gaza, one thing is certain: there is no Israeli atrocity, however diabolical, that the US will not back. Here I pick at Dorothy Shea’s narrative after yet another US veto blocking moves to put an end to the genocide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, Dorothy Shea (acting US Representative at the UN), as you rightly suggest, your 4 June 2025 veto on the resolution to put an end to the carnage in Gaza comes as no surprise. Your country has not only undermined every possible attempt to stop the genocide, vetoing resolution after resolution, but is actively involved in perpetrating it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Trumpian Flirtations with Total Denuclearization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 18:11:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Donald Trump to be taken seriously when openly speaking of denuclearization? The Center for Public Integrity reported in an article from 2020 on the future of warfare that the nuclear weapons industry under Trump&amp;rsquo;s first term flourished to heights not seen since before the end of the Cold War. He effectively catapulted an aggressive nuclear rearming of America at an estimated 1.7 trillion-dollar cost to the American taxpayer. Despite the massive cost, politicians like Republican Senator Deb Fischer argued that the nuclear rearming of America in a multipolar world is to be considered an essential but not sufficient national security imperative, implying the 1.7 trillion-dollar price tag for the nuclear rearming of America is substantively insufficient. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking away from Gaza will not assuage our conscience; only action will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 08:27:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently, amidst the clinking glasses and idle chatter of a social gathering, I ventured to pierce this bubble. I posed a question to my friends, seemingly simple yet laden with the weight of untold suffering, which asked for their thoughts on the current mass slaughter of Palestinians by Israel; an atrocity that enjoys, astonishingly, the tacit approval—if not outright support—of our governments. One friend, embodying the spirit of our age&amp;rsquo;s indifference, confessed to avoiding the subject altogether. The casual dismissal struck me—not for its rarity, but for its brazenness, as if the very act of engagement with such a grave matter was itself a burden too heavy to bear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Imagined Unity’: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:15:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few terms in political science hold as complex a definition as “Nation”. As UN-aligned launches its new volume of The Gordian, exploring Nation Building, it becomes crucial to establish a clear understanding of the term and its multilayered complexities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-nation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a nation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nation is defined as “a group of people who share a history, traditions, culture and, often, language – even if the group does not have a country of its own”, writes National Geographic. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;24 Years of Missed Opportunities&#39;: How the UN Failed to Secure Peace in the DRC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:28:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 7th, 2023, after an extensive visit and tour of the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), senior UN official Jean-Pierre Lacroix spoke to reporters in the country’s capital, Kinshasa. The line of questioning was centered entirely around the UN’s 24-year long peacekeeping mission, known as MONUSCO. His response to these questions was brief, yet it made headlines globally: the peacekeepers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rfi.fr/en/africa/20230609-un-peacekeeping-mission-in-drc-is-to-withdraw-as-quickly-as-possible&#34;&gt;should withdraw&lt;/a&gt; from the conflict-torn country “as quickly as possible”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
