<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gallery on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/categories/gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gallery on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:35:04 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contemporary Pottery From the Heart of Esfahan, Iran - In Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:35:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/iranian-women-transforming-contemporary-pottery/</guid>
      <description>Step into a world where tradition meets innovation in the works of Samira Ghafori and Anahita Ahmadi</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Iranian-Women-Transforming-Contemporary-Pottery-In-Pictures.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fight to Eliminate Jiggers Disease - In Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/the-fight-to-eliminate-jiggers-disease-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/the-fight-to-eliminate-jiggers-disease-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Joe Wain’s collection of photos portray the devastating effects of Jiggers Disease in Kenya.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Children-receive-treatment-for-jiggers-africa-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finland’s troubled history with Russia — A Story in Photos</title>
      <link>/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:36:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/finlands-troubled-history-with-russia-a-photo-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Finland is a young country, but one with a heartbreaking history. In this photo timeline, which consists of 11 events showcasing 80 photos, we’ll guide you through the country’s tragic history with Russia.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/fortification-in-the-Karelian-Isthmus-in-1939..jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where water is a gift: The outskirts of Nairobi in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/IMG_7996-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A female tailor living in her one-roomed house made with corrugated metal sheets. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/IMG_7787-2-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two girls from the Masai tribe. In this tribe, literacy for girls has no value and families consider it  just a waste of money. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/IMG_8019-1024x819.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A family in Gaucho, the suburbs of Nairobi. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/IMG_7890-1024x682.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The containers that are used to carry water were used for storing fertilisers or oil. The water in basins and pumps is often contaminated. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/IMG_8036.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portraits from Tanzania - In Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/portraits-from-tanzania-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 07:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/portraits-from-tanzania-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Anahita Ahmadi&#39;s gallery consisting of portrait of Maasai people in Kenya.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Maasai-woman-Tooth-extraction-7631.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The world stands up to Putin’s bloodthirsty antics — in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/standing-up-to-putin-bloodthirsty-antics/</guid>
      <description>Take a trip around the world with these photos of protestors standing up to Putin’s bloodthirsty antics.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/London-The-world-stands-up-to-Putins-bloodthirsty-antics.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The painful history of Ukraine — A photo timeline</title>
      <link>/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</guid>
      <description>A photo timeline of over 35 images explores 12 painful events from Ukraine&#39;s tragic history, suggesting the country&#39;s past is key to understanding its present fate.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Ukrainian-War-of-Independence-1917-to-1921-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the microscopic world: 10 stunning photos</title>
      <link>/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</guid>
      <description>In this gallery we will introduce you to 10 extraordinary microscopic photos. See if you can guess the object in question before reading the description on the side. Do also let us know if you have any suggestions about other items that look amazing under the microscope.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Gecko-toe-hairs.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in Iran: Inside The 17th Century Iranian-Armenian Monastery of St. Amenaprkich (Vank Church) — In Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/inside-vank-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 06:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/inside-vank-church/</guid>
      <description>Located in Isfahan&#39;s New Jolfa neighbourhood, the Vank Cathedral is a major UNESCO World Heritage site that serves as a historic cultural and religious bridge between the Armenian and Iranian communities.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Kamchatka in pictures: A visual tour of this stunning region&#34;</title>
      <link>/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 04:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>/gallery/a-look-inside-kamchatka-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Famous for its active volcanoes and brown bears, Russia&#39;s remote Kamchatka peninsula offers stunning yet hostile terrain where unprepared tourists are advised to travel with a guide for safety.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/2.-camp-where-Lunar-Rover-was-tested-during-soviet-times.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Travelling around China and India has provided me with memories of fantastic nature and beautiful cities and towns, all of which have their own unique charm and sights. The most memorable moments of visiting new places, however, are the encounters with friendly and warmhearted locals. I still remember, years after, the kind people who stopped to pose for a stranger with a camera. This gallery presents some of the beautiful portraits along the way.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/9-1024x683.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>The 44th session of the World Heritage Committee saw Liverpool stripped of its heritage status due to development concerns, while Venice and the Great Barrier Reef narrowly avoided being added to the list of endangered sites.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/18-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This gallery is the second part of the exhibition of the Torlonia Marbles, the largest collection of classical sculpture still in private ownership and one of the most valuable in the world.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/28-The-penis.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</guid>
      <description>The exhibition of the Torlonia Marbles, the largest collection of classical sculpture still in private ownership and one of the most valuable in the world, closed in Rome on June 29. A selection of 92 of the 620 statues and busts had been on display in the Villa Caffarelli on the Capitoline Hill since October 2020, although until April, the exhibition was subject to sporadic closures owing to the pandemic. The marbles had been on restricted display since the mid-19th century, but were moved into storage for safety reasons during WWII, where they languished until now. Some of the sculptures are now due to be sent on loan to museums around the world; in the meantime, a permanent gallery will be set up for them in Rome by the Italian government in accordance with an agreement that was reached with the Torlonia estate a few years ago. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Torlonia family (Tourlonias) moved to Rome in the mid-18th century from France under the employ of a French abbot and soon found favour with the clergy. Marino (Marin), opened a mercer’s shop specialising in silks and brocades imported from France, while gradually expanding into the banking business. Giovanni, his son, focused on banking and real-estate, becoming the banker of some of the most powerful people of the times, including the Pope and Napoleon Bonaparte, increasing his wealth and family titles in the process. His son, Prince Alessandro Torlonia, built on his father&#39;s interests, including his passion for collecting classical sculptures. The drive for Italian unification that led to the creation of the Monarchy of Italian (1861-1946) had created a liquidity crisis for many noble and wealthy families, who were often forced to sell their art collections in order to keep afloat. The Torlonias were ready at hand to swoop up some of these outstanding collections, such as those belonging to the Cavaceppi and Giustiniani families. Here are some of the highlights of the exhibition.  • See &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Part 2 of this collection.&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/4-Marsyas-Detail.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN Secretaries-General: A Gallery Timeline</title>
      <link>/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Since its foundation in October 1945, nine Secretary-Generals have been appointed by the General Assembly. This gallery presents them in chronological order from the first Acting Secretary General Gladwyn Jebb to the present António Guterres.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/1_Gladwyn_Jebb.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surviving the victory: life in the war-torn Gaza Strip - in Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Both Israel and Hamas claimed victory over the conflict that lasted for two weeks, took the lives of more than 250 people from both sides, wounded thousands and destroyed buildings including residences, schools and hospitals. It is difficult to see the victory in a conflict that has continued for decades and taken its toll on the civilians. This gallery shows the harsh living conditions in the war-torn Gaza Strip.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/8-Gaza.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look into the Iranian Turkmen Sahra - in Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/iranian-turkmen-sahra-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/10-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An immigrant family from Sistan and Baluchestan living in one of the Turkmen villages. Their different culture and religion have prevented them from having friendly relationships with other residents of the village.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/7-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old woman and her grandchildren in beautiful Turkmen dress wear. Even though Turkman in Iran make beautiful rugs and are wonderful artists, they still live in extreme poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/6-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malik Banoo is an artist who enthusiastically invited me to take a picture of a wall rug that she had just finished weaving. Many Turkmen women weave carpets and Kilims, but very few agree to have their pictures taken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/8.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Day protests: A celebration of spring or a day for activism? - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>While its roots lie in ancient spring festivals, the modern May Day is now a global day of action for workers&#39; rights, commemorating the 1886 Haymarket Affair and the international labour movement.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/4-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Church of Putin: Inside The Cathedral of Russian Armed Forces - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>/gallery/the-church-of-putin-inside-the-cathedral-of-russian-armed-forces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces1-502x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has long been a link between Russian banks and the Russian Orthodox Church, so for many it came as no surprise to learn that an extraordinary new cathedral was being built in the outskirts of Moscow costing allegedly 82 Million USD. Photo by Alexia James.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces10-498x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about the mixture of military and religious imagery. Some may consider it distasteful, while other patriots may view it as complimentary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Cathedral-of-Russian-Armed-Forces9.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 40th day of winter: Kurdistan Celebrates Pir Shaliar - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:27:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/kurdistan-celebrates-pir-shaliar/</guid>
      <description>In the Kurdish city of Uraman Takht, the ancient Pir Shalyar festival marks a legendary wedding with roots in pre-Islamic Zoroastrian tradition.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/IMG_6451.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hormoz and its People - in picture</title>
      <link>/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/hormoz-and-its-people-in-picture/</guid>
      <description>With colourful coastal soils and kind, simple and friendly people, Hormoz Island is a stunning blend of culture and natural beauty. Join Anahita Ahmadi for a quick tour of the Island.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/10-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Bukhara: A UNESCO Gem - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/the-noble-bukhara-a-unesco-gem-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 17:32:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/gallery/the-noble-bukhara-a-unesco-gem-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Walking the ancient streets of Bukhara in Uzbekistan is like being sucked into the pages of One Thousand and One Nights: mosques, madrasahs and markets follow you wherever you go, while the smells and ancient hues add to the dreaminess of the place. However, there is no Scheherazade here and you will have to weave your own stories. Years of Soviet rule appears to have left a wedge between Bukhara’s history and its people.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/3.jpeg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathmandu: The Colorful Lands of Nepal - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 15:00:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</guid>
      <description>A journey beyond tourism in Nepal and India reveals how the most genuine smiles and a profound sense of humanity can be found in the most unexpected of places.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/4.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music, Drama, Comedy &amp; Illusion at Sichuan Opera - in Pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:29:32 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/10.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man wearing a red mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise technique behind the skill is a guarded secret, traditionally transmitted from generation to generation among theater families. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/9.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man spitting fire in a Sichuan opera show.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mask changing is often combined with fire spitting. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/8.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chinese man wearing a blue mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mask changing - a miraculous, almost instantaneous change of vividly colourful masks dates back to c. 300 years. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/2.bak_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earning a Living in the Remote Areas of Baluchestan - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 11:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/earning-a-living-in-baluchestan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/10-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of Baluchi women holding a Shisha.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman Knitting ornaments on scarfs. The colorful shisha keeps her company during the long days. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/9-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man selling petrol in middle of a desert.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part of the country there is no gas station. This old man makes a living by selling small quantities of petrol to passing motorcycles and cars. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheep Shearing Amongst the Nomads of Kurdistan - in pictures</title>
      <link>/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 09:36:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>anahitaahmadi</author>
      <guid>/gallery/sheep-shearing-amongst-the-nomads-of-kurdistan/</guid>
      <description>Anahita Ahmadi travelled to distant lands of Kurdistan to observe a small portion of Iranian Nomads’ life. Iranian nomads work extremely hard, but they also lead extraordinary lives with individual and unique dreams. Anahita has provided us with the opportunity to take a short glance at their mysterious lives.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/15.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
