<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Country Profile on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/categories/country-profile/</link><description>Recent content in Country Profile on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/categories/country-profile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Tibet's Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid><description>Despite relentless conquests, the struggle for Tibet’s sovereignty extends beyond the protection of its heritage; it's a fight for the nation's very spirit, enduring as the mountains that embrace it.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/How-Tibets-Peaceful-Nation-Building-Challenges-Chinese-Rule.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Iranian Government: How is it structured?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/the-iranian-government-how-is-it-structured/</guid><description>From the Assembly of Experts to the Guardian Council, learn about the complex process of electing the Supreme Leader of Iran, the commander-in-chief of the Armed Forces and the highest authority in the country.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Islamic-Consultative-Assembly.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Lobbyland: The Story of American Lobbying and Campaign Donations</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:07:15 +0300</pubDate><author>Nick Hautamaki</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</guid><description>What is lobbying and is it bad for our democracy? Here is your guide to lobbying in the United States.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/American-lobbying-and-campaign-donations-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>At last, European Unity Prevails</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 10:28:36 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/at-last-european-unity-prevails/</guid><description>For years Europe has watched iron-man rising worldwide and polarising the advance of authoritarianism. Now, we proved it: we can take action, but only if we want to.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/At-last-European-Unity-Prevails-2-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Vlady Hell: Putin Strikes Again!</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:05:45 +0200</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the August 2020 issue of The Gordian titled Russian Roulette: &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/">Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity&lt;/a> we published an article cheekily called Vlad the Terrible. It listed a range of crimes committed by Putin ranging from mass murder to mass deceit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vlad-the-terrible">&lt;strong>Vlad the Terrible&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You play with fire and you risk getting burned; play with the devil and you end up screwed. Sadly, this is exactly what is happening to Europe and beyond now that the demon is waving his devil’s fork and even threatening nuclear destruction. The good news is not only that we have learned a lesson, but even more remarkably, that we are prepared to suffer the consequences of our mistakes and send this devil to hell!&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/001Putin-The-Preaching-of-the-Antichrist-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Language to Unite, Language to Separate: The Tale of Serbian &amp; Croatian</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:35:41 +0200</pubDate><author>aryan.yekrangi1</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</guid><description>&lt;p>Croatia and Serbia, once brothers united, have experienced many conflicts since the collapse of Yugoslavia in 1991. In fact, conflicts existed even prior to the demolition of Yugoslavia and can even be traced back as a cause for its collapse. Thus, it is worth looking at the role of language in this conflict. More specifically, how the classification of two languages can be utilized as a tool, sometimes even a weapon. We do this by answering the following question: “Are Serbian and Croatian two different languages, or simply two dialects of the same language”?&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Language-to-Unite-Language-to-Separate_-The-Tale-of-Serbian-Croatian--scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="when-federalism-is-not-enough">&lt;strong>When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Yugoslavias-Failed-Social-Contract-Lessons-Worth-Learning-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid><description>The 44th session of the World Heritage Committee saw Liverpool stripped of its heritage status due to development concerns, while Venice and the Great Barrier Reef narrowly avoided being added to the list of endangered sites.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/18-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Surviving against the odds: life in an overlooked Bangladeshi locality</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/life-in-an-overlooked-bangladeshi-locality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 10:55:49 +0300</pubDate><author>MdGolamHabib</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/life-in-an-overlooked-bangladeshi-locality/</guid><description>&lt;p>I live in a southernmost Upazila (administrative district) of Bangladesh called Gabura. Bangladesh is an underdeveloped country and my village is typical of the struggling communities of the delta region. Many people here do not have access to basic education and the village does not even have electricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are three distinct seasons in Bangladesh: a hot, humid summer from March to June; a cool rainy monsoon season from June to October; and a cool dry winter from October to March. Life in Gabura changes dramatically with each season.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/FLOODED20HOUSE_auto_x1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>India on the Brink</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:48:37 +0200</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="the-enemy-within">&lt;strong>The Enemy Within&lt;/strong>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When Martin Luther King Jr. visited India in 1959, he paid the homage to the venerable land with these powerful words:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“To other countries I may go as a tourist, but to India I come as a pilgrim.” Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would Mr. King think differently of India if he were alive today? Probably not. The narrowminded fanaticism that is trying to drag India down is not a new phenomenon. Even if one cannot ignore it, one can always look beyond it. However, the world is not what it was 60 years ago. It is a much more dangerous place. Our efficiency in depleting the earth’s life and resources is only matched by the relentlessness of nature’s means of revenge, such as climate change or the smog that has recently been chocking Delhi.  Moreover, if we should end up fighting for whatever is left, we would be able to do so with much more devastating results. Finally, mass media have altered the way in which we communicate. Just as the Internet, for instance, helps the wise become wiser, it often has the opposite effect with fools, who become easy prey to those who would exploit them. &lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/1529427239324.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>How the recent conflicts in Syria could shape its future</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:46:17 +0200</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/how-the-recent-conflicts-in-syria-could-shape-its-future/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-happened">&lt;strong>What happened?&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although people are long used to the erratic twists and turns of Donald Trump, his decision to sell the Kurds down the river by withdrawing American troops from Syria caught everyone by surprise. Whether Trump was right to extricate his forces from Syria remains debatable, but just as there is rarely a good time to start international military interventions, so there is rarely a good time to discontinue them. One would have thought that Libya’s and Iraq’s ongoing atrocities would have made this clear.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/image1170x530cropped-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>An Assembly that is stuck in time</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:09:40 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/an-assembly-that-is-stuck-in-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year we took it upon ourselves to go through every speech of the United Nations General Assembly and brief you about the most important updates. In doing so, we got to hear some of the most bold and exciting statements from leaders around the world. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe that the President of El Salvador’s speech was courageous, effective and to the point and thus, deserves the prize of the best statement of the debate.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/825277-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Nothing empties the top resorts of Biarritz like a shark attack; or a G7 summit - a guide to what happened at the 2019 summit</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:10:02 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/nothing-empties-the-top-resorts-of-biarritz-like-a-shark-attack-or-a-g7-summit-a-guide-to-what-happened-at-the-2019-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>A number of thorny topics were on the agenda this year. Some of the key issues included: foreign policy, trade and, of course, climate change. Let’s start with the last one shall we?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="climate-change-and-oceans">&lt;strong>Climate change and oceans&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While world leaders gather around the table to endorse a new charter on biodiversity and renew their commitments to the Paris Agreement, the climate-denier-in-chief, Trump, didn’t feel like attending these talks. He’d rather focus on trade, he says. The Metz Charter on Biodiversity attempts to boost efforts to stop biodiversity loss and sustain life on the planet. This is certainly welcomed, but we can, and should, do more in a much faster way.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/G7Biarritz_48616362963-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Uraman Takht - a journey to the forgotten lands of Kurdistan</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 05:51:04 +0300</pubDate><author>anahitaahmadi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/uraman-takht-a-journey-to-the-forgotten-lands-of-kurdistan/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>After publishing the August issue of &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/the-gordian/">The Gordian&lt;/a>, we received the kind message from an UN-aligned member, Anahita, saying the magazine had inspired her to travel to the &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/MAGAZINE-ISSUE-3VOL.1-3.pdf">Iranian Kurdistan&lt;/a>. As a thank you we received beautiful pictures from her which we decided to publish as a bonus, showcasing Uraman Takht, a magnificent village in the west of &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/tag/iran/">Iran&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uraman Takht is indeed one of the wonders of what Iran has to offer. With a population of less than 3000, this village hosts the kindest and most hard-working people that I have yet seen throughout my journeys. This paradise is located in eastern part of Marivan city of Kurdistan and lies 1450 meters above sea level on the alluring heights of the Zagros mountains.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/WhatsApp-Image-2019-08-29-at-18.13.48.jpeg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Reflections on the Sri Lanka bombings</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 08:15:23 +0300</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bloody-motives">Bloody motives!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If an angel came and told me that all the world problems would be solved if I just put a few bombs around killing innocent people in mosques, synagogues, churches, market places or hotels… would I do it? Of course not. Firstly, because I do not even have the right to insult an innocent person, let alone take their life. Secondly, because it would be like asking me to believe that good is founded on evil, or harmony on hatred. Rather obvious, you would say… Then why, oh why, does it keep happening again and again!&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/shutterstock-164109974.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>