<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refugees on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/refugees/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refugees on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/refugees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary Cities: Shattering Myths, Protecting Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Alexander Stoney</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>Salvation of subterfuge? Since 1979, Sanctuary Cities have become the hot political potato — are they migrant safe havens or is there a hidden truth?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/sanctuary-cities.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My internship comes to an end, but my journey continues</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</guid>
      <description>Education in refugee camps has the transformative power to break the chains of poverty and rebuild lives, bringing hope for a better tomorrow.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Syrian-refugee-children-in-a-Lebanese-school-classroom-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Arizona&#39;s Hostile Stance Towards Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Elvira_Ineza</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>Arizona&#39;s hostile immigration policies come at a hidden cost, with human lives lost and contributions to the economy ignored, while political tactics further complicate the issue.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Hidden-Costs-of-Arizonas-Hostile-Stance-Towards-Immigrants.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Elvira_Ineza</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>Personal interviews with Kevin, an immigrant from Rwanda, and a former employee of the International Rescue Committee, uncover the complex realities of immigration in America</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Journey-of-Immigrants-in-America-Experiences-from-Within.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Almoallem Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>An armed attack on our camp shakes our security and frightens us, but what can we do but return to our tents and accept what happened as par of the course?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/A-Day-in-Almoallem-Refugee-Camp-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I entered the university and my heart is leaping with joy!” — An extracts from a refugee’s journal</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:31:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the days of the war in Syria, we lost our safety. We used to sleep to the sound of cannons and wake up to the sound of planes. One day, my mother asked me to go to the pharmacy near our house to buy a fever-reducing medicine for my little brother; while I was on the way back with my little sister, a shell fell in front of us. The people on the street started running to see what happened. We did not stop running until I got home, and we survived. This is one of the most difficult memories that stick in my memory and cannot be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/I-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy-%E2%80%94-An-extracts-from-a-refugees-journal-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education of Syrian Refugees During the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 09:59:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Once again, refugees in Lebanon find themselves vulnerable to discrimination as  thousands of pupils are forced to leave their school seats.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Education-of-Syrian-refugees-during-coronavirus.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a Syrian refugee?</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 09:42:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</guid>
      <description>Arabs say, “Who lives with a people for 40 days has become one of them.” How is it, then, that we have lived here for so many years now and are still living half-lives?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/What-it-means-to-be-Syrian-refugee.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate refugees in the modern world</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 13:28:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Kaitlyn.Rivera</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>By the year 2050, more than 200 million people will become classified as climate refugees. Climate change has accelerated the rates of human migration, and this effect will continue to intensify.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“My religion is myself and my nationality is my heart”: Five days inside a refugee’s diary</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 10:22:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During her internship with UN-aligned, Jihan Al-Assad was asked to write about her life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Her experiences, along with those of other refugees are published in a new series titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/diaries-from-refugee-camps/&#34;&gt;Diaries from Refugee Camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-1122021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1/12/2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a new month and the end of a whole year. This does not feel like the beginning of a month or a day or anything new. I am afraid because I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what is coming to me, and this idea is a big horror for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/My-religion-is-myself-and-my-nationality-is-my-heart-Five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disheartening revelations about the UNHCR in Lebanon — A refugee’s perspective</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 09:53:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>The primary mission of the UNHCR is to provide emergency assistance to those forced to flee their homes, but how is this achieved in the current reality, especially in a Lebanon?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-UNHCR-in-Lebanon-is-not-doing-enough-%E2%80%94-A-refugees-perspective-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>Our silence is pernicious and yet we seem to not care; not when caring can threaten the comfort zones we have become so used to. Here are five points that will shed some light on the issue of migration.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Citizenship-is-a-construct-our-primary-duty-is-to-humankind_-5-problems-solutions-to-the-migrant-problem-2-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Life Without Flowers: A Glimpse Into The Arsal Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I will talk about my place of residence in one of the camps in Lebanon, Arsal, and how I was able to adapt to this difficult life, which does not resemble life at all. It is only days that pass without taste. One of the most difficult days of my life was when I was fifteen years old. My family decided that we should live In a refugee camp. At that time, misfortune and sadness overtook me, and I went into a state of depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Photo-by-Atika-Harba.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>jihan.alassad</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Syrian-Refugees-Heading-for-Another-Tough-Winter.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Pay no heed to the hippie”: Filippo Grandi, UNHCR chief, ignored once again</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/news/pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-filippo-grandi-unhcr-chief-ignored-once-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The globally displaced rose from 79.5 million in 2019 to 82.4 million by the end of 2020, a near 3 million increase. This is as the G7 decides to take no action whatsoever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNHCR says that the number of refugees around the world has hit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unhcr.org/refugee-statistics/&#34;&gt;a new high&lt;/a&gt;, this is in spite of the pandemic, a time in which over 160 countries closed their borders. More than a third of those who fled abroad came from just five countries: Syria (6.7 million); Venezuela (4 million); Afghanistan (2.6 million); South Sudan (2.2 million); Myanmar (1.1 million). Many more are expected to have been displaced within Africa due to conflicts in Mozambique, Ethiopia and the Central Sahel region. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Pay-no-heed-to-the-hippie-UNHCR-chief-Filippo-Grandi-ignored-once-again-scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/7-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wishing to stay above the ground: immigration and survival</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>fared.fared</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/wishing-to-stay-above-the-ground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is by Abdelkander, an UN-aligned member from Algeria who is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned English Language Programme&lt;/a&gt;. He is currently living and working in Turkey.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;immigration-and-survival&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immigration and survival&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Abdelkader, though I am also known as Faysal. I am from Algeria and I am 37-years-old. Like most young people, I want to have a decent life. Of course, I have dreams, but my main dream is simple: I just want an honest job. In my country, however, whether you studied or did not finish your studies, the matter will not be different, because in either case you will not get a job unless you have mediation, or you pay a bribe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/6-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When grandmama fell off the boat… Very nearly taking note of migration</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:50:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A raft full of migrants who are fleeing war and famine are awaiting at the bay. What would &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture this: you have five buttons in front of you. They are all linked to a raft full of migrants trying to get into your country. Many are fleeing war and famine, some may be simply looking for a better life, while a few may be nasty characters out for what they can get. Button 1: Destroy. Button 2: Ignore. Button 3: Repatriate. Button 4: Assist. Which would you press? Buttons one and two are more or less as deadly, while the consequences of button 3 are often not much better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/5-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking at migration in the face</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-has-not-been-a-good-week-for-refugees-but-then-again-it-never-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has not been a good week for refugees; but then again, it never is…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s The Guardian reports how the Lebanese government forced 5,000 refugee families to demolish their own home in order to induce them to return to Syria. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the captain of rescue ship Sea-Watch 3, Carola Rackete, was arrested after she forcefully docked her ship in the Italian island of  Lampedusa. Having rescued 53 migrants drifting off the coast of Libya on June 12, the Sea-Watch 3 was left stranded while the Italian authorities kept refusing to let her dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/f7e8a41211aedeeb17ed5e3bf0576d6d.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonising Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 06:40:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-on-the-weakest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking on the weakest…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people just need a common enemy. Any group that can be easily picked on offers the perfect target. Minorities of every sort are often chosen because of their vulnerability. Bullying them makes weak or bigoted citizens feel superior. Some of these minorities have fought back and with time secured a certain level of safety, and the protection of their human rights. Still, immigrants are often the most threatened, because they are insecure. They do not know the ropes and cannot easily fight back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/tumblr_nrfitz91k61txoxklo1_1280-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
