<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haiti on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/haiti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Haiti on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/haiti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council: Differences over Haiti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many international organisations have warned about the worsening situation in Haiti, but some members of the United Nations were set on keeping the aid package to Haiti strictly humanitarian stating that they would let the Haitians solve their own political issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in the face of the growing threat to peace and security due to gang-related violence, hunger and an infrastructure crisis caused by several natural disasters, as well as the lack of proper medical equipment and personnel in response to the needs of the Haitian population amid several health emergencies such as the cholera outbreak, on October 21, 2022, the UN Security Council unanimously voted to establish a sanctions regime on Haiti to punish the actors responsible or complicit in actions that threaten peace, security, and financial stability in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF and WHO: Alarm over cholera outbreaks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 05:42:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-human-tragedy&#34;&gt;A human tragedy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Victims of the cholera outbreak have now been reported in more than 29 countries including Kenya, Somalia, RDC, Haiti, Syria, and Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On top of numerous issues plaguing Syrians, the outbreak of cholera and the start of winter all chip away at the already thinning resources in the region. It is reported that more than 14.6 million people there need assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF has appealed for $27.5 million to help combat the spread of cholera in Haiti, where roughly 40% of confirmed cases are children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
