<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opportunities on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/categories/opportunities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opportunities on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:33:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/categories/opportunities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Onward and upwards: UN-aligned priorities for 2025</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/campaigns/call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:33:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/campaigns/call-to-action/</guid>
      <description>Following a successful AGM, during which Adrian Liberto was confirmed as Chair and Partho Chatterjee as Vice-Chair, UN-aligned highlights some of the priorities for the remainder of 2025</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Eugene_Delacroix_-_Le_28_Juillet._La_Liberte_guidant_le_peuple.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s 2023 Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:31:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/join-us-at-un-aligneds-2023-annual-general-meeting/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to extend an invitation to all our members for the UN-aligned 2023 Annual General Meeting, scheduled for Thursday, December 14th, 2023.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/UN-aligned-agm-2023.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned Annual General Meeting 2022</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 19:46:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/events/un-aligned-annual-general-meeting-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s 2022 Annual General Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also an opportunity for you to express yourself and play an active role in the major decisions of the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below you will find the agenda and instructions on how to participate in this meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/UN-aligneds-AGM-2022.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a PR Manager</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/pr-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/pr-manager/</guid>
      <description>Do you love writing a good pitch? Would your friends describe you as confident? Want to get involved with UN-aligned and help us with our media work? We think you might be a great fit for our new open position: PR Manager. Apply now!</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/PR-Manager-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a Puzzle Creator</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 11:27:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you enjoy a good puzzle? Would your friends describe you as creative? Want to get involved with UN-aligned but don’t have too much spare time? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think you might be a great fit for our new and unique open position: Puzzle Creator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at UN-aligned spread our message of fairness and equality through many platforms including our Newsletter, monthly publication ‘The Gordian’ and social media. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the United Nations may be in a sorry state, it’s not all doom and gloom and we like to drop in interactive quizzes to The Gordian for our readers. Until now we’ve been using multiple choice quizzes, you can see an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/category/quiz/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Puzzle-Creator-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support The Gordian with a Patreon subscription</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 17:43:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/support-the-gordian-with-a-patreon-subscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is an open, independent publication that is read by hundreds of people around the world. Its main purpose has always been the creation of a platform for discussion and dissemination of knowledge; and with your support, we hope to take our game up a notch and build on this for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we have managed to do without any financial support, however, as the organisation has grown our need for fundraising has become more and more crucial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Donate-to-UN-aligned.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned&#39;s first Annual General Meeting</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 11:19:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/events/un-aligned-first-agm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned’s first AGM was held on Wednesday, November 24th, 2021, at 19:30 - 20:30 (EET) on Google Meet. The proposals included in the agenda of UN-aligned’s AGM, together with this invitation, the NGO’s Financial Statement and the Auditor&amp;rsquo;s Report are all available on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to invite you to UN-aligned’s first Annual General Meeting. The Annual General Meeting is a special occasion for the exchange of information and discussion between UN-aligned members across the world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/UN-aligneds-invites-you-to-its-first-AGM.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Magazine introduces new series about “social issues”</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/the-gordian-magazine-introduces-new-series-about-social-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month marks the last issue of the 4th Volume of the Gordian Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it may not seem like much, to date we have published more than 25 issues of the Gordian, all of which can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;accessed for free&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words cannot express how grateful we are to the generous support of our writers, contributors and, you, our readers. Thank you for using this magazine as a platform to express your ideas for a better and fairer world. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Gordian-Magazine-introduces-new-series-about-Social-Issues.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp; music with our international readers</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 11:17:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</guid>
      <description>As summer holidays begin, we want to hear from our readers about their favorite books, TV shows or music.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Share-your-favourite-books-TV-shows-music-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewed for September! The free UN-aligned writing course</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/events/the-un-aligned-writing-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Join this practical and informative online workshop, which will culminate in a published article in The Gordian.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the space of just five lessons, starting on the first of July, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/adrian-liberto/&#34;&gt;Adrian Liberto&lt;/a&gt;, author, journalist, a former professor at the American University of Rome and current editor-in-chief of the Gordian Magazine, will teach you how to overcome your weaknesses in writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrian will use his vast reserves of experience and enthusiasm to give you an overall assessment of your writing strengths and weaknesses and how to maximise the former and overcome the latter. This is an unmissable opportunity for anyone looking to sharpen their journalistic skills. After the course you will be offered the opportunity to send your piece for publication in the Gordian, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/194953390_2893916164184528_7060861168912488824_n-copy.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is the UN-aligned Person of the Year?</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:50:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is excited to announce a new opportunity for its readers to nominate any individual or organisation whom they believe deserves more attention for championing their cause. Although the prize can go to literally anyone, we encourage you to think twice before nominating dictators, fascists or possibly your grandmother. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we have received the final results, we will shortlist your submitted names. An appointed executive committee, who will consist of UN-aligned staff and editors of the Gordian, will decide on the final winner. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/pexels-gotta-be-worth-it-5214869.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Voluntary Ambassador</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/become-a-voluntary-ambassador/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 14:02:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/become-a-voluntary-ambassador/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All articles in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned manifesto&lt;/a&gt; are important, but it is only natural that we will feel more attached to some rather than to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are particularly passionate about one of the articles in the manifesto, we would like you to consider becoming a voluntary Ambassador for that specific article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task will involve taking the standard and campaigning for that particular issue, with the full force of the organisation behind you. You will be giving guidance on how best to carry out this mission, as well as ongoing support. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/business-indoors-man-2173508.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Voice in UN-aligned and The Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 10:15:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>UN-aligned</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/write-for-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>Do you wish to write and contribute articles, photo essays, analyses, interviews and much more to The Gordian Magazine?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/write-for-UN-aligned-and-the-gordian-magazine.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
