<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eston.mckeague on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/eston.mckeague/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eston.mckeague on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:37:45 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/eston.mckeague/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“With a democratic world federation, humanity can address global problems”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:37:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/with-a-democratic-world-federation-humanity-can-address-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The political movement to unite the world is nearly one hundred years old. Most identify the Campaign for World Government founded in 1937 by Lola Maverick Lloyd and Rosika Schwimmer as the genesis of the movement. Since then the world has transformed in ways unimaginable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, humanity is grappling with a growing pile of existential global challenges. Twentieth-century holdovers like poverty, inequality, human rights abuses, corruption, and the threat of nuclear war are now being complemented with an array of new challenges like the climate crisis, misinformation, and of course — the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation Earth: Why Youth are Necessary for Solving Global Problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;humanity-faces-immense-challenges&#34;&gt;Humanity faces immense challenges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many young people are global. Growing up online has predisposed a generation to a cosmopolitan perspective previously only accessible by the elite. Interacting with a culture different from your own has become a commonplace occurrence online, which has led many to retreat into safe, echo chambers with people of the value system. This retreat is exemplified by private chat groups which at best, provide a welcoming space for a niche community, and at worst, provide a space for terrorists to plan attacks. Yet, if you’ve grown up online, you’ll know that an echo chamber is far less fun than a debate space. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
