<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letters on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letters on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:05:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OHCHR: Take action to ban harmful conversion practices against LGBTQIA&#43;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Michelle Bachelet Jeria, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, a Finland-based NGO whose mission is to create a better and fairer United Nations that promotes ethical principles of human rights, animal welfare, environmental well-being, and world peace. Pertaining to human rights and global justice, I request that the OHCHR address and take action to eliminate harmful conversion practices that promote violence and invalidate the LGBTQIA+ community worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned calls on UNHRC to ban members that criminalise homosexuality</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the United Nations’ Declaration of Human Rights, we, the undersigned firmly believe in “the inherent dignity and the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family”. This is “the foundation of freedom, justice and peace in the world”, whereas “disregard” and “contempt” for these rights “have resulted in barbarous acts which have outraged the conscience of mankind.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst many member states flout human rights on a regular basis, certain states actually enshrine these abuses in law. This is very much the case with LGBT+ rights in as much as almost a third of United Nations’ member States criminalise homosexuality with penalties ranging from death and lengthy prison sentences to beatings and fines. This proportion does not include States that oppress the LGBT+ rights in other ways, such as Hungary and Poland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help safeguard the access of Palestinian children to health services</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/help-safeguard-the-access-of-palestinian-children-to-health-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 11:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/help-safeguard-the-access-of-palestinian-children-to-health-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Palestinian health authorities, during the recent clashes between Israel and Gaza, at least 254 Palestinians including 66 children were killed. This is while more than 1,900 are reported to be wounded. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 30 years, the Palestinian Children’s Relief Fund (PCRF), a nonpolitical humanitarian relief organisation, has provided the children of Gaza with free medical care. However, on the 17th of May, their main Gaza office was arbitrarily targeted by the Israeli military. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters: Help us raise our banner in support of animals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey members and readers! &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need your assistance for our next publication of The Gordian, which will focus on ANIMAL RIGHTS. Please contribute material or ideas to ensure it will be a vibrant and interesting issue. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help us raise our banner in support of animals, who cannot speak for themselves other than with their eyes and screams; “words” most people are immune to. You could write an article, tell a story, write a poem, draw a picture… Anything that could add spice to the issue and bring the message home. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to UN-aligned members: Ask your government to take immediate action against the looming hunger crisis affecting millions of people worldwide</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/ask-your-government-to-take-immediate-action-against-hunger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 11:22:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/ask-your-government-to-take-immediate-action-against-hunger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/how-to-prevent-the-food-crisis-of-2021/&#34;&gt;In a recent publication&lt;/a&gt;, UN-aligned joined the voices of organisations, like Oxfam and the WFP, in warning against a hunger catastrophe already targeting millions of children and adults in the world’s most vulnerable places. The good earth is rich and can provide for everyone and in our world of plenty, no one should have to suffer hunger or malnutrition.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solid frame-work the sustainable development goals provided during the last decade is threatened by an awful melange of disasters, such as Covid-19 and climate change. If no action is taken, many lives will be lost. Some estimates by Oxfam suggest up to 12,000 people could die every day as a result of hunger. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the Arab League &amp; the OIC: Take immediate action to counter discriminatory practices against LGBTQ individuals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:30:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a cofounder of UN-aligned, and representative of the organisation, I am writing to request that, in the name of human rights and international justice, you take immediate action to review your policy at the United Nations of blocking legislation, and other positive moves, to counter violence and discriminatory practices against individuals based on their sexual orientation and gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islam, like most religions, has evolved, and continues to evolve, with time; just as humankind does. Nevertheless, those who do not wish to change have no right to impose their outdated views on others. In the words of Barack Obama: “Religious freedom doesn’t mean you can force others to live by your own beliefs.” As long as a person is not harming anyone else, he or she should not be victimised. This premise is essential if harmony is to flourish on earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Zsuzsanna Jakab: Why is it so difficult for the WHO to take a non-political approach towards Taiwan?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:55:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Dr. Zsuzsanna Jakab, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that laid the foundations for an alternative United Nations, which aims to serve people, before nationstates. Although we regularly campaign for reforms to the United Nations, particularly with regards to its structure and principles, we are also involved with other issues, such as human rights, animal welfare and environmental protection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus pandemic has become the defining global health crisis of our time and the greatest challenge we have faced since the Second World War. Since its emergence last year, the virus has spread to every continent. UN-aligned greatly admires the tireless work of the WHO and its dedication to catalysing global and national responses to this and other serious health crises. However, this pandemic has become more than an unprecedented tragedy. Recently we have received questions from our members about the relevance of the WHO’s principles and its ability to serve everyone, regardless of their country’s membership status in the United Nations. On behalf of our members we would therefore like to ask you the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Ashin Wirathu: Can your monastery do anything now to restore the spirit of fraternity that should reign amongst all the residents of Myanmar?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 11:16:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bhante Ashin Wirathu, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that focusses on the need to replace the United Nations with a more effective and principled organisation, although we also work to promote human and animal rights, as well as the welfare of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Institutionalised religion has had a sad history in a number of countries around the world owing to its bigotry and abuse of power. Many spiritual people, including some of our members, have therefore looked to Buddhism as a beacon of justice and openness. This image has been tainted over the last few years by portrayals of monks leading a crusade against the Rohingya inhabitants of Myanmar. The contradiction here reminds many people of the darkest periods of some of the leading world religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters: The Lives of Three Iranian Protestors are on the Line - Take Action Now</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:57:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/iranian-protesters-to-be-hanged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, a spokesman for Iran&amp;rsquo;s judiciary confirmed the death sentence of three young men who were participants in the nationwide unrest that swept across the country in November 2019. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “November protests” started with anger over the government&amp;rsquo;s decision to increase diesel prices, and soon developed into violent clashes between police and  protestors, with many chanting slogans against the Islamic Republic. Protests also echoed concerns over an increasing assault on individual liberties by the Iranian establishment, massive corruption scandals and a dying economy in which many struggle to make ends meet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Amazon: Feedback &amp; suggestions for a more  effective &amp; environmentally friendly practices</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-amazon-about-a-more-effective-packaging-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 18:45:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-amazon-about-a-more-effective-packaging-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Amazon,I am writing on behalf of UN-aligned. An alternative United Nations organization that seeks to put humanity before nationality and planet before greed. We consider topics ranging from the current United Nations, Human Rights, Environment, Economy and Trade. Today I am writing to you in relation to our commitment to the environment. In particular, our members are interested in schemes to limit the need for packaging and on this topic, we reach out to you for answers. Naturally, the scope of this is limitless, but I’d like to address to you some concerns regarding Amazons conscious effort towards sustainable packaging materials in your orders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
