<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elvira_Ineza on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/elvira_ineza/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Elvira_Ineza on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:25:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/elvira_ineza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Arizona&#39;s Hostile Stance Towards Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state of Arizona has been a hotspot for immigrants for many years. The US state, which shares about 600 km of border with Mexico, has become a popular destination for refugees and migrants who escape their homes searching for a better and safer life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While some advocate for mass deportations of these ‘illegal immigrants’, others argue for faster processing and greater protections for those seeking asylum or other forms of humanitarian assistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey of Immigrants in America: Experiences from Within</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-journey-of-immigrants-in-america-experiences-from-within/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years immigration has been a controversial subject in the US. Some Americans call for harsher policies against immigration, others for a revision of immigration policies to allow for easier processing and more assistance to refugees. All in all, one after the other, governments have tried to revise these policies in hopes of appeasing the American population, but neither has been able to fully address this issue in a manner favourable to all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council: Differences over Haiti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many international organisations have warned about the worsening situation in Haiti, but some members of the United Nations were set on keeping the aid package to Haiti strictly humanitarian stating that they would let the Haitians solve their own political issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in the face of the growing threat to peace and security due to gang-related violence, hunger and an infrastructure crisis caused by several natural disasters, as well as the lack of proper medical equipment and personnel in response to the needs of the Haitian population amid several health emergencies such as the cholera outbreak, on October 21, 2022, the UN Security Council unanimously voted to establish a sanctions regime on Haiti to punish the actors responsible or complicit in actions that threaten peace, security, and financial stability in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia booted out of the UN Human Rights Council. What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to its charter, the UN was created to maintain international peace and security, protect human rights, deliver humanitarian aid, and support sustainable development. Each of these is an honourable goal that is sometimes brought to fruition in parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;193 countries around the globe are members of the United Nations and among those are the P5 (permanent Security Council Members) chosen because of their importance in the aftermath of WWII. Each one of these countries is part of the UN because they claim to believe in what this organisation stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who are the 2022 Nobel Prize Winners?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/who-are-the-2022-nobel-prize-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:elviraineza5@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Nobel Prize is a prestigious international award that recognizes individuals who have made significant contributions to various fields, including physics, chemistry, physiology or medicine, literature, peace, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Established by Swedish inventor Alfred Nobel in 1895, the award is presented annually to individuals who have demonstrated exceptional achievements in their respective fields. The Nobel Prize is considered one of the highest honours that can be awarded, and recipients are often recognized as leaders in their fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF and WHO: Alarm over cholera outbreaks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 05:42:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-human-tragedy&#34;&gt;A human tragedy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Victims of the cholera outbreak have now been reported in more than 29 countries including Kenya, Somalia, RDC, Haiti, Syria, and Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On top of numerous issues plaguing Syrians, the outbreak of cholera and the start of winter all chip away at the already thinning resources in the region. It is reported that more than 14.6 million people there need assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF has appealed for $27.5 million to help combat the spread of cholera in Haiti, where roughly 40% of confirmed cases are children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
