<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/women/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/women/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘No Girl Left Behind’: How Taliban&#39;s Ban on Girls&#39; Education Imperils Afghanistan&#39;s Future</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/education/how-talibans-ban-on-girls-education-imperils-afghanistans-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-historical-context-afghanistans-education-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The historical context: Afghanistan&amp;rsquo;s education system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan is currently the only country in the world where girls are forbidden to go to school. The decision to stop women being able to access school and university by the Taliban in August 2021, has consequently denied millions of girls their fundamental right to education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afghanistan has a complex and turbulent history and this has had undeniable consequences on its education system. The department of education was established in Afghanistan in 1913, with the goal of a national education system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran&#39;s Removal from the Commission on the Status of Women: Change in Membership Standards?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/irans-removal-from-the-commission-on-the-status-of-women-change-in-membership-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/irans-removal-from-the-commission-on-the-status-of-women-change-in-membership-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a decision that is being celebrated as a victory for women’s rights, the UN’s Economic and Social Council has removed Iran from the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW). The country’s tenure, meant to last until 2026, was cut short in response to Iran’s repeated violations against the rights of women, including the violent suppression of protests demanding justice for the death of &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/&#34;&gt;Mahsa Amini&lt;/a&gt;, a young woman who died in police custody last September.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar 2022: A World Cup for Straight Men</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I wrote an article for The Gordian Magazine celebrating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/lifestyle/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/&#34;&gt;growth of women’s football&lt;/a&gt; in the UK, and hailing 2022 as a watershed year in women’s sport around the world. Now, just a few months later, nothing seems further from the truth. In choosing to host one of the world’s biggest sporting competitions in Qatar this year, a country run on Sharia law and plagued by inequalities, FIFA has let the world know that football remains the domain of straight men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Zahhak to the Islamic Republic of Iran: Has Ferdowsi prophesied the future of the republic?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:21:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/zahhak-to-iran-has-ferdowsi-prophesied-the-future-of-the-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zahhak was the evil king of Mesopotamia who conquered Iran and, together with his army and serpents that grew out of his two shoulders, terrorised the people of the land for thousands of years. It all started when in order to congratulate the new king on his new position, the embodiment of evil, known in the Book of Kings as Ahriman, disguises himself as the royal cook and asks to kiss the new king’s shoulders. Zahhak agrees and moments after Ahriman’s lips touch Zahhak’s shoulders two black snakes emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petronilla Paolini: Her tragic life and daring poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Up to now, I have mostly shared my impressions on art intended as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/art&#34;&gt;visual art&lt;/a&gt;, examining paintings or sculptures. I have rarely strayed into technical intricacies when writing about art because when I decide to talk about a topic, I do not follow particular selective criteria, I simply rely on my instinct, on the urgency to share emotions and these are almost always solicited by the great works of art history. This time I felt the same solicitations and emotions that I have just mentioned, and I discovered them in part thanks to a casual &amp;ldquo;encounter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Football: ‘Unsuitable for Women’ or were you just not brave enough to see the vision?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/sports/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:01:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/sports/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that football has a problem with sexism, which is why the Lioness’ (English Women’s football team) victory on Sunday 31st July 2022 at the Women’s European Championship means so much. I am a 23-year-old English woman who grew up playing football, and I had never even thought to dream that I might watch the England Women’s team win whilst 17.4 million people tuned in to watch. Very few did; it simply seemed impossible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Glass Ceiling: Women in India are not Behind</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:47:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glass-ceiling-effect-in-the-west&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Ceiling Effect in the West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th century, women in other parts of the industrialised world had also experienced what is popularly known as the &amp;lsquo;glass ceiling&amp;rsquo; phenomenon, which meant that women found they could only rise to a certain level in corporations and no further. This raises two immediate questions. What were the reasons that could have led to such a thought? And, were men keeping women away from the top?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
