<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adrian.liberto on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/adrian.liberto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adrian.liberto on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:54:35 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/adrian.liberto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Kakistocracy Sanctions Humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/when-kakistocracy-sanctions-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:54:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/when-kakistocracy-sanctions-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday July 9, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio announced the imposition of sanctions by the United States under a Presidential Executive Order targeting Francesca Albanese, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Palestine. Her crime? Speaking the truth about the Gaza genocide and those who profit from it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;United Nations representatives of Human Rights Council lost no time in expressing their objections, but of course in the customary UN watered-down sort of way. Meanwhile, on the same day, Wednesday 10, Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu left Washington after two days of meetings with Trump and more US protection and support for his country’s genocide against Gaza.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The last straw for the genocidaires was Albanese’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ohchr.org/sites/default/files/documents/hrbodies/hrcouncil/sessions-regular/session59/advance-version/a-hrc-59-23-aev.pdf&#34;&gt;Report&lt;/a&gt; published on June 16 that unequivocally exposed their heinous crimes, their accomplices and the heartless greed that motivates them. The Summary sets the scene nicely:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“This report investigates the corporate machinery sustaining Israel’s settler-colonial project of displacement and replacement of the Palestinians in the occupied territory. While political leaders and governments shirk their obligations, far too many corporate entities have profited from Israel’s economy of illegal occupation, apartheid and now, genocide. The complicity exposed by this report is just the tip of the iceberg…”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In this climate of impunity, perhaps the real wonder is that Albanese has not been assassinated yet. She is well aware of the risks and has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vtXeZoezhJE&#34;&gt;compared these intimidation tactics to those used by the Mafia&lt;/a&gt;, but has made it very clear that she will not be silenced. Still, whether they try to assassinate her or not, one thing is certain: if these demons have their way and manage to silence the truth, sooner or later, every honest person will become a target.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another US Condemns Gaza to Further Genocide </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/another-us-veto-supporting-genocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 22:09:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/another-us-veto-supporting-genocide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Trump and Netanyahu cosy up in Washington again with fresh talks on Gaza, one thing is certain: there is no Israeli atrocity, however diabolical, that the US will not back. Here I pick at Dorothy Shea’s narrative after yet another US veto blocking moves to put an end to the genocide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, Dorothy Shea (acting US Representative at the UN), as you rightly suggest, your 4 June 2025 veto on the resolution to put an end to the carnage in Gaza comes as no surprise. Your country has not only undermined every possible attempt to stop the genocide, vetoing resolution after resolution, but is actively involved in perpetrating it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua’s War on the Press: New Report Highlights Escalating Repression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:52:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned recently partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fled.ong/&#34;&gt;FLED Nicaragua&lt;/a&gt; to translate their annual report from Spanish into English, highlighting the grave state of press freedom in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assassination of retired Nicaraguan army officer and outspoken critic of President Daniel Ortega, Roberto Samcam, on June 19 while in exile in Costa Rica, underscores the urgency of the crisis and the critical need to raise international awareness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Press-Freedom-Report-January%E2%80%93March-2025-%E2%80%93-Copy.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read full report -&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confronting a Genocide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/confronting-a-genocide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:28:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/confronting-a-genocide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the “business as usual” attitude of most of the world’s politicians and the people the media like to keep in the spotlight, the genocidaires are hurting. The protests, the immolations, the hunger strikes, the courageous acts of defiance… They are slowly taking their toll. The genocidaires know that even if they managed to kill every single Palestinian living in Gaza and the West Bank, they will always be branded as mass-murderers. And now, on the first day of June, another remarkable challenge: Greta Thunberg and other 11 activists have set sail towards Gaza on the Madleen, a small ship operated the Freedom Flotilla, to dent the siege and raise “international awareness” to the atrocities that are being committed by Israel. Speaking before her departure, the brave activist acknowledged the dangers involved, but equally the more insidious risks of doing nothing: “Because the moment we stop trying is when we lose our humanity. And no matter how dangerous this mission is, it’s not even near as dangerous as the silence of the entire world in the face of the live-streamed genocide.” Activists on board include “Game of Thrones” actor Liam Cunningham and French member of the European Parliament Rima Hassan. They are expected to reach Gaza in about a week’s time. Unsurprisingly, haughty critics soon attacked from their Pro- Zionist ivory towers. Republican senator Lindsey Graham, sneered: “Hope Greta and her friends can swim!”; while Brendan&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call to Action!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/onward-and-upwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 17:05:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/onward-and-upwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Standing by, while destructive, self-serving oligarchs destroy our planet and the international order, is not an option. UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s warnings about the dangers of the United Nations, in particular its dominance by the Five Permanent Members of the Security Council, could have proved prophetic, had the writing not been on the wall from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite some well-functioning aspects of the organisation and some remarkable people, like the Secretary General himself and the Special Rapporteur for Palestine, Francesca Albanese, who is truly outstanding, the structure of the organisation does not allow it to meet the dire challenges the world is facing in these unpresented times. We, “the people”, need to mobilise; make sure our voices are heard; we need to stand up for every citizen of this planet and the planet itself. In order to achieve this more effectively we are looking for dedicated people to join our Board and bring our mission forward according to the urgency the time demands. So, whatever your skills, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:adrian.liberto@un-aligned.org&#34;&gt;adrian.liberto@un-aligned.org&lt;/a&gt; to see how you can take on a leading role in UN-aligned and be at the forefront of our action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onward and upwards: UN-aligned priorities for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:33:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/call-to-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following a successful AGM, during which Adrian Liberto was confirmed as Chair and Partho Chatterjee as Vice-Chair, UN-aligned would like to highlight some of the priorities for the remainder of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our first priority is to bolster our membership board with dedicated members who can propel the organisation forward. The mission remains the same: the creation of a united nations that is fit for purpose, supported by inviolable values, rather than subservience to the self-interest of dominant member-states. This we are now prepared to do in collaboration with those sectors of the current United Nations that are not compromised beyond redemption.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘If it ain’t broke... break it’: How the US betrayed  free speech and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;loving-guns-hating-free-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loving guns, hating free speech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely amazing how the US government bows with such unquestioning fervour and reverence to the Second Amendment, while comfortably sticking its middle finger up to the First.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Second Amendment, ratified in 1791, in the heyday of the Wild West and almost 100 years before the iconic gunfight at the O.K. Corral (1881), stipulates “the right of the people to keep and bear Arms”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of a charade: Israel&#39;s collapse under global condemnation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel is as good as finished. It has lost all credibility as a responsible nation in-the-making. From the onset its creation has depended on abusing superpowers, injustice and crime. It has been those three forces that have kept it enduring and spreading until now, while skilfully dodging every attempt to hold it to account, often by playing the victim. Despite the numerous massacres perpetrated along the way, something very different has happened now that has shaken its very foundations; mortally so: Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To be or not to be European alone: Horizons of EU expansion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/horizons-of-eu-expansion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Europe is a continent; a land mass. Politically, of course, Europe is much more. It is an entity. The history of its various nations interlaces intricately, more so than with other parts of the world, as does its culture. Its aspirations are also different, though many of these overlap with those of people all around the world. The EU encapsulates some of these hopes, such as a desire for peace, security, justice and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>António Guterres Named as the UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/antonio-guterres-announced-as-the-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-antónio-guterres&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why António Guterres?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considering UN-aligned is an organisation whose chief aim is to supplant the United Nations with a workable structure and agenda, António Guterres may seem one of the most unlikely choices for the UN-aligned Person of the Year. Nevertheless, all said and done, he too is striving for a better world order; the difference is that he is doing it from within: a losing battle, perhaps, but one that is not without its relevance and impact. He has proved to be brave and outspoken and unflinching in his support for the issues that matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Council in Deadlock: The UN&#39;s Faltering Quest for Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst the United Nations bats resolutions from one side of the Security Council’s court to another, people are dying in their thousands. This is not the United Nations; this is the Disunited Nations, failing in its primary mission of fostering world peace. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, on October 16, a Russian-sponsored draft text, which had called for an immediate cease-fire, fell through because it did not manage to garner enough votes. Then, on October 18, the US vetoed a Brazilian draft that called for “humanitarian pauses” to allow unhindered humanitarian access. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India has certainly been in the spotlight these last few months and anyone not looking too closely would be justified in thinking that the country was rising, phoenix-like, from its post-colonial ashes to virtual super power status. In April 2023 it overtook China as the most populous nation on Earth with well over 1.4 billion people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 4, Rahul Gandhi, champion of the Congress Party and heir to the Nehru-Gandhi dynasty, had his two-year prison sentence for disparaging comments made against Modi, suspended by India’s supreme court, suggesting a robust democratic rule of law. Also in August (23rd), India’s Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft landed on the lunar surface. This was all the more spectacular coming so soon after Russia’s failed moon mission. Moreover, it was the very first successful landing on the dark side of the moon. Then, in September, with much pomp and circumstance, India hosted the 2023 G20 Summit. Its presidency may not have been a roaring success, but it was a success nonetheless. Though Russia’s President Vladimir Putin and China’s Xi Jinping did not attend, and organisers had to forego the traditional “family” photo owing to disagreements over Ukraine, the overall outcome was positive, with the African Union’s addition to the block being one of this G20’s notable achievements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 22, 2023, Riyad H. Mansour, the Palestinian-American diplomat who has been the Permanent Observer of Palestine to the United Nations since 2005, wrote a letter, his 794th, to the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was triggered by the recent atrocities in Jenin. The letter, addressed to the Secretary-General, the President of the General Assembly and the President of the Security Council, highlighted the crimes committed by Israel against the Palestinian people. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:27:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaac Newton famously said: “If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.” Sadly, society is where it is today because most people have stood on the shoulders of ogres. The past sticks to us like shit on a shoe and we have become so accustomed to the foul smell, that rather than scrape off the dung, we wallow in it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: planet earth in the 21st century, but one that had never witnessed the advent of humankind. Then, suddenly, it is discovered by an alien species much like our own. Before long, the planet is plundered, ravaged and abused. Life forms are enslaved, tortured and killed for entertainment, fashion and culinary delights, their habitats destroyed; forests are cut down; and rivers and seas polluted beyond recognition, as are the skies. Finally, having exhausted every possible resource, the alien species moves on, like a plague of locusts, to its next quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Defining Stories of May 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/the-defining-stories-of-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 09:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/the-defining-stories-of-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-natural-disasters&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Natural Disasters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rwanda and Uganda Encounter Devastating Flash Floods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 130 people have tragically lost their lives in Rwanda due to flash floods and mudslides following torrential rains on May 3rd, 2023. A similar catastrophe struck neighbouring Uganda, where at least six people were reported dead. Climate change continues to wreak havoc across Africa, raising questions about preparedness and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Kivu Province in DR Congo Ravaged by Torrential Rains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 4th, 2023, the South Kivu province of DR Congo was brought to its knees as torrential rains swept away villages and killed hundreds of people. The DR Congo government is grappling with disaster response and reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Infernal Gates: Confronting the Oil Industry&#39;s Greed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:24:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beneath the surface of our greedy economy lies a lurking danger, driven by the relentless greed of giant oil companies. Like the ominous entrance to Dante&amp;rsquo;s Inferno, their self-serving position and inaction threaten to unleash chaos and destruction. However, before shedding light on hidden environmental and ethical transgressions across scattered timelines, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the lethal nature of the oil giants&amp;rsquo; self-serving stance and their culpability for inaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;barring-the-gates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barring the gates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All art aficionados would be familiar with Rodin’s The Thinker, or representations of it, some may have even been lucky enough to see the pensive figure in his intended setting sitting atop of The Gates of Hell. Whatever was he thinking? My guess is that he was contemplating what Sartre put into words decades later: &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;enfer, c&amp;rsquo;est les autres&amp;rdquo; (Hell is other people).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Scenarios of Russia’s Removal from the UN Security Council: A Bleak Future or a Chance for a Fresh Start?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 08:23:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia’s permanent seat on the UN Security Council is under scrutiny like never. What would happen if the UN decided to expel this rogue state from the Security Council? Will it lead to war, polarisation, or perhaps a new beginning for the UN?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About a year ago now, on 7 April 2022, the UN General Assembly adopted a resolution triggering the suspension of Russia from the Human Rights Council. Oh, would it not be lovely if it could also be suspended from its status as a permanent member of the Security Council! But first things first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Wealth Gap: A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Redefining our modern self-serving economics to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reality is what keeps us safe. It informed our past and it guides our present. Reality is our safe zone. It is the anchor on which our boat is secured. It is the devil we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as anyone who has owned a boat can tell you, a tight anchor is the surest way to sink your boat: a change in tide, a swell… and without the leeway in your rope, you are underwater. The fact is, reality changes and unless we adapt and evolve with it, we are done for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Odessa&#39;s Cultural Heritage Threatened by Ongoing Conflict in Ukraine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/odessas-cultural-heritage-threatened-by-ongoing-conflict-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 25, UNESCO inscribed the historical Ukrainian city of Odessa on the World Heritage List and the World Heritage in Danger List. “Odessa, a free city, a world city, a legendary port that has left its mark on cinema, literature and the arts, is thus placed under the reinforced protection of the international community,” said Audrey Azoulay, Director-General of UNESCO. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The people of the port city were delighted as was its mayor, Gennady Trukhanov. He pointed out, however, that the task would not be an easy one:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Like heads in the sand’: United Nations Votes on Israeli Occupation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/like-heads-in-the-sand-united-nations-votes-on-israeli-occupation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/like-heads-in-the-sand-united-nations-votes-on-israeli-occupation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ostriches are said to bury their heads in the sand to avoid facing the facts, politicians bury theirs in the dung of deliberate ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On December 30, the United Nations General Assembly held a vote on whether to submit a request to the International Court of Justice (ICJ) for an advisory opinion on the consequences of the Israeli occupation of the Palestinian territories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Ecc6TPEIckuW0z-5e-BYtexjnhxoaXq7ursfLHGT830UC-MTfpqLrVwUikHznQEh5ih-Afp4q7LRGm3DZIazGqG9rofPXMaTFtHDZxS84rClG-yKBCe8n0tOCUztO87TlLy68GmtqLdSeSVEXJd-zzU&#34; alt=&#34;UNGA votes on the Israel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNGA voted on the Israeli occupation of Palestinian territories. 87 in favour, 26 Against and 53 Abstentions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secret Visits, Insane Politics and Devastating Natural Disasters: February 2023 in One Look</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/february-2023-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/february-2023-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Burkina-Faso-army.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Burkina Faso army&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Burkina Faso army. Photo: Defence Visual Information Distribution Service © Public Domain&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.02.23: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. Suspected Islamist insurgents have killed 16 members of the security service in an ambush in the north of the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09/10.02.23: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 12 civilians were killed by militants on motorbikes in the village of Sanakadougou in the northwest of the country. Many were wounded, while the village itself was burned down. Al-Qaida-linked terrorists have been operating in the area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye United Nations: A Jolly Good Move!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/__trashed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/__trashed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;American award-winning actress, film director, producer, and humanitarian, Angelina Jolie, has decided to quit her role as a Special Envoy to the United Nations refugee agency, the UNHCR, citing a desire to “work differently”. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Jolie has worked with the UNHCR since 2001, and has been a Special Envoy for the organisation since 2012. Her role involved building awareness and support for refugees and highlighting the need for urgent action to be taken in order to tackle issues relating to the serious events that force people to flee their homes, such as conflict and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Subtle Manipulation of News Media in the Age of Pseudo-Enlightenment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-the-sun-wot-won-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the Sun wot won it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The older generation may remember it well. It was 11 April, 1992. Neil Kinnock and his Labour Party were set to win the general election and the best the Conservatives could have hoped for was a hung parliament. Then, however, The Sun, one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s right wing tabloid newspapers owned by Australian-American media mogul Rupert Murdoch, launched an aggressive campaign to swing things around&amp;hellip; and sure enough it did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of an Era: December 2022 in One Look</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/december-2022-in-one-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/december-2022-in-one-look/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Cyril-Ramaphosa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cyril Ramaphosa&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyril Ramaphosa. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/governmentza/&#34;&gt;GovernmentZA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13.12.22: &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt;. Scandal-engulfed President Cyril Ramaphosa, who is being investigated for serious violations and misconduct, survived a vote in parliament which could have set in motion impeachment proceedings that could have forced him out of office.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18.12.22: &lt;strong&gt;Tunisia&lt;/strong&gt;. The electorate has given President Kais Saied a clear message by boycotting yesterday’s elections, with less than 9% turning up to vote. The President had suspended parliament on March 30, 2022 and revised the constitution in the hope that he could cling to power, a prospect that has now become more unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obituary: Ayten Aydın</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/obituary/obituary-ayten-aydin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/obituary/obituary-ayten-aydin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ayten was born in Turkey and started her career in Istanbul where she had graduated as a civil engineer in 1951. She worked as a hydraulic engineer, mainly with the State Hydraulic Works, improving the infrastructure relating to land and water development throughout the country. In 1966 she joined the United Nations and worked at the Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) in Rome on global projects relating to urban development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Key Points to Consider for Effective Law Enforcement and Justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/10-key-points-to-consider-for-effective-law-enforcement-and-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few issues of The Gordian, we have covered various aspects of justice, from the definition of justice itself to specific instances regarding the assaults it is often subject to. In order to understand justice from a legal perspective, however, it is important to bear in mind the various aspects that are involved in law enforcement. Here are some important points to bear in mind:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ensuring ethical, global, flexible and measured definitions of criminal acts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madness in Israel, coup attempt in Sao Tome and Principe and earthquake in Indonesia: November 2022 in one look</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/november-2022-in-one-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/november-2022-in-one-look/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.11.22: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. After little more than a week of negotiations in South Africa, the parties in the conflict in the northern region of Tigray have agreed to cease hostilities permanently and work towards lasting peace and orderly disarmament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.11.22: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 22 people died when a minibus plunged into a canal in Cairo-Mansoura Road. Eight people were also injured in the accident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Trovoada-announces-the-successful-thwarting-of-a-coup-attempt-at-a-press-conference-on-November-25th..jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Patrice Trovoada&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Patrice Trovoada announces the successful thwarting of a coup attempt at a press conference on November 25th. © Creative Commons&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make War Redundant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/how-to-make-war-redundant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When I see all my kingsmen, Krishna, who have come here on this field of battle, life goes from my limbs and they sink, and my mouth is sear and dry; a trembling overcomes my body, and my hair shudders in horror. My great bow, Gandiva, falls from my hands and the skin of my flesh is burning; I am no longer able to stand, because my mind is whirling and wondering. And I see forebodings of evil, Krishna. I cannot foresee any glory if I kill my own kinsmen in the sacrifice of battle. Because I have no wish for victory, Krishna, nor for kingdom, nor for its pleasures. How can we want a kingdom, Govinda, or its pleasures or even life, when those for whom we want a kingdom and its pleasures, and the joys of life are here in this field of battle, giving up their wealth and their life?” (Translation by Juan Mascaró)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here are what your leaders had to say at the UN General Debate 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/here-are-what-you-leaders-had-to-say-at-the-un-general-debate-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/here-are-what-you-leaders-had-to-say-at-the-un-general-debate-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summaries and transcripts are available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gadebate.un.org/en&#34;&gt;General Debate pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10_Antonio_Guterres@0.5x-edited.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;antónio-guterres-un-secretary-general&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;António Guterres, UN Secretary-General:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have a duty to act. And yet we are gridlocked in colossal global dysfunction. The international community is not ready or willing to tackle the big dramatic challenges of our age. These crises threaten the very future of humanity and the fate of our planet. Crises like the war in Ukraine and the multiplication of conflicts around the globe. Crises like the climate emergency and biodiversity loss&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women in power, nasty hurricanes and religious zealots — Monthly recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/september-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;AFRICA  &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.09.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. The supreme court has upheld William Ruto’s victory in the presidential elections. The results had been challenged by long-time opposition leader Raila Odinga, who has now agreed to accept the court’s ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.09.22: &lt;strong&gt;Uganda&lt;/strong&gt;. The government has paid of $65m to the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) as the first instalment of the $325m Uganda was ordered to pay by the ICJ as compensation for its occupation of eastern areas of the DRC and for supporting other armed groups during the 1998-2003 conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th July, the Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. That’s no big deal, one would imagine, but sadly, for the United Nations, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is why a few months ago UN-aligned launched a campaign to bar countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from the Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the fact that our open letter to the United Nations was backed by several organisations and human rights activists, the letter was ignored.&lt;a href=&#34;https://documents-dds-ny.un.org/doc/UNDOC/GEN/G22/407/77/PDF/G2240777.pdf?OpenElement&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ukraine Recovery Conference: When Guterres (almost) told Russia to piss off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/the-ukraine-recovery-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres addressed the Ukraine Recovery Conference, which was held in Lugano Switzerland, on the 4th and 5th of July.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The event was attended by over 40 nations and nearly 20 international organisations who approved the Outcome Declaration, vowing support for Ukraine. It is estimated that the recovery plan is already worth $750 billion. The UN chief spoke boldly via a video link:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Russia’s war in Ukraine has taken thousands of lives and forcibly displaced millions of people. Millions of Ukrainians have lost their livelihoods and 90% risk of falling into poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WHO warns of pathogenic outbreaks  threatening Africa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The WHO reported that zoonotic outbreaks on the African continent increased by 63% from 2012 to 2022 compared to the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global situation was also alarming with pathogens found in animals responsible for more than 60% of human infectious diseases, and more than 75% of emerging infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The WHO noted that these diseases sicken about one billion people every year, while killing millions of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Monkeypox, which was declared a Public Health Emergency of International Concern by the WHO Director-General on July 23, and other diseases whose names clearly indicate their animal origins, many like Aids and Ebola, do not; so for many people these diseases are just a natural hazard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Mexico suing the United Nations?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mexico has finally lost its patience with the United Nations and on August 22, President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador announced that he would be filing a formal complaint with the organisation regarding its failure to honour its commitment to supply the country with 10 million COVID-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The frustration only increased as the week went on, even as the World Health Organisation offered to ship over some of the owed vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s barbaric and repulsive: Let&#39;s Axe the Death Penalty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/its-barbaric-and-repulsive-lets-axe-the-death-penalty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the death penalty involves legally killing an alleged criminal. “Alleged”, not only because the person may not have committed the crime in the first place, but equally because the crime may have been labelled as such only due to the distorted perspective of the lawmakers. At times, this perspective is biassed in favour of jealousy, bigotry, the acquisition of wealth and power; or the neutralising of a rival or critic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isreal kills like it&#39;s no one&#39;s business and Asia becomes a new playground for super bullies - August 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/august-2022-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/august-2022-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Polling-station-in-Nairobi-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Polling station in Nairobi following Kenyan elections.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Polling station in Nairobi. Photo: Joewain Production&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15.08.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. Deputy President William Ruto has been declared the winner of the presidential election, narrowly defeating his rival, incumbent Raila Odinga. The announcement, which was only endorsed by three of seven members of the electoral commission, was delayed as violent scenes erupted in Parliament. Odinga has yet to concede defeat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Al-Shabaab-fighters.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An Al Shabaab fighter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN human rights report on Belarus is worrying, but there is precious little the UN can do</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-human-rights-report-on-belarus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 12:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-human-rights-report-on-belarus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;She said that the situation has been deteriorating steadily since the UN OHCHR condemned the violent crackdowns against mass protests challenging the presidential elections held in August 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapporteur also highlighted that the constitutional referendum held on February 27, which endorsed further oppression, was neither free nor fair.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sinister reforms included the extension of the death penalty to “planning” or “attempting” to commit what the State can arbitrarily define as terrorist acts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Curtain: Does the EU Stand on the Side of Justice?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/does-the-eu-stand-on-the-side-of-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many criticisms have been levied at the EU, a fair amount, as we shall see, may be justified, but most are part of that process that developing organisations with such a mighty mandate have to go through. All said and done, the benefits far outweigh the drawbacks, as Britain’s ever-increasing list of post-Brexit crises, on the one hand, and the eagerness of neighbouring nations to join, on the other, makes evidently clear. There is, however, one flaw that unless remedied as a priority, will risk making the Union a gentlemen’s club, whose head is very much up its own backside. Rude language, but the reality is far ruder. I am referring to the EU’s callous exclusivity, which I will refer to as its Golden Curtain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t the UN expel Russia like the League of Nations did in 1939?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 10:32:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-doesnt-the-un-expel-russia-like-the-league-of-nations-did-in-1939/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via a video address to the UN security Council on April 5, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky urged the Council to expel Russia “so it cannot block decisions about its own war”, which he emphasised was responsible for “the most terrible war crimes”. Some days ago, on June 28, he went further and called for a complete expulsion, adding that an international tribunal should investigate &amp;ldquo;the actions of Russian occupiers on Ukrainian soil&amp;rdquo; so that the Kremlin could be “brought to justice”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America going bananas, new dinosaur and an independent Scotland: June 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 07:41:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;06.06.22**: Nigeria**. Over 50 people, including many children, were gunned down in a catholic church in Ondo State. So far, no group has claimed responsibility for the brutal attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/new-abelisaurid-dinosaur-Egypt-1024x409.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A size comparison of five family members of the abelisaurids.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.06.22: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. A study published today in the journal Royal Society Open Science confirmed the discovery of a new abelisaurid dinosaur that lived more than 98 million years ago in the Bahariya Oasis depression of Egypt’s Western Desert. Studies on the fossil of the yet unnamed dinosaur took several years since its discovery in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Curse of Babel: The Drawbacks of Language for Communication and Thought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 10:54:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biblical story of the Tower of Babel portrays God rather like the trickster Loki, more intent on mischief, than promoting harmony. Surveying the city and the tower that the descendants of Noah had started to build in order to achieve a level of security and prestige, God says: “If as one people, all sharing a common language they have begun to do this, then nothing they plan to do will be beyond them. Come, let’s go down and confuse their language so they won’t be able to understand each other.&amp;quot; (Genesis 11: 6-7) The final touch was scattering the people all over the world. (Genesis 11:8)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appeasement: Forfeiting somebody else’s justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:11:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/appeasement-forfeiting-somebody-elses-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although this may come across as helping, it is in actual fact the exact opposite of that because it perpetuates a mechanism of exploitation. The bully may tire of beating the same person for no tangible results, but they will never stop preying on them when their threats reap handsome rewards. Sometimes, therefore, peace negotiators are more of a problem than a solution. This is big-boy politics that treats smaller nations like pawns that can and often are compromised for the bigger picture, which is the status quo for the power brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHO? Yes, Tedros Again!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 12:01:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 24, 2022, Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus was re-elected by the World Health Assembly to a second term as WHO Director-General. His renewed mandate officially starts on August 16. Dr Tedros’s experience includes field-level practice as a malariologist as well as political roles in Ethiopia, his country of origin, which included stints as Minister of Health and Minister of Foreign Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This affiliation with a repressive regime that has been accused of torture, repression, and electoral fraud did not prove problematic enough to jeopardise his first election, which owed much to the support of China. It has even been suggested that Dr Tedros’s appointment of Zimbabwean President Mugabe as Goodwill Ambassador may have been done at the behest of China, although the gushing words that accompanied the nomination appear to have been his own, despite the well-known human rights abuses Mugabe was notorious for. Unsurprisingly, Mugabe’s tenure as Goodwill Ambassador for the agency did not last more than a few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Bachelet&#39;s visit to China: &#34;Unacceptable&#34; is a missing word from the UN&#39;s arsenal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 11:46:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 28, Michelle Bachelet, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, ended a six-day official visit to China. The trip was controversial from the start as critics claimed it would gloss over Beijing’s human rights abuses. On May 29, the UN issued a press release aimed at addressing some of these concerns, particularly with regards to the crackdown on political freedoms in Hong Kong, the governance of Tibet and the treatment of the Uyghurs in Xinjiang.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Musk, new Nato members and the most expensive 20th-century art: May 2022 Recap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:52:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-may-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;Africa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;Western Sahara&lt;/strong&gt;. About 44 migrants trying to reach the Canary Islands have drowned off the coast of Moroccan-occupied Western Sahara after their boat capsized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10.05.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. An overnight raid on a camp for displaced persons in the Ituri Province has left at least 14 people dead, including women and children. The attack follows a similar raid on a nearby mining site on Sunday that killed about 35 people. The CODECO militia is blamed for the brutal attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rehauling Lady Justice: Is the United Nations guilty in Ukraine?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:51:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/is-the-united-nations-guilty-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As long as international justice is left in the hands of nation states at the UN nothing will ever improve because self-interest will always win the day. This needs to change. Meet the new lady justice!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lady-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady Justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why representations of Lady Justice depict her in a blindfold? The accepted explanation is that the blindfold symbolises impartiality. Lady Justice is supposed to be oblivious to power, status, wealth or any other privilege. She also sports scales, which represent fairness through the weighing up of the facts, and a sword, which represents swift and thorough retribution. Although the scales date back to her earliest manifestations as the Egyptian goddess Maat, the blindfold probably originated with Hans Gieng’s 1543 Gerechtigkeitsbrunnen (Fountain of Justice) in the Old City of Bern. Despite the accepted wisdom, however, one cannot help comparing the blindfold to that of “blind” Fortune, whose largess is purely random. How else can there be so much injustice in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutterres&#39; visit to Ukraine: Another blow to the UN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/gutterres-visit-to-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/gutterres-visit-to-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 28 April, UN Secretary-General António Guterres visited Kiev directly after an official visit to Moscow. His tour included sites of suspected war crimes in Ukraine, namely the suburbs of Borodianka, Bucha and Irpin. Guterres did not hide his horror and indignation, nor did he mince his words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“When we see this horrendous site, it makes me feel how important it is [to have] a thorough investigation and accountability... I appeal to the Russian Federation to accept to cooperate with the International Criminal Court.”  &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, Guterres had been criticised for visiting Moscow before Kyiv, but in retrospect it became clear that his frank assessment would have been harder to voice if it were to be followed by a meeting with Putin. Of course, this did not stop Putin from blasting the Secretary-General anyway: not figuratively, but literally by bombing Kyiv during the high-profile visit. The message was loud and clear and President Zelensky summed it up nicely:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in April 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-april-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-april-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. As the United Nations confirmed hundreds of civilian deaths owing to the jihadist insurgency, the government announced that the army had killed 203 militants and arrested about 50 others in the Sahel region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. The Abuja-Kaduna train has been overrun by gunmen who have killed at least eight people and taken scores hostage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.04.22: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. About 90 people drowned over the weekend when their boat capsized as they were trying to migrate to Europe in hazardous conditions. &lt;strong&gt;18.04.22&lt;/strong&gt;: Another boat carrying migrants has capsized resulting in at least another 35 deaths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pissing in the sacred brook: humanity’s abuse of water</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Water, water, every where, And all the boards did shrink; Water, water, every where, Nor any drop to drink.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from &lt;em&gt;The Rime of the Ancient Mariner&lt;/em&gt;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/&#34;&gt;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;/a&gt; describes part of the curse inflicted on the mariner and his crew for his having shot the albatross whose noble presence had been bestowing a blessing to their voyage. In many ways, most of our leaders are like that mariner, killing Mother Earth who guarantees our wellbeing: only that these leaders have been doing it more slowly. We are polluting the air, the land and the waters, and even though we can see the curse materialising before our very eyes, we carry on, regardless. Today I will focus on Water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Putin: “You are a serial killer, but there is one thing I must thank you for…”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/letter-to-putin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Putin,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not mean to be rude by not gracing your name with a salutation or title; quite the contrary; if I had done so, only obscenities would have been appropriate under the circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The situation I am referring to is, of course, your ever-increasing list of crimes: yours, plus the many your soldiers are sanctioned to carry out in your name, such as murdering innocent men, women and children, rape and pillaging. “Kill one man, and you are a murderer. Kill millions of men, and you are a conqueror. Kill them all, and you are a god.”  I see that a god is what you are aspiring to become; a sinister god of the underworld, no doubt, but don’t delude yourself! Jean Rostand was referring to the perception in the minds of fools. You are no god. You are just a serial killer, a rapist, a bully and a thief. You will join the ranks of other sadists, who like you, abused their power to bring death and destruction into the world. However, in some ways you are worse than they are. They operated in darker times, when Truth was still struggling to climb out of her well. You have not got the luxury of mitigating circumstances. Truth is easily accessible now. The fanaticism of the past had been shown up for what it is, but you embrace it and with cynical irony you justify your onslaught on Ukraine as a Nazi-clensing operation, when in fact, it is your evil that is the closest thing to Nazism the world has known since Hitler’s demise. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education’s Paradigm Shift: “Another Brick in the Wall!”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 12:05:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/educations-paradigm-shift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a child, one gets fed a lot of crap from one’s elders. Fortunately, not all of it is swallowed. “You’ll see! As you grow older, you’ll look back at your school days and you’ll remember them as the best days of your life!” Whether the many grownups who preached this believed it or not (it may have been true for some of them), I wonder how they could have possibly thought that these words could have been considered reassuring in any way. It is like telling a prisoner in a torture chamber: “You think this is bad, wait until they put you on the rack!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t be NATO, it should be the United Nations: The Poetry of Appeasement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-the-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We the people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the list of governments I hate grows longer by the day, I cannot help but wonder about all the people who elected them into power in the first place. True, sometimes the system is rigged against the people, either because of the iron grip of despotic regimes or through a flawed system that only provides an illusion of choice. What Julius Nyerere said about America, applies to many democracies: “The United States is also a one-party state but, with typical American extravagance, they have two of them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in March 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-march-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 07:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-march-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Dozens of soldiers have been killed and many have been wounded when jihadists attacked a military camp in the centre of the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;: Over 60 volunteer vigilantes in the northwestern Kebbi State who were planning a raid on bandits operating in the area were killed by gunmen after their plans were leaked to the gang.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13.03.22: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. About 13 gendarmes have been killed in an ambush in Taparko, a mining town that is often targeted by jihadists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is a death knell for the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-united-nations-death-knell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;ould you entrust a child you love to the care of a school or nursery if you knew that not only many of its teachers, but the school board itself, consisted of child abusers, rapists and murderers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course not! And yet that is exactly what we are doing when we entrust world peace and human rights to the United Nations. The enemy is not only within the walls of the United Nations, in most cases, the enemy constitutes an integral part of the organisation itself. By ‘integral’ I am particularly referring to the five permanent members (P5) of the UN Security Council. In fact, most of the world problems since WWII stem directly or indirectly from one or more of these five permanent members. The Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine is just one of the many instances of a crisis that has been caused or exacerbated by one of these powers. I have discussed the flaws of the UN at length in my recent book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/&#34;&gt;Unravelling the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;, so I will not dwell on its lack of structural integrity or its monumental failures here. Instead, I wish to focus on the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vlady Hell: Putin Strikes Again!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:05:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the August 2020 issue of The Gordian titled Russian Roulette: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity&lt;/a&gt; we published an article cheekily called Vlad the Terrible. It listed a range of crimes committed by Putin ranging from mass murder to mass deceit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vlad-the-terrible&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vlad the Terrible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You play with fire and you risk getting burned; play with the devil and you end up screwed. Sadly, this is exactly what is happening to Europe and beyond now that the demon is waving his devil’s fork and even threatening nuclear destruction. The good news is not only that we have learned a lesson, but even more remarkably, that we are prepared to suffer the consequences of our mistakes and send this devil to hell!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in February 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:29:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/monthly-recap-feb-2022-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;Guinea-Bissau&lt;/strong&gt;. President Umaro Sissoco Embalo survived a coup attempt that went on for five hours. Several people died during the assault, which the president blames on elements involved in corruption and drug trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.02.22: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 60 people have been confirmed dead, including 15 children, after an attack on a camp for displaced people in the eastern province of Ituri. CODECO, a militia that was originally a peaceful agricultural cooperative, is thought to be responsible for the attack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeking Behind the Fig Leaf: Our Journey to Sexual Liberation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/our-journey-to-sexual-liberation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Society is a raft made from the wreckage of our dreams and fears. Space is limited and we struggle to keep aboard, scrambling for the middle ground so we do not have to witness those sacrificed at the rim: pushed, or slipping, or just unable to grab a hold. Smug, we pretend that they are not there or that they are so out of reach that we are quite exonerated from any obligation to assist them from their demise. Some would rather swim. Others choose to drown. Reality, as we perceive it, as we live it, is a fragile thing, so we cling on to the raft despite its many flaws. We ignore them. We justify them. We acknowledge and accept them. Often, religions sanction them. And so we paddle on, tossed by abysmal waves, never quite certain where we are heading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstaining in the face of war</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/abstaining-in-unsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-un-security-council-not-prepared-to-put-up-with-moscows-bullshit&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UN Security Council not prepared to put up with Moscow’s bullshit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Following weeks of heightened tensions around Ukraine, with reports that Russia has been deploying more than 100,000 troops and heavy weapons close to its border, the United Nations’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/securitycouncil/&#34;&gt;Security Council&lt;/a&gt; held its first meeting to discuss ways of de-escalating the crisis on Monday.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/01/1110912&#34;&gt;United Nations News Page&lt;/a&gt;, 31 January 2022&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For an organisation that was founded primarily to promote world peace, the United Nations is a sad joke. The crisis in Ukraine has been intensifying for weeks and yet the Security Council waited until January 31 to convene in order to have a discussion on the issue and it did so only because it was urged to by the US. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2022: What you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/february-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/february-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;Sudan&lt;/strong&gt;.  Prime Minister Abdalla Hamdok has resigned in the wake of continuing street protests. Despite having been restored to his position after the military coup in October last year, the move did little to restore confidence in the new military regime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;Kenya&lt;/strong&gt;. Ground-breaking palaeontologist, conservationist and politician Richard Leakey, who unearthed evidence suggesting humankind evolved in Africa, died aged of 77.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.22: &lt;strong&gt;South Africa&lt;/strong&gt;. A fire has been raging through the parliament building and has already destroyed the chamber of the National Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship is a construct, our primary duty is to humankind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/5-problems-and-solutions-to-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migrant-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The migrant problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied their history will know that migrations are what shaped the world as we know it today, both politically and ethnically. At times these migrations were peaceful. Often, they were predatory. At times they were gradual, spreading like an oil stain; often, they were sudden and quite alien, like a frenzied splash from a Jackson Pollock paintbrush. At times the end result was growth and a fusion of cultures; often, it was genocide. So we built walls of brick and paper to keep the undesirables out. Most of us belonged to those undesirables once, but that was a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domenico Lucano declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 15:04:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/domenico-lucano-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned has chosen Domenico Lucano as its Person of the Year 2021. The ex-mayor of the Italian town of Riace has been chosen for his vision regarding the integration of refugees into their destination of choice, while at the same time revitalising a dying town.  Riace became a showcase of prosperity and integration and was hailed in 2016 by Fortune magazine as one of the world’s 50 greatest leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 30th September 2021, Lucano was sentenced to 13 years in prison for abetting illegal migration. His “crimes” included awarding waste collection contracts to companies that were set up to help migrants look for work and arranging a marriage of convenience to help a Nigerian woman escape prostitution and find legal work. The accusation that he enriched himself in the process, seems contrived, considering he does not even have the funds to pay for his legal fees. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s everything you may have missed in December 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-december-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 10:44:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/heres-everything-you-may-have-missed-in-december-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. Ugandan troops have joined government forces in the DRC in order to coordinate attacks on the Allied Democratic Forces, an extremist group responsible for the slaughter of civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Jihadist militants open fire on a bus transporting civilians, including women and children, killing over 30 passengers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.12.21: &lt;strong&gt;The Gambia&lt;/strong&gt;. President Adama Barrow has won a second term with a comfortable margin of 53 percent; opponents, however, are disputing the results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cherry picking justice: 9 rings of moral tunnel vision</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 13:50:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nine-rings-of-moral-tunnel-vision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deluded people generally believe that they would have been on the right side of history, without ever really questioning whether they are on the right side of what is making history. Sure, now, most people are convinced that they would have been against slavery, child labour, the burning of heretics and cannibalism&amp;hellip; but given their same mindset, would they have been?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All those practices were legal or socially acceptable; and sadly, for most of us, that social acceptability is what defines our morals. Only activists, innovators, rebels and the like push those boundaries, often at a crushing personal cost, until one fine day, after they may have been dead, buried and forgotten for many years, the lazy majority mindlessly enjoys and takes for granted those hard-won rights. The problem is not only the perpetrators of injustice. As Einstein rightly pointed out:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed in November 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-november-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-in-november-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria.&lt;/strong&gt; A 21-story building collapsed in Lagos killing dozens of people. The exact toll will take several days to ascertain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;06.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Sierra Leone&lt;/strong&gt;. About a 100 people have died and many have been injured after an oil tanker exploded following a collision in the capital, Freetown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.11.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 26 kindergarten school children have been killed when their straw-hut classroom caught fire in the southern Maradi region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yugoslavia’s Failed Social Contract: Lessons Worth Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 13:16:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/yugoslavias-failed-social-contract-lessons-worth-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-federalism-is-not-enough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When federalism is not enough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (SFR Yugoslavia, or simply Yugoslavia) fell apart in the early 1990s, its ruins bred unimaginable chaos and destruction. Even though the founding of the federation dated back to anti-Fascist resistance following the occupation of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia by the Axis powers in 1941, the Kingdom itself had been a precursor to the entity since the end of WWI. In the light of this common history and the predominantly Slavic ancestry, the bloodbath that followed, which dragged on for a decade (1991-2001), seems all the more outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in October 2021 You May Have Missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 11:06:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/news-in-october-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/news/october-the-gordian-monthly-recap/&#34;&gt;Listen to Ruby Goldenberg and Ariana Yekrangi help you catch up with everything that happened in October 2021.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. At least six refugees were shot dead by Libyan guards as they tried to leave a detention centre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15.10.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. In what had been described as a &amp;ldquo;first institutional return of its kind&amp;rdquo;, Jesus College, Cambridge, has agreed to return one of the Benin bronzes that had been looted from the area during colonial times. The National Commission for Museums and Monuments will receive a bronze cockerel later this year. France has also agreed to return many of the looted bronzes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned calls on UNHRC to ban members that criminalise homosexuality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the United Nations’ Declaration of Human Rights, we, the undersigned firmly believe in “the inherent dignity and the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family”. This is “the foundation of freedom, justice and peace in the world”, whereas “disregard” and “contempt” for these rights “have resulted in barbarous acts which have outraged the conscience of mankind.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst many member states flout human rights on a regular basis, certain states actually enshrine these abuses in law. This is very much the case with LGBT+ rights in as much as almost a third of United Nations’ member States criminalise homosexuality with penalties ranging from death and lengthy prison sentences to beatings and fines. This proportion does not include States that oppress the LGBT+ rights in other ways, such as Hungary and Poland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it was illegal for me to be alive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster&amp;hellip; it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us&amp;hellip; Then, out of the blue, or through a slow and inevitable twist of events, it does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;There is too much stupidity around&#34;: The UN&#39;s Climate Change Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sixth Assessment Report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change was published on August 9, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/&#34;&gt;The Report&lt;/a&gt; paints a grim picture of the planet’s health owing to human induced climate change and rising temperatures. These seem set to rise above the 1.5° threshold, which will signal a critical point of no return for those most exposed to the catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the report, UN Secretary-General António Guterres did not mince his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in August 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-august-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-august-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;. Egyptian actress Dalal Abdel Aziz died aged 61 as a result of having contracted COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Algeria&lt;/strong&gt;. Wildfires in the north of the country have already claimed 65 lives and are continuing to threaten further death and destruction as firefighters struggle to bring them under control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16.08.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Suspected Islamists on motorbikes killed 37 people including 14 children. This year alone, Islamist groups have killed at least 420 civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/security-council-arria-formula-meeting-on-myanmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 29, the UN had a Security Council Arria-Formula meeting on the deteriorating situation in Myanmar. US ambassador and senior advisor for political affairs, Jeffrey DeLaurentis, summarised the dire situation, stating:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;“Humanitarian aid workers inside Burma are sounding the alarm. As a direct result of the military’s brutality and administrative failures since its coup six months ago, Burma is reeling from a surge in COVID-19 cases. This burgeoning health catastrophe comes at a time when hundreds of thousands of people remain internally displaced by the recent violence, with the World Food Program projecting between 1.5 and 2.8 million additional people in the country could now be at risk of food insecurity.”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are reports of scores of doctors being rounded up and imprisoned because of the medical profession’s reaction to the coup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Not Trust The United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-the-devil-you-know&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations: the devil you know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met someone from a peculiar land with a completely messed up political system yielding a society that was plagued with poverty, oppression, corruption and strife. I commiserated until I found out that there actually was an alternative party that, given the chance, would put things right, yet nobody seemed to care about it. “Hey! What’s wrong with you people?” I asked my new acquaintance, pointing this out. “Many do not know; many do not care&amp;hellip;” “And what about you?”  I petitioned. “Ah, better the devil you know!” They replied smugly, as a demon dragged them to hell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in July 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-july-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-july-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.07.21: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 10 people were killed in a terrorist raid on the city of Beni in the east of the country. Islamists are thought to be behind the attack, though as yet no group has claimed responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.07.21: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. Shortly after the government announced a unilateral ceasefire, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs announced that more than 400,000 have “crossed the threshold into famine in the Tigray region. Unless urgent action is taken to address the problems, the situation is likely to continue to deteriorate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new UN-peacekeeping budget: pun intended!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-peacekeeping-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-peacekeeping-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of June, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://undocs.org/en/A/C.5/75/25&#34;&gt;budget for peacekeeping operations for the period from 1 July 2021 to 30 June 2022&lt;/a&gt; was approved by the United Nations. Eye-watering sums have been allocated in order to maintain buffers between hostilities that have been stewing for decades. This is not what peacekeeping should be about. Peacekeeping ought to be a temporary measure while every effort is put into resolving a conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, what is happening is that resources are being pumped into keeping the symptoms under control rather than removing the cause of the problem. As long as the wound is festering and the patient is alive, the doctor’s job is secured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alone against the world: The US betrays the UN on Cuba</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/alone-against-the-world-the-us-betrays-the-un-on-cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:01:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/alone-against-the-world-the-us-betrays-the-un-on-cuba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the 29 years in a row, the UN General Assembly voted overwhelmingly in favour of a resolution demanding the end of the 60-year embargo on Cuba imposed by the US. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US and Israel were the only countries opposed to the June 30 resolution: 184 voted in support of it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cuban Foreign Minister Bruno Rodríguez Parrilla did not mince his words lambasting the US for human rights violations:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>António Guterres: The Power Under The Throne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/antonio-guterres-the-power-under-the-throne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 13:21:14 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/antonio-guterres-the-power-under-the-throne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The feeling I experience when plunging into the ocean of communiques from the United Nations is always the same: drowning in an alphabet soup. Often, the words are noble, the causes honourable. Occasionally they even make a difference. Report after report; document after document; resolution after resolution&amp;hellip; and yet the members of this mighty club behave like undisciplined children who delight in doing just as they please. The world of politics rolls on like a combined harvester devoid of breaks, macerating anyone unfortunate enough to get in its way. They only serve to create one grim statistic after another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN&#39;s slow pace of justice &amp; UNESCO&#39;s decision on Venice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/uns-slow-pace-of-justice-unesco-making-a-decision-on-venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/uns-slow-pace-of-justice-unesco-making-a-decision-on-venice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-slow-pace-of-justice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slow pace of justice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN judges have still not quite finished with the aftermath of the atrocities relating to the breakup of the former Yugoslavia almost 30 years ago. On June 30, they convicted former head of Serbia’s State Security Service, Jovica Stanisic, and his subordinate Franko “Frenki” Simatovic to 12 years in prison. The two men, now in their seventies, were initially acquitted in 2013, after having entered into court custody ten years earlier, but a retrial was ordered in 2015. If UN justice were any slower, it would probably have to be a post mortem affair involving psychopomps and psychostasis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in June 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-june-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-june-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. The African Union has suspended Mali from the African Union over its second coup in nine months.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Burkina Faso&lt;/strong&gt;. At least 160 villagers were slaughtered in a brutal onslaught that ended with the village being set on fire. Islamic militants are the likely perpetrators of the attack, though no group has as yet claimed responsibility for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12.06.21: &lt;strong&gt;Nigeria&lt;/strong&gt;. Another senseless killing spree has left 53 people dead in the north of the country.  The assailants hunted people down as they fled for their lives in a number of villages in northwest Nigeria’s Zamfara state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:57:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/11-Goat-1024x787.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caprone: this goat from the Giustiniani collection highlights the care that went into the restoration of these ancient sculptures. The body dates from the 1st century CE, but the head is attributed to Gian Lorenzo Bernini (1598-1680).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/12-Athena-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Athena Giustiniani (Greek marble with Italian marble additions: c. 140-160 CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/13-Ptolemy-757x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ptolemy (Pentelic marble: c. 120-140 CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/14-Germanicus-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Germanicus (Bronze: 1st century CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/15-Artemis-693x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artemis Ephesia: this statue from the Giustiniani collection was restored using black marble (2nd century CE).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Torlonia Marbles - in Pictures (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-torlonia-marbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-Seated-Philosopher--768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This sculpture of a seated philosopher formally belonged to the Cesarini collection and is known as the Cesarini Chrysippus (Greek marble: 1st Century CE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2-Apollo-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apollo holding the skin of the satyr Marsyas after having skinned him alive. One of the more popular versions of the story relates how Marsyas had challenged the god to a musical contest that was to be judged by the Muses. The winner would have had the right to do as he pleased with the loser and when Apollo won (in some versions via a ruse) he chose to flay Marsyas for having dared challenge a god. The statue from the Giustiniani collection may have been very different in its original form and was restored extensively and with much imagination. (1st century CE)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres publishes report about the lack of progress of UNSC Resolution 2334</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 23, the Secretary General, António Guterres, published a report on the progress (or rather lack of it) of Security Council &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/webcast/pdfs/SRES2334-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;Resolution 2334&lt;/a&gt; (2016) which “reaffirmed that the establishment by Israel of settlements in the Palestinian territory occupied since 1967, including East Jerusalem, had no legal validity and constituted a flagrant violation under international law and a major obstacle to the achievement of the two-State solution and a just, lasting and comprehensive peace.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eradicate colonialism by 2030? Unlikely.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 21st of June the United Nations General Assembly started publishing a number of draft resolutions calling on the colonial powers to relinquish their control on the few remaining colonies. The UN states that its target is to eradicate colonialism by 2030. To date, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/dppa/decolonization/en/nsgt&#34;&gt;17 non-self-governing territories&lt;/a&gt; remain. Of these, fifteen are governed by permanent members of the Security Council:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 by the UK,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 by the US and;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 by France.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list does not include occupied territories, such as Palestine, the Chagos Archipelago and Crimea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France halts its joint military operations in Mali as the G7 pledge 870 million doses of vaccine to the world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/france-halts-joint-military-operations-in-mali-as-the-g7-pledge-870-million-doses-of-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 10:57:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/france-halts-joint-military-operations-in-mali-as-the-g7-pledge-870-million-doses-of-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlike-france-the-un-must-not-suspend-its-peacekeeping-operations-in-mali&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlike France, the UN must not suspend its peacekeeping operations&lt;/strong&gt; in Mali&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following Mali’s latest coup on May 24, France decided to stop joint military operations with Malian forces until it is convinced that a civilian government will be returning to power. Some may argue that the UN should also take a step back and suspend its peacekeeping operations rather than indirectly aid a regime that usurped power. This would be a mistake and fortunately one the UN is not prepared to make. After Colonel Assimi Goïta’s first coup of 18 August 2020, the UN spokesperson, Stéphane Dujarric stressed that the mission “must and will continue” and the situation is just as dire now as it was then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mladic revisited: An unremarkable news item, were it not for the absurdity of the process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:04:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/mladic-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ratko Mladic, the former Bosnian Serb commander largely responsible for the Srebrenica Massacre in 1995 lost his appeal with the special UN tribunal set up to judge the case. He had been convicted on ten counts including genocide and crimes against humanity. This is an unremarkable news item really, were it not for the absurdity of the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuremberg_trials&#34;&gt;Nuremberg Trial&lt;/a&gt; (20 November 1945 - 1 October 1946) took less than a year to try 24 of the most prominent Nazis after World War II. Imagine if that trial had dragged on for as long: it would have been lingering on until the 1970’s. True, despite having been charged in July 1996, Mladic was not apprehended and extradited to the Hague for trial by the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) until May 2011. Still, most of the ICTY’s cases had been dealt with by then. Nevertheless, the trial formally began a whole year later and he was not convicted until 22 November 2017, after which, the appeals process, that has only now been completed, was referred to the successor body, International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to achieve a robust legal system? Solutions towards comprehensive global justice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/towards-comprehensive-global-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; in last month’s issue of The Gordian, I highlighted some of the weaknesses of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and the International Criminal Court (ICC). Whilst these bodies are merely a part of a wider international legal system that is also governed by various treaties, conventions and accords, they are pivotal in as much as their focus is on safeguarding human life and world peace. My conclusion was that these two institutions were flawed, compromised and generally ineffective. In this issue, therefore, I intend to offer some concrete ideas for a robust legal system. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paralysed, Betrayed &amp; Battled: UN in Focus - May 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/paralysed-betrayed-battled-un-in-focus-may-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 09:34:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/paralysed-betrayed-battled-un-in-focus-may-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;battling-for-universally-affordable-and-available-vaccines&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battling for universally affordable and available vaccines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights released a &lt;a href=&#34;https://undocs.org/en/E/C.12/2021/1&#34;&gt;Statement&lt;/a&gt; on May 11 calling for COVID-19 vaccines to be universally affordable and accessible. The five-page document covered all the main issues comprehensively and with refreshing lucidity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Statement starts by highlighting the fact that everyone has the right “to enjoy the benefits of scientific progress and its applications” and proceeded to lament “the current unhealthy race among States for COVID-19 vaccines, which has created a sort of temporary monopoly by some developed States of the first vaccines to be produced.” This is underscored by the fact that current production capacity is at its limit in as much as stocks are already sold out through public procurement by such States. This has created an unacceptable situation of “health isolationism”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between the ICJ and the ICC?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-La-giustizia-di-chi.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Justice is not a relative term, but for much of our history we have manipulated it to such an extent that we have created a parallel sort of justice. More often than not, human justice is just a sinister doppelgänger of justice in its purest form. This is because human justice depends on laws, and as we all know, laws are biased. The justice of the Inquisition, a sharia court or the sham courts of dictatorial regimes are based on very different laws and therefore profess their own unique brands of justice. The one main thing that they do have in common, though, is that they are self-serving. Being tried by a self-serving court is not justice, but rather, quite the opposite, namely, injustice or anti-justice. However, laws are not the only factor influencing justice, as the mechanisms that are in place to apply these laws also play a crucial part in the administration of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in May 2021 you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-may-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 09:19:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-may-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Italiano_-Notizie-Aprile-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.04.21: &lt;strong&gt;Sudan&lt;/strong&gt;. An armed attack by militias in El Geneina, the capital of West Darfur State left at least 18 people dead and 54 others injured according to the Sudanese Doctors&amp;rsquo; Committee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.04.08: &lt;strong&gt;DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. The United Nation has raised the alarm stating that the country is heading towards a famine with up to 27 million people, a third of the population, likely to experience acute hunger. The situation is exacerbated by ongoing conflicts and the rising COVID-19 cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding and Fiscal Responsibility of the United Nations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 09:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/funding-and-fiscal-responsibility-of-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Unravelling-United-Nations-Argead-style/dp/B08T7J1QX4/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1612176186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;UN-aligned’s new publication&lt;/a&gt; that highlights the shortcomings of the United Nations with details that cover its foundation, structure and monumental failures. You may be surprised at the murky facts that this book will bring to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thorough critique of the UN finances would therefore involve a massive amount of time and investigation, which exceeds the remit of this work. Nevertheless, even without specific details regarding UN spending, some of its weaknesses in this regard have been manifestly exposed from within the organisation. The two main criticisms concern the manifold overlaps in UN operations and the inflated salaries of UN personnel. These issues go hand in hand and can be summed up in one word: bureaucracy. They give rise to an unnecessary multiplying of well-paid personnel and a replication of resources, which means that while employees and their administrative needs receive the lion’s share of the allocated funds, identified problems are left with the crumbs. Of course, decision-making is also impaired, which in turn affects efficiency in general. Speaking at a UN Reform Event in September 2017, Secretary General António Guterres summed up the situation without mincing his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Doughnut Economy: &#34;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 10:40:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yesterday, upon the stair,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I met a man who wasn&amp;rsquo;t there!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t there again today,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh how I wish he&amp;rsquo;d go away!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from Hughes Mearns’ poem, &lt;em&gt;Antigonish&lt;/em&gt;, could so easily allude to sanctions. They are full of sound and fury, and yet, they signify nothing concrete, but rather an absence of something. Of course, sometimes, a lack of something can have devastating effects: if you stop my air supply, for instance, I am dead. Sanctions, however, are very limited in what they can stop, because what comes from outside one’s borders was not there in the first place, like the man upon the stair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is The United Nations General Assembly?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-the-united-nations-general-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:28:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-the-united-nations-general-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is an extract from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Unravelling-United-Nations-Argead-style/dp/B08T7J1QX4/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1612176186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;UN-aligned’s new publication&lt;/a&gt; that highlights the shortcomings of the United Nations with details that cover its foundation, structure and monumental failures. You may be surprised at the murky facts that this book will bring to your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly is the community of UN members in their representative role. It is subordinate to the Security Council and it was stipulated that it could only engage in resolving issues that were not already being dealt with by the Security Council (Article 12.1). It is the duty of the Secretary General, “with the consent of the Security Council”, to keep the Assembly informed of matters that are being tackled by the Council, so that the latter’s deliberations are not infringed upon. (Article 12.2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in February 2021 You May Have Missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-february-2021-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 08:50:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-february-2021-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-notizie-nel-febbraio-2021-che-potresti-esserti-perso.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.02.21: &lt;strong&gt;Somalia.&lt;/strong&gt; Al-Shabab militants stormed the Afrik Hotel in the capital Mogadishu and started shooting at guests. At least nine people were killed including a former military general and four of the assailants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.02.21: &lt;strong&gt;Libya&lt;/strong&gt;. UN-brokered peace talks held in Geneva have led to the formation of an interim unity government that will put an end to rival administrations. The government will work towards holding free elections in December. The country has been in turmoil since NATO-backed forces killed leader Muammar Gaddafi in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photographer Anwar Sadat: “If you listen, people are always willing to talk”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 16:28:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/a-conversation-with-photographer-anwar-sadat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 15th of February 2021, the 2020 UN-aligned photo competition winner, Anwar Sadat, tells us about the story behind his prize-winning photos and his love for photography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-22Se-ascolti-le-persone-sono-sempre-disponibili-a-parlare22-Una-conversazione-con-il-fotografo-Anwar-Sadat.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;could-you-tell-us-a-bit-about-yourself-and-your-love-for-photography&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Could you tell us a bit about yourself and your love for photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, my name is Anwar Sadat and I am a photographer based in Nairobi Kenya. My focus in photography is documentary, photojournalism, street reportage and portraiture. I often tell stories of the buzzing streets of Nairobi and my community that often go unseen and unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religion that unites...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/religion-that-unites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 09:59:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/religion-that-unites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Le-religioni-che-uniscono.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People with bigotted or selfish agendas have always tried to hijack religion, but there have always been spiritual adherents who have understood that kindness is paramount and they have highlighted the essence that unites us rather than the dross that divides us. Here are some inspirational quotes from a range of religious thinkers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanskrit-hymn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanskrit Hymn&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As different streams having their sources in different places all mingle their waters in the sea, so, Oh Lord, the different paths which men take through different tendencies, various though they appear, crooked or straight, all lead to Thee.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;No, it&#39;s not just a snip&#34;: Why Circumcision is Legalised Child Abuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:56:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mutilating the sexual organs of a child (circumcision) in the name of culture, religion or dubious preventative medical claims is outrageous and a blatant breach of the child’s human rights. Female genital mutilation is thankfully on the decline and relatively rare in developed countries. The cutting of little boys, however, is not. Approximately one third of males are circumcised worldwide. In this article I intend to highlight the futility and barbarity of the practice. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lingering Sins of Religion: When books weigh us down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 08:35:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-lingering-sins-of-religion-when-books-weigh-us-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;written-in-stone&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written in stone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of religions in the world today and many thousands more have come and gone. Many of these claim or have claimed a monopoly on truth relating to the divine and the moral, as well as to the rituals necessary to accompany a devout life. No doubt, much good has come from these religions in as much as they have contributed to unifying people around a set of values that have generally been beneficial to society and wellbeing. Often, they coalesce around scriptures that are professed to have been inspired or dictated by heaven itself. The Abrahamic religions, Judaism, Christianity and Islam are very much of this mould. There is only one problem: societies change, but books do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed January 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:02:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Italian_-What-you-may-have-missed-in-Jan-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Niger&lt;/strong&gt;. Scores of villagers were slaughtered by suspected Islamist terrorists in coordinated attacks on two villages near the border with Mali.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. Incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadera was declared the winner of the presidential election that was held last month against a backdrop of unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05/06.01.21: &lt;strong&gt;DRC Congo&lt;/strong&gt;. A ferryboat carrying over 70 people capsized on Lake Kivu. About 50 people were rescued and the bodies a woman and two children found. Twenty or so people are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iranian lawyer declared as UN-aligned Person of the Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/nasrin-sotoudeh-declared-as-un-aligned-person-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nasrin Sotoudeh is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nasrin_Sotoudeh&#34;&gt;Iranian human rights lawyer&lt;/a&gt; who has been in and out of prison since 2010 for no other reason than defending men, women and children who suffered under the oppressive Iranian regime. Her clients included opposition politicians, journalists, abused women and children, women who were arrested for not wearing the hijab and prisoners on death row for crimes they allegedly committed when they were minors. On several occasions she went on extended hunger strikes to protest against the severity of the prison regime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annus Horribilis? Looking on the brighter side of 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:25:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/annus-horribilis-looking-on-the-brighter-side-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2020 has certainly been an Annus Horribilis, with plagues, floods, fires, terrorist attacks and wars, but it wasn’t all bad&amp;hellip; In the sciences for instance, vaccines to fight the coronavirus were created in record time. In business, SpaceX ferried astronauts to the International Space Station in the first commercial flight of its kind. Here are some of the success stories from 2020 with regards to human rights and animal welfare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed December 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-december-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Africa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;03.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/strong&gt;. The top court rejected former President François Bozizé’s bid to run for president in the December 27 election against incumbent President Faustin-Archange Touadéra. The former president failed to meet the ethical standards required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;09.12.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ghana&lt;/strong&gt;. Results of the presidential election held on Monday have confirmed a narrow victory for incumbent President Nana Akufo-Addo. His main rival was ex-President John Mahama. Supporters of both candidates took to the streets following delays in the announcement of the results and at least five people were killed in the unrest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Boy who Produces Golden Eggs – an interview with the 11 year old Andrea Piccinelli</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Il-ragazzo-che-produce-uova-doro.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Italian version of this interview can be read here.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;La versione originale italiana di questa intervista può essere letta qui.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview with UN-aligned coordinator, Adrian Liberto, the 11 year old &lt;strong&gt;Andrea Piccinelli&lt;/strong&gt; shares his story about how he developed a love and friendship with his chickens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, some are literally golden in as much as they have a golden hue, but they are all golden in the sense that they are entirely cruelty free. Andrea Piccinelli lives in Magliano de Marsi, a small town in the Abruzzi, Italy, at the foot of the Monte Velino. His passion is looking after his chickens. His love for the animals and his determination are so strong that you would think that these traits must be in his genes. Maybe they are, a distant relative was a Franciscan Friar Pamfilo of Magliano, famous for compassion and for his part in founding &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sbu.edu/&#34;&gt;St. Bonaventure University&lt;/a&gt; in New York. What is certain, is that this young lad has come up with his own exit strategy for intensive chicken farming. His enterprise is also a wakeup call. What will the future be for all these farm animals we have enthralled for millennia? This is something that without doubt requires considerably more thought, especially now that intensive farming may be meeting its nemesis thanks to growing public awareness into the unethical practices of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letters: Help us raise our banner in support of animals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey members and readers! &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need your assistance for our next publication of The Gordian, which will focus on ANIMAL RIGHTS. Please contribute material or ideas to ensure it will be a vibrant and interesting issue. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help us raise our banner in support of animals, who cannot speak for themselves other than with their eyes and screams; “words” most people are immune to. You could write an article, tell a story, write a poem, draw a picture… Anything that could add spice to the issue and bring the message home. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Bukhara: A UNESCO Gem - in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-noble-bukhara-a-unesco-gem-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 17:32:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/the-noble-bukhara-a-unesco-gem-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Bukhara8-1024x768.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Toki Zargaron Trading Domes were a major hub of the Great Silk Road. They were described by Khafizi Tanysh, a 16th century chronicler, as the largest of all existing arcades in Bukhara. Photographer: Adrian Liberto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Bukhara7-767x1024.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intricate walls of the Magoki Attori Mosque. Photographer: Adrian Liberto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Bukhara6-1024x938.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amazing portal of the Nadir Divan Begi Khanaka. The building was originally built as a caravanserai, however, the imam officiating the opening ceremony unexpectedly called it a madrasah, so the portal, side towers, loggias, and students quarters had to be added on. Photographer: Adrian Liberto&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on the Ashin Wirathu Campaign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-the-afshin-wirathu-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 07:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/update-on-the-afshin-wirathu-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 27 July 2020, UN-aligned sent a &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/&#34;&gt;letter to the Burmese Buddhist monk Ashin Wirathu&lt;/a&gt; asking him, amongst other things, how he could reconcile his hostility to the Rohingya with his Buddhist creed. The letter was sent registered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three months later, the letter is still sitting in a post office in Myanmar and the status of the letter is described as “in transit.” The address was of course correct; in fact, the monastery he resides in is the well-known and accessible New Masoyein Monastery in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;. So why on earth is the letter still stuck in Nowhere Land?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons why the 2020 Nobel Peace Prize was misplaced</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-2020-nobel-peace-prize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 09:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-2020-nobel-peace-prize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 9 October 2020, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wfp.org/&#34;&gt;World Food Programme&lt;/a&gt; (WFP) was awarded the prestigious Nobel Peace Prize by the Norwegian Nobel Committee: “for its efforts to combat hunger, for its contribution to bettering conditions for peace in conflict-affected areas and for acting as a driving force in efforts to prevent the use of hunger as a weapon of war and conflict.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No doubt this was a safe political move since even leaders who are hostile to the United Nations, of which the WFP is a branch, cannot feel affronted by such a selection. In dangerous times, however, a safe move is often a cowardly one and, in this case, it certainly feels like one. Here are five reasons why choosing the WFP was a bad decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News in October 2020 you may have missed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-october-2020-you-may-have-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 17:52:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/news-in-october-2020-you-may-have-missed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;europe&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Europe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;UK&lt;/strong&gt;. The EU has set in motion legal proceedings against the UK after it reneged on sections of its Brexit “divorce” deal. Talks, however, are set to continue. The UK was given until November to respond to EU concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;07.10.20: &lt;strong&gt;Greece&lt;/strong&gt;: The neofascist party Golden Dawn was declared a criminal organization for its role in a series of attacks on migrants and left-wing activists. &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; called it the “biggest trial of fascists since Nuremberg.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the Arab League &amp; the OIC: Take immediate action to counter discriminatory practices against LGBTQ individuals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:30:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a cofounder of UN-aligned, and representative of the organisation, I am writing to request that, in the name of human rights and international justice, you take immediate action to review your policy at the United Nations of blocking legislation, and other positive moves, to counter violence and discriminatory practices against individuals based on their sexual orientation and gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islam, like most religions, has evolved, and continues to evolve, with time; just as humankind does. Nevertheless, those who do not wish to change have no right to impose their outdated views on others. In the words of Barack Obama: “Religious freedom doesn’t mean you can force others to live by your own beliefs.” As long as a person is not harming anyone else, he or she should not be victimised. This premise is essential if harmony is to flourish on earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Wedlock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:26:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-slow-pace-of-same-sex-marriage&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slow pace of same-sex marriage…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same-sex marriage is now legal in almost thirty countries in the world. Considering same-sex unions date back over 12,000 years and that there are almost 200 countries in the world, this is not much of an achievement. In recent times, the first country to legalise same-sex marriage was the Netherlands. That law was passed in December 2000 and came into effect in April 1, 2001. So, even in the last few decades, progress has been slow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When grandmama fell off the boat… Very nearly taking note of migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:50:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/when-grandmama-fell-off-the-boat-very-nearly-taking-note-of-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A raft full of migrants who are fleeing war and famine are awaiting at the bay. What would &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; do?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: you have five buttons in front of you. They are all linked to a raft full of migrants trying to get into your country. Many are fleeing war and famine, some may be simply looking for a better life, while a few may be nasty characters out for what they can get. Button 1: Destroy. Button 2: Ignore. Button 3: Repatriate. Button 4: Assist. Which would you press? Buttons one and two are more or less as deadly, while the consequences of button 3 are often not much better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you may have missed: August 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 17:00:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-august-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;02.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Cameroon&lt;/strong&gt;. In a vicious grenade attack targeting a camp for displaced people, as they slept, suspected Boko Haram militants murdered over 16 people and wounded several others in the village of Nguetchewe, northern Cameroon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;04.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Tanzania&lt;/strong&gt;. Tundu Lissu, an opposition politician who survived being shot 16 times in an assassination attempt, will challenge President Magufuli in the October elections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.08.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mauritius&lt;/strong&gt;. A state of emergency has been announced after an oil spill from a damaged Japanese ship is contaminating vast tracts of water. Baby tortoises and rare plants from an island near the spill, Ile aux Aigrettes, are being taken to the mainland to protect them from the worsening situation. The ship had struck a reef on July 25.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to Ashin Wirathu: Can your monastery do anything now to restore the spirit of fraternity that should reign amongst all the residents of Myanmar?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 11:16:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-mr-ashin-wirathu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bhante Ashin Wirathu, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that focusses on the need to replace the United Nations with a more effective and principled organisation, although we also work to promote human and animal rights, as well as the welfare of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Institutionalised religion has had a sad history in a number of countries around the world owing to its bigotry and abuse of power. Many spiritual people, including some of our members, have therefore looked to Buddhism as a beacon of justice and openness. This image has been tainted over the last few years by portrayals of monks leading a crusade against the Rohingya inhabitants of Myanmar. The contradiction here reminds many people of the darkest periods of some of the leading world religions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian Roulette: Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-grim-trend&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Grim Trend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July seems to have accelerated the grim trend that has been eroding civility and security over the last few years. The month dawned with Hong Kong finding itself stripped of many of its civil liberties. A few days later, on the 6th, President Trump formally notified the World Health Organisation that the US would be withdrawing from the organisation once the required twelve-month’s period of notice was over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You May Have Missed: July 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:27:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-july-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Mali&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 30 farmers were slaughtered by armed jihadists on motorcycles while they were returning home from their fields in villages in the Mopti region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;05.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/strong&gt;. The number of people killed in protests over the murder of popular political singer, Hachalu Hundessa, on June 29 rose to 156 according to a senior official.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;08.07.20: &lt;strong&gt;Ivory Coast&lt;/strong&gt;. Prime Minister Amadou Gon Coulibaly died aged 61 a few days after returning from France where he had undergone a medical check-up relating to a heart condition. He fell ill at a ministerial meeting and was rushed to hospital where he died shortly afterwards. He was the ruling party&amp;rsquo;s candidate for the October presidential election and was expected to replace the outgoing President Alassane Ouattara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compassion fatigue: How to turn your compassion into positive action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:03:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/compassion-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;symptoms-of-compassion-fatigue&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symptoms&lt;/strong&gt; of Compassion Fatigue&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you ever catch yourself feeling really moved by something quite trivial when reading the news, as you skimmed past some tragedy in Yemen or Syria without even paying the slightest bit of attention? Or are you prone to add a like or comment to a Facebook GIF about a silly animal situation, for instance, while ignoring a poignant post about social injustice or an environmental emergency?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the New UN-aligned Campaigns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/un-aligned-campaigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 11:09:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/un-aligned-campaigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is proud to announce the launch of a series of campaigns in line with its manifesto. UN-aligned campaigns will cover a range of issues concerning human rights, the environment and United Nations reform, and we will be reporting on them in The Gordian, as well as on our website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our campaigns will start by targeting blatant disregard to clearcut issues of social or environmental justice by powerful corporations, organisations or individuals. We will be highlighting their shortcomings and asking them to take positive steps in order to improve their undertakings in line with a fairer and safer world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What you May Have Missed in June 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-june-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 08:51:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/what-you-may-have-missed-june-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/VhGGrppQsg4&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/VhGGrppQsg4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;africa&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFRICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O4.05.20: &lt;strong&gt;Burundi&lt;/strong&gt;. President Pierre Nkurunzizahas, who had been in power for 15 years, died aged 55 following a heart attack. He was due to step down in August. Riots following the start of his third term, five years ago, which many considered unconstitutional, resulted in 1,200 deaths and widespread violence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5.06.20: &lt;strong&gt;Uganda&lt;/strong&gt;. The Buganda Kingdom and local communities were in shock over a fire that destroyed one of the sacred houses at the Tombs of Buganda Kings of Kasubi. The site is inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waste and Mismanagement: The Devil in the Detail That is Back to Haunt us!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/waste-and-mismanagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 09:05:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/waste-and-mismanagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation-is-rarely-green&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creation is rarely green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The forces of creation are often seen as a trinity. In philosophy we have the Hegelian dialectic of Thesis, Antithesis and Synthesis, where the synthesis then becomes a new thesis which in turn postulates another antithesis, thus propelling evolution in a perpetual thrust forward. In religion, we have, for example, the Hindu trinity made up of Brahma (the creator), Vishnu (the preserver) and Shiva (the destroyer).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned becomes one year old!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 06:54:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-becomes-one-year-old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned is one year old this month! The seed was sown some years ago in China and developed thanks to the dedication of like-minded people. We have gone from 22 Foundation Members to hundreds of followers from around the world: some are full members, others are subscribers, while many follow us on Facebook. To all our supporters, we wish to offer a big THANK YOU!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike most organisations, UN-aligned is, primarily, its members. We are the New United Nations and though just a drop in the ocean, for now, we will carry on growing until we will become a force to be reckoned with! Our Mission Statement and Manifesto clearly indicate what we stand for, but they are not written in stone and with your help we hope to learn and evolve so that we can bring about the change that we know will make the world more sustainable and harmonious.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Klaatu barada nikto”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 16:53:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These words are taken from the classic 1951 film directed by Robert Wise: The Day the Earth Stood Still. The film, based on a short story by Harry Bates, is about an alien, Klaatu, who comes to earth in order to warn humanity of its pending obliteration by an interplanetary police force, unless it mends its destructive ways. The words were uttered to Gort, the robot, after Klaatu was shot. They delivered a stay of execution. Nevertheless, the film ends with the ball in earth’s court; their decision still to be made. We are now in 2020 and it seems as though many of our leaders are still hellbent on pursuing a self-destructive agenda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned in 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 22:07:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/un-aligned-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2019 was a momentous year for UN-aligned! The organisation was launched in May after years of preparation and it only took a few months to attract members from all over the world. The first months were focussed on perfecting and consolidating the website and communication structures, including the magazine and language options. We also worked on the services we provide to our members, such as the free English language courses to promote a lingua franca and the virtual library. Moreover, much energy was invested in the writing of a book that will challenge the structures and mechanisms of the United Nations; this should be ready for publication in Spring 2020. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India on the Brink</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:48:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/india-on-the-brink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-enemy-within&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Enemy Within&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Martin Luther King Jr. visited India in 1959, he paid the homage to the venerable land with these powerful words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“To other countries I may go as a tourist, but to India I come as a pilgrim.” Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Would Mr. King think differently of India if he were alive today? Probably not. The narrowminded fanaticism that is trying to drag India down is not a new phenomenon. Even if one cannot ignore it, one can always look beyond it. However, the world is not what it was 60 years ago. It is a much more dangerous place. Our efficiency in depleting the earth’s life and resources is only matched by the relentlessness of nature’s means of revenge, such as climate change or the smog that has recently been chocking Delhi.  Moreover, if we should end up fighting for whatever is left, we would be able to do so with much more devastating results. Finally, mass media have altered the way in which we communicate. Just as the Internet, for instance, helps the wise become wiser, it often has the opposite effect with fools, who become easy prey to those who would exploit them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separatism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/separatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/separatism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;national-identity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Villages and towns, built on cooperation, existed long before nations did. With time, however, the need for security threaded them together like a string of pearls. Sometimes, the unification was voluntary, sometimes it was not. The necklaces became kingdoms and empires; republics even. Polities and economies began to evolve, as did religion, language and culture. The process continues to this day. Nevertheless, threats to national borders remain. These threats come from abroad, as in the case of Georgia and Ukraine, or from within, as is happening in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labelling Suicide while Missing the Point</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/labelling-suicide-while-missing-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:02:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/labelling-suicide-while-missing-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-forty-seconds&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every Forty Seconds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 10th September was World Mental Health Day. In this context the WHO published a flyer to raise awareness on suicide and how to help prevent it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/mental-health/suicide/flyer-40seconds-web.pdf?sfvrsn=5ba643c_2&#34;&gt;Working Together to Prevent Suicide&lt;/a&gt;. The WHO highlights the fact that every forty seconds a life is lost to suicide. This is tragic and all the more so because so much more could be done to help, both on an individual and on a social basis. It is reassuring that the WHO is taking this problem seriously, but I object to suicide being so often linked with mental health. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s shopping list!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/trumps-shopping-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 06:05:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/trumps-shopping-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, President Trump now wants to buy Greenland! An uninhabited Greek island is one thing, but the largest island in the world that is also an autonomous territory… Well! Although Greenland has been a part of Denmark for over 200 years, it has been increasingly self-governing since 1979, with only foreign affairs and defence still controlled by Denmark. The suggestion just highlights how callous and clueless the American President is. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN unable to condemn attack on migrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-un-unable-to-condemn-attack-on-migrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 03:27:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-un-unable-to-condemn-attack-on-migrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-so-it-continues&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And so it continues…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Migrants are once again the victims of indifference and direct aggression. Six children and about 50 adults were killed and more that three times as many were badly hurt when a migrant detention centre was bombed by the forces of General Khalifa Haftar who are fighting the UN recognised government of Libya. The site had clearly been designated as a UN sanctuary, but this made no difference. The attack that took place on the early hours of Wednesday, but reports are now coming to light that people were fired on as they tried to escape the bombardment.  No surprise there. Migrants are treated as sub-human even by those who have the responsibility of attending to them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking at migration in the face</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:34:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/looking-at-migration-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-has-not-been-a-good-week-for-refugees-but-then-again-it-never-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has not been a good week for refugees; but then again, it never is…&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s The Guardian reports how the Lebanese government forced 5,000 refugee families to demolish their own home in order to induce them to return to Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the captain of rescue ship Sea-Watch 3, Carola Rackete, was arrested after she forcefully docked her ship in the Italian island of  Lampedusa. Having rescued 53 migrants drifting off the coast of Libya on June 12, the Sea-Watch 3 was left stranded while the Italian authorities kept refusing to let her dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>150 Lives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/150-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 06:28:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/150-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-thoughts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second thoughts…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After ordering an attack on Iran last week, president Trump had an after thought. How many human lives would it cost? One wonders: what amount of casualties would have made his strike acceptable? Fifty? A hundred? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-problem&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Iranian problem is of Trump’s making. He pulled out of the 2015 Iran nuclear deal, started a war of words and began imposing harsh sanctions. On top of that, Trump bullied all other nations to follow suit. A legally binding deal became powerless in the face of Trump’s financial blackmail. Of course that did not have to be the case, but few countries had the backbone to stand up to Trump’s threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan gives the world a lesson in democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:15:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-a-thing-or-two-from-taiwan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning a thing or two from Taiwan…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan gave the world a lesson in real democracy last month when same-sex marriage was legalised in the “country“. In a referendum last November, 72% of the population had voted against allowing same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two years earlier, however, Taiwan’s supreme court had ruled that limiting the definition of marriage to couples of the opposite sex was unconstitutional. Legislators therefore backed the Government Bill, putting justice before numbers. This is real democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonising Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 06:40:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demonising-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;picking-on-the-weakest&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking on the weakest…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some people just need a common enemy. Any group that can be easily picked on offers the perfect target. Minorities of every sort are often chosen because of their vulnerability. Bullying them makes weak or bigoted citizens feel superior. Some of these minorities have fought back and with time secured a certain level of safety, and the protection of their human rights. Still, immigrants are often the most threatened, because they are insecure. They do not know the ropes and cannot easily fight back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is wrong with the United Nations to warrant the founding of an organisation like UN-aligned?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-wrong-with-the-united-nations-to-warrant-the-founding-of-an-organisation-like-un-aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 12:22:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/what-is-wrong-with-the-united-nations-to-warrant-the-founding-of-an-organisation-like-un-aligned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations (UN) is a remarkable organisation. It has achieved some outstanding results for humanity and it continues to do so. The 17 Sustainable Development Goals offer an example, amongst many, of its tireless work for the planet and its people. Despite its achievements, however, the UN is flawed. Its many failings relate to its structure, its principles and its functions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-language-and-structure-of-the-un-charter-are-engrained-in-the-post-war-world-of-1945&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The language and structure of the UN Charter are engrained in the post war world of 1945&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Those countries who had fought against the Allies are referred to as “enemy” states in the UN Charter and treated differently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The five permanent members of the Security Council were the main victors of the Second World War. Their selection had nothing to do with fair representation or moral authority.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One of the six organs of the UN, the Trusteeship Council is redundant. It was established to oversee the independence process of territories still occupied by colonial powers. Of course, it could have diversified and worked for oppressed people within nations, but it chose not do this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-permanent-members&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The permanent members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The privilege of the five permanent members to wield the veto (Article 27) allows for gross misjustice and abuse. IN 2015 France even tried to limit its use in cases that could lead to genocide, but their proposal was dismissed by Russia as “populist”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Sri Lanka bombings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 08:15:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/reflections-on-the-sri-lanka-bombings-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bloody-motives&#34;&gt;Bloody motives!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an angel came and told me that all the world problems would be solved if I just put a few bombs around killing innocent people in mosques, synagogues, churches, market places or hotels… would I do it? Of course not. Firstly, because I do not even have the right to insult an innocent person, let alone take their life. Secondly, because it would be like asking me to believe that good is founded on evil, or harmony on hatred. Rather obvious, you would say… Then why, oh why, does it keep happening again and again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
