<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Voluntary Positions on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/tags/voluntary-positions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Voluntary Positions on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/voluntary-positions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a PR Manager</title>
      <link>/opportunities/pr-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>/opportunities/pr-manager/</guid>
      <description>Do you love writing a good pitch? Would your friends describe you as confident? Want to get involved with UN-aligned and help us with our media work? We think you might be a great fit for our new open position: PR Manager. Apply now!</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/PR-Manager-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New voluntary position: UN-aligned is looking for a Puzzle Creator</title>
      <link>/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 11:27:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>/opportunities/puzzle-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you enjoy a good puzzle? Would your friends describe you as creative? Want to get involved with UN-aligned but don’t have too much spare time? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think you might be a great fit for our new and unique open position: Puzzle Creator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at UN-aligned spread our message of fairness and equality through many platforms including our Newsletter, monthly publication ‘The Gordian’ and social media. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the United Nations may be in a sorry state, it’s not all doom and gloom and we like to drop in interactive quizzes to The Gordian for our readers. Until now we’ve been using multiple choice quizzes, you can see an example &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/category/quiz/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Puzzle-Creator-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
