<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unregisteredauthor on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/unregisteredauthor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unregisteredauthor on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:19:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/unregisteredauthor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Gordian Companion 2023: Your Stories from a Year on Edge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-companion-2023-your-stories-from-a-year-on-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:19:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-aligned-news/the-gordian-companion-2023-your-stories-from-a-year-on-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Step into the world of The Gordian Companion 2023 and experience a year of groundbreaking stories. This collection, consisting of the best reads from The Gordian Magazine, is not just a book; it is a revolution in citizen journalism. Edited by Ariana Yekrangi, every page challenges, inspires and awakens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Featuring a star-studded roster of writers such as Adrian Liberto, Omar Alansari-Kreger, Dinojah Patkunarajah, Elvira Ineza, Dawn Roy, Alex Liberto, Partho Pratim Chatterjee, Alexander Stoney, Sunil Kumar Pariyar, Amy Church and Carla Pietrobattista, The Gordian Companion is where diverse perspectives ignite. Each voice in this anthology does not simply recount the year&amp;rsquo;s events; they redefine them, offering fresh, bold insights that break the mould.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation-Building and Indigenous Struggles: Histories, Rights and Representation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where borders are drawn and redrawn, the quest for a homeland remains fraught with strife for many. Nation-building, the process of constructing a national identity and establishing political and social structures, is pivotal in this quest. It is not just about hotly-debated independence stories or drawing lines on a map; it involves acknowledging diverse histories, cultures and rights to create a cohesive and inclusive society. This is crucial for ensuring peace, stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Montreux Declaration: An Alternative Vision for World Peace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-montreux-declaration-an-alternative-vision-for-world-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-montreux-declaration-an-alternative-vision-for-world-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After two devastating world wars, the prospect of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pugwash.org/1955/07/09/statement-manifesto/&#34;&gt;universal death&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; was on everyone&amp;rsquo;s mind. It was time for global institutions to ensure genuine world peace. The United Nations was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/en/about-us/un-charter/preamble&#34;&gt;formed&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;to save succeeding generations from the scourge of war&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its mission statement reflected the deep desire of war-ravaged humankind to put an end to international violence once and for all. Yet even before the foundation of the UN, activists and scholars had warned about the UN Charter&amp;rsquo;s design flaws. The criticism of the UN structure has lost nothing in relevance to this day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let technology become a bane for future generations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology helps us improve our lives and make things easier. However, there are two sides to everything. Undoubtedly, for instance, Artificial Intelligence will grow further, but I am sure it has both a positive and a negative impact on the world. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me be honest, when technology just started to enter our lives in the early 90’s in India I was super thrilled with it. I was fascinated with the pagers and then the mobiles in the late 90’s and I liked the fact that at the press of a button I could reach my near and dear ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>86 Billion: The human spirt&#39;s fight to live a meaningful life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LED,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where is Dendrite?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;That Synapse - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To my fiery colours of hope&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To feed my soul, To feel my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my soul, To kiss my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my fire&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hear me&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To talk to me!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Speech me - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To hold me in words,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hold me in paint,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To violins,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To my treasures, to loves.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Anode and Cathode before the dark -&#xA;A light emitting diode,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A neural implant, never was,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To trigger years loves, laughter, dreams, memories, hope, passion;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pain, despair, angst, anxiety, fear -&#xA;Fiery Colours of hope always. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Stop this rape in Ukraine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gruesome rape and torment in Ukraine&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Causing women and children agonising pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Horrific headlines curdles one to the bone.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Russian soldiers have no hearts of their own.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can&amp;rsquo;t they leave the innocent alone?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Women like prisoners tied to a chain,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gory details of Women and babies raped&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s no escape.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bodies of women and children everywhere.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rape is a weapon of war.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The innocent have no sword or spear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only the bloody scar.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers strangle them with hatred,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Is this why you were created?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Innocent lives are wasted.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing sacred.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;How can this evil be tolerated?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotional health: 4 ways you can improve it today</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/emotional-health-4-ways-you-can-improve-it-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/emotional-health-4-ways-you-can-improve-it-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Emotions change the way we see the world”. This is a quote by Paul Ekman and it has been interpreted in so many different ways in so many movies and books. Emotion is a powerful word and dictates a huge part of our lives, but it is surprising to see that a minuscule amount of people know about emotional health and even a smaller number work towards achieving it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the book “Chaos of Standing Still” by Jessica Brody, the hero, Ryn, is dealing with the insurmountable loss of her childhood best friend, but rather than facing her grief, sadness and anger, she just buries these feelings under a rock. She doesn’t cry for a year and cuts everyone out of her life, while just clinging to the last memento of her best friend (an unread message). When she finally lets go and embraces that grief and cries, she starts seeing things clearly. She finally feels happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia Needs to Legalise Drugs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/australia-needs-to-legalise-drugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 12:00:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/australia-needs-to-legalise-drugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many drugs taken for pleasure in Australia are illegal. Examples include cannabis (cannabis can be grown and consumed legally, but not sold, in the Australian Capital Territory), heroin, ice (crystal meth) and many others. Some drugs taken for pleasure are legal, such as nicotine, with tobacco smoked by 2.5 million Australians, and alcohol, drunk at least once per week by 8 million. In addition, about 800 prescription drugs are subsidised under the pharmaceutical benefits scheme. Prescription drugs are reported to be misused by around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2017/dec/19/prescription-drugs-misused-by-one-million-australians-in-year-report-shows&#34;&gt;1 million Australians&lt;/a&gt;. Cannabis can be taken legally for medicinal purposes in all Australian states by people with certain limited classes of health problems. The obvious question is – why are some drugs legal and others illegal?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Glass Ceiling: Women in India are not Behind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:47:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/women-in-india-are-not-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glass-ceiling-effect-in-the-west&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Ceiling Effect in the West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 20th century, women in other parts of the industrialised world had also experienced what is popularly known as the &amp;lsquo;glass ceiling&amp;rsquo; phenomenon, which meant that women found they could only rise to a certain level in corporations and no further. This raises two immediate questions. What were the reasons that could have led to such a thought? And, were men keeping women away from the top?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems For a Better World: This War of MMXXII</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:54:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Invasion for pure greed and gratification.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else can this be?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Civilians, soldiers, casualties dying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In their blood lying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lives are meaningless,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The soul is downcast and sighing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is the battlefield, blood, brutality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Politicians lacking  rationality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aggression, destruction, death and ravished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers and innocent lying on the streets.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Surely logic has perished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The cold carnage continues …&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Unleashed on humanity.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mourning for innocent lives.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who will stop the insanity?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can people not see such torment and tragedy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is only depravity and brutality…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Forging of an East African Federation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:37:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-shot-at-an-east-african-community&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Shot at an East African Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three countries of East Africa - Kenya, Tanzania (which is a union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar), and Uganda - were administered as one unit under the East African Common Services. When granting them independence, the British expected that these countries would eventually integrate into one political union, as had happened to Tanganyika and Zanzibar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of a political federation for East Africa emerged in the 1960s. The idea took shape in 1967 when the East African Community, a confederate government, was formed by the republics of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania. The heads of states of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania, by signing the treaty establishing the community, became its patron and hoped to use the community as a launching pad towards deeper political, economic, and socio-cultural integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 most fascinating scientific discoveries of 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/10-most-fascinating-scientific-discoveries-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 09:30:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/10-most-fascinating-scientific-discoveries-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-medicine-mrna-vaccines-we-found-a-new-way-to-directly-talk-to-our-body&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Medicine/ mRNA vaccines: We found a new way to directly talk to our body!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/mRNA-vaccines.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An illustration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mechanism_of_action&#34;&gt;mechanism of action&lt;/a&gt; of a messenger RNA vaccine. Photo: Jmarchn&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vaccines have been around — and have noticeably extended the life expectancy of humans — since a few centuries ago. Research on mRNA technology is also longstanding and has been conducted for decades. What is new, however, is the ability to harness the power of mRNA in developing state-of-the-art vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Silence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;i&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silence is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Silence is complicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Complicity is violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So in the violence of our silence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let us take stock of our complicity &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;ii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our complicity silences truth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muffles honour, rapes innocence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The same innocence we plead&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Confronted by shattered delusion&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“We didn’t know” &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;iii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wished to not know&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Blinded, deafened, deadened&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We turned away Bedecked ourselves in laurel&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Which now turns to rue &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;iv&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our silence - yours and mine - is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is complicit It is violent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And in its complicit explicit violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We too have bloodied our souls&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Terra Australis Incognita</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;and those black fellas believed these white fellas spirits of their ancestors (pale time travellers of everywhen) and those black fellas received venereal, opium, rum and pox and they returned witchetty grubs, honey ants and fruit bats and the white fellas killed no one with their guns because the new land was called &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (land belonging to no one) and it was fair to say that these white fellas did not include themselves nor irony in their census taking and the captain struck the collarbone of the elder (he that had helped himself to the white fellas shovel) and the aborigine elder embraced the captain and spread his arm to indicate everything he could see and the captain surrendered his shovel of wrought iron just as black fellas shared their axes of polished greenstone and so it was with ropes and stakes and sacred land; these white fellas pushed the black fellas further from the sea, scattered burial totems of coral, red basket and seagull feather and there was bile and spleen between the groups and dead black fellas (females and young, too) and the aborigine elder pushed the collarbone of the captain and the captain knew it was wrong to survey and deed what wasn’t theirs and he was ashamed and he agreed that his voice was no greater than the magpie or the blue winged kookaburra and he negotiated to settle the interior space of &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (that ground that was less hospitable like them) and handcuffs and leg irons fell from the poors and politicals and these made a mountain of metal where everyone was free to piss and the captain cast off his blue jacket and white waistcoat and humbled himself to learn yellomundi (or storyteller) and butbut (or heart) and he was granted initiation by they that met and decided he was ten years old and he was painted with red clay and fat of the wallroo and wombat and he received cuts to his chest arms shoulders and buttocks and sand in each produced voluminous scars and the penis of this white fella was split with a stone knife and a front tooth was knocked out to mark him as community and he danced the tree lion climbing ripping and pulling but laying in peace with brother and sister alike and he sang the songlines that trek creation and he blew didjerry didjerry through termite eucalyptus, pressed his lips to beeswax and shook out grins and guffaws and the black fellas did not call him apostle but he returned his blind eye seeing to the white sails of sirius of the orion and he stayed the cannons and six-pounder guns and his voice was dreamtime and ancestral beings and why it is that men and women walk upright and those that saw and heard were ashamed and they pushed the collarbone one of the other and they agreed against greed to call this place “must be there somewhere land” and it remains so to this day&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the United Nations, Argead style</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/unravelling-the-united-nations-argead-style-officially-published/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How exactly has the United Nations failed in its primary mission of securing world peace? What went wrong? Who or what is to blame? Can reform absolve the organisation of its monumental shortcomings and put it back on course with regards to meeting its obligations? These are just some questions this book aims to answer. And here is the spoiler: no, the United Nations cannot be salvaged. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the book presents an alternative vision: an organisation that can achieve the sacred mission without the shackles of obsolete structures and bullying superpowers. The organisation, UN-aligned, has already been founded and it is introduced in this groundbreaking work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
