<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atika.Harba on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/authors/atika.harba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Atika.Harba on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/authors/atika.harba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My internship comes to an end, but my journey continues</title>
      <link>/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/my-internship-comes-to-an-end-but-my-journey-continues/</guid>
      <description>Education in refugee camps has the transformative power to break the chains of poverty and rebuild lives, bringing hope for a better tomorrow.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Syrian-refugee-children-in-a-Lebanese-school-classroom-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;We always hope for change, but we are powerless. We are just refugees&#34;</title>
      <link>/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/we-always-hope-for-change-but-we-are-powerless-we-are-just-refugees/</guid>
      <description>Atika describes her difficult day as refugee.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Diaries-from-Refugee-Camps-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Almoallem Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/a-day-in-almoallem-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>An armed attack on our camp shakes our security and frightens us, but what can we do but return to our tents and accept what happened as par of the course?</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/A-Day-in-Almoallem-Refugee-Camp-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I entered the university and my heart is leaping with joy!” — An extracts from a refugee’s journal</title>
      <link>/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:31:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/i-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the days of the war in Syria, we lost our safety. We used to sleep to the sound of cannons and wake up to the sound of planes. One day, my mother asked me to go to the pharmacy near our house to buy a fever-reducing medicine for my little brother; while I was on the way back with my little sister, a shell fell in front of us. The people on the street started running to see what happened. We did not stop running until I got home, and we survived. This is one of the most difficult memories that stick in my memory and cannot be forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/I-entered-the-university-and-my-heart-is-leaping-with-joy-%E2%80%94-An-extracts-from-a-refugees-journal-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“I still have hope that we will all return to our warm home and beautiful city” — Interview with Syrian refugee, Somaya</title>
      <link>/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/interview-with-syrian-refugee-somaya/</guid>
      <description>In another piece from our series &#34;Diaries from Refugee Camps&#34;, Atika Harba talks to the Somaya, a mother of three and a refugee inside a Lebanese refugee camp. Are you a refugee and would like to share your story inside this series? Please contact us.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/nterview-with-Syrian-refugee-Somaya.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Every day my heart squeezes with sadness and pain”: An Interview with Amna, a Syrian refugee in Lebanon’s Arsal Camp</title>
      <link>/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:12:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/interview-with-a-syrian-refugee-in-arsal-camp-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>During her internship with UN-aligned, Atika Harba was asked to write about life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Atika, who at the time of publishing, was a 17-year-old refugee, wrote several articles and diaries that gives readers a glimpse inside the difficult life of inside the refugee camp.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Every-day-my-heart-squeezes-with-sadness-and-painAn-Interview-with-Amna-a-Syrian-refugee-in-Lebanons-Arsal-Camp.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Life Without Flowers: A Glimpse Into The Arsal Refugee Camp</title>
      <link>/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Atika.Harba</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/a-glimpse-into-the-arsal-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I will talk about my place of residence in one of the camps in Lebanon, Arsal, and how I was able to adapt to this difficult life, which does not resemble life at all. It is only days that pass without taste. One of the most difficult days of my life was when I was fifteen years old. My family decided that we should live In a refugee camp. At that time, misfortune and sadness overtook me, and I went into a state of depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Photo-by-Atika-Harba.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
