<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Democracy on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/democracy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Democracy on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/democracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Love for Erdogan&#39;s Autocracy in the Heart of German Democracy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recep Tayyip Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s name echoes in Istanbul and Berlin alike. As Turkey&amp;rsquo;s President, he commands attention and drives conversation in both these distinct locales, exerting an influence that, to many observers, seems paradoxical. Despite being in the heart of Europe, where democracy is a foundational value, Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s autocratic approach finds a surprisingly receptive audience within a substantial German-Turkish community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s influence over this diaspora often equals, and at times even outstrips, his hold over his own nation, a conundrum that pushes against traditional ideas about the strength of democracy. But how can an autocratic leader secure such steadfast loyalty from a community residing in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most solid democracies?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the United Nations Parliamentary Assembly Address Failed State Realities?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What can the movement for a United Nations Parliamentary Assembly takeaway from the World Development Index? According to the United Nations Surviving on Pennies Global Awareness Initiative, 1 billion people live on $1.00 daily. We have been trained to localize the concept of gross domestic product by national classification, but on average, how widely considered as the world&amp;rsquo;s gross domestic product per capita?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of 2021, Macrotrends reported &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrotrends.net/countries/WLD/world/gdp-gross-domestic-product&#34;&gt;the world GDP&lt;/a&gt; at a meager $11,407 (per capita), less than what the United States Assistant Office of Planning &amp;amp; Evaluation identified as poverty for one person at $12,880 for the same year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lobbyland: The Story of American Lobbying and Campaign Donations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:07:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/lobbyland-the-story-of-american-lobbying-and-campaign-donations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States, although a mighty country, has its flaws. One of its flaws is how some lobbying groups hold immensely more significant sway than others, thus unfairly eliciting beneficial results for a minority group. Another such flaw is the restriction of representatives to be solely those who may afford to run. These systemic flaws, among others not mentioned, when compounded together, erode democratic representation and must be viewed as an existential threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It shouldn&#39;t be NATO, it should be the United Nations: The Poetry of Appeasement</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/it-should-not-be-nato-it-should-be-the-united-nations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-the-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We the people&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the list of governments I hate grows longer by the day, I cannot help but wonder about all the people who elected them into power in the first place. True, sometimes the system is rigged against the people, either because of the iron grip of despotic regimes or through a flawed system that only provides an illusion of choice. What Julius Nyerere said about America, applies to many democracies: “The United States is also a one-party state but, with typical American extravagance, they have two of them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
