<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment Report on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/environment-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment Report on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 12:37:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/environment-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Use Carbon Dioxide to Curb Global Warming</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-use-carbon-dioxide-to-curb-global-warming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 12:37:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-use-carbon-dioxide-to-curb-global-warming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Global warming, a crisis primarily driven by the emission of greenhouse gases such as carbon dioxide, calls for innovative solutions. Our reliance on fossil fuels for electricity generation, transportation, industrial processes and domestic heating has exponentially escalated carbon dioxide levels. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This gas is a significant contributor to the greenhouse effect, which in turn accelerates global warming. But what if we could transform this problem into a solution? Here are four ways we can utilise carbon dioxide to help keep the global temperature rise below 1.5 degrees Celsius by 2100.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is UK&#39;s North Sea Drilling Plan a Sustainable Solution? An Impact Assessment Report</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-findings&#34;&gt;Key findings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK&amp;rsquo;s proposed drilling plan has minimal immediate impact on energy security, offering only short-term reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With sustainable energy advancements, extensive reliance on fossil fuels is becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan&amp;rsquo;s short-term financial benefits are economically short-sighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investing in a net-zero economy and green jobs is more beneficial for long-term economic growth and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drilling plan could harm climate commitments and marine biodiversity in the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shift to renewable energy and green bond financing is advised, echoing global body recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Solutions to Combat Climate Change: 4 Groundbreaking Approaches</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ingenious-engineering-solutions-to-cool-down-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 12:31:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ingenious-engineering-solutions-to-cool-down-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the effects of climate change continue to worsen, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to explore innovative engineering solutions that can help us mitigate these impacts. This article delves into four groundbreaking engineering solutions that are providing hope for a more sustainable future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases from fossil fuel-based power generation, transportation, industrial processes, and the like, are exacerbating the process of global warming. To restrict the global temperature rise to 1.5 degrees centigrade by 2100, it is essential to adopt engineering solutions that can aid in reducing this warming effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of a Thriving Bioeconomy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/unlocking-the-power-of-a-thriving-bioeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/unlocking-the-power-of-a-thriving-bioeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we face the pressing issue of climate change, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we need solutions that are both sustainable and equitable. That&amp;rsquo;s where the concept of a bioeconomy comes in. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By harnessing renewable resources, a bioeconomy has the potential to not only help mitigate emissions, but also support communities that have been historically marginalised, such as forest dwellers, farmers and indigenous populations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in order to fully realise the benefits of a bioeconomy, we need to ensure that it is supported by smart policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Combat the Negative Impacts of Global Warming on Biodiversity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The contemporary phenomena of global warming has created a &amp;ldquo;Hothouse Earth&amp;rdquo; and has wreaked havoc on pristine ecosystems. The melting of glaciers exposes vast swathes of marine water to atmospheric carbon dioxide, lowering pH from alkaline values and threatening the survival of corals and other marine organisms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the indiscriminate felling of certain species of flora and the poaching of certain species of animals for medicinal purposes exacerbates their extinction. Clearing tropical rainforests for agriculture also strips the planet of its carbon sinks and lungs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for achieving decarbonisation in consonance with energy security</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/strategies-for-achieving-decarbonisation-in-consonance-with-energy-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/strategies-for-achieving-decarbonisation-in-consonance-with-energy-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy is one of the inalienable stanchions of modern human-social-industrial life. The current global temperature is 1.1 degree centigrade above pre-industrial levels. The recent devastating events like increase in glacial lake outburst floods,  droughts , cyclones, forest fires, and the like could be attributed to the rising global temperatures. As the pernicious effects of global warming are now no longer covert, it is high time to resort to decarbonisation using a combination of efficient technologies and carbon dioxide sequestration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to combat forest fires: causes and 4 solutions</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-combat-forest-fires-causes-and-4-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-combat-forest-fires-causes-and-4-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, forest fires are proliferating. The current temperature is around 1.1. degree centigrade above pre-industrial levels. This increase in temperature could be attributed to anthropogenic activity-induced global warming. The concentration of gases like carbon dioxide is increasing continuously in the atmosphere due to anthropogenic activities like fossil fuel-based power generation and the use of fossil fuels in internal combustion engines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s (NOAA) Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii, USA recorded high amounts of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. The greenhouse gases trap infrared radiation leading to a spike in global temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ingenious solutions to abate the overexploitation of water</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:28:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Water is one of the stanchions of life. Around 60 % of the human body is made up of water. Drinking water from pristine sources has been linked to a higher lifespan. Water provides oxygen in the form of dissolved oxygen to marine organisms. Global warming leads to an increase in the temperature of the water. This reduces the amount of oxygen dissolved in the water proving detrimental for aquatic life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Transportation Green? 3 Alternatives to Internal Combustion Engines</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-make-transportation-green-3-alternatives-to-internal-combustion-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 10:46:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-make-transportation-green-3-alternatives-to-internal-combustion-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pollution from transportation is an inexorable contributor towards climate change. Internal Combustion Engine (ICE) powered vehicles use fossil fuels like Compressed Natural Gas, Gasoline, Diesel etc. Here, an interesting trend is observed. The higher the hydrocarbon, the greater is the extent of pollution caused because of it. This could be attributed to the presence of a larger number of impurities in the liquid stage compared to the gaseous stage. Thus, the extent of environmental pollution caused by Diesel powered vehicles is greater than Natural Gas based vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making environment and development go hand in hand</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/making-environment-and-development-go-hand-in-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/making-environment-and-development-go-hand-in-hand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;remediation-and-restoration&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remediation and restoration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrestrial ecosystem restoration can be augmented with novel afforestation techniques like Miyawaki method thereby increasing biodiversity along with sequestering greenhouse gasses. Marine ecosystems can be restored by techniques like Floating Solar PhotoVoltaics, offshore wind farms, wind-Solar hybrids and powered Biorock accretion techniques followed by the insertion of a living coral in the skeleton to enhance biodiversity in these “rainforests” of the oceans. Oil spills from ships can have a pernicious effect on fragile marine ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
