<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azerbaijan on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/azerbaijan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azerbaijan on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/azerbaijan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Armenia’s ICC Pivot: Defying Russia and Eyeing European and Iranian Ties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unprecedented development, Armenian lawmakers have ratified the Rome Statute, thereby signifying the nation&amp;rsquo;s intent to join the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This development has sent ripples all the way to the Kremlin, which seems less than pleased. Given the earlier move by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;ICC to issue an arrest warrant for Russian President&lt;/a&gt; Vladimir Putin in March, Armenia now finds itself on a tightrope, precariously balancing its long-standing alliance with Russia. This recent gesture by Armenia has not only added a strain to its delicate camaraderie with Russia but also hints at a cautious pivot towards the West for a security umbrella. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The OSCE Minsk Group is Unfit to Conciliate Between Azerbaijan &amp; Armenia over Nagorno-Karabakh</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/the-osce-minsk-group-is-unfit-to-conciliate-between-azerbaijan-armenia-over-nagorno-karabakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1992, two years before the war between the neighbouring Armenia and Azerbaijan ended, the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), met in Helsinki and decided to chair negotiations towards a peaceful political settlement for the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The body, also known as the Minsk group, is led and co-chaired by the US, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Russia&lt;/a&gt; and France with Belarus, Germany, Italy, Portugal, The Netherlands, Sweden, Finland, Turkey, Armenia and Azerbaijan as participating member states. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
