<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utopian Ideas on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/utopian-ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Utopian Ideas on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/utopian-ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Wealth Gap: A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Redefining our modern self-serving economics to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reality is what keeps us safe. It informed our past and it guides our present. Reality is our safe zone. It is the anchor on which our boat is secured. It is the devil we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as anyone who has owned a boat can tell you, a tight anchor is the surest way to sink your boat: a change in tide, a swell… and without the leeway in your rope, you are underwater. The fact is, reality changes and unless we adapt and evolve with it, we are done for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Transcending the Moon, a Democratic Encounter</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this story, we postulate an interview with the representative of a more advanced civilisation; and within this setting, novel visions are juxtaposed to some of our pressing problems. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/&#34;&gt;Learn more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could scarcely believe that I was about to embark on such a venture. The prospect of meeting an otherworldly being – a genuine extraterrestrial – was almost too fantastic to contemplate. And not just any alien, mind you, but the Dengilaun ambassador to our very own Moon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utopian Ideas from an Alien Society: Conversations with the Dengilauns</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian Magazine is excited to unveil a new series of short stories that will be featured in our upcoming volume, with a theme of Utopia. This series is an innovative and experimental form of storytelling that combines key utopian ideas with elements of science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our mission at the magazine is to promote the message of UN-aligned, which works towards creating a more effective and principled United Nations. This new series aligns with that mission by exploring the possibilities of a better world that upholds human rights, animal welfare, and environmental protection. These stories will take readers to imagined worlds where these values are prioritized and where current societal issues have been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
