<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegan Recipes on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/vegan-recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegan Recipes on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:20:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/vegan-recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Vegan Peach Cobbler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/a-simple-vegan-peach-cobbler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:20:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/a-simple-vegan-peach-cobbler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; 4 cups (946.35 ml) of peeled sliced peaches&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; ½ cup (118.3 ml)  of water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; 2 cups (473.17 ml) of organic sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; 1 ½ cups (354.88 ml) of self-rising flour (must be self-rising!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; 1 ½ cups (354.88 ml) of almond milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 stick (8 tbsp) vegan butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ground cinnamon &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Suggested toppings: vegan vanilla ice cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to make it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat oven to 350°F /176 °C/gas 4 and let warm up while prepping the cobbler.  &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Place a medium (3Q) saucepan on the stove and set the heat to medium. Pour peaches, water, and 1 cup (236.59 ml) of sugar into the pan and mix. Let heat for about 10 minutes and mix occasionally. Set aside when done. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take out another medium mixing bowl. Pour in self-rising flour and 1 cup (236.59 ml) sugar and mix. Next, pour in almond milk and mix together. Set bowl aside. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take 1 stick ( 8 tbsp) of butter and heat until soft (Do not melt entirely!). Take soft butter and spread it into a 9x9 glass baking dish. Take the mixture from the bowl and pour it evenly into the dish. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Next, take the peaches from the pan and drain the water. Using a spoon, evenly spread peaches over the mixture in the dish. Then, take a generous amount of cinnamon and sprinkle it over top of the cobbler. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Place cobbler into the oven and bake for approx. 45-50 minutes. Timing may vary. Take the cobbler out of the oven and set it aside to cool down for about 5-10 minutes. Serve with vegan vanilla ice cream and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tip: To check if the mixture is baked to your liking, take the pan out of the oven. Take a fork or knife and poke into the mixture. If a bit of mixture is still left on the utensil, feel free to bake the cobbler for another 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Disclaimer: The recipe was made with non-organic sugar. In order to be a completely vegan recipe, be sure to use organic sugar. Timing may vary based on this change.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese with lentils</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Veganuary approaches, more and more people are looking to find ideas for healthier, more environment-friendly, and really yummy vegan recipes. To support your efforts The Gordian Magazine has decided to regularly include new recipes in our monthly publication. Whether you are turning vegan to reduce carbon emissions, protect animals from slaughter or to save a few quid, we got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any favourite vegan/vegetarian recipes, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/&#34;&gt;send them to us&lt;/a&gt;. We would love to publish them. The following Bolognese with lentils recipe was sent to us by UN-aligned treasurer, Jonna Lappalainen. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
