<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/categories/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let technology become a bane for future generations</title>
      <link>/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>unregisteredauthor</author>
      <guid>/comments/dont-let-technology-become-a-bane-for-future-generations/</guid>
      <description>The negative impact of technology, particularly on children, cannot be understated. For our wellbeing’s sake, we need a healthier balance, argues Sailaja.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Technologys-harmful-effects-on-children.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>86 Billion: The human spirt&#39;s fight to live a meaningful life</title>
      <link>/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>unregisteredauthor</author>
      <guid>/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</guid>
      <description>Poems for a better world is collection of poems composed by UN-aligneders for a better better and fairer future.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/86-million-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNICEF and WHO: Alarm over cholera outbreaks</title>
      <link>/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 05:42:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Elvira_Ineza</author>
      <guid>/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</guid>
      <description>As Cholera outbreak spreads across 29 countries, UNICEF calls for 27.5 million to combat disease.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Cholera-case-management-training.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional health: 4 ways you can improve it today</title>
      <link>/health/emotional-health-4-ways-you-can-improve-it-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>unregisteredauthor</author>
      <guid>/health/emotional-health-4-ways-you-can-improve-it-today/</guid>
      <description>Being emotionally healthy is just as important as being physically healthy: the two are closely connected at various levels. To ensure that we lead a fulfilling life, we have to take that extra step.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Emotional-health-4-ways-you-can-improve-it.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHO? Yes, Tedros Again!</title>
      <link>/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 12:01:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</guid>
      <description>Tedros Ghebreyesus gets re-elected by the World Health Assembly (WHA) to a second term despite his affiliation with the repressive regime  that has been accused of torture, repression, and electoral fraud.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Tedros-Honey-Im-home.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is circumcision abuse?</title>
      <link>/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 15:43:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/health/circumcision-is-child-abuse-stop-it/</guid>
      <description>Mutilating the sexual organs of a child, circumcision, in the name of culture, religion or dubious preventative medical claims is outrageous and a blatant breach of the child’s human rights.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Circumcision-is-Child-Abuse-%E2%80%94-Stop-it-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When it was illegal for me to be alive</title>
      <link>/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/health/when-it-is-illegal-for-me-to-be-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Disaster&amp;hellip; it could happen to anyone.” Think about it too much and you will go mad: that endless list of slings and arrows. Yes, it could happen to anyone, but it is best to plod along as though it could never happen to us. Perhaps they deserved it. Karma. Their suffering is like a parallel universe: it need never touch us&amp;hellip; Then, out of the blue, or through a slow and inevitable twist of events, it does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Adrian-Liberto.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“A preventable tragedy”: How dementia became the catalyst that eroded Noor’s family</title>
      <link>/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rubygoldenberg</author>
      <guid>/health/how-dementia-became-the-catalyst-that-eroded-noors-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine visiting your mother or father in their home. When you arrive, you discover that they are in distress in front of the television. They look at you with fear in their eyes; you look at them and then to the ordinary television screen, not understanding the problem. Your mother or father imagines that the people on the television are home intruders, and they ask you how those people got into the house. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/A-story-of-Dementia_-How-a-vivacious-and-vibrant-lady-fell-victim-to-her-own-lack-of-planning.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP is an impostor, so why are we still using it to measure happiness?</title>
      <link>/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-PIL-non-significa-nulla-di-concreto-quindi-perche-lo-utilizziamo-ancora-per-misurare-la-felicita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDP is not a suitable measurement for happiness or welfare. It sucks. Assessing the economy using GDP is destroying our planet. The global community and the United Nation’s sustainable development solutions network (SDSN) need to find other suitable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, the SDSN, an initiative operating under the auspices of the United Nations, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/happiness-trust-and-deaths-under-covid-19/&#34;&gt;publishing a yearly report&lt;/a&gt; on how happy the world is. Embarking upon this fundamentally subjective and unquantifiable quest is no easy task and although the SDSN has significantly improved its methods to measure happiness throughout the years, it still has a long way to go before becoming perfect. This year the report used a host of different criteria to grade the happiness of a nation, these included: gross domestic product per capita (GDP), social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make your own life choices, generosity of the general population and perceptions of internal and external corruption levels. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/GDP-is-an-imposto-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;No, it&#39;s not just a snip&#34;: Why Circumcision is Legalised Child Abuse</title>
      <link>/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 08:56:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/health/why-circumcision-is-legalised-child-abuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mutilating the sexual organs of a child (circumcision) in the name of culture, religion or dubious preventative medical claims is outrageous and a blatant breach of the child’s human rights. Female genital mutilation is thankfully on the decline and relatively rare in developed countries. The cutting of little boys, however, is not. Approximately one third of males are circumcised worldwide. In this article I intend to highlight the futility and barbarity of the practice. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/2.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Tear Gas in the 21st Century is Unacceptable.</title>
      <link>/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 09:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/the-use-of-tear-gas-is-unacceptable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have come a long way since World War I and World War II, yet we still see police forces using dangerous chemical weapons, such as tear gas, against their own civilians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How dangerous are these chemical substances and should local police be permitted to use such weapons against people? How were these weapons used in WWI and WWII?  The following article aims to answer a few of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/WP-Photo-7.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Traumatic Experience with Postpartum - An interview with Rahima El Harrak</title>
      <link>/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rahimaelharrak</author>
      <guid>/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The period soon after childbirth poses substantial health risks for both mother and new-born infant. Yet the postpartum and postnatal period receives less attention from health care providers than pregnancy and childbirth. Models of postpartum and postnatal care have changed little since first developed a century ago. The World Health Organization (WHO) is in the process of revising and updating its guidance on postpartum and postnatal care delivered by skilled providers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Social-Media-post-2-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title>
      <link>/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/The-Use-of-Chinese-Medicine-in-Treating-Covid-19-1.png" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labelling Suicide while Missing the Point</title>
      <link>/health/labelling-suicide-while-missing-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 07:02:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/health/labelling-suicide-while-missing-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-forty-seconds&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every Forty Seconds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 10th September was World Mental Health Day. In this context the WHO published a flyer to raise awareness on suicide and how to help prevent it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/mental-health/suicide/flyer-40seconds-web.pdf?sfvrsn=5ba643c_2&#34;&gt;Working Together to Prevent Suicide&lt;/a&gt;. The WHO highlights the fact that every forty seconds a life is lost to suicide. This is tragic and all the more so because so much more could be done to help, both on an individual and on a social basis. It is reassuring that the WHO is taking this problem seriously, but I object to suicide being so often linked with mental health. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Labelling-Suicide-while-Missing-the-Point-.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
