<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonna.Lappalainen on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/authors/jonna.lappalainen/</link><description>Recent content in Jonna.Lappalainen on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/authors/jonna.lappalainen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring the microscopic world: 10 stunning photos</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</guid><description>In this gallery we will introduce you to 10 extraordinary microscopic photos. See if you can guess the object in question before reading the description on the side. Do also let us know if you have any suggestions about other items that look amazing under the microscope.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Gecko-toe-hairs.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Join the campaign to save cruelty-free cosmetics</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:14 +0200</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</guid><description>On 15th September 2021, the European Parliament voted in favor of a resolution that demands an EU-wide action plan to end the use of animals in testing and research. It also calls for sufficient fundings for developing non-animal testing methods further. Give your support for cruelty-free cosmetics in the EU and join PETA and others by signing the European citizens’ initiative.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/oin-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid><description>Travelling around China and India has provided me with memories of fantastic nature and beautiful cities and towns, all of which have their own unique charm and sights. The most memorable moments of visiting new places, however, are the encounters with friendly and warmhearted locals. I still remember, years after, the kind people who stopped to pose for a stranger with a camera. This gallery presents some of the beautiful portraits along the way.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/9-1024x683.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp; music with our international readers</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 11:17:46 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</guid><description>As summer holidays begin, we want to hear from our readers about their favorite books, TV shows or music.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Share-your-favourite-books-TV-shows-music-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>UN Secretaries-General: A Gallery Timeline</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</guid><description>Since its foundation in October 1945, nine Secretary-Generals have been appointed by the General Assembly. This gallery presents them in chronological order from the first Acting Secretary General Gladwyn Jebb to the present António Guterres.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/1_Gladwyn_Jebb.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Surviving the victory: life in the war-torn Gaza Strip - in Pictures</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</guid><description>Both Israel and Hamas claimed victory over the conflict that lasted for two weeks, took the lives of more than 250 people from both sides, wounded thousands and destroyed buildings including residences, schools and hospitals. It is difficult to see the victory in a conflict that has continued for decades and taken its toll on the civilians. This gallery shows the harsh living conditions in the war-torn Gaza Strip.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/8-Gaza.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>May Day protests: A celebration of spring or a day for activism? - in pictures</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</guid><description>While its roots lie in ancient spring festivals, the modern May Day is now a global day of action for workers' rights, commemorating the 1886 Haymarket Affair and the international labour movement.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/4-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Understanding conspiracy theories and its victims in the golden age of nonsense</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guarded by some 25 000 troops, Joe Biden successfully took the oath of office. Earlier Mr Ex-President had taken off for Mar-a-Lago. Hopes and dreams were shattered. I felt a rush of compassion for the QAnon believers who felt betrayed realising that nothing happened; no arrests, no intervention. It is bitter to realise that the firm ground below one’s feet has collapsed. The liberating, newly revealed truth turned out to be yet another lie. Yet, the question remains: What were they thinking?&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Bolognese with lentils</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</guid><description>&lt;p>As Veganuary approaches, more and more people are looking to find ideas for healthier, more environment-friendly, and really yummy vegan recipes. To support your efforts The Gordian Magazine has decided to regularly include new recipes in our monthly publication. Whether you are turning vegan to reduce carbon emissions, protect animals from slaughter or to save a few quid, we got you covered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have any favourite vegan/vegetarian recipes, please &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/">send them to us&lt;/a>. We would love to publish them. The following Bolognese with lentils recipe was sent to us by UN-aligned treasurer, Jonna Lappalainen. &lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/image-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Music, Drama, Comedy &amp; Illusion at Sichuan Opera - in Pictures</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:29:32 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://un-aligned.org/images/10.bak_-1024x683.jpg" alt="This is a photo of a man wearing a red mask.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The precise technique behind the skill is a guarded secret, traditionally transmitted from generation to generation among theater families. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://un-aligned.org/images/9.bak_-1024x683.jpg" alt="This is a photo of a man spitting fire in a Sichuan opera show.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mask changing is often combined with fire spitting. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://un-aligned.org/images/8.bak_-1024x683.jpg" alt="Chinese man wearing a blue mask.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mask changing - a miraculous, almost instantaneous change of vividly colourful masks dates back to c. 300 years. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/2.bak_.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Cultural Appropriation: What is the Harm?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/cultural-appropriation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/cultural-appropriation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wimoweh / The Lion Sleeps Tonight, Memoirs of a Geisha, Karlie Kloss wearing a Native American inspired headdress at the Victoria’s Secret fashion show. Miley Cyrus twerking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The list could be filled with other, more ordinary affairs such as costume parties, authentic Chinese food, yoga, cornrows, ethnic fabrics or chopsticks as hair sticks. The list of examples of cultural appropriation is so long that it became an activity itself to google what kind of results are given for cultural appropriation combined to any non-Western element. &lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/WP-Photo-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Here is What Social Psychology Say About Prejudice &amp; Discrimination</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/social-psychology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 08:49:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/social-psychology/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>P&lt;/strong>rotests and clashes have spread across the US after the death of African-American George Floyd on May 25th 2020, in police custody. Frustration over the deaths of African-Americans at the hands of police was already rising over the recent deaths of &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52623151">Ahmaud Arbery&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/breonna-taylor-police.html">Breonna Taylor&lt;/a>. These terrible events are only a few examples among the many of conflicts rooted in false judgement, prejudice and discrimination.   &lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article presents prejudice and discrimination from the perspective of social psychology.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Social-Media-post-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Women Composers in the Western Tradition</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 17:24:16 +0200</pubDate><author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</guid><description>&lt;p>The history of western classical music has traditionally been the province of male composers making music for the aristocracy. Rather than due to nonexistence, the absence of women in the standard music histories has been the result of the common practices of musicologists of the past. First of all, many musicologists focused more on the documents of music (manuscripts, prints and treatises) than on the sociology of music. Fewer documents of the music of women or of the lower classes have remained. Second, musicologists have focused on the development of musical styles and the progressive works that engendered new genres. &lt;a href="https://un-aligned.org/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/">Most women&lt;/a> were excluded from professional musical positions, which at least partly led to them entering new styles “late”.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Bernardo_Strozzi_001-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>