<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonna.Lappalainen on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/jonna.lappalainen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jonna.Lappalainen on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/jonna.lappalainen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the microscopic world: 10 stunning photos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 06:58:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/10-photos-of-the-microscopic-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Sand.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Sand&lt;/strong&gt;: Composed of finely divided rock and mineral particles, sand looks surprisingly beautiful under a microscope. This image shows the star-shaped sand in Hatoma Island. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:2085f_Japon_Hatoma.jpg&#34;&gt;Alain Couette/CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Butterfly-wing-1024x782.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Butterfly wing&lt;/strong&gt;: Thousands of pigmented scales cover butterfly wings, giving the insect its magnificent colourful appearance. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/zeissmicro/8271132283&#34;&gt;Zeiss Microscopy/CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Sea-water-1024x716.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Sea water&lt;/strong&gt;: This image shows a range of marine microplankton found in sea water. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Marine_microplankton.jpg&#34;&gt;David Liittschwager/CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the campaign to save cruelty-free cosmetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/join-the-campaign-to-save-cruelty-free-cosmetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EU&amp;rsquo;s ban on animal testing for cosmetics is under threath as new analysis (link) finds that cosmetics sold in the EU and UK contain chemicals tested on animals. Furthermore, the European Chemicals Agency (ECHA) is requesting new animal tests on ingredients that have been used in cosmetics safely for years. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than 400 animal rights organizations and companies, including PETA, The Body Shop, Dove and it´s parent company Unilever have signed and sent an open letter to the Presidents of the European Commission, the Parliament and the Council to fully commit to the EU-regulation and continue with its course for a global ban by 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/8-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man stops to smile while playing cards in a town of northwestern Sichuan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Rajasthani man plays music on the street. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man who arranges camel safari tours rests on the desert in Rajasthan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man prepares for a photoshoot in a teahouse in Pengzhen town. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A woman celebrates New Year in the monastic town of Tongren. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fervid summer: Share your favourite books, TV shows &amp; music with our international readers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 11:17:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/opportunities/share-your-favourite-books-tv-shows-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more people are using their free time in summer to relax and enjoy a good book, movie, TV show or a piece of music. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UN-aligneders are from all across the world. We currently have members from over 24 countries, so we are certain that curating a list of your favorite entertainment will help inspire our international community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please fill out the form below and send us your suggestions; tell us also why enjoyed them and will publish your answers on The Gordian Magazine, UN-aligned’s monthly publication. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Secretaries-General: A Gallery Timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1_Gladwyn_Jebb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First General Assembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gladwyn Jebb (on the right) attending the first session of the United Nations General Assembly in London on the 10th of January 1946. Jebb was the Acting Secretary-General from October 1945 to the appointment of Trygve Lie in 1946. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/un_photo/24229280176/in/album-72157663180292401/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; by Marcel Bolomey / UN Photo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2_Trygve_Lie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trygve Lie, first UN Secretary-General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lie served as the Secretary-General from 1946 until his resignation from his second term in 1952. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/norwayun/4898234974&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; by UN Photo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving the victory: life in the war-torn Gaza Strip - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10-Gaza-1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Al-Shati camp/Beach camp. At least 10 people, including 8 children, were killed in the bombardment of the Al-Shati refugee camp during the May 2021 conflict. Photo by Magne Hagesæter / CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9-Gaza-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11 year old Manar and her friends at their damaged school in Gaza. Manar and her family´s house was destroyed during the 2014 Gaza War. After losing her home, Manar hopes to find happiness in her school. Photo by Anas al Baba/Oxfam / CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May Day protests: A celebration of spring or a day for activism? - in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/may-day-protests-and-celebrations-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May Day, Labour Day or International Workers´ Day has been celebrated in various ways throughout history. The Modern May Day is not only celebrated around the world by parades and parties, but also demonstrations and rallies in support of workers and human rights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On May 1st, 1890, demonstrators called by the Second International gathered together to honour the martyrs of the Haymarket Affair in 1886. Since then, it has been more associated with the labour movement of the 20th century than with its roots as an ancient spring festival. This gallery guides you through some of the various different events that take place on May Day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding conspiracy theories and its victims in the golden age of nonsense</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guarded by some 25 000 troops, Joe Biden successfully took the oath of office. Earlier Mr Ex-President had taken off for Mar-a-Lago. Hopes and dreams were shattered. I felt a rush of compassion for the QAnon believers who felt betrayed realising that nothing happened; no arrests, no intervention. It is bitter to realise that the firm ground below one’s feet has collapsed. The liberating, newly revealed truth turned out to be yet another lie. Yet, the question remains: What were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bolognese with lentils</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bolognese-with-lentils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Veganuary approaches, more and more people are looking to find ideas for healthier, more environment-friendly, and really yummy vegan recipes. To support your efforts The Gordian Magazine has decided to regularly include new recipes in our monthly publication. Whether you are turning vegan to reduce carbon emissions, protect animals from slaughter or to save a few quid, we got you covered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any favourite vegan/vegetarian recipes, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/about/contact/register/&#34;&gt;send them to us&lt;/a&gt;. We would love to publish them. The following Bolognese with lentils recipe was sent to us by UN-aligned treasurer, Jonna Lappalainen. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music, Drama, Comedy &amp; Illusion at Sichuan Opera - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:29:32 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man wearing a red mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The precise technique behind the skill is a guarded secret, traditionally transmitted from generation to generation among theater families. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man spitting fire in a Sichuan opera show.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mask changing is often combined with fire spitting. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/8.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chinese man wearing a blue mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mask changing - a miraculous, almost instantaneous change of vividly colourful masks dates back to c. 300 years. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Appropriation: What is the Harm?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/cultural-appropriation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wimoweh / The Lion Sleeps Tonight, Memoirs of a Geisha, Karlie Kloss wearing a Native American inspired headdress at the Victoria’s Secret fashion show. Miley Cyrus twerking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The list could be filled with other, more ordinary affairs such as costume parties, authentic Chinese food, yoga, cornrows, ethnic fabrics or chopsticks as hair sticks. The list of examples of cultural appropriation is so long that it became an activity itself to google what kind of results are given for cultural appropriation combined to any non-Western element. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here is What Social Psychology Say About Prejudice &amp; Discrimination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 08:49:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rotests and clashes have spread across the US after the death of African-American George Floyd on May 25th 2020, in police custody. Frustration over the deaths of African-Americans at the hands of police was already rising over the recent deaths of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52623151&#34;&gt;Ahmaud Arbery&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/article/breonna-taylor-police.html&#34;&gt;Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;. These terrible events are only a few examples among the many of conflicts rooted in false judgement, prejudice and discrimination.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article presents prejudice and discrimination from the perspective of social psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women Composers in the Western Tradition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 17:24:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/women-composers-in-the-western-tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The history of western classical music has traditionally been the province of male composers making music for the aristocracy. Rather than due to nonexistence, the absence of women in the standard music histories has been the result of the common practices of musicologists of the past. First of all, many musicologists focused more on the documents of music (manuscripts, prints and treatises) than on the sociology of music. Fewer documents of the music of women or of the lower classes have remained. Second, musicologists have focused on the development of musical styles and the progressive works that engendered new genres. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/ruth-crawford-seeger-an-avant-gardist-who-defined-modern-american-music/&#34;&gt;Most women&lt;/a&gt; were excluded from professional musical positions, which at least partly led to them entering new styles “late”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
