<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wangzhi on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>https://un-aligned.org/authors/wangzhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wangzhi on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 20:46:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/authors/wangzhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with UN-aligned&#39;s Language Courses</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 20:46:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>wangzhi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/un-aligned-news/my-experience-with-unaligneds-language-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally discovered UN-aligned through a post on Facebook and then joined the community as I found it quite interesting and inspiring. I also thought that reading articles of interest, such as those relating to climate change, could help me improve my English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was amazed about the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I desperately need to improve my English, I later also registered onto the English course. My tutor, Adrian, reached out to me soon after, and unexpectedly, this course turned out to be totally free! But what amazed me the most, was the tutor&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and wide range of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Bitmap-Copy-3.png" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan and its nuclear waste problem</title>
      <link>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>wangzhi</author>
      <guid>https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear leaks are probably among the most horrifying accidents possible due to their long-term detrimental damage to life and environment. Eight years after the nuclear leak from Japan’s Fukushima power plant, local residents, many of whom are fishermen, are still suffering the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dumping-the-radioactively-contaminated-water-directly-into-the-sea-in-order-to-dilute-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tragically, they now have to face another nightmare. However, rather than being triggered by a natural disaster, like the nuclear accident was, this time, it was all caused by their government’s proposal of dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it. So far, the plant’s operator, Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO), has already stored over 1 million tons of radioactive water used to cool destroyed reactors and the amount is still increasing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/jason-blackeye-zAITDJYV09w-unsplash.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
