<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:24:13 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Infernal Gates: Confronting the Oil Industry&#39;s Greed</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 15:24:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/confronting-the-oil-industry-greed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beneath the surface of our greedy economy lies a lurking danger, driven by the relentless greed of giant oil companies. Like the ominous entrance to Dante&amp;rsquo;s Inferno, their self-serving position and inaction threaten to unleash chaos and destruction. However, before shedding light on hidden environmental and ethical transgressions across scattered timelines, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the lethal nature of the oil giants&amp;rsquo; self-serving stance and their culpability for inaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;barring-the-gates&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barring the gates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All art aficionados would be familiar with Rodin’s The Thinker, or representations of it, some may have even been lucky enough to see the pensive figure in his intended setting sitting atop of The Gates of Hell. Whatever was he thinking? My guess is that he was contemplating what Sartre put into words decades later: &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rsquo;enfer, c&amp;rsquo;est les autres&amp;rdquo; (Hell is other people).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Wealth Gap in Arab Economies: The Power of a Progressive Taxation System</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/closing-the-wealth-gap-in-arab-economies-the-power-of-a-progressive-taxation-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/closing-the-wealth-gap-in-arab-economies-the-power-of-a-progressive-taxation-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 4th 2023, Dubai announced an 8.7 trillion-dollar expansion plan as a part of its diversification plan to shift its focus from revenues generated from oil reserves. The emirate aspires to become a global financial hub by boosting its manufacturing and logistics, making it an attractive proposition for foreign investors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saudi Arabia’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vision2030.gov.sa/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vision 2030&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is another diversification strategy under the leadership of Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman to reduce its dependence on hydrocarbons. The government estimates it can raise 1 trillion riyals in non-governmental revenue and decrease the unemployment rate from 12% to 7% by 2030. Qatar also positions itself to be one of the emerging investment destinations by implementing the policies from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gco.gov.qa/en/about-qatar/national-vision2030/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Qatar National Vision 2030&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Wealth Gap: A Blueprint for Poverty Eradication</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/strongbridging-the-wealth-gap-a-blueprint-for-poverty-eradication-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Redefining our modern self-serving economics to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reality is what keeps us safe. It informed our past and it guides our present. Reality is our safe zone. It is the anchor on which our boat is secured. It is the devil we know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as anyone who has owned a boat can tell you, a tight anchor is the surest way to sink your boat: a change in tide, a swell… and without the leeway in your rope, you are underwater. The fact is, reality changes and unless we adapt and evolve with it, we are done for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UN is failing to eradicate poverty</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/the-un-is-failing-to-eradicate-poverty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poverty, to put it simply, is one of humankind’s greatest ills and despite various ways to quantify, analyse or measure it, the problem remains unsolved. With the world finding itself in unprecedented straits owing to the COVID-19 pandemic, which has not only claimed the lives of 4,000,000, but has revealed ominous and record-breaking poverty worldwide, humanity more than ever needs its leaders to come together and work towards effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Growth Dilemma</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 11:08:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/the-growth-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-della-crescita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcending-simplistic-assumptions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transcending simplistic assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Society is faced with a profound dilemma. To reject growth is to risk economic and social collapse. To pursue it relentlessly is to endanger the ecosystems on which we depend for long term survival. This delusional strategy has reached its limits. Simplistic assumptions that capitalism’s propensity for efficiency will stabilise the climate and solve the problems of resource scarcity are almost literally bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Ways to Create a Healthy Economy with Kate Raworth - Podcast</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:36:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kate Raworth first introduced her visual representation of what a healthy economy could look like in a 2012 OXFAM discussion paper titled: &amp;ldquo;A safe and just space for humanity: can we live within the doughnut?&amp;rdquo; The doughnut represented the safe space where humanity could thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits, namely our social and planetary boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raworth’s 2017 book develops the idea further. The seven “ways” she explores are simple, well researched, grounded and achievable. Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/the-doughnut-economy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GDP is an impostor, so why are we still using it to measure happiness?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/why-are-we-still-using-gdp-to-measure-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Italiano_-Il-PIL-non-significa-nulla-di-concreto-quindi-perche-lo-utilizziamo-ancora-per-misurare-la-felicita.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GDP is not a suitable measurement for happiness or welfare. It sucks. Assessing the economy using GDP is destroying our planet. The global community and the United Nation’s sustainable development solutions network (SDSN) need to find other suitable alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since 2011, the SDSN, an initiative operating under the auspices of the United Nations, has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://worldhappiness.report/ed/2021/happiness-trust-and-deaths-under-covid-19/&#34;&gt;publishing a yearly report&lt;/a&gt; on how happy the world is. Embarking upon this fundamentally subjective and unquantifiable quest is no easy task and although the SDSN has significantly improved its methods to measure happiness throughout the years, it still has a long way to go before becoming perfect. This year the report used a host of different criteria to grade the happiness of a nation, these included: gross domestic product per capita (GDP), social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make your own life choices, generosity of the general population and perceptions of internal and external corruption levels. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Doughnut Economy: &#34;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 10:40:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
