<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th July, the Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity. That’s no big deal, one would imagine, but sadly, for the United Nations, it is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is why a few months ago UN-aligned launched a campaign to bar countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;criminalise LGBTQ+ rights from the Human Rights Council&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the fact that our open letter to the United Nations was backed by several organisations and human rights activists, the letter was ignored.&lt;a href=&#34;https://documents-dds-ny.un.org/doc/UNDOC/GEN/G22/407/77/PDF/G2240777.pdf?OpenElement&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Bachelet&#39;s visit to China: &#34;Unacceptable&#34; is a missing word from the UN&#39;s arsenal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 11:46:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 28, Michelle Bachelet, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, ended a six-day official visit to China. The trip was controversial from the start as critics claimed it would gloss over Beijing’s human rights abuses. On May 29, the UN issued a press release aimed at addressing some of these concerns, particularly with regards to the crackdown on political freedoms in Hong Kong, the governance of Tibet and the treatment of the Uyghurs in Xinjiang.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/8-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man stops to smile while playing cards in a town of northwestern Sichuan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Rajasthani man plays music on the street. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man who arranges camel safari tours rests on the desert in Rajasthan. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/1-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A man prepares for a photoshoot in a teahouse in Pengzhen town. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2-683x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A woman celebrates New Year in the monastic town of Tongren. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music, Drama, Comedy &amp; Illusion at Sichuan Opera - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:29:32 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man wearing a red mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The precise technique behind the skill is a guarded secret, traditionally transmitted from generation to generation among theater families. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man spitting fire in a Sichuan opera show.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mask changing is often combined with fire spitting. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/8.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chinese man wearing a blue mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mask changing - a miraculous, almost instantaneous change of vividly colourful masks dates back to c. 300 years. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document no. 3 and what it reveals about the Chinese Communist Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:07:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is lying about the coronavirus, document no.3 reveals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-we-are&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we are&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic known as the coronavirus Pandemic started in December in Wuhan China, and as of 26th of April, 210 countries and territories have been affected by the virus, close to 3 million people have been diagnosed with the disease, and more than 200,000 people have tragically passed away of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In late January Dr. Zhong Nanshan, one of the advisors in managing the crisis in China, was asked whether he thought that the virus outbreak would be as bad as the 2003 SARS pandemic. Dr. Zhong Nanshan replied with absolute certainty that this would not be the case. He attributed this to advancements in medical sciences and the experience gathered from the SARS pandemic. The SARS outbreak in 2003 only infected around 8000 people and killed a bit over 800. At this point approximately three months have passed since that initial interview and we must ask ourselves how things ended up like this…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
