<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>Despite relentless conquests, the struggle for Tibet’s sovereignty extends beyond the protection of its heritage; it&#39;s a fight for the nation&#39;s very spirit, enduring as the mountains that embrace it.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/How-Tibets-Peaceful-Nation-Building-Challenges-Chinese-Rule.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China in Focus at UN &#34;Selective Rights Council&#34; (UNRC)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/china-in-focus-at-un-selective-rights-council-unrc/</guid>
      <description>The Human Rights Council passed a resolution on the protection against violence and discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/China-in-Focus-at-UN-22Selective-Rights-Council22-UNRC.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Bachelet&#39;s visit to China: &#34;Unacceptable&#34; is a missing word from the UN&#39;s arsenal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 11:46:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/michelle-bachelet-visit-to-china/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, “concerns” is one of the strongest words in the United Nations’ arsenal, only a notch or two below “unacceptable”- its primary weapon – which, to no one’s surprise, was not used during this visit.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/Michelle-Bachelet-visit-to-China.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portraits along the way - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/portraits-along-the-way-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Travelling around China and India has provided me with memories of fantastic nature and beautiful cities and towns, all of which have their own unique charm and sights. The most memorable moments of visiting new places, however, are the encounters with friendly and warmhearted locals. I still remember, years after, the kind people who stopped to pose for a stranger with a camera. This gallery presents some of the beautiful portraits along the way.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/9-1024x683.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea: A convenient pawn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:55:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/north-korea-a-convenient-pawn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Korea is usually in the headlines for reasons ranging from the terrifying to the bizarre. This month, their leader Kim Jong-Un is once again subject to rumours that he is dead. This is the second time since April that the speculation has emerged and been dismissed by North Korea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much time can be spent considering what would have to occur in order for the regime to collapse. Some speculate that the death of Kim Jong-Un could have a snowball effect on North Korea as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/9-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music, Drama, Comedy &amp; Illusion at Sichuan Opera - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:29:32 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Jonna.Lappalainen</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/music-drama-comedy-and-illusion-at-sichuan-opera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man wearing a red mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise technique behind the skill is a guarded secret, traditionally transmitted from generation to generation among theater families. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is a photo of a man spitting fire in a Sichuan opera show.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mask changing is often combined with fire spitting. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/8.bak_-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chinese man wearing a blue mask.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mask changing - a miraculous, almost instantaneous change of vividly colourful masks dates back to c. 300 years. © Jonna Lappalainen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/2.bak_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/The-Use-of-Chinese-Medicine-in-Treating-Covid-19-1.png" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document no. 3 and what it reveals about the Chinese Communist Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:07:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Anonymous</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/china-is-lying-about-the-coronavirus-document-no-3-reavels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is lying about the coronavirus, document no.3 reveals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-we-are&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where we are&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global pandemic known as the coronavirus Pandemic started in December in Wuhan China, and as of 26th of April, 210 countries and territories have been affected by the virus, close to 3 million people have been diagnosed with the disease, and more than 200,000 people have tragically passed away of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late January Dr. Zhong Nanshan, one of the advisors in managing the crisis in China, was asked whether he thought that the virus outbreak would be as bad as the 2003 SARS pandemic. Dr. Zhong Nanshan replied with absolute certainty that this would not be the case. He attributed this to advancements in medical sciences and the experience gathered from the SARS pandemic. The SARS outbreak in 2003 only infected around 8000 people and killed a bit over 800. At this point approximately three months have passed since that initial interview and we must ask ourselves how things ended up like this…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://localhost:1313/images/Pissing-in-the-sacred-brook_-humanity%E2%80%99s-abuse-of-water-and-water%E2%80%99s-revenge-1-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
