<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/water/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Water on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:28:47 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 ingenious solutions to abate the overexploitation of water</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:28:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Water is one of the stanchions of life. Around 60 % of the human body is made up of water. Drinking water from pristine sources has been linked to a higher lifespan. Water provides oxygen in the form of dissolved oxygen to marine organisms. Global warming leads to an increase in the temperature of the water. This reduces the amount of oxygen dissolved in the water proving detrimental for aquatic life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where water is a gift: The outskirts of Nairobi in pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 07:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/where-water-is-a-gift-the-outskirts-of-nairobi-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7996-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A female tailor living in her one-roomed house made with corrugated metal sheets. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7787-2-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two girls from the Masai tribe. In this tribe, literacy for girls has no value and families consider it  just a waste of money. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_8019-1024x819.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A family in Gaucho, the suburbs of Nairobi. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/IMG_7890-1024x682.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The containers that are used to carry water were used for storing fertilisers or oil. The water in basins and pumps is often contaminated. © Anahita Ahmadi&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pissing in the sacred brook: humanity’s abuse of water</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Water, water, every where, And all the boards did shrink; Water, water, every where, Nor any drop to drink.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from &lt;em&gt;The Rime of the Ancient Mariner&lt;/em&gt;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/&#34;&gt;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;/a&gt; describes part of the curse inflicted on the mariner and his crew for his having shot the albatross whose noble presence had been bestowing a blessing to their voyage. In many ways, most of our leaders are like that mariner, killing Mother Earth who guarantees our wellbeing: only that these leaders have been doing it more slowly. We are polluting the air, the land and the waters, and even though we can see the curse materialising before our very eyes, we carry on, regardless. Today I will focus on Water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
