<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caravaggio on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/caravaggio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Caravaggio on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/caravaggio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Michelangelo’s &#34;Fruit Basket&#34; captures the fleeting essence of life</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/michelangelos-fruit-basket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/michelangelos-fruit-basket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always postponed examining the canvas: the &amp;ldquo;Fruit Basket&amp;rdquo; for various, and undoubtedly futile, reasons. The first and foremost relates to the subjects, or rather objects to be examined. In fact, the absence of any human presence seemed to me to be an almost insurmountable hurdle in my search for feelings, in contrast to the various subjects depicted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/caravaggio/&#34;&gt;Caravaggio in his other works&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, the setting of the canvas also initially blocked me, because it lacked the obvious theatricality of Merisi&amp;rsquo;s Roman works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Caravaggio&#39;s &#39;The Burial of Saint Lucy&#39; Transforms the Divine into the Earthly</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-caravaggios-the-burial-of-saint-lucy-transforms-the-divine-into-the-earthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-caravaggios-the-burial-of-saint-lucy-transforms-the-divine-into-the-earthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-from-iconic-traditions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking from iconic traditions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both artistic and sculptural representations traditionally depict St. Lucy in celestial grandeur. She is often shown holding the palm of her martyrdom, which occurred in Syracuse in 304, in one hand, and a saucer containing her eyes in the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This iconographic element is a nod to her role as the protector of sight, although it bears no relation to the martyrdom she endured. The origin of this specific veneration is tied to her name: Lucy, or Lucia, derives from the Latin term &amp;rsquo;lux,&amp;rsquo; meaning light—an element naturally associated with eyesight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Transcending Strokes&#39;: Caravaggio&#39;s Unmistakable Emotion in &#34;Judith and Holofernes&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/transcending-strokes-caravaggios-unmistakable-emotion-in-judith-and-holofernes-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:15:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/transcending-strokes-caravaggios-unmistakable-emotion-in-judith-and-holofernes-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The repetition of distinctive stylistic elements helps art scholars, when necessary, to identify and recognise the authors. In the case of Caravaggio, the most frequent distinctive elements are different: the stroke of the drawing; the choice of the same models for the various characters; the way of interpreting the colours; the contrast between shadow and light…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet what in my eyes makes Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s hand truly unmistakable, even more than the presence of these objective stylistic elements, is the emotional tension that shines through the faces of the characters who, in most cases, tell us about the eternal conflict between good and evil that has always accompanied man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caravaggio&#39;s Crucifixion of St. Peter: The Unseen Heroism</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-the-crucifixion-of-saint-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 13:38:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-the-crucifixion-of-saint-peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My fixation with Caravaggio is one that prompts me to continually seek avenues to discuss his work. The necessity to scrutinise the Crucifixion of St. Peter, residing in the Cerasi Chapel, provides a convenient pretext. This painting, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/&#34;&gt;the Conversion of St. Paul,&lt;/a&gt; was crafted for the same patron.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, the underlying motivation is less about circumstance and more about an earnest fascination with Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s life and artistic creations, even though the root of this allure remains elusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conversion of St. Paul by Caravaggio: A Masterpiece of Dramatic Intensity and Transformative Power</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-conversion-of-st-paul-by-caravaggio-a-masterpiece-of-dramatic-intensity-and-transformative-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-conversion-and-its-relevance-to-the-painting&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meaning of ‘Conversion’ and Its Relevance to the Painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;lsquo;conversion&amp;rsquo; is derived from the Latin word &amp;lsquo;conversio&amp;rsquo;, which denotes a movement from one place to another, a turning towards something or someone, or a change of direction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the word itself does not necessarily connote any religious or moral significance, it presents boundless possibilities for internal and external transformation. Change can happen by deliberate choice or can be brought about unexpectedly by life&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable events, which often add new shades and dimensions to our existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caravaggio and the unveiling of truth</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-and-the-unveiling-of-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/caravaggio-and-the-unveiling-of-truth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each of us is constantly torn between comfortable facade truths, and those deep and real truths that sometimes elude us. For most people, it is relatively easy to keep the uncomfortable aspects of authentic truths hidden. In the case of artists, on the other hand, especially the best known ones, this secrecy is lost because their lives, and their works, are often under the lens of historical and stylistic research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Caravaggio&#39;s Nativity with Saints Lorenzo and Francesco</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:02:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lost-nativity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lost Nativity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The multiplicity of subjects and themes present in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/&#34;&gt;Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s works&lt;/a&gt; allows me to continue talking about him, through his works, even in the period of the year when each of us could succumb to the easy temptation to choose discounted topics, through clichés. During the month of December we were constantly bombarded with images that create romantic and idealised suggestions. Despite the decidedly muffled atmosphere, I will try to talk with you about the nativity in art trying to maintain a critical, attentive and open attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Michelangelo to Michelangelo: The story behind Caravaggio his &#34;Death of the Virgin&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have yet reached my own style in writing and I don&amp;rsquo;t even think I want to reach it so as not to end up entangled in webs created by myself. I do not love to rely on chance, but do enjoy spontaneous and sudden thoughts. Precisely for this reason, following what came to my mind as soon as I delivered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/when-art-is-mystery-the-sculpture-of-the-veiled-christ/&#34;&gt;last article&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to continue talking about freedom of expression in art, just as I had already done when talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-perfected-thought-michelangelo-buonarroti/&#34;&gt;Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s Pietà Rondanini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
