<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nepal on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nepal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nepal on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nepal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nepal&#39;s National Parks: A Conservation Success Shadowed by Local Struggles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Nepal, majestic national parks thrive as sanctuaries for wildlife, but for the local communities who are grappling with human rights abuses the path to harmonious coexistence remains fraught with challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The value of protected spaces like National Parks is undeniable. Nepal&amp;rsquo;s journey with these parks began in 1993, when the Forest Act recognised certain &amp;lsquo;protected forests&amp;rsquo; for their environmental, scientific and cultural value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the royal hunting grounds, these spaces have evolved into critical conservation centres, forming a key part of Nepal&amp;rsquo;s forest management strategy. Today, Nepal boasts about 20 such protected spaces. However, while these parks aim for conservation, they also pose challenges, particularly for local communities with restricted access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Forest Boundaries: Sunil Pariyar on the Dalit Struggle and DANAR&#39;s Impact in Nepal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the northern region of the Indian subcontinent, at the base of the Himalayan Mountains, lies the country of Nepal. A place rich in cultural and natural diversity, Nepal&amp;rsquo;s vibrant history intertwines with the lives of its Dalit citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dalit communities in South Asian countries like India and Nepal endure persistent marginalisation, exclusion and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/pages/article/indias-untouchables-face-violence-discrimination&#34;&gt;human rights violations&lt;/a&gt;. They live in constant apprehension of public humiliation, assault and abuse, with upper-caste groups frequently using violence as a means to maintain societal hierarchies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kathmandu: The Colorful Lands of Nepal - in pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 15:00:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/kathmandu-the-colorful-lands-of-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in my life, I discovered a truthful and genuine smile in the poor areas of Nepal and India. From a distance you may only see men, women, and children who live in squatter areas or even on the streetsides, but when you get closer, you see a special kind of joy in the occasional smiles of these people. These smiles may not last forever, but when they appear, they&amp;rsquo;re as genuine as they can be. I call this the magic of Nepal and India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
