<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate Emergency on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/climate-emergency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate Emergency on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 21:33:28 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/climate-emergency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sky-Born Infernos: How Pyrocumulonimbus Clouds Supercharge Wildfires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sky-born-infernos-the-deadly-feedback-loop-of-pyrocumulonimbus-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 21:33:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sky-born-infernos-the-deadly-feedback-loop-of-pyrocumulonimbus-clouds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pyrocumulonimbus clouds—towering thunderclouds born from wildfire heat—are becoming an increasingly dangerous force in today’s fire-prone world. Unlike typical storm clouds, these massive systems form when the intense heat from large wildfires creates powerful updrafts, carrying smoke, ash, and moisture high into the atmosphere. As the rising air cools and condenses, it forms thunderclouds that do far more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Far from offering relief, pyrocumulonimbus clouds often worsen fire conditions. They generate lightning capable of sparking new fires miles away from the original blaze, while their strong winds can fan existing flames, pushing wildfires across vast stretches of land with alarming speed. Despite their storm-like appearance, these clouds rarely produce significant rainfall—leaving the fires beneath them undoused and free to spread.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Use Carbon Dioxide to Curb Global Warming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-use-carbon-dioxide-to-curb-global-warming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 12:37:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-use-carbon-dioxide-to-curb-global-warming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Global warming, a crisis primarily driven by the emission of greenhouse gases such as carbon dioxide, calls for innovative solutions. Our reliance on fossil fuels for electricity generation, transportation, industrial processes and domestic heating has exponentially escalated carbon dioxide levels. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This gas is a significant contributor to the greenhouse effect, which in turn accelerates global warming. But what if we could transform this problem into a solution? Here are four ways we can utilise carbon dioxide to help keep the global temperature rise below 1.5 degrees Celsius by 2100.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is UK&#39;s North Sea Drilling Plan a Sustainable Solution? An Impact Assessment Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-findings&#34;&gt;Key findings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK&amp;rsquo;s proposed drilling plan has minimal immediate impact on energy security, offering only short-term reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With sustainable energy advancements, extensive reliance on fossil fuels is becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan&amp;rsquo;s short-term financial benefits are economically short-sighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investing in a net-zero economy and green jobs is more beneficial for long-term economic growth and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drilling plan could harm climate commitments and marine biodiversity in the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shift to renewable energy and green bond financing is advised, echoing global body recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal&#39;s National Parks: A Conservation Success Shadowed by Local Struggles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/ramifications-of-nepal-forest-policies-on-marginalised-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Nepal, majestic national parks thrive as sanctuaries for wildlife, but for the local communities who are grappling with human rights abuses the path to harmonious coexistence remains fraught with challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The value of protected spaces like National Parks is undeniable. Nepal&amp;rsquo;s journey with these parks began in 1993, when the Forest Act recognised certain &amp;lsquo;protected forests&amp;rsquo; for their environmental, scientific and cultural value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the royal hunting grounds, these spaces have evolved into critical conservation centres, forming a key part of Nepal&amp;rsquo;s forest management strategy. Today, Nepal boasts about 20 such protected spaces. However, while these parks aim for conservation, they also pose challenges, particularly for local communities with restricted access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Forest Boundaries: Sunil Pariyar on the Dalit Struggle and DANAR&#39;s Impact in Nepal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:30:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/sunil-pariyar-on-dalit-and-danar-impact-in-nepal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the northern region of the Indian subcontinent, at the base of the Himalayan Mountains, lies the country of Nepal. A place rich in cultural and natural diversity, Nepal&amp;rsquo;s vibrant history intertwines with the lives of its Dalit citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dalit communities in South Asian countries like India and Nepal endure persistent marginalisation, exclusion and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/pages/article/indias-untouchables-face-violence-discrimination&#34;&gt;human rights violations&lt;/a&gt;. They live in constant apprehension of public humiliation, assault and abuse, with upper-caste groups frequently using violence as a means to maintain societal hierarchies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Solutions to Combat Climate Change: 4 Groundbreaking Approaches</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ingenious-engineering-solutions-to-cool-down-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 12:31:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ingenious-engineering-solutions-to-cool-down-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the effects of climate change continue to worsen, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to explore innovative engineering solutions that can help us mitigate these impacts. This article delves into four groundbreaking engineering solutions that are providing hope for a more sustainable future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases from fossil fuel-based power generation, transportation, industrial processes, and the like, are exacerbating the process of global warming. To restrict the global temperature rise to 1.5 degrees centigrade by 2100, it is essential to adopt engineering solutions that can aid in reducing this warming effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Power of a Thriving Bioeconomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/unlocking-the-power-of-a-thriving-bioeconomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/unlocking-the-power-of-a-thriving-bioeconomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we face the pressing issue of climate change, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we need solutions that are both sustainable and equitable. That&amp;rsquo;s where the concept of a bioeconomy comes in. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By harnessing renewable resources, a bioeconomy has the potential to not only help mitigate emissions, but also support communities that have been historically marginalised, such as forest dwellers, farmers and indigenous populations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in order to fully realise the benefits of a bioeconomy, we need to ensure that it is supported by smart policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Combat the Negative Impacts of Global Warming on Biodiversity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/4-ways-to-combat-the-negative-impacts-of-global-warming-on-biodiversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The contemporary phenomena of global warming has created a &amp;ldquo;Hothouse Earth&amp;rdquo; and has wreaked havoc on pristine ecosystems. The melting of glaciers exposes vast swathes of marine water to atmospheric carbon dioxide, lowering pH from alkaline values and threatening the survival of corals and other marine organisms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the indiscriminate felling of certain species of flora and the poaching of certain species of animals for medicinal purposes exacerbates their extinction. Clearing tropical rainforests for agriculture also strips the planet of its carbon sinks and lungs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategies for achieving decarbonisation in consonance with energy security</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/strategies-for-achieving-decarbonisation-in-consonance-with-energy-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/strategies-for-achieving-decarbonisation-in-consonance-with-energy-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy is one of the inalienable stanchions of modern human-social-industrial life. The current global temperature is 1.1 degree centigrade above pre-industrial levels. The recent devastating events like increase in glacial lake outburst floods,  droughts , cyclones, forest fires, and the like could be attributed to the rising global temperatures. As the pernicious effects of global warming are now no longer covert, it is high time to resort to decarbonisation using a combination of efficient technologies and carbon dioxide sequestration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to combat forest fires: causes and 4 solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-combat-forest-fires-causes-and-4-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-combat-forest-fires-causes-and-4-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, forest fires are proliferating. The current temperature is around 1.1. degree centigrade above pre-industrial levels. This increase in temperature could be attributed to anthropogenic activity-induced global warming. The concentration of gases like carbon dioxide is increasing continuously in the atmosphere due to anthropogenic activities like fossil fuel-based power generation and the use of fossil fuels in internal combustion engines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s (NOAA) Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii, USA recorded high amounts of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere. The greenhouse gases trap infrared radiation leading to a spike in global temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 ingenious solutions to abate the overexploitation of water</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:28:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/3-ingenious-solutions-to-abate-the-overexploitation-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Water is one of the stanchions of life. Around 60 % of the human body is made up of water. Drinking water from pristine sources has been linked to a higher lifespan. Water provides oxygen in the form of dissolved oxygen to marine organisms. Global warming leads to an increase in the temperature of the water. This reduces the amount of oxygen dissolved in the water proving detrimental for aquatic life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Transportation Green? 3 Alternatives to Internal Combustion Engines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-make-transportation-green-3-alternatives-to-internal-combustion-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 10:46:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/how-to-make-transportation-green-3-alternatives-to-internal-combustion-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pollution from transportation is an inexorable contributor towards climate change. Internal Combustion Engine (ICE) powered vehicles use fossil fuels like Compressed Natural Gas, Gasoline, Diesel etc. Here, an interesting trend is observed. The higher the hydrocarbon, the greater is the extent of pollution caused because of it. This could be attributed to the presence of a larger number of impurities in the liquid stage compared to the gaseous stage. Thus, the extent of environmental pollution caused by Diesel powered vehicles is greater than Natural Gas based vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making environment and development go hand in hand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/making-environment-and-development-go-hand-in-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/making-environment-and-development-go-hand-in-hand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;remediation-and-restoration&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remediation and restoration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrestrial ecosystem restoration can be augmented with novel afforestation techniques like Miyawaki method thereby increasing biodiversity along with sequestering greenhouse gasses. Marine ecosystems can be restored by techniques like Floating Solar PhotoVoltaics, offshore wind farms, wind-Solar hybrids and powered Biorock accretion techniques followed by the insertion of a living coral in the skeleton to enhance biodiversity in these “rainforests” of the oceans. Oil spills from ships can have a pernicious effect on fragile marine ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pissing in the sacred brook: humanity’s abuse of water</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/humanitys-abuse-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Water, water, every where, And all the boards did shrink; Water, water, every where, Nor any drop to drink.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from &lt;em&gt;The Rime of the Ancient Mariner&lt;/em&gt;, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/&#34;&gt;Samuel Taylor Coleridge&lt;/a&gt; describes part of the curse inflicted on the mariner and his crew for his having shot the albatross whose noble presence had been bestowing a blessing to their voyage. In many ways, most of our leaders are like that mariner, killing Mother Earth who guarantees our wellbeing: only that these leaders have been doing it more slowly. We are polluting the air, the land and the waters, and even though we can see the curse materialising before our very eyes, we carry on, regardless. Today I will focus on Water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Policy Making: How to Achieve Net Zero</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/policy-making-how-to-achieve-net-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/policy-making-how-to-achieve-net-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clean-energy-imperative&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Clean Energy Imperative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clean energy sources like solar, wind, hydropower and nuclear energy have low Levelized Cost of Electricity (LCOE). This makes electricity purchase from clean energy sources more economically viable and environmentally sustainable for domestic as well as commercial applications. Therefore, increasing the share of clean energy sources in the energy generation mix is essentially advisable. Historically, developing nations have been dependent upon fossil fuel based power generation at large to meet their primary energy requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate refugees in the modern world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 13:28:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/climate-refugees-in-the-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A climate refugee is someone displaced from their home because of an extreme weather event caused by climate change. This particular category of refugees is coming from all over the world to various places that are not being affected as deeply by extreme weather. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate change is nothing new and neither is human migration. Migration has been a huge factor in international interactions since the dawn of written history. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Global climate change however, is a relatively recent occurrence. Climate change is defined as “the increasing changes in the measures of climate over a long period of time – including precipitation, temperature, and wind patterns”. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Standing up for the planet&#39;: An interview with climate activist Partho Chatterjee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:46:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/interview-with-partho-pratim-chatterjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Partho Pratim Chatterjee, a citizen of India and a member of UN-aligned. I hail from the mineral rich eastern state of Jharkhand. I am an engineer by profession and working in the capacity of Co-Founder and Technical Advisor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adityabioinnovation.in/&#34;&gt;Aditya Bioinnovation&lt;/a&gt; Private Limited, Nagpur, India. I have a keen penchant for eco-friendly technologies which include clean nanofluids, clean energy and clean transportation. My hobbies include penning poems and biodiversity exploration. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machines for the environment: 10 Simple machines that made our lives more sustainable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The advent of machines has heralded a new dawn for Homo Sapiens. Machines date back to antiquity. They have been ubiquitous right from the era of the first industrial revolution till the present, contemporary fourth industrial revolution. From tangible mechanical gears to the intangible virtual space, the progress mankind has made in the field of technology from the 1st Industrial Revolution to the 4th has been stupendous and awe inspiring. The effects of machines on our homes has been astounding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: An Ode to Environmental Restoration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 10:20:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ode-to-environmental-restoration&#34;&gt;An Ode to Environmental Restoration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human Beings since the onset of the Industrial Revolution have been obtuse,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The contemporary generation now finds the effects of global warming abstruse. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pernicious effects of climate change are no longer covert, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods, droughts, and forest fires have now become rampant and overt. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The indiscriminate chopping of trees, which we would all agree, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Has pared the earth’s carbon sinks to a substantial degree. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is high time that the words of the environmentalists are heard, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Or our next generations might not hear the chirp of a single bird.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;There is too much stupidity around&#34;: The UN&#39;s Climate Change Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:58 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/there-is-too-much-stupidity-around-the-climate-change-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sixth Assessment Report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change was published on August 9, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/&#34;&gt;The Report&lt;/a&gt; paints a grim picture of the planet’s health owing to human induced climate change and rising temperatures. These seem set to rise above the 1.5° threshold, which will signal a critical point of no return for those most exposed to the catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the report, UN Secretary-General António Guterres did not mince his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN is failing to combat Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-is-failing-to-combat-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change is the world’s biggest collective enemy, which threatens to destroy the very planet that we all live on. Whether it be rising sea levels, global warming, record-breaking temperatures, melting ice caps or an overall shift in severity of natural disasters, we as humankind need to strategise together for immediate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the UN’s response, it can be commended for shining light upon the escalating emergency; with, for example, setting up the annual COP meetings since 1995 to assess progress in dealing with climate change. Also, at COP 21, the UN established the landmark 2016 Paris Agreement, which was signed by 196 parties worldwide and is based upon limiting a global temperature increase to below 2 degrees. Other exposure includes promoting sustainable lifestyle changes, working with climate activists, and dedicating an entire Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) to combating climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Ways to Create a Healthy Economy with Kate Raworth - Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 10:36:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/seven-ways-to-create-a-healthy-economy-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kate Raworth first introduced her visual representation of what a healthy economy could look like in a 2012 OXFAM discussion paper titled: &amp;ldquo;A safe and just space for humanity: can we live within the doughnut?&amp;rdquo; The doughnut represented the safe space where humanity could thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits, namely our social and planetary boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raworth’s 2017 book develops the idea further. The seven “ways” she explores are simple, well researched, grounded and achievable. Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/climate-emergency/the-doughnut-economy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Doughnut Economy: &#34;humanity to thrive sandwiched between its inner and outer limits&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 10:40:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/economy/the-doughnut-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few centuries, economics has been dominated by a doctrine of perpetual growth. The prevailing idea was that there were no limits to how much we could exploit the earth and its resources. Today we know better, but sadly, we still behave as though we did not. As Kate Raworth states in her book &lt;em&gt;Doughnut Economics: Seven Ways to Think Like a 21st-Century Economist&lt;/em&gt; (2017), the citizens of the next few decades are being cultivated in a mindset that is obsolete for the 21st century as it is “rooted in the textbooks of 1950, which in turn are rooted in the theories of 1850.” This, she points out, is proving to be a veritable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How cultivated meat can save the planet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-cultivated-meat-can-save-the-planet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animal agriculture is a major contributor to greenhouse gas emissions; it is driving up climate change, antibiotic resistance, deforestation and the resulting biodiversity loss. It is also an incredibly inefficient, as well as immoral, way to feed the planet. For example, in the United States alone, 56 million acres of land are used to grow feed for animals, while only 4 million acres are cultivated to produce plants for humans to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accidentally Vegan Feature?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/animal-rights/accidentally-vegan-feature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve pondered veganism but haven’t yet followed through, it may be that you are put off by the myth of the diet being restricted. As with any lifestyle change, slow and steady tends to lead to longevity. It is much better to gradually cut animal products from your diet permanently than trying to be a strict vegan for a month, falling off the wagon, and being put off enough to never try it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waste and Mismanagement: The Devil in the Detail That is Back to Haunt us!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/waste-and-mismanagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 09:05:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/waste-and-mismanagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;creation-is-rarely-green&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creation is rarely green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The forces of creation are often seen as a trinity. In philosophy we have the Hegelian dialectic of Thesis, Antithesis and Synthesis, where the synthesis then becomes a new thesis which in turn postulates another antithesis, thus propelling evolution in a perpetual thrust forward. In religion, we have, for example, the Hindu trinity made up of Brahma (the creator), Vishnu (the preserver) and Shiva (the destroyer).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An end to the “Fairytales of Eternal Economic Growth”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 11:35:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-end-to-the-fairytales-of-eternal-economic-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 27th February, a British appeals court ruled that a planned expansion of Heathrow airport is unconstitutional because the planning process was not in accordance with the government&amp;rsquo;s own climate policies set out in the Paris Agreement. Lords Justice Lindblom, Singh and Haddon-Cave ruled that when setting out their support for the measures in their National Policy Statement (NPS), the government did not take adequate account of its contribution to the Paris Agreement on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Klaatu barada nikto”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 16:53:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/klaatu-barada-nikto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These words are taken from the classic 1951 film directed by Robert Wise: The Day the Earth Stood Still. The film, based on a short story by Harry Bates, is about an alien, Klaatu, who comes to earth in order to warn humanity of its pending obliteration by an interplanetary police force, unless it mends its destructive ways. The words were uttered to Gort, the robot, after Klaatu was shot. They delivered a stay of execution. Nevertheless, the film ends with the ball in earth’s court; their decision still to be made. We are now in 2020 and it seems as though many of our leaders are still hellbent on pursuing a self-destructive agenda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan and its nuclear waste problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 12:02:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/japan-and-its-nuclear-waste-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear leaks are probably among the most horrifying accidents possible due to their long-term detrimental damage to life and environment. Eight years after the nuclear leak from Japan’s Fukushima power plant, local residents, many of whom are fishermen, are still suffering the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dumping-the-radioactively-contaminated-water-directly-into-the-sea-in-order-to-dilute-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tragically, they now have to face another nightmare. However, rather than being triggered by a natural disaster, like the nuclear accident was, this time, it was all caused by their government’s proposal of dumping the radioactively contaminated water directly into the sea in order to dilute it. So far, the plant’s operator, Tokyo Electric Power Company (TEPCO), has already stored over 1 million tons of radioactive water used to cool destroyed reactors and the amount is still increasing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned’s view on the climate protests: the days of self-serving governments are over</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:22:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/un-aligneds-view-on-the-climate-protests-the-days-of-self-serving-governments-are-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;were-at-war-with-nature-if-we-win-were-lost-hubert-reeves&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re at war with nature. If we win, we&amp;rsquo;re lost&amp;rdquo; Hubert Reeves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the level of CO2 emissions reach their highest level in 10 million years, children and adults,  from an estimated of 185 countries, unite across continents and time-zones to demonstrate against politicians’ incompetence in dealing with this extraordinary challenge of our time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These protests come at a time when the Amazon forests are being burnt to ashes, a “biological annihilation” of wildlife is in sight and the consequences of melting ice in Greenland is about to give birth to a whole new group of internationally displaced people: climate refugees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
