<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animal Rights on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/animal-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animal Rights on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/animal-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How CalAnimals is making a difference for animals in California</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Victoria-Davila</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/animal-rights/how-californias-animal-welfare-association-calanimals-is-caring-for-thousands-animals-across-the-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people who love their companion animals, it may be surprising how so many animals wind up in shelters unclaimed, says Jill Tucker, CEO of California Animal Welfare Association&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tucker, who originally started her career in software, shifted into the animal sector in 2003, where she moved from California to Vermont to run an animal humane society organisation. From starting as a foster parent to making her way as the president of that same organisation, Tucker found herself as a leader in protecting animals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Californias-Animal-Welfare-Association.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Boy who Produces Golden Eggs – an interview with the 11 year old Andrea Piccinelli</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/interview/the-boy-who-produces-golden-eggs-an-interview-with-the-11-year-old-andrea-piccinelli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Il-ragazzo-che-produce-uova-doro.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The original Italian version of this interview can be read here.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;La versione originale italiana di questa intervista può essere letta qui.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview with UN-aligned coordinator, Adrian Liberto, the 11 year old &lt;strong&gt;Andrea Piccinelli&lt;/strong&gt; shares his story about how he developed a love and friendship with his chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some are literally golden in as much as they have a golden hue, but they are all golden in the sense that they are entirely cruelty free. Andrea Piccinelli lives in Magliano de Marsi, a small town in the Abruzzi, Italy, at the foot of the Monte Velino. His passion is looking after his chickens. His love for the animals and his determination are so strong that you would think that these traits must be in his genes. Maybe they are, a distant relative was a Franciscan Friar Pamfilo of Magliano, famous for compassion and for his part in founding &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sbu.edu/&#34;&gt;St. Bonaventure University&lt;/a&gt; in New York. What is certain, is that this young lad has come up with his own exit strategy for intensive chicken farming. His enterprise is also a wakeup call. What will the future be for all these farm animals we have enthralled for millennia? This is something that without doubt requires considerably more thought, especially now that intensive farming may be meeting its nemesis thanks to growing public awareness into the unethical practices of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/Cover.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters: Help us raise our banner in support of animals</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 10:00:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/letters/letters-help-us-raise-our-banner-in-support-of-animals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey members and readers! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need your assistance for our next publication of The Gordian, which will focus on ANIMAL RIGHTS. Please contribute material or ideas to ensure it will be a vibrant and interesting issue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help us raise our banner in support of animals, who cannot speak for themselves other than with their eyes and screams; “words” most people are immune to. You could write an article, tell a story, write a poem, draw a picture… Anything that could add spice to the issue and bring the message home. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="//localhost:1313/images/December-Social-Media-posts.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
