<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Explainer on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/explainer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explainer on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/explainer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Armenia’s ICC Pivot: Defying Russia and Eyeing European and Iranian Ties</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/armenias-icc-pivot-defying-russia-and-eyeing-european-and-iranian-ties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unprecedented development, Armenian lawmakers have ratified the Rome Statute, thereby signifying the nation&amp;rsquo;s intent to join the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This development has sent ripples all the way to the Kremlin, which seems less than pleased. Given the earlier move by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/icc-pursues-putin-and-lvova-belova/&#34;&gt;ICC to issue an arrest warrant for Russian President&lt;/a&gt; Vladimir Putin in March, Armenia now finds itself on a tightrope, precariously balancing its long-standing alliance with Russia. This recent gesture by Armenia has not only added a strain to its delicate camaraderie with Russia but also hints at a cautious pivot towards the West for a security umbrella. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-icj-the-icc-whose-justice/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary Cities: Shattering Myths, Protecting Human Rights</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/sanctuary-cities-shattering-myths-protecting-human-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received a parking ticket? Most are undoubtedly familiar with this feeling of intense frustration at the sight of a small fine tucked at the base of their windshield.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, what if a minor parking ticket posed the threat of a much larger consequence? What if it meant your children would be taken out of school? What if it meant you and your family could be deported? This is the reality for thousands of illegal immigrant families living in North America.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice across the EU: 6 ways the EU ensures fairness</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/6-ways-the-eu-secures-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-acquis-communautaire&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Acquis communautaire&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Acquis Communautaire is the EU rule book that protects all member states&amp;rsquo; citizens under the rule of law. Fun fact, if you read two pages of this EU treaty an hour, without any breaks because duh, stuff your dinner plans, you’ll be through it in just 4.5 easy years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ginormous legal textbook, which consists of 35 chapters within &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=COM:2001:0645:FIN:EN:PDF&#34;&gt;80,000 pages&lt;/a&gt;, is a combination of all European legislation, including all treaties, directives and regulations established by the EU&amp;rsquo;s institutions, as well as all decisions rendered by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and Moldova&#39;s EU candidacy status… beneficial?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 08:52:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/ukraine-and-moldovas-eu-candidacy-status-beneficial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-ukraine-and-moldova-are-granted-candidacy-status-does-that-mean-they-are-members-now&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So Ukraine and Moldova are granted candidacy status, does that mean they are members now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If only it were that easy! Based on a recommendation from the European Commission, the European Council can grant Candidate Status to prospective members of the European Union. The right to join the block, however, is not one that is automatically granted to countries who receive a candidacy status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the European Council decides to begin accession negotiations with the candidate country, the Commission evaluates the application in light of the Copenhagen criteria, which we will talk more about below, and formulates an opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Overturning of Roe v. Wade: Here’s what this will mean</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/the-overturning-of-roe-v-wade-heres-what-this-will-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 10:18:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/the-overturning-of-roe-v-wade-heres-what-this-will-mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States Supreme Court ruled on January 22, 1973, that under the Due Process Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment, a person’s choice on whether or not to have an abortion was protected in the United States and could not be criminalized. This constitutional right would stand for nearly 50 years and result in safer abortion procedures and reproductive healthcare that saved lives across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the developing decision was leaked prior to its final release, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.loc.gov/item/usrep410113/&#34;&gt;Roe v. Wade&lt;/a&gt; was officially overturned by the U.S. Supreme Court on June 24, 2022, marking the erasure of progress for human reproductive rights in the U.S. and leaving the decision of legalizing abortion up to the states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2021: UN-Ukraine Timeline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 09:33:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-ukraine-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-30-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyiv has urged Moscow to pull back its troops from Ukraine’s border and continue dialogue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;january-31-2022&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;US and Russia spar over the Ukraine crisis at a special closed session of the &lt;strong&gt;UN Security Council&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s UN envoy Vasily Nebenzya accused Washington and its allies of drumming up the threat of war despite Moscow’s repeated denials of a planned invasion. “The discussions about a threat of war is provocative in and of itself. You are almost calling for this. You want it to happen”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vlady Hell: Putin Strikes Again!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:05:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/vlad-the-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the August 2020 issue of The Gordian titled Russian Roulette: &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/human-rights/russian-roulette-why-putins-referendum-victory-is-a-threat-to-humanity/&#34;&gt;Why Putin’s Referendum Victory is a Threat to Humanity&lt;/a&gt; we published an article cheekily called Vlad the Terrible. It listed a range of crimes committed by Putin ranging from mass murder to mass deceit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vlad-the-terrible&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vlad the Terrible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You play with fire and you risk getting burned; play with the devil and you end up screwed. Sadly, this is exactly what is happening to Europe and beyond now that the demon is waving his devil’s fork and even threatening nuclear destruction. The good news is not only that we have learned a lesson, but even more remarkably, that we are prepared to suffer the consequences of our mistakes and send this devil to hell!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The painful history of Ukraine — A photo timeline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/history-of-ukraine-photo-timeline-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ukraine’s fate may be rooted in its heartbreaking past. In this photo timeline, which consists of more than 35 photos and 12 painful events, we’ll guide you through the county&amp;rsquo;s tragic history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukrainian-war-of-independence-1917-to-1921&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukrainian War of Independence (1917 to 1921)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 1917 to 1921, with the invasion of Bolsheviks, a series of conflicts and battles led to the establishment of the Ukrainian Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Ukrainian-War-of-Independence-1917-to-1921--1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A patriotic demonstration in Kyiv, Ukraine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;holodomor-1932-to-1933&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holodomor (1932 to 1933)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Holodomor, meaning to kill by starvation, is another dark chapter in Ukraine’s history. It is widely believed that the famine was orchestrated by Joseph Stalin to impose collectivism and tamp down Ukrainian nationalism. Hunger was so common that the Soviet regime convicted more than 2,500 people for cannibalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Caravaggio&#39;s Nativity with Saints Lorenzo and Francesco</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 11:02:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-caravaggio-nativity-with-saints-lorenzo-and-francesco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lost-nativity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lost Nativity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The multiplicity of subjects and themes present in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/the-story-behind-caravaggio-his-death-of-the-virgin/&#34;&gt;Caravaggio&amp;rsquo;s works&lt;/a&gt; allows me to continue talking about him, through his works, even in the period of the year when each of us could succumb to the easy temptation to choose discounted topics, through clichés. During the month of December we were constantly bombarded with images that create romantic and idealised suggestions. Despite the decidedly muffled atmosphere, I will try to talk with you about the nativity in art trying to maintain a critical, attentive and open attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machines for the environment: 10 Simple machines that made our lives more sustainable</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/10-machines-for-the-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The advent of machines has heralded a new dawn for Homo Sapiens. Machines date back to antiquity. They have been ubiquitous right from the era of the first industrial revolution till the present, contemporary fourth industrial revolution. From tangible mechanical gears to the intangible virtual space, the progress mankind has made in the field of technology from the 1st Industrial Revolution to the 4th has been stupendous and awe inspiring. The effects of machines on our homes has been astounding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 most fascinating scientific discoveries of 2021</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/10-most-fascinating-scientific-discoveries-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 09:30:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/10-most-fascinating-scientific-discoveries-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-medicine-mrna-vaccines-we-found-a-new-way-to-directly-talk-to-our-body&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Medicine/ mRNA vaccines: We found a new way to directly talk to our body!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/mRNA-vaccines.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An illustration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mechanism_of_action&#34;&gt;mechanism of action&lt;/a&gt; of a messenger RNA vaccine. Photo: Jmarchn&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vaccines have been around — and have noticeably extended the life expectancy of humans — since a few centuries ago. Research on mRNA technology is also longstanding and has been conducted for decades. What is new, however, is the ability to harness the power of mRNA in developing state-of-the-art vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Not Trust The United Nations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/5-reasons-why-the-un-cannot-be-trusted-to-represent-let-alone-advance-humanitys-ideals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-the-devil-you-know&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations: the devil you know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I met someone from a peculiar land with a completely messed up political system yielding a society that was plagued with poverty, oppression, corruption and strife. I commiserated until I found out that there actually was an alternative party that, given the chance, would put things right, yet nobody seemed to care about it. “Hey! What’s wrong with you people?” I asked my new acquaintance, pointing this out. “Many do not know; many do not care&amp;hellip;” “And what about you?”  I petitioned. “Ah, better the devil you know!” They replied smugly, as a demon dragged them to hell&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNESCO’s 44th Session: 27 sites that made it into the World Heritage List - in Pictures</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 08:03:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gallery/unescos-44th-session-27-sites-that-made-it-into-the-world-heritage-list-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Heritage Committee’s 44th session took place virtually from 16 to 31 July. It covered issues left outstanding since last year, when the annual meeting was postponed due to COVID-19. The extended session was chaired by Tian Xuejun, China’s Vice Minister for Education and Director of China’s National Commission for UNESCO. The session looked at 42 nominations to the World Heritage List (24 submitted for 2020 and 18 for 2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 UN Secretariat Offices explained in 10 minutes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/8-un-secretariat-offices-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/8-un-secretariat-offices-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Secretariat consists of the personnel of the United Nations, with the Secretary-General as its head. It is estimated that as of 2021, more than 35,000 people are employed by the United Nations. Currently, the Secretariat consists of about 30 departments and offices. In this article, we will take a look at some of the most interesting ones (you can find a full list of them at the end of this article). &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Secretaries-General: A Gallery Timeline</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 07:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/explainer/un-secretaries-general-a-gallery-timeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/1_Gladwyn_Jebb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First General Assembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gladwyn Jebb (on the right) attending the first session of the United Nations General Assembly in London on the 10th of January 1946. Jebb was the Acting Secretary-General from October 1945 to the appointment of Trygve Lie in 1946. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/un_photo/24229280176/in/album-72157663180292401/&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; by Marcel Bolomey / UN Photo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/2_Trygve_Lie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trygve Lie, first UN Secretary-General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lie served as the Secretary-General from 1946 until his resignation from his second term in 1952. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/norwayun/4898234974&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; by UN Photo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
