<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jihan.alassad on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/authors/jihan.alassad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jihan.alassad on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/authors/jihan.alassad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life on Repeat: Jihan&#39;s Diary from the Frontlines of a Refugee Camp&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/life-on-repeat-jihans-diary-from-the-frontlines-of-a-refugee-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life in a refugee camp seems stuck in an unending cycle of sameness. Days blur into one another, the only change being the unpredictable and often unforgiving weather conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is an attempt to document the individual days, but the repetition of the mundane is all too clear. Every harsh, cold morning feels identical, showing no mercy to the inhabitants. The only source of warmth is the resilience of the human spirit, akin to the skeletal structure of a body that refuses to succumb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education of Syrian Refugees During the Coronavirus Pandemic</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 09:59:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/education/education-of-syrian-refugees-during-the-corona-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to the epidemic, the refugee child was twice as likely to leave school as a non-refugee child. In Lebanon, poverty-related changes have been driven largely by inflation and poverty has increased by about 33 percentage points among the Lebanese population; the increase among Syrian refugees here, however, has increased by 55 percent. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Children have not been able to continue their studies because of closures, but they are also constrained by a lack of educational opportunities at home and the digital divide.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a Syrian refugee?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 09:42:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-syrian-refugee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Syrian; I think this phrase is enough to indicate that I may be in Sweden, Germany, Egypt or one of the many countries Syrians have resorted to in order to survive the tragedy inside Syria. This tragedy has left Syrians under the rubble, submerged in the Mediterranean Sea as they try to cross into Europe, or languishing in a prison under interrogation; perhaps eviscerated or eviscerating themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I Am A Syrian Refugee Who Lives In Lebanon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My religion is myself and my nationality is my heart”: Five days inside a refugee’s diary</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 10:22:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/five-days-inside-a-refugees-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During her internship with UN-aligned, Jihan Al-Assad was asked to write about her life inside the refugee camp in Lebanon. Her experiences, along with those of other refugees are published in a new series titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/diaries-from-refugee-camps/&#34;&gt;Diaries from Refugee Camps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday-1122021&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1/12/2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a new month and the end of a whole year. This does not feel like the beginning of a month or a day or anything new. I am afraid because I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what is coming to me, and this idea is a big horror for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disheartening revelations about the UNHCR in Lebanon — A refugee’s perspective</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 09:53:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/unhcr-in-lebanon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary mission of the United Nations Refugee Agency, the UNHCR in Lebanon, is to provide emergency assistance to those forced to flee their homes. This is the first step towards long-term protection and rehabilitation, as well as a means to support in various sectors for refugees and asylum seekers. But how is this achieved in the current reality, especially in a country like Lebanon? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;positive-action-of-the-unhcr-in-lebanon&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive action of the UNHCR in Lebanon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The achievements of the UNHCR include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Refugees Heading for Another Tough Winter</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 12:10:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/syrian-refugees-heading-for-another-tough-winter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mere mention of the word ‘refugee’ immediately evokes scenes of pain, sadness, hardship and cold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syrian refugees in Lebanon seem fated to suffer in all seasons. After the summer heat they face a wave of frost and snow, with cracked tents that do not protect against cold or rain. In addition, the lack of heating, coupled with malnourished bodies, means that the coronavirus is much more of an existential threat. They suffer; just as migrants and other refugees do, whether it is on the Belarusian-Polish border or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
