<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nuclear Weapons on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nuclear-weapons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nuclear Weapons on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:38:09 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nuclear-weapons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Nuclear Deterrence: Geopolitical Bravado or Our Obligation Towards Peace?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:38:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuclear-threats-past-and-present&#34;&gt;Nuclear Threats: Past and Present&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every historical curiosity is borne out of a rhetorical question that challenges the accepted narratives of the past. The history we are taught is often presented as simplified stories with humanity at the existential core. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, history is actually moulded by successive generations. With Vladimir Putin ordering Russia&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Rocket Forces to perform battle readiness drills with live nuclear weapons on Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s border, the spectre of nuclear war has returned in a starkly real manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demilitarising the Manipulable Atom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When World War One broke out, one of the founding fathers of modern science fiction, H.G. Wells, popularised the &amp;ldquo;war to end all wars&amp;rdquo; antiwar euphemism while trenches were dug on the Western front as British, French and German militaries mobilised for war. That same euphemism is often adopted and overused by aggressive unilateralists bent on justifying wanton militarism in pursuit of lopsided geopolitical objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Wells juxtaposed as the seminal foundation for a future liberated from the scourge of war, the Serbian American inventor Nikola Tesla fashioned in the form of a &amp;ldquo;death ray&amp;rdquo; to deny the possibility of war by vaporising invading militaries with &amp;ldquo;national energy shields&amp;rdquo; powered by alternating current. If history has proved anything, it is that war is one of man&amp;rsquo;s seminal preoccupations. War colleges churning out young military officers would have us believe wars are justifiable if waged to restore order to a Westphalian international balance of power system to make world peace possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
