<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oceans on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/oceans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oceans on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/oceans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diving Into the Enigmatic World of Deep Sea Creatures – A Photo Essay</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/science/diving-into-the-enigmatic-world-of-deep-sea-creatures-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the challenging conditions of the deep sea, life thrives in this surreal world. The pressure can be unfathomable, temperatures can plummet to subzero, and darkness is all-consuming, yet a vast array of life forms, ranging from bioluminescent jellyfish to colossal squids, showcase exquisite diversity and beauty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deep sea is an enigmatic and mesmerising environment that never ceases to amaze us with its extraordinary inhabitants. Join us as we embark on an extraordinary expedition to the unfamiliar, as we unravel the wonders of the deep sea and the creatures that inhabit it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three UN conventions on the laws of the sea and how they are failing to secure it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:50:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-three-un-conventions-on-the-laws-of-the-sea-and-how-they-are-failing-to-secure-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-united-nations-convention-on-the-law-of-the-sea&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1982, the third United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS) was adopted after nearly 26 years of attempts to replace the archaic “freedom of the seas” concept, which dated all the way back to the 17th century. The convention came into force in 1994 and established rules governing the uses of the oceans and their resources. Essentially encapsulating traditional rules for ocean use in a single instrument while also introducing new legal concepts, as well as addressing new concerns that arose with modern times. Some notable developments ushered by the convention include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
