<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More than Just a Gay Icon: Edmund White (1940-2025) </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:32:26 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/more-than-just-a-gay-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“When we are young… we often experience things in the present with a nostalgia-in-advance, but we seldom guess what we will truly prize years from now.” (City boy: My Life in New York in the 1960s and 70s)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As the outpouring of tributes to author Edmund White continues to flood the world, I cannot help feeling how the man, Edmund White, would have reacted to the adulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was a very reserved and unassuming gentle soul, with a wicked sense of humour; always on board for a laugh. I met Edmund several years back when I was a lecturer at the American University of Rome. Our first encounter was fraught with laughter and surreptitious jokes. He was about to give a talk and a reading of his book A Married Man at John Cabot University in Trastevere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Poetry After WWII: The Rise and Evolution of Post-War Literature in The UK</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-war-english-literature&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-War English Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have already seen while analysing the literary background of previous periods, the literature of each historical age often reflected the political and social situation of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post World War II literature was no different. Those terrible years of violence and devastation created a sense of general pessimism, cynicism and disillusionment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Literature after the Second World War clearly portrayed man&amp;rsquo;s disorientation, which was not only evident in the content of literary works but also characterised by the absence of one specific major school of thought or movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of the Angry Young Men in British Drama</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-rise-of-the-angry-young-men-in-british-drama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-look-back-in-anger-by-john-osborne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘A Look Back in Anger’ by John Osborne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drama, like the novel, reflected the discontent and disillusionment of the younger generations. The Angry Young Men were not only novelists but also playwrights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look Back in Anger by John Osborne was certainly the turning point of British drama. The main character, Jimmy Porter, an intellectual who had to work in the market-place to support his family, represented that new kind of dissatisfaction and rage. He, in fact, was rejected by society and subsequently turned against it with indiscriminate fury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Drama in the Age of Self-Discovery: Significant Plays and Key Themes</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/british-drama-in-the-age-of-self-discovery-significant-plays-and-key-themes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In last month’s issue we surveyed the two literary genres of poetry and the novel at the turn of the 20th century which we defined as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/&#34;&gt;an Age of Self-Discovery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We saw how the tide began to change during the last two decades of Queen Victoria’s reign, when some writers sought a newer and fresher approach to literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We then surveyed the literature that developed with the onset of the First World War, which had triggered in man the awareness to see life as an abyss of incessant self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the age of self-discovery changed the English poetry and novel forever</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/how-the-age-of-self-discovery-changed-the-english-poetry-and-the-novel-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Literature during the Victorian Era identified itself with the ethical values of that society. The superficial optimism and bigotry of a self-righteous attitude forged a kind of literature that was condescending and emotionally wanting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from the few exceptions like Emily Bronte’s Wuthering Heights, most of the production of that period lacked the emotional intensity or the daring experimentation of writers belonging to other periods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tide began to change during the last two decades of Victoria’s reign, when some writers sought a newer and fresher approach to literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dante Alighieri&#39;s Vision for World Government: The Pathway to Abolishing War</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dante&amp;rsquo;s death 700 years ago marked the end of an era. But his lasting legacy may be his vision for a world government, outlined in his work De Monarchia. Written in 1313, this work may be the first literature to present a comprehensive solution to the problem of war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to imagine any sort of connection between the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, and something that occurred in an unremarkable bedroom in Italy almost exactly 700 years prior. It has nothing whatsoever to do with the deep historical connections between Russia and Ukraine, at many times one and the same state, during the preceding seven centuries. But last autumn marked the 700th anniversary of the death of the great Italian poet Dante Alighieri, from malaria, in Ravenna, on September 14, 1321. His bones lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>86 Billion: The human spirt&#39;s fight to live a meaningful life</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-86-billion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LED,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where is Dendrite?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;That Synapse - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To my fiery colours of hope&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To feed my soul, To feel my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my soul, To kiss my soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To light my fire&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hear me&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To talk to me!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Speech me - &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To hold me in words,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To hold me in paint,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To violins,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To my treasures, to loves.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Anode and Cathode before the dark -&#xA;A light emitting diode,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A neural implant, never was,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To trigger years loves, laughter, dreams, memories, hope, passion;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pain, despair, angst, anxiety, fear -&#xA;Fiery Colours of hope always. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Herbert Lawrence: The Freudian who hated industrialisation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/david-herbert-lawrence-the-freudian-who-hated-industrialisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-life&#34;&gt;Early Life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David Herbert Lawrence was born on the 11th September 1885 at Eastwood, a poor small mining town near Nottingham. He was the fourth of five children. His father was an uneducated collier who was fond of drinking and having a good time. His mother, on the contrary, was a well-educated retired teacher whose determination and puritanical strength of character greatly influenced her son&amp;rsquo;s psyche. The social difference between D.H. Lawrence&amp;rsquo;s parents was the major cause of the endless quarrels and rows that used to take place in the Lawrence family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Stop this rape in Ukraine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/stop-this-rape-in-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gruesome rape and torment in Ukraine&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Causing women and children agonising pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Horrific headlines curdles one to the bone.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Russian soldiers have no hearts of their own.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can&amp;rsquo;t they leave the innocent alone?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Women like prisoners tied to a chain,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gory details of Women and babies raped&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s no escape.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only pain.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bodies of women and children everywhere.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rape is a weapon of war.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The innocent have no sword or spear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only the bloody scar.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers strangle them with hatred,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Is this why you were created?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Innocent lives are wasted.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing sacred.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;How can this evil be tolerated?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petronilla Paolini: Her tragic life and daring poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/petronilla-paolini-her-tragic-life-and-daring-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Up to now, I have mostly shared my impressions on art intended as &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/art&#34;&gt;visual art&lt;/a&gt;, examining paintings or sculptures. I have rarely strayed into technical intricacies when writing about art because when I decide to talk about a topic, I do not follow particular selective criteria, I simply rely on my instinct, on the urgency to share emotions and these are almost always solicited by the great works of art history. This time I felt the same solicitations and emotions that I have just mentioned, and I discovered them in part thanks to a casual &amp;ldquo;encounter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocked and Unbolted: Virginia Woolf&#39;s Life and Works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 11:26:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/virginia-woolf-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-life&#34;&gt;Early life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Virginia Woolf was born in London on the 25th of January 1882. Her father, Leslie Stephen, was an eminent Victorian critic and man of letters. He was the first editor of the Dictionary of National Biography. He was married twice. His first wife was William Thackeray’s daughter Minny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After her death, he married Virginia’s mother, Julia Duckworth, who was also from an illustrious family. She was a widow and had three children from her first marriage. One of these children, George Duckworth, sexually harassed Virginia later on in life, devastating her psychological stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doris Lessing: Subjecting a Divided Civilisation to Scrutiny</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 10:40:18 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/doris-lessing-subjecting-a-divided-civilisation-to-scrutiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doris Lessing was born in Iran on the 22nd of October 1919 to Alfred Cook Taylor and Emily Maud McVeigh. Her parents were both very involved in the Second World War. Her father was an active fighter and her mother was a nurse. It was in this capacity that Emily Maud met Alfred, who had been seriously injured in battle. His leg was, in fact, eventually amputated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doris Lessing spent the first six years of her life in Tehran, where her father worked at the Imperial Bank of Persia. After a brief return to England the family moved to Zimbabwe, which was then known as Rhodesia. There, Alfred invested all his capital on a 3000 acre farm which he hoped to develop. Life in southern Africa was to leave an indelible influence on Doris Lessing&amp;rsquo;s existence and on her written work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edward Morgan Forster: Life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 11:17:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/edward-morgan-forster-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Morgan Forster was born in London on the 1st January 1879. His family was typically upper-middle class. Edward Forster senior was a Cambridge graduate architect and Lily, his wife, was the adopted child of a rich family. However, when E.M. Forster was still a baby, Edward, his father, died of tuberculosis leaving his only son in the care of Lily. The child was brought up only by women, a fact which was to influence his formative years. After his father&amp;rsquo;s death, mother and son moved to Stevenage in Hertfordshire. There they lived in a large house in the middle of the English countryside, visited only by Lily&amp;rsquo;s female relatives and friends. Lily and her son developed a deep and loving relationship. In later years Forster wrote that his mother had given him &amp;ldquo;a sort of rich subsoil where I have been able to rest and grow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems For a Better World: This War of MMXXII</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:54:05 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/poems-for-a-better-world-this-war-of-mmxxii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Invasion for pure greed and gratification.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What else can this be?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Civilians, soldiers, casualties dying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;In their blood lying.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Lives are meaningless,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The soul is downcast and sighing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is the battlefield, blood, brutality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Politicians lacking  rationality.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Aggression, destruction, death and ravished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soldiers and innocent lying on the streets.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Surely logic has perished.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The cold carnage continues …&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Unleashed on humanity.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mourning for innocent lives.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Who will stop the insanity?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Can people not see such torment and tragedy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is war my dear!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There is only depravity and brutality…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From patriotism to pure poetry: Isaac Rosenberg’s Break of Day in the Trenches</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 11:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/break-of-day-in-the-trenches-rosenberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The darkness crumbles away&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is the same old druid Time as ever,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Only a live thing leaps my hand,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A queer sardonic rat,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As I pull the parapet&amp;rsquo;s poppy&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To stick behind my ear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Droll rat, they would shoot you if they knew&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Your cosmopolitan sympathies,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now you have touched this English hand&lt;br&gt;&#xA;You will do the same to a German&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Soon, no doubt, if it be your pleasure&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To cross the sleeping green between.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It seems you inwardly grin as you pass&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Strong eyes, fine limbs, haughty athletes,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Less chanced than you for life,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bonds to the whims of murder,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sprawled in the bowels of the earth,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The torn fields of France.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What do you see in our eyes&lt;br&gt;&#xA;At the shrieking iron and flame&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hurled through still heavens?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What quaver - what heart aghast?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Poppies whose roots are in men&amp;rsquo;s veins&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Drop, and are ever dropping;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But mine in my ear is safe,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Just a little white with the dust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The master of the Bildungsroman: Leslie Poles Hartley’s life and works</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/leslie-poles-hartleys-life-and-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leslie Poles Hartley was born in England on the 30th of December 1895. He grew up in the relatively peaceful period of Edwardian England. He had an excellent education at Harrow and subsequently at Oxford University. After the outbreak of the First World War, the peace and tranquillity of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trafalgar.com/real-word/definitive-downton-a-guide-to-edwardian-britain/&#34;&gt;Edwardian English society&lt;/a&gt;, which he had been accustomed to, was suddenly disrupted. Hartley joined the army as an officer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was never involved in fighting, but gained a certain amount of experience of the military world. After the war, he became a journalist, reviewing literature for the Spectator, the Observer and other London papers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: When People Gather</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 10:37:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/when-people-gather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-people-gather&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When People Gather&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news is published everywhere&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It tells us the world is in disrepair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you turn and pretend it&amp;rsquo;s not there&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you consume the news in despair&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe you say that you&amp;rsquo;re not political&lt;br&gt;&#xA;What a privilege you have, that&amp;rsquo;s not typical!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Things only seem to get worse by the day&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods and plagues, corruption, decay&lt;br&gt;&#xA;While thoughts and prayers might be a gesture&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Stand up, be proactive or the problems fester&lt;br&gt;&#xA;These are man-made issues and ours to undo&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Where do we start? You haven&amp;rsquo;t a clue.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Well there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just I can do&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But what if your neighbour thought that too?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And their neighbour thought they didn&amp;rsquo;t matter&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Changes happen when people gather &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/in-english/&#34;&gt;UN-aligned&amp;rsquo;s message&lt;/a&gt; is loud and clear&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The earth is for sharing, all welcome here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: An Ode to Environmental Restoration</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 10:20:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/climate-emergency/an-ode-to-environmental-restoration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ode-to-environmental-restoration&#34;&gt;An Ode to Environmental Restoration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human Beings since the onset of the Industrial Revolution have been obtuse,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The contemporary generation now finds the effects of global warming abstruse. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pernicious effects of climate change are no longer covert, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Floods, droughts, and forest fires have now become rampant and overt. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The indiscriminate chopping of trees, which we would all agree, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Has pared the earth’s carbon sinks to a substantial degree. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is high time that the words of the environmentalists are heard, &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Or our next generations might not hear the chirp of a single bird.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Osborne and The Angry Young Men</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 13:59:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-osborne-and-the-angry-young-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our overview of post-war British drama with a survey of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1aFPD3yGlnWubBApVyOyjFgWhXeP1qBShaTKmbLeM_8I/edit#&#34;&gt;Theatre of the Absurd&lt;/a&gt;, let us now look at another important literary movement that developed after the end of World War II. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The end of the war left a sense of discontent and disillusionment, especially with the younger generation. As society developed into a more affluent capitalistic and class-conscious structure, the younger generation became aware that the poorer classes were being exploited and this prompted them to voice their anger. A new class of writers, known as the Angry Young Men, came into being. They were expressing their anger through various literary genres, in particular through prose and drama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harold Pinter: a mirror for the common people</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 12:50:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/harold-pinter-a-mirror-for-the-common-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last issue we saw how Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/&#34;&gt;developed a new drama&lt;/a&gt; that was characterized by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time: the Theatre of the Absurd. In this issue we shall take a closer look at Nobel Prize winner Harold Pinter, one of the most influential modern British dramatists with a writing career spanning over more than 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayesha Kajee Talks to UN-aligned About Her Poem &#34;Silence&#34;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/ayesha-kajee-on-her-poem-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The second place was awarded to Ayesha Kajee for her poem Silence. The following interview was conducted on the 2nd of November 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch the interview here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o33ltCPX_6I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Read Ayesha&amp;rsquo;s poem “Silence&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Silence</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 09:53:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;i&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silence is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Silence is complicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Complicity is violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So in the violence of our silence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let us take stock of our complicity &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;ii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our complicity silences truth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Muffles honour, rapes innocence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The same innocence we plead&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Confronted by shattered delusion&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“We didn’t know” &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;iii&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wished to not know&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Blinded, deafened, deadened&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We turned away Bedecked ourselves in laurel&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Which now turns to rue &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;iv&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our silence - yours and mine - is explicit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is complicit It is violent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;And in its complicit explicit violence&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We too have bloodied our souls&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Terra Australis Incognita” &amp; “Silence” chosen as the winners of the 2021 UN-aligned poetry competition</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:13:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita-silence-chosen-as-the-winners-of-the-2021-un-aligned-poetry-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure to announce the winners of this year&amp;rsquo;s poetry competition arranged by UN-aligned. This year, we have received 17 poems that creatively portrayed the values that UN-aligned’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/our-manifesto/&#34;&gt;Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; campaigns for. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Dean Gessie from Canada for his poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Terra Australis Incognita&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And the &lt;strong&gt;second place&lt;/strong&gt; goes to Ayesha Kajee from South Africa for her poem “&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/silence/&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection in the call for works was made by UN-aligned’s literary editor and winner of the international ‘Il Leone D’Oro’ award, &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/author/alex-liberto/&#34;&gt;Alex Liberto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author Dean Gessie Talks to UN-aligned about his “Terra Australis Incognita”</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:40:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/dean-gessie-on-terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2021, UN-aligned arranged a poetry competition and asked writers to creatively portray the values that its Manifesto campaigns for. The first place was awarded to Dean Gessie for his poem “Terra Australis Incognita”. The following interview was conducted on the 31st of October 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/terra-australis-incognita/&#34;&gt;Read Dean&amp;rsquo;s poem “Terra Australis Incognita”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch our interview with Dean Gessie here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B39EuPH21Ng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems for a Better World: Terra Australis Incognita</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/terra-australis-incognita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;and those black fellas believed these white fellas spirits of their ancestors (pale time travellers of everywhen) and those black fellas received venereal, opium, rum and pox and they returned witchetty grubs, honey ants and fruit bats and the white fellas killed no one with their guns because the new land was called &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (land belonging to no one) and it was fair to say that these white fellas did not include themselves nor irony in their census taking and the captain struck the collarbone of the elder (he that had helped himself to the white fellas shovel) and the aborigine elder embraced the captain and spread his arm to indicate everything he could see and the captain surrendered his shovel of wrought iron just as black fellas shared their axes of polished greenstone and so it was with ropes and stakes and sacred land; these white fellas pushed the black fellas further from the sea, scattered burial totems of coral, red basket and seagull feather and there was bile and spleen between the groups and dead black fellas (females and young, too) and the aborigine elder pushed the collarbone of the captain and the captain knew it was wrong to survey and deed what wasn’t theirs and he was ashamed and he agreed that his voice was no greater than the magpie or the blue winged kookaburra and he negotiated to settle the interior space of &lt;em&gt;terra nullius&lt;/em&gt; (that ground that was less hospitable like them) and handcuffs and leg irons fell from the poors and politicals and these made a mountain of metal where everyone was free to piss and the captain cast off his blue jacket and white waistcoat and humbled himself to learn yellomundi (or storyteller) and butbut (or heart) and he was granted initiation by they that met and decided he was ten years old and he was painted with red clay and fat of the wallroo and wombat and he received cuts to his chest arms shoulders and buttocks and sand in each produced voluminous scars and the penis of this white fella was split with a stone knife and a front tooth was knocked out to mark him as community and he danced the tree lion climbing ripping and pulling but laying in peace with brother and sister alike and he sang the songlines that trek creation and he blew didjerry didjerry through termite eucalyptus, pressed his lips to beeswax and shook out grins and guffaws and the black fellas did not call him apostle but he returned his blind eye seeing to the white sails of sirius of the orion and he stayed the cannons and six-pounder guns and his voice was dreamtime and ancestral beings and why it is that men and women walk upright and those that saw and heard were ashamed and they pushed the collarbone one of the other and they agreed against greed to call this place “must be there somewhere land” and it remains so to this day&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Beckett &amp; Harold Pinter: 2 Giants of the Theatre of the Absurd</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:53:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-beckett-harold-pinter-two-giants-of-the-theatre-of-the-absurd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/literature/&#34;&gt;the last issue&lt;/a&gt; we saw how some 20th century writers envisioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/&#34;&gt;a dystopian future&lt;/a&gt; in reaction to the two world wars and to the dwindling human values. Protesting against society and the situation of man, but in a different way, were the giants of the Theatre of the Absurd Samuel Beckett and Harold Pinter. Both playwrights developed a new drama which was characterised by features that had nothing in common with the prevailing criteria of the time. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dystopian Novel: &#34;Beyond Utopia&#34;!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-dystopian-novel-beyond-utopia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dystopian novel developed during the 20th century when the reality of humanity’s volatile condition became evident after both the first and second world wars. The word, dystopia, refers to Utopia, the fictitious name of an ideal country, coined by Thomas More in his famous book Libellus &amp;hellip; de optimo reipublicae statu deque nova Insula &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/2130&#34;&gt;Utopia (1516)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was designed as a political, social and religious system which was not supposed to be reflected in reality, but proposed as an ideal model.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitzgerald&#39;s Great Gatsby VS T. S. Eliot&#39;s Waste Land: Portraying a dusty vastness where nothing thrives</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/fitzgeralds-great-gatsby-vs-t-s-eliots-waste-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The situation that plagued the world after World War One was one of callous apathy and emotional aridity. My last article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/&#34;&gt;T. S. Eliot’s poetic portrayal of the early 20th century&lt;/a&gt; ended with the line, “The dehumanisation of the modern world is complete.” This ‘dehumanisation’, which Eliot portrayed as a waste land in his poetry, was also described very clearly in prose by F. S. Fitzgerald in his novel &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The freedom to choose</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 10:50:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/700-years-of-dante-the-freedom-to-choose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following article is taken from a speech given by Carla Pietrobattista on Dante Day, March 25, which is traditionally held as the day the “divine poet” started his masterpiece, the &lt;em&gt;Divine Comedy&lt;/em&gt;. 2021 also marks the 700th anniversary of Dante’s death. The event was presided by the Mayor of Magliano dei Marsi, Pasqualino di Cristofano. Ms. Pietrobattista will also be collaborating on the new Art Section of &lt;em&gt;The Gordian&lt;/em&gt;, which will start next month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your guide to T.S Eliot poems - April is the cruellest month</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 11:13:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/your-guide-to-t-s-eliot-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;T.S Eliot is perhaps the best example of the modern metaphysical poet. Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/&#34;&gt;17th century poet, John Donne&lt;/a&gt;, Eliot veered from the ethereal world of romance and idealisation, to head directly towards a concrete reality through conceits and extended metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His work reflected the upheaval of the social order in the aftermath of World War I, and the failure of all of man’s social, political and philosophical aspirations. On the wake of death and destruction, all seemed to flounder on the crags of a festering humanity that had turned to superficial desires and material gain. Ethical and moral values were reduced to a vast expanse of ash and aridity; a waste land void of any humanity. Humankind had lost its soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Donne&#39;s No Man is an Island: Feeling a Oneness With Humanity</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 08:38:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/donne-no-man-is-an-island-and-feeling-a-oneness-with-the-rest-of-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s world besieged by isolationism, America First, Britain First, white supremacy, cyber bullying, homophobia, racism, vaccine tug-of-war, colonialist withdrawal symptoms (… shall I go on?) and the like, never before have the words of John Donne been more relevant; “No man is an island…”. In the age of Brexit, the very notion that every man is part of a greater humanity is a powerful assertion. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the profound conviction that ‘every man is a piece of the continent, a part of the main’ has a far more universal metaphorical significance; a spiritual and existential significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Greatest Metaphysical Poet&#34;: Your Full Guide to John Donne’s Life, Career &amp; Poems</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/john-donne-life-career-and-poems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;family-background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John Donne was born in London in 1572 to a relatively wealthy family.  His father, who died when Donne was only four, was a successful tradesman and his mother, Elizabeth, was the daughter of the writer John Heywood.  Both parents were Roman Catholics and were in obvious difficulty to come to terms with the newly established Church of England.  Donne’s family, especially on his mother’s side, were persecuted for being Roman Catholics and for refusing to swear the Oath of Supremacy which acknowledged the English monarch as the Head of the Church of England.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Pepys: A peep into the life of a gentleman in the Restoration period</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-pepys-a-peep-into-the-life-of-a-gentleman-in-the-restoration-period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cannot speak of a literary career for Samuel Pepys (1633 -1703), since he wrote predominantly for his own private reading. He is known for his diary which was written in a special code (Shelton’s system of tachygraphy) and was not meant to have been deciphered and read by others.  This naturally makes his account of life during the Restoration period free from prejudice and all the more authentic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diary of Pepys is of paramount importance since it illustrates an informative and unique picture of Restoration life. It is a stunning self-portrait of the middle-class gentleman whose social position exemplifies the Restoration years of readjustment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maurice and Sexual Awakening</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:55:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/maurice-and-sexual-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to start a short cycle on love with a work about the “love that dare not speak its name”; the love between two men. Maurice was written by E. M. Forster back in the Edwardian England of respectability and bigotry. Not that any other period in the last few centuries were any more progressive or open minded. As Forster put it, “England has always been disinclined to accept human nature.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Taylor Coleridge: The Supernatural Poet</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:55:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/samuel-coleridge-natural-supernatural/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coleridge, like Wordsworth, loved nature and together they enjoyed walking in the Lake District, in the heart of the natural surroundings. However, Coleridge also loved the supernatural. His fantastic and mysterious imagination was an infinite source of inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was this poetic process of creation that laid the foundations for the haunting scenes of &lt;em&gt;The Rime of The Ancient&lt;/em&gt; Mariner and the visionary surrealistic world of &lt;em&gt;Kubla Khan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/Samuel-Taylor-Coleridge-KublaKhan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kubla Khan handwritten sketch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bluster of Arrogance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 12:40:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/culture/the-bluster-of-arrogance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Popular leaders nowadays seem to owe their success to noise, aggression and self-aggrandisement. I call this the Cassius Clay syndrome. The louder they shout, the more they are respected. The more brazen they are, the more they gain trust. The more they blow their own trumpet, the more credible they appear. This is the leader of our 21st century populist culture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These loudmouths are distorted Machiavellian politicians. Distorted because the ends justified by their means are void of any political or social ideals. Their modus operandi is not based on any strategic acumen, it is improvised and opportunistic. It is sheer megalomania. They wallow in their own narcissism and arrogance, advocating an impoverished makeshift political agenda. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
