<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lgbtq on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lgbtq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lgbtq on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:11:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lgbtq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Could Uganda&#39;s Anti-Gay Law Alter the Lives of All Ugandans, Straight or Not?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/could-ugandas-anti-gay-law-alter-the-lives-of-all-ugandans-straight-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:11:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/could-ugandas-anti-gay-law-alter-the-lives-of-all-ugandans-straight-or-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The President of Uganda, Yoweri Museveni, has signed an Anti-Homosexuality Act (AHA), outlawing homosexuality in the country. Uganda&amp;rsquo;s penal code already prohibits same-sex conduct, but the new bill, signed on the 26th of May, introduced the death penalty for acts classified as “aggravated homosexuality”, which includes spreading HIV, rape and serial offending. Moreover, it raised the imprisonment term for same-sex conduct to 10 years, while a 20-year sentence could be handed to anyone promoting homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qatar 2022: A World Cup for Straight Men</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/qatar-2022-a-world-cup-for-straight-men/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I wrote an article for The Gordian Magazine celebrating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/lifestyle/women-football-not-brave-enough-to-see-the-vision/&#34;&gt;growth of women’s football&lt;/a&gt; in the UK, and hailing 2022 as a watershed year in women’s sport around the world. Now, just a few months later, nothing seems further from the truth. In choosing to host one of the world’s biggest sporting competitions in Qatar this year, a country run on Sharia law and plagued by inequalities, FIFA has let the world know that football remains the domain of straight men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mridul Wadhwa on Conversion Therapy and Edinburgh Rape Crisis Centre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/mridul-wadhwa-conversion-therapy-and-edinburgh-rape-crisis-centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mridul Wadhwa, and I am originally from India, and I’ve lived in Scotland since 2004. I started working in the violence against women or gender-based violence sector in 2005. With a small break in between, I’ve worked in that sector since then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I primarily worked with minority ethnic women, immigrant women, and women from communities of colour living in Scotland. For most of that time, my job was to work with the white majority community, primarily service providers, to help them develop an understanding of what kind of barriers minority ethnic women in Scotland face when experiencing and leaving abusive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OHCHR: Take action to ban harmful conversion practices against LGBTQIA&#43;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-ohchr-ban-conversion-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Michelle Bachelet Jeria, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, a Finland-based NGO whose mission is to create a better and fairer United Nations that promotes ethical principles of human rights, animal welfare, environmental well-being, and world peace. Pertaining to human rights and global justice, I request that the OHCHR address and take action to eliminate harmful conversion practices that promote violence and invalidate the LGBTQIA+ community worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on UN-aligned’s open letter to the United Nations Human Rights Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 11:11:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/update-on-un-aligneds-open-letter-to-the-united-nations-human-rights-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second half of 2021, we launched an &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/letters/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/&#34;&gt;Open Letter&lt;/a&gt; to the United Nations Human Rights Commission requesting that countries that criminalise LGBTQ+ rights be barred from forming part of the commission. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, the letter has been signed by over a dozen LGBT+ organisations from around the globe, as well as individual activists. We originally planned to send the letter on 22 February 2022. However, owing to the latest developments in the United Nations and the ongoing war in Ukraine, we have decided to postpone the open letter as otherwise it would be sounded out by these tragic events. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN-aligned calls on UNHRC to ban members that criminalise homosexuality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 16:54:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/counties-who-criminalise-homosexuality-must-not-be-allowed-a-seat-on-the-unhrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of the United Nations’ Declaration of Human Rights, we, the undersigned firmly believe in “the inherent dignity and the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family”. This is “the foundation of freedom, justice and peace in the world”, whereas “disregard” and “contempt” for these rights “have resulted in barbarous acts which have outraged the conscience of mankind.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst many member states flout human rights on a regular basis, certain states actually enshrine these abuses in law. This is very much the case with LGBT+ rights in as much as almost a third of United Nations’ member States criminalise homosexuality with penalties ranging from death and lengthy prison sentences to beatings and fines. This proportion does not include States that oppress the LGBT+ rights in other ways, such as Hungary and Poland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the Arab League &amp; the OIC: Take immediate action to counter discriminatory practices against LGBTQ individuals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:30:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/campaigns/letter-to-the-arab-league-the-oic-take-immediate-action-lgbtq-rights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a cofounder of UN-aligned, and representative of the organisation, I am writing to request that, in the name of human rights and international justice, you take immediate action to review your policy at the United Nations of blocking legislation, and other positive moves, to counter violence and discriminatory practices against individuals based on their sexual orientation and gender identity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Islam, like most religions, has evolved, and continues to evolve, with time; just as humankind does. Nevertheless, those who do not wish to change have no right to impose their outdated views on others. In the words of Barack Obama: “Religious freedom doesn’t mean you can force others to live by your own beliefs.” As long as a person is not harming anyone else, he or she should not be victimised. This premise is essential if harmony is to flourish on earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misgendering people: Identity and Gender Pronouns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:50:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/misgendering-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article does not intend to offend or devalue anyone with a non-binary gender identity. It only tries to explain why fixing misgendering is a larger problem than most people think, and why there is no immediate solution to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-misgendering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is misgendering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Misgendering is the act of using language to describe or talk to a person in a manner that does not align with their affirmed gender, intentionally or unintentionally. This can be in the form of personal pronouns, such as referring to someone as a ‘he’ when they’re a woman or when they do not identify with the male gender, but also through the use of gender specific nouns such as ‘boy’ and ‘girl’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LGBTQ Rights: Zombie Democracy and Loveless Religion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/lgbtq-rights-zombie-democracy-and-loveless-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiding-behind-democracy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiding behind democracy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any lover of democracy would be justified in feeling a sense of alarm when faced with such statements as “an assault on democracy…” and “a direct political attack against the democratically elected government…”, but as the Bard of Avon put it: “The devil can cite Scripture for his purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above two quotes come from Polish Justice Minister Zbigniew Ziobro and Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban, respectively. They are directed against the EU presidency for calling their countries to task for their deteriorating record on human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Wedlock</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:26:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/unlocking-wedlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-slow-pace-of-same-sex-marriage&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slow pace of same-sex marriage…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same-sex marriage is now legal in almost thirty countries in the world. Considering same-sex unions date back over 12,000 years and that there are almost 200 countries in the world, this is not much of an achievement. In recent times, the first country to legalise same-sex marriage was the Netherlands. That law was passed in December 2000 and came into effect in April 1, 2001. So, even in the last few decades, progress has been slow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan gives the world a lesson in democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:15:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/taiwan-gives-the-world-a-lesson-in-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-a-thing-or-two-from-taiwan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning a thing or two from Taiwan…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan gave the world a lesson in real democracy last month when same-sex marriage was legalised in the “country“. In a referendum last November, 72% of the population had voted against allowing same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two years earlier, however, Taiwan’s supreme court had ruled that limiting the definition of marriage to couples of the opposite sex was unconstitutional. Legislators therefore backed the Government Bill, putting justice before numbers. This is real democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
