<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nation Building on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/nation-building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nation Building on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/nation-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nation-Building and Indigenous Struggles: Histories, Rights and Representation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nation-building-and-indigenous-struggles-histories-rights-and-representation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where borders are drawn and redrawn, the quest for a homeland remains fraught with strife for many. Nation-building, the process of constructing a national identity and establishing political and social structures, is pivotal in this quest. It is not just about hotly-debated independence stories or drawing lines on a map; it involves acknowledging diverse histories, cultures and rights to create a cohesive and inclusive society. This is crucial for ensuring peace, stability and progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Table Tennis to the UN: How Kosovo Used Sports for Nation Building</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never before has the nexus between sport and international relations been more prominent than in the last 10 years. Even a cursory examination of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most publicised sporting events from the last decade reveals a clear link between the games and athletes we love to watch and money, power, and strategic international diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports-events-reflect-on-a-nations-best-and-worst&#34;&gt;Sports events reflect on a nations&amp;rsquo; best and worst&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Brazil hosted the FIFA World Cup, aiming to exhibit the beauty and rich culture of Brazil. However, the exciting football was overshadowed by extreme poverty; the inequality highlighted by the slums of Rio de Janeiro and the displacement of thousands to accommodate new stadiums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Constitution: The New Social Contract Inside the October Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As October’s chill sets in, ‘The Gordian’ returns from its brief hiatus with a meticulously curated issue titled ‘Global Constitution: The New Social Contract.’ This edition seeks to weave together the intricate threads of geopolitics, art, culture, and science, presenting a cohesive narrative of our shared global destiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In ‘&lt;em&gt;The Imagined Unity&lt;/em&gt;: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock,’ Alexander Stoney offers an exploration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/&#34;&gt;nuanced concept of ‘Nation’.&lt;/a&gt; This sets the stage for Adrian Liberto’s discourse on the pressing need for a global constitution in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/&#34;&gt;‘&lt;em&gt;The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it&lt;/em&gt;.’&lt;/a&gt; Liberto subsequently scrutinises the UN’s role in the Palestinian crisis in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/&#34;&gt;‘Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Imagined Unity’: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:15:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few terms in political science hold as complex a definition as “Nation”. As UN-aligned launches its new volume of The Gordian, exploring Nation Building, it becomes crucial to establish a clear understanding of the term and its multilayered complexities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-nation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a nation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A nation is defined as “a group of people who share a history, traditions, culture and, often, language – even if the group does not have a country of its own”, writes National Geographic. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:27:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaac Newton famously said: “If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.” Sadly, society is where it is today because most people have stood on the shoulders of ogres. The past sticks to us like shit on a shoe and we have become so accustomed to the foul smell, that rather than scrape off the dung, we wallow in it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: planet earth in the 21st century, but one that had never witnessed the advent of humankind. Then, suddenly, it is discovered by an alien species much like our own. Before long, the planet is plundered, ravaged and abused. Life forms are enslaved, tortured and killed for entertainment, fashion and culinary delights, their habitats destroyed; forests are cut down; and rivers and seas polluted beyond recognition, as are the skies. Finally, having exhausted every possible resource, the alien species moves on, like a plague of locusts, to its next quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
