<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ywf on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/ywf/</link><description>Recent content in Ywf on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:37:59 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/ywf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Forging of an East African Federation</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:37:59 +0200</pubDate><author>Kennedy Karanja</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/forging-an-east-african-federation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-first-shot-at-an-east-african-community">&lt;strong>The First Shot at an East African Community&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The three countries of East Africa - Kenya, Tanzania (which is a union of Tanganyika and Zanzibar), and Uganda - were administered as one unit under the East African Common Services. When granting them independence, the British expected that these countries would eventually integrate into one political union, as had happened to Tanganyika and Zanzibar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The concept of a political federation for East Africa emerged in the 1960s. The idea took shape in 1967 when the East African Community, a confederate government, was formed by the republics of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania. The heads of states of Kenya, Uganda, and Tanzania, by signing the treaty establishing the community, became its patron and hoped to use the community as a launching pad towards deeper political, economic, and socio-cultural integration.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Fasttracking-East-African-Federation.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Generation Earth: Why Youth are Necessary for Solving Global Problems</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 14:05:59 +0200</pubDate><author>Eston McKeague</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/generation-earth-why-youth-are-necessary-for-solving-global-problems/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="humanity-faces-immense-challenges">Humanity faces immense challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many young people are global. Growing up online has predisposed a generation to a cosmopolitan perspective previously only accessible by the elite. Interacting with a culture different from your own has become a commonplace occurrence online, which has led many to retreat into safe, echo chambers with people of the value system. This retreat is exemplified by private chat groups which at best, provide a welcoming space for a niche community, and at worst, provide a space for terrorists to plan attacks. Yet, if you’ve grown up online, you’ll know that an echo chamber is far less fun than a debate space. &lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Photo-Fabrice-Florin_Flickr.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>