<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linguistics on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>/tags/linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linguistics on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>Ariana Yekrangi</author>
      <guid>/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>In the UN&#39;s high-stakes negotiations, a pivotal linguistic duel over &#39;cessation&#39; versus &#39;suspension&#39; casts Gaza&#39;s fate into uncertainty.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Weak-and-Ambiguous-Words-How-Diplomacy-Hinders-Peace-in-Gaza-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Curse of Babel: The Drawbacks of Language for Communication and Thought</title>
      <link>/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 10:54:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>Adrian Liberto</author>
      <guid>/culture/the-drawbacks-of-language-for-communication-and-thought/</guid>
      <description>This article highlights the drawbacks of language, not only in its cursed post-Babel scattered metamorphosis, but also in itself, as a means to communication and thought.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/The-hidden-curse-of-Babel-The-drawbacks-of-language-as-a-means-communication-and-thought.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Russian and Ukrainian are not the same language</title>
      <link>/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:05:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/culture/why-russian-and-ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language/</guid>
      <description>As the Ukrainian invasion enters its third month, Aryan Yekrangi writes about the difference between Russian and Ukrainian language, which are often mistaken as the same.</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Why-Russian-and-Ukrainian-are-not-the-same-language.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language to Unite, Language to Separate: The Tale of Serbian &amp; Croatian</title>
      <link>/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:35:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/country-profile/language-to-unite-language-to-separate-the-tale-of-serbian-croatian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Croatia and Serbia, once brothers united, have experienced many conflicts since the collapse of Yugoslavia in 1991. In fact, conflicts existed even prior to the demolition of Yugoslavia and can even be traced back as a cause for its collapse. Thus, it is worth looking at the role of language in this conflict. More specifically, how the classification of two languages can be utilized as a tool, sometimes even a weapon. We do this by answering the following question: “Are Serbian and Croatian two different languages, or simply two dialects of the same language”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Language-to-Unite-Language-to-Separate_-The-Tale-of-Serbian-Croatian--scaled.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Why are you talking like that?&#39;: How politicians use words to influence and mislead</title>
      <link>/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:56:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/culture/how-politicians-use-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever found yourself agreeing with a politician for no apparent reason? Have you ever thought why many people support a certain politician even though they hold a ‘foolish’ standpoint? Have you ever thought of how language influences people’s decisions in a political environment? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is true that humans are complex creatures and clear linear relationships rarely apply in the real world, language usage and perception undoubtedly plays a significant role in the world of politics, especially today where social factors such as gender and ethnicity are gaining more attention. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/how-politicians-use-language.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Have Been Called &#39;Laowai&#39;? Here&#39;s What it Means</title>
      <link>/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 08:56:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/culture/the-semantic-colour-of-the-chinese-word-laowai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Chinese, foreigners are often referred to as &amp;rsquo;laowai&amp;rsquo;, a term that carries different meanings depending on context and perception. In this article, we shed light on the social and cultural aspects of language use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single person may often be categorized and called in many different ways. I, for instance, may be categorized as ‘Iranian’, ‘Middle Eastern’, ‘brown’, etc. These separations and categorisations typically occur due to cultural differences between two or more groups. A common separation in China is that of a Chinese person and a foreigner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/Image-by-Collagist-from-pixabay.com_.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misgendering people: Identity and Gender Pronouns</title>
      <link>/culture/misgendering-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:50:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/culture/misgendering-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article does not intend to offend or devalue anyone with a non-binary gender identity. It only tries to explain why fixing misgendering is a larger problem than most people think, and why there is no immediate solution to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-misgendering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is misgendering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misgendering is the act of using language to describe or talk to a person in a manner that does not align with their affirmed gender, intentionally or unintentionally. This can be in the form of personal pronouns, such as referring to someone as a ‘he’ when they’re a woman or when they do not identify with the male gender, but also through the use of gender specific nouns such as ‘boy’ and ‘girl’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/3-1.jpg-1.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigrants: Language Acquisition and Education</title>
      <link>/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:02:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>aryan.yekrangi1</author>
      <guid>/global-issues/immigrants-language-acquisition-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that immigrants make up close to 15 percent of the US population. In other countries, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/daily-quotidien/171025/dq171025b-eng.htm&#34;&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blick.ch/news/schweiz/infografik-auslaender-in-zahlen-id7040362.html&#34;&gt;Switzerland,&lt;/a&gt; this number can even rise to 20 percent. Furthermore, language proficiency is an essential factor in immigrant and refugee integration. It’s also a crucial element in increasing job opportunities, as well as social and political participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why do some immigrants and refugees have a hard time integrating into society and what can be done about the current language education models?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="/images/7-1.jpg.webp" type="image/jpeg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
