<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Who on UN-aligned</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/tags/who/</link><description>Recent content in Who on UN-aligned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 05:42:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://un-aligned.org/tags/who/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UNICEF and WHO: Alarm over cholera outbreaks</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 05:42:12 +0200</pubDate><author>Elvira_Ineza</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/unicef-and-who-alarm-over-cholera-outbreaks/</guid><description>As Cholera outbreak spreads across 29 countries, UNICEF calls for 27.5 million to combat disease.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Cholera-case-management-training.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The WHO warns of pathogenic outbreaks threatening Africa</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/animal-rights/the-who-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-africa/</guid><description>The WHO regional director for Africa, Matshidiso Moeti, warned of a growing risk of pathogenic outbreaks on the continent, caused by human proximity to wild and domesticated animals.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-WHO-warns-of-pathogenic-outbreaks-threatening-Africa-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Is Mexico suing the United Nations?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/news/is-mexico-suing-the-united-nations/</guid><description>Mexico threatens to sue the UN following the WHO's failure to provide the country with covid vaccines.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/President-of-Mexico-Andres-Manuel-Lopez-Obrador.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>WHO? Yes, Tedros Again!</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 12:01:41 +0300</pubDate><author>Adrian Liberto</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/who-yes-tedros-again/</guid><description>Tedros Ghebreyesus gets re-elected by the World Health Assembly (WHA) to a second term despite his affiliation with the repressive regime that has been accused of torture, repression, and electoral fraud.</description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Tedros-Honey-Im-home.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>Letter to Zsuzsanna Jakab: Why is it so difficult for the WHO to take a non-political approach towards Taiwan?</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:55:01 +0300</pubDate><author>Ariana Yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/letters/letter-to-zsuzsanna-jakab/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dear Dr. Zsuzsanna Jakab, I am writing to you on behalf of UN-aligned, an international organisation that laid the foundations for an alternative United Nations, which aims to serve people, before nationstates. Although we regularly campaign for reforms to the United Nations, particularly with regards to its structure and principles, we are also involved with other issues, such as human rights, animal welfare and environmental protection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The coronavirus pandemic has become the defining global health crisis of our time and the greatest challenge we have faced since the Second World War. Since its emergence last year, the virus has spread to every continent. UN-aligned greatly admires the tireless work of the WHO and its dedication to catalysing global and national responses to this and other serious health crises. However, this pandemic has become more than an unprecedented tragedy. Recently we have received questions from our members about the relevance of the WHO’s principles and its ability to serve everyone, regardless of their country’s membership status in the United Nations. On behalf of our members we would therefore like to ask you the following questions:&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/zsuzsanna-jakab.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>My Traumatic Experience with Postpartum - An interview with Rahima El Harrak</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><author>rahimaelharrak</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;The period soon after childbirth poses substantial health risks for both mother and new-born infant. Yet the postpartum and postnatal period receives less attention from health care providers than pregnancy and childbirth. Models of postpartum and postnatal care have changed little since first developed a century ago. The World Health Organization (WHO) is in the process of revising and updating its guidance on postpartum and postnatal care delivered by skilled providers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/Social-Media-post-2-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"/></item><item><title>The Use of Chinese Medicine in Treating Covid-19</title><link>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate><author>aryan.yekrangi</author><guid>https://un-aligned.org/health/the-use-of-chinese-medicine-in-treating-covid-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>China is promoting the use of traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and has even donated traditional Chinese medicine to a handful of countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may all be in good will, however studies suggest that there are serious side effects to the use of traditional Chinese medicine. In a corrupt world where the responsible organizations, such as the World Health Organization (WHO), have such strong political bounds to governmental entities, such as the Chinese Communist Party, it becomes our duty, as members of the society, to inform others on such crucial matters, especially when it could be a matter of life and death such as this one.&lt;/p></description><enclosure url="https://un-aligned.org/images/The-Use-of-Chinese-Medicine-in-Treating-Covid-19-1.png" type="image/jpeg"/></item></channel></rss>