<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaza on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gaza/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaza on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gaza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘If it ain’t broke... break it’: How the US betrayed  free speech and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 14:41:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-the-us-betrayed-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;loving-guns-hating-free-speech&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loving guns, hating free speech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely amazing how the US government bows with such unquestioning fervour and reverence to the Second Amendment, while comfortably sticking its middle finger up to the First.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Second Amendment, ratified in 1791, in the heyday of the Wild West and almost 100 years before the iconic gunfight at the O.K. Corral (1881), stipulates “the right of the people to keep and bear Arms”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“We’ve seen this before”: Inside Israel’s war on truth, journalists and the free media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first casualty in any assault is invariably the truth. But what is it about journalists that tyrants find so terrifying? It is the fear of empowerment that comes with knowledge. Despots thrive in the shadows that ignorance casts, manipulating and controlling through a cocktail of misinformation and deceit. Yet, a journalist can spark a flame in our mind, capable of incinerating the very foundations of tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiding the truth is not merely the erratic behaviour of the paranoid or the despotically inclined; it is a clear indication of inherent weakness. A government that stands firm in its legitimacy and moral authority does not flinch at criticism nor recoil from dissent. It is the inherent brittleness of despotic rule that dreads the light of scrutiny, much like a rotten structure teetering on the verge of collapse at the merest prod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Embracing genocide’: How Iranian monarchists are championing Israel&#39;s deadly onslaught on Palestine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:55:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-iranian-monarchists-are-championing-israel-deadly-onslaught-on-palestine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you encounter the rare sight of individuals rallying in support of Israel&amp;rsquo;s actions in Gaza, your attention might be drawn to an unexpected symbol: a variant of the Iranian flag. This particular flag, adorned with the Lion and Sun against a backdrop of green, white and red, harks back to Iran&amp;rsquo;s monarchical past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ensign, displayed alongside Israel&amp;rsquo;s, hails from a time when monarchs reigned over Iran, now seized upon by a diverse array within the Iranian diaspora, particularly those championing freedom in Iran, which includes the monarchists also known as Pahlavis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking away from Gaza will not assuage our conscience; only action will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 08:27:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/looking-away-from-gaza-will-not-assuage-our-conscience-only-action-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just recently, amidst the clinking glasses and idle chatter of a social gathering, I ventured to pierce this bubble. I posed a question to my friends, seemingly simple yet laden with the weight of untold suffering, which asked for their thoughts on the current mass slaughter of Palestinians by Israel; an atrocity that enjoys, astonishingly, the tacit approval—if not outright support—of our governments. One friend, embodying the spirit of our age&amp;rsquo;s indifference, confessed to avoiding the subject altogether. The casual dismissal struck me—not for its rarity, but for its brazenness, as if the very act of engagement with such a grave matter was itself a burden too heavy to bear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of a charade: Israel&#39;s collapse under global condemnation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel is as good as finished. It has lost all credibility as a responsible nation in-the-making. From the onset its creation has depended on abusing superpowers, injustice and crime. It has been those three forces that have kept it enduring and spreading until now, while skilfully dodging every attempt to hold it to account, often by playing the victim. Despite the numerous massacres perpetrated along the way, something very different has happened now that has shaken its very foundations; mortally so: Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;No place for the politicisation of aid&#39;: Why the West&#39;s UNRWA fund cuts are nakedly political</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-the-wests-unrwa-fund-cuts-are-nakedly-political/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:38:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/why-the-wests-unrwa-fund-cuts-are-nakedly-political/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 27th of January, a day after Israel was ordered by the International Court of Justice to take all measures to prevent its genocidal acts in Gaza, Germany, Canada, the UK and six other Western nations joined the US in pausing funding for the UN Palestinian refugee agency (UNRWA). This decision followed Israel’s allegation that 12 UNRWA employees were involved in the October 7 Hamas terrorist attack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNRWA, a UN agency founded in 1949 by the UN General Assembly, responded by terminating the employment of the accused individuals and initiating a thorough investigation. Secretary-General António Guterres expressed his horror at the allegations, stating that those found guilty would face criminal prosecution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Council in Deadlock: The UN&#39;s Faltering Quest for Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst the United Nations bats resolutions from one side of the Security Council’s court to another, people are dying in their thousands. This is not the United Nations; this is the Disunited Nations, failing in its primary mission of fostering world peace. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, on October 16, a Russian-sponsored draft text, which had called for an immediate cease-fire, fell through because it did not manage to garner enough votes. Then, on October 18, the US vetoed a Brazilian draft that called for “humanitarian pauses” to allow unhindered humanitarian access. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bombing Civilian Areas &amp; Killing Children is Wrong. Even for Revenge, Especially for Revenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:54:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bombing-civilian-areas-and-killing-children-is-wrong-even-for-revenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grief and fury brew a potent concoction for vengeance in the hearts of those who have lost all. The cycle of violence spirals, each rotation taking it to a ghastly new level. Israeli officials, under the banner of ‘self-defence’, have adopted a scorched earth policy towards Gaza. Yet, the international community&amp;rsquo;s reaction often diverges sharply into one of two markedly distinct viewpoints: unflinching support for Israel and utter condemnation for Hamas, or justifying Hamas&amp;rsquo;s targeted killings as acts of legitimate resistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guterres publishes report about the lack of progress of UNSC Resolution 2334</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/guterres-publishes-report-about-the-lack-of-progress-of-unsc-resolution-2334/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 23, the Secretary General, António Guterres, published a report on the progress (or rather lack of it) of Security Council &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/webcast/pdfs/SRES2334-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;Resolution 2334&lt;/a&gt; (2016) which “reaffirmed that the establishment by Israel of settlements in the Palestinian territory occupied since 1967, including East Jerusalem, had no legal validity and constituted a flagrant violation under international law and a major obstacle to the achievement of the two-State solution and a just, lasting and comprehensive peace.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Led by extremists, bombed by extremists - Gaza in the midst of insanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/led-by-extremists-bombed-by-extremists-gaza-in-the-midst-of-insanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your past is in front of your eyes, it’s 2014, 2012 and 2008 all over again. You cannot escape it, visual reminders are scattered all over the city. Being bombed back to the middle ages seems to be a recurring theme in Gaza. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history concerning the Israel and Palestine conflict is complicated. What is not at all complicated, however, is whether or not it is admissible to airstrike civilian areas, news buildings, health facilities or Covid labs. Whether or not it is acceptable to take away life should not be a controversial issue, one would hope. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surviving the victory: life in the war-torn Gaza Strip - in Pictures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 07:45:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/gallery/surviving-the-victory-life-in-the-war-torn-gaza-strip-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/10-Gaza-1024x678.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Al-Shati camp/Beach camp. At least 10 people, including 8 children, were killed in the bombardment of the Al-Shati refugee camp during the May 2021 conflict. Photo by Magne Hagesæter / CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/9-Gaza-1024x683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11 year old Manar and her friends at their damaged school in Gaza. Manar and her family´s house was destroyed during the 2014 Gaza War. After losing her home, Manar hopes to find happiness in her school. Photo by Anas al Baba/Oxfam / CC BY-NC-ND 2.0&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
