<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding conspiracy theories and its victims in the golden age of nonsense</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:14:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-conspiracy-theories-and-its-victims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guarded by some 25 000 troops, Joe Biden successfully took the oath of office. Earlier Mr Ex-President had taken off for Mar-a-Lago. Hopes and dreams were shattered. I felt a rush of compassion for the QAnon believers who felt betrayed realising that nothing happened; no arrests, no intervention. It is bitter to realise that the firm ground below one’s feet has collapsed. The liberating, newly revealed truth turned out to be yet another lie. Yet, the question remains: What were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Traumatic Experience with Postpartum - An interview with Rahima El Harrak</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/health/postpartum-a-personal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The period soon after childbirth poses substantial health risks for both mother and new-born infant. Yet the postpartum and postnatal period receives less attention from health care providers than pregnancy and childbirth. Models of postpartum and postnatal care have changed little since first developed a century ago. The World Health Organization (WHO) is in the process of revising and updating its guidance on postpartum and postnatal care delivered by skilled providers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here is What Social Psychology Say About Prejudice &amp; Discrimination</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 08:49:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/human-rights/social-psychology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rotests and clashes have spread across the US after the death of African-American George Floyd on May 25th 2020, in police custody. Frustration over the deaths of African-Americans at the hands of police was already rising over the recent deaths of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52623151&#34;&gt;Ahmaud Arbery&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/article/breonna-taylor-police.html&#34;&gt;Breonna Taylor&lt;/a&gt;. These terrible events are only a few examples among the many of conflicts rooted in false judgement, prejudice and discrimination.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article presents prejudice and discrimination from the perspective of social psychology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:56:33 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/global-issues/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why some of us choose to set up life in a new country. The prospect offers numerous benefits, such as satisfying a yearning for exploration, self-improvement or a higher standard of living.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Living abroad is undoubtedly a highly enriching experience, it broadens your mind and provides exposure to different ways of life; it offers a more immersive language learning opportunity and your self-sufficiency will come to know no bounds as a result of having to jump through strange and complex bureaucratic hoops in a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
