<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unsc on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/unsc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unsc on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/unsc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Council in Deadlock: The UN&#39;s Faltering Quest for Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/united-nation-faltering-quest-for-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whilst the United Nations bats resolutions from one side of the Security Council’s court to another, people are dying in their thousands. This is not the United Nations; this is the Disunited Nations, failing in its primary mission of fostering world peace. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, on October 16, a Russian-sponsored draft text, which had called for an immediate cease-fire, fell through because it did not manage to garner enough votes. Then, on October 18, the US vetoed a Brazilian draft that called for “humanitarian pauses” to allow unhindered humanitarian access. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 22, 2023, Riyad H. Mansour, the Palestinian-American diplomat who has been the Permanent Observer of Palestine to the United Nations since 2005, wrote a letter, his 794th, to the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was triggered by the recent atrocities in Jenin. The letter, addressed to the Secretary-General, the President of the General Assembly and the President of the Security Council, highlighted the crimes committed by Israel against the Palestinian people. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;24 Years of Missed Opportunities&#39;: How the UN Failed to Secure Peace in the DRC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:28:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 7th, 2023, after an extensive visit and tour of the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), senior UN official Jean-Pierre Lacroix spoke to reporters in the country’s capital, Kinshasa. The line of questioning was centered entirely around the UN’s 24-year long peacekeeping mission, known as MONUSCO. His response to these questions was brief, yet it made headlines globally: the peacekeepers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rfi.fr/en/africa/20230609-un-peacekeeping-mission-in-drc-is-to-withdraw-as-quickly-as-possible&#34;&gt;should withdraw&lt;/a&gt; from the conflict-torn country “as quickly as possible”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Scenarios of Russia’s Removal from the UN Security Council: A Bleak Future or a Chance for a Fresh Start?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 08:23:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-3-scenarios-of-russias-removal-from-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russia’s permanent seat on the UN Security Council is under scrutiny like never. What would happen if the UN decided to expel this rogue state from the Security Council? Will it lead to war, polarisation, or perhaps a new beginning for the UN?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About a year ago now, on 7 April 2022, the UN General Assembly adopted a resolution triggering the suspension of Russia from the Human Rights Council. Oh, would it not be lovely if it could also be suspended from its status as a permanent member of the Security Council! But first things first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Solutions to Overhaul the United Nations Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/6-solutions-to-overhaul-the-united-nations-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/6-solutions-to-overhaul-the-united-nations-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Security Council (UNSC) is in desperate need of reform. Its current structure and its voting system have failed to effectively address global conflicts and address the needs of its member states.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The council, made up of 15 members, including the five permanent members or P5 (China, France, Russia, the United Kingdom and the United States) who hold unbridled veto power, has remained largely unchanged since its creation in 1945.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Permanent Continental Members at the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-permanent-continental-members-at-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-permanent-continental-members-at-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest impediment to world peace is the United Nations Security Council itself. This is felt by the power of the mighty veto held by each of the five permanent members.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The image of the Security Council is that of a &amp;ldquo;club of superpowers&amp;rdquo; each prioritising its own national interests over the other. In the rule of the jungle, realities of realpolitik assume total precedence where &amp;ldquo;might is right decision theory&amp;rdquo; rules supremely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council: Differences over Haiti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/un-security-council-differences-over-haiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many international organisations have warned about the worsening situation in Haiti, but some members of the United Nations were set on keeping the aid package to Haiti strictly humanitarian stating that they would let the Haitians solve their own political issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in the face of the growing threat to peace and security due to gang-related violence, hunger and an infrastructure crisis caused by several natural disasters, as well as the lack of proper medical equipment and personnel in response to the needs of the Haitian population amid several health emergencies such as the cholera outbreak, on October 21, 2022, the UN Security Council unanimously voted to establish a sanctions regime on Haiti to punish the actors responsible or complicit in actions that threaten peace, security, and financial stability in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia booted out of the UN Human Rights Council. What&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/will-russia-be-kicked-off-the-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to its charter, the UN was created to maintain international peace and security, protect human rights, deliver humanitarian aid, and support sustainable development. Each of these is an honourable goal that is sometimes brought to fruition in parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;193 countries around the globe are members of the United Nations and among those are the P5 (permanent Security Council Members) chosen because of their importance in the aftermath of WWII. Each one of these countries is part of the UN because they claim to believe in what this organisation stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eradicate colonialism by 2030? Unlikely.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/clinging-on-to-colonialism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 21st of June the United Nations General Assembly started publishing a number of draft resolutions calling on the colonial powers to relinquish their control on the few remaining colonies. The UN states that its target is to eradicate colonialism by 2030. To date, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/dppa/decolonization/en/nsgt&#34;&gt;17 non-self-governing territories&lt;/a&gt; remain. Of these, fifteen are governed by permanent members of the Security Council:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 by the UK,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 by the US and;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 by France.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list does not include occupied territories, such as Palestine, the Chagos Archipelago and Crimea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Powerful Panacea? The Sanctions Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:07:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-sanctions-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Italiano_-Il-dilemma-delle-sanzioni.pdf&#34;&gt;Read this article in Italian (Leggi questo articolo in italiano) →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yesterday, upon the stair,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I met a man who wasn&amp;rsquo;t there!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t there again today,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Oh how I wish he&amp;rsquo;d go away!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above quote from Hughes Mearns’ poem, &lt;em&gt;Antigonish&lt;/em&gt;, could so easily allude to sanctions. They are full of sound and fury, and yet, they signify nothing concrete, but rather an absence of something. Of course, sometimes, a lack of something can have devastating effects: if you stop my air supply, for instance, I am dead. Sanctions, however, are very limited in what they can stop, because what comes from outside one’s borders was not there in the first place, like the man upon the stair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
