<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inside Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/inside-gordian-magazine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inside Gordian Magazine on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:30:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/inside-gordian-magazine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Global Constitution: The New Social Contract Inside the October Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/global-constitution-the-new-social-contract-inside-the-october-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As October’s chill sets in, ‘The Gordian’ returns from its brief hiatus with a meticulously curated issue titled ‘Global Constitution: The New Social Contract.’ This edition seeks to weave together the intricate threads of geopolitics, art, culture, and science, presenting a cohesive narrative of our shared global destiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In ‘&lt;em&gt;The Imagined Unity&lt;/em&gt;: Understanding Nations, Nationalism and Their Bedrock,’ Alexander Stoney offers an exploration of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/nations-nationalism-and-their-bedrock/&#34;&gt;nuanced concept of ‘Nation’.&lt;/a&gt; This sets the stage for Adrian Liberto’s discourse on the pressing need for a global constitution in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/&#34;&gt;‘&lt;em&gt;The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it&lt;/em&gt;.’&lt;/a&gt; Liberto subsequently scrutinises the UN’s role in the Palestinian crisis in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/un-in-focus/palestine-and-794-letters-to-unsc/&#34;&gt;‘Palestine and the UN: Will this 794th letter jolt the Security Council into action?’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dismantling the war machine: Inside the October Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-gordian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-gordian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gordian rolls on with its messages of peace and light and respect, but notwithstanding, the world seems to be getting darker and more troubled. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Climate disasters are no longer the exception, while the threat of a nuclear apocalypse is more real than it ever has been. Giving in is not an option. On the contrary we must double our efforts to combat all that is a threat to the dignity and wellbeing of humanity and the survival of earth’s multifaceted manifestations of nature. Being marginally involved with organisations like UN-aligned is no longer enough. Each and every one of us needs to do more, both as individuals and as part of our communities, be they local, or global like UN-aligned. For want of a nail the shoe was lost… then the horse, the rider, the message, the battle and finally, the kingdom. We are that nail, but we have been led to believe that our input is insignificant. It isn’t. So The Gordian will continue to roll on with your support and inspiration: a platform for the sharing of ideas and information and a launchpad for exiting ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU and Justice: Inside the July Gordian Magazine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 10:09:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inside-gordian-magazine/inside-the-july-gordian-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the July 2022 issue of The Gordian. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was obvious to most that civilisation shall have had to deal with far more than a war of aggression after one of Putin’s casual malign interferences around the world morphed into an unscrupulous war in &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/tag/ukraine/&#34;&gt;Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. A social and economic crisis was, perhaps, expected. Four months on, however it is clear that we are heading towards far worse: an orgy of human rights violations spearheaded by unsavoury governments and bureaucrats who are supposed to protect the rule of law and human dignity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
