<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CristinaMihailescu on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/authors/cristinamihailescu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CristinaMihailescu on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/authors/cristinamihailescu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s London through the eyes of an old Communist hag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/2022-london-through-the-eyes-of-an-old-communist-hag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/2022-london-through-the-eyes-of-an-old-communist-hag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communism forbade any dreams of travelling abroad. Apart from going to some other communist countries nearby, one couldn’t imagine any trip to Europe unless they belonged to the upper echelon of the Party. My parents did not belong to the Party at all- minor intellectuals could escape such honour, since they were neither the praised workforce nor dangerous through their profession. I also managed to avoid becoming a member of the Romanian Communist Party, but only for a couple of years - and then in 1989 the Revolution came and many things changed. For me, the most important achievements were the freedom of speech and the fact that my dream of travelling across the borders could finally become true.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romania Always Welcomes Ukrainian Refugees: Support and Opportunities Await</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 10:06:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/ukrainians-romania-is-alway-open-to-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few days since Romanians stopped wearing masks. Literally speaking, we have finally been told that such protection is no longer necessary, even though the hospitals are still full of sick people. The pandemic is not over, but a greater evil has appeared at the borders of our country, an evil we would hopefully never meet face to face: war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terrible as it sounds and can be felt in the images broadcast 24 hours a day on all the TV stations, the war in the neighbouring country has produced an unprecedented, totally unexpected outcome: Romanians stopped wearing masks in their daily lives and started showing their true colours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
