<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Solutions With Omar on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/new-solutions-with-omar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Solutions With Omar on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 18:11:40 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/new-solutions-with-omar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Trumpian Flirtations with Total Denuclearization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 18:11:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/beyond-trumpian-flirtations-with-total-denuclearization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is Donald Trump to be taken seriously when openly speaking of denuclearization? The Center for Public Integrity reported in an article from 2020 on the future of warfare that the nuclear weapons industry under Trump&amp;rsquo;s first term flourished to heights not seen since before the end of the Cold War. He effectively catapulted an aggressive nuclear rearming of America at an estimated 1.7 trillion-dollar cost to the American taxpayer. Despite the massive cost, politicians like Republican Senator Deb Fischer argued that the nuclear rearming of America in a multipolar world is to be considered an essential but not sufficient national security imperative, implying the 1.7 trillion-dollar price tag for the nuclear rearming of America is substantively insufficient. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revitalising Global Engagement: The Case for a United Nations Peace Corps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-a-united-nations-peace-corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:53:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-a-united-nations-peace-corps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United Nations is as much an organisation of ironies as it is of stark contradictions. This is particularly true when comparing geopolitical power differentials between the global North and South. It is therefore unsurprising that the annual budgetary contributions of United Nations member states are calculated using strictly the US dollar. Based on details from the New York-based Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), an article on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/article/funding-united-nations-what-impact-do-us-contributions-have-un-agencies-and-programs&#34;&gt;American subsidisation of the United Nations&lt;/a&gt; revealed that one-fifth of the world&amp;rsquo;s premier supranational organisation is directly subsidised by the United States, to the tune of $12 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Peacekeeping: The Case for a United Nations Corps of Peacekeeping Engineers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/redefining-peacekeeping-the-case-for-a-united-nations-corps-of-peacekeeping-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/redefining-peacekeeping-the-case-for-a-united-nations-corps-of-peacekeeping-engineers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Civilisation cannot be achieved without modern infrastructure. In one way or another, there will always be infrastructural failures impacting the development of nations. Can one nation have too much infrastructure? How do nations overbuild themselves to points of sprawling ostentation? The image of the United Nations peacekeeper is routinely overshadowed with powerlessness and melancholic despair.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their purpose is to keep the peace under shaky truces prolonging geopolitical stalemates as things in society go from bad to worse in failed state realities. UN peacekeepers are not builders. They are placeholders with little to no power to influence the restoration of peace. Is it possible to &amp;ldquo;civilianised&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; military power for peaceful purposes in conflict zones steeped in crises?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Nuclear Deterrence: Geopolitical Bravado or Our Obligation Towards Peace?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:38:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/rethinking-nuclear-deterrence-geopolitical-bravado-or-our-obligation-towards-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuclear-threats-past-and-present&#34;&gt;Nuclear Threats: Past and Present&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every historical curiosity is borne out of a rhetorical question that challenges the accepted narratives of the past. The history we are taught is often presented as simplified stories with humanity at the existential core. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet, history is actually moulded by successive generations. With Vladimir Putin ordering Russia&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Rocket Forces to perform battle readiness drills with live nuclear weapons on Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s border, the spectre of nuclear war has returned in a starkly real manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bots for a Demining Peace Initiative: The Path Towards a World Free of Landmines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bots-for-a-demining-peace-initiative-the-path-towards-a-world-free-of-landmines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/bots-for-a-demining-peace-initiative-the-path-towards-a-world-free-of-landmines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Could the development of robots capable of demining, ensure that peace is within reach for regions recovering from or living through conflict?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest escapes for children growing up against the backdrop of war and famine is in their creative imaginations. The power of pretend is brilliantly articulated by children in games where they explore and adventure in the unforgiving rubble and debris of their war-torn communities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine, a child wanders to the outskirts of town kicking stone pebbles in between barbed wiring, intermittingly dispersed in a seemingly unsuspecting demarcation area alluding to some kind of Neverland. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Peace and Heritage: Converting Woodrow Wilson&#39;s Vision into a UN World Park Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/preserving-peace-and-heritage-converting-woodrow-wilsons-vision-into-a-un-world-park-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:07:19 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/preserving-peace-and-heritage-converting-woodrow-wilsons-vision-into-a-un-world-park-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Could Wilson&amp;rsquo;s vision for the US National Park Service inspire a UN World Park Service? This global agency, dedicated to preserving ecological and historic sites, could promote international cooperation, environmental conservation, and the collective appreciation of our cultural heritage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-internationalism-with-wilsonian-idealism&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern Internationalism with Wilsonian Idealism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Woodrow Wilson left behind a legacy of would-be idealism most aptly characterised by his Fourteen Points speech he delivered before the United States Congress on January 8th, 1918. The end of World War I would arrive ten months later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New International Man: Can World Federalism Overcome Nationalism?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-new-international-man-can-world-federalism-overcome-nationalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an old millennial having experienced childhood in the nineties, my generation grew up with the quintessential strongmen movies personified in protagonists like Rocky Balboa, Ivan Drago and Apollo Creed, as seen in the Rocky franchise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Rocky 4, Dolph Lundgren portrayed a rather intimidating antihero; an opponent more machine than man. My generation remembers a world before it was possible to Google our curiosities away into the ether of the internet. Exposure to the world in terms of different cultures, languages and ways of life was primarily derived from movies like Rocky 4. Ivan Drago, Rocky&amp;rsquo;s deadly opponent having killed Apollo Creed in the boxing ring, seemingly revisited the literal definition of the New Soviet Man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Permanent Continental Members at the UN Security Council</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-permanent-continental-members-at-the-un-security-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-case-for-permanent-continental-members-at-the-un-security-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest impediment to world peace is the United Nations Security Council itself. This is felt by the power of the mighty veto held by each of the five permanent members.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The image of the Security Council is that of a &amp;ldquo;club of superpowers&amp;rdquo; each prioritising its own national interests over the other. In the rule of the jungle, realities of realpolitik assume total precedence where &amp;ldquo;might is right decision theory&amp;rdquo; rules supremely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the United Nations Parliamentary Assembly Address Failed State Realities?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/can-the-united-nations-parliamentary-assembly-address-failed-state-realities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What can the movement for a United Nations Parliamentary Assembly takeaway from the World Development Index? According to the United Nations Surviving on Pennies Global Awareness Initiative, 1 billion people live on $1.00 daily. We have been trained to localize the concept of gross domestic product by national classification, but on average, how widely considered as the world&amp;rsquo;s gross domestic product per capita?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of 2021, Macrotrends reported &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrotrends.net/countries/WLD/world/gdp-gross-domestic-product&#34;&gt;the world GDP&lt;/a&gt; at a meager $11,407 (per capita), less than what the United States Assistant Office of Planning &amp;amp; Evaluation identified as poverty for one person at $12,880 for the same year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demilitarising the Manipulable Atom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/demilitarising-the-manipulable-atom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When World War One broke out, one of the founding fathers of modern science fiction, H.G. Wells, popularised the &amp;ldquo;war to end all wars&amp;rdquo; antiwar euphemism while trenches were dug on the Western front as British, French and German militaries mobilised for war. That same euphemism is often adopted and overused by aggressive unilateralists bent on justifying wanton militarism in pursuit of lopsided geopolitical objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Wells juxtaposed as the seminal foundation for a future liberated from the scourge of war, the Serbian American inventor Nikola Tesla fashioned in the form of a &amp;ldquo;death ray&amp;rdquo; to deny the possibility of war by vaporising invading militaries with &amp;ldquo;national energy shields&amp;rdquo; powered by alternating current. If history has proved anything, it is that war is one of man&amp;rsquo;s seminal preoccupations. War colleges churning out young military officers would have us believe wars are justifiable if waged to restore order to a Westphalian international balance of power system to make world peace possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the World Atomic Weapons Disarmament Agency (WAWDA) and why do we need it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-need-for-a-world-atomic-weapons-disarmament-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/the-need-for-a-world-atomic-weapons-disarmament-agency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Atomic Energy Agency was established on July 29th, 1957, to relegate atomic energy exploits for peaceful purposes. The idea was to deny the militarization of atomic weapons, but how successful has the same agency been in working toward a future free of nuclear weapons?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Russia&amp;rsquo;s unilateralist war in Ukraine was a rude awakening as fears of nuclear war returned to the public discourse. Unfortunately, we live in a reality where not every concerned world citizen is also a world federalist. This is most evident in national societies inhibited by limited free assembly. In controlled societies where official state discourse assumes supreme precedence over the individual discourse of citizens, disconnects in communicating the mission of world federalism will remain a tremendous challenge for global audiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The need for an International Anti-Corruption Court (IACC) is greater than ever before</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-need-for-an-international-anti-corruption-court-is-greater-than-ever-before/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the law of the jungle, kleptocracies are shielded by plutocracies. The latter keeps the former in power. A reality all too familiar in a world dominated by the black and white absolutisms of realpolitik. It is for this reason that geopolitical power alliances currently assume complete precedence over the rule of international law. Dictatorial regimes almost always double up as localised kleptocracies. They serve as the ultimate fodder for competing foreign policy interests allowing world powers to act unilaterally outside the purview of international law. Such exchanges are all too typical of fledgling geopolitical arenas in the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
