<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Long Read on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/long-read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Long Read on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/long-read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“We’ve seen this before”: Inside Israel’s war on truth, journalists and the free media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first casualty in any assault is invariably the truth. But what is it about journalists that tyrants find so terrifying? It is the fear of empowerment that comes with knowledge. Despots thrive in the shadows that ignorance casts, manipulating and controlling through a cocktail of misinformation and deceit. Yet, a journalist can spark a flame in our mind, capable of incinerating the very foundations of tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiding the truth is not merely the erratic behaviour of the paranoid or the despotically inclined; it is a clear indication of inherent weakness. A government that stands firm in its legitimacy and moral authority does not flinch at criticism nor recoil from dissent. It is the inherent brittleness of despotic rule that dreads the light of scrutiny, much like a rotten structure teetering on the verge of collapse at the merest prod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of a charade: Israel&#39;s collapse under global condemnation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:35:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/israels-collapse-under-global-condemnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel is as good as finished. It has lost all credibility as a responsible nation in-the-making. From the onset its creation has depended on abusing superpowers, injustice and crime. It has been those three forces that have kept it enduring and spreading until now, while skilfully dodging every attempt to hold it to account, often by playing the victim. Despite the numerous massacres perpetrated along the way, something very different has happened now that has shaken its very foundations; mortally so: Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is UK&#39;s North Sea Drilling Plan a Sustainable Solution? An Impact Assessment Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/climate-emergency/uk-north-sea-drilling-impact-assessment-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-findings&#34;&gt;Key findings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UK&amp;rsquo;s proposed drilling plan has minimal immediate impact on energy security, offering only short-term reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With sustainable energy advancements, extensive reliance on fossil fuels is becoming obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan&amp;rsquo;s short-term financial benefits are economically short-sighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investing in a net-zero economy and green jobs is more beneficial for long-term economic growth and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drilling plan could harm climate commitments and marine biodiversity in the North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shift to renewable energy and green bond financing is advised, echoing global body recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frail and Ambiguous Words: How Diplomacy Hinders Peace in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/how-diplomacy-hinders-peace-in-gaza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words are more than mere vessels of communication; they are potent instruments that can alter the course of history. The recent debate at the United Nations Security Council (UNSC), which centred on the choice between ‘cessation’ and ‘suspension’ of hostilities in Gaza, starkly illustrates this power. This debate, far from being a mere matter of semantics, carries profound implications, particularly in terms of human lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As diplomats at the UNSC convened hours before a pivotal vote, they found themselves at a crossroads, their negotiations reaching a fever pitch. The United States, challenging the use of ‘cessation of hostilities’ in &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.un.org/en/story/2023/12/1144937&#34;&gt;the draft resolution&lt;/a&gt;, sparked intense diplomatic manoeuvring. The suggested alternative, ‘suspension of hostilities,’ while not finalised, opened a veritable Pandora’s box.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Headlines: India&#39;s Rising Power, Lingering Poverty and the Quest for Balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/india-rising-power-lingering-poverty-and-the-quest-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India has certainly been in the spotlight these last few months and anyone not looking too closely would be justified in thinking that the country was rising, phoenix-like, from its post-colonial ashes to virtual super power status. In April 2023 it overtook China as the most populous nation on Earth with well over 1.4 billion people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 4, Rahul Gandhi, champion of the Congress Party and heir to the Nehru-Gandhi dynasty, had his two-year prison sentence for disparaging comments made against Modi, suspended by India’s supreme court, suggesting a robust democratic rule of law. Also in August (23rd), India’s Chandrayaan-3 spacecraft landed on the lunar surface. This was all the more spectacular coming so soon after Russia’s failed moon mission. Moreover, it was the very first successful landing on the dark side of the moon. Then, in September, with much pomp and circumstance, India hosted the 2023 G20 Summit. Its presidency may not have been a roaring success, but it was a success nonetheless. Though Russia’s President Vladimir Putin and China’s Xi Jinping did not attend, and organisers had to forego the traditional “family” photo owing to disagreements over Ukraine, the overall outcome was positive, with the African Union’s addition to the block being one of this G20’s notable achievements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Table Tennis to the UN: How Kosovo Used Sports for Nation Building</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:02:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/from-table-tennis-to-the-un-kosovos-sport-driven-nation-building/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never before has the nexus between sport and international relations been more prominent than in the last 10 years. Even a cursory examination of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most publicised sporting events from the last decade reveals a clear link between the games and athletes we love to watch and money, power, and strategic international diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports-events-reflect-on-a-nations-best-and-worst&#34;&gt;Sports events reflect on a nations&amp;rsquo; best and worst&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, Brazil hosted the FIFA World Cup, aiming to exhibit the beauty and rich culture of Brazil. However, the exciting football was overshadowed by extreme poverty; the inequality highlighted by the slums of Rio de Janeiro and the displacement of thousands to accommodate new stadiums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tibet&#39;s Peaceful Nation-Building Challenges Chinese Rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/country-profile/how-tibets-peaceful-nation-building-challenges-chinese-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shrouded in the mystique of the high Himalayas, Tibet presents a realm of stark duality. Its tranquil scenery and the hallowed quietude of temples whisper tales of deep-rooted spirituality. Yet, beneath this cloak of tranquillity, a spirited narrative of national identity and governance grapples with forces of external influence and internal doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story of Tibet is not solely one of idle meditation; it is equally about active engagement in the arduous task of nation-building. Here, the Dalai Lama stands not only as a spiritual zenith but also as a symbol of the unyielding campaign for cultural and political self-determination. This is a journey into the heart of an aspiring nation, where the pursuit of peace is as much an internal journey as it is a political quest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;24 Years of Missed Opportunities&#39;: How the UN Failed to Secure Peace in the DRC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:28:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/un-in-focus/how-the-un-failed-to-secure-peace-in-the-drc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On June 7th, 2023, after an extensive visit and tour of the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), senior UN official Jean-Pierre Lacroix spoke to reporters in the country’s capital, Kinshasa. The line of questioning was centered entirely around the UN’s 24-year long peacekeeping mission, known as MONUSCO. His response to these questions was brief, yet it made headlines globally: the peacekeepers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rfi.fr/en/africa/20230609-un-peacekeeping-mission-in-drc-is-to-withdraw-as-quickly-as-possible&#34;&gt;should withdraw&lt;/a&gt; from the conflict-torn country “as quickly as possible”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Constitution: And Why we Need it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:27:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-global-constitution-and-why-we-need-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaac Newton famously said: “If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.” Sadly, society is where it is today because most people have stood on the shoulders of ogres. The past sticks to us like shit on a shoe and we have become so accustomed to the foul smell, that rather than scrape off the dung, we wallow in it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picture this: planet earth in the 21st century, but one that had never witnessed the advent of humankind. Then, suddenly, it is discovered by an alien species much like our own. Before long, the planet is plundered, ravaged and abused. Life forms are enslaved, tortured and killed for entertainment, fashion and culinary delights, their habitats destroyed; forests are cut down; and rivers and seas polluted beyond recognition, as are the skies. Finally, having exhausted every possible resource, the alien species moves on, like a plague of locusts, to its next quarry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Poetry After WWII: The Rise and Evolution of Post-War Literature in The UK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/english-poetry-after-world-war-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-war-english-literature&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-War English Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have already seen while analysing the literary background of previous periods, the literature of each historical age often reflected the political and social situation of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post World War II literature was no different. Those terrible years of violence and devastation created a sense of general pessimism, cynicism and disillusionment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Literature after the Second World War clearly portrayed man&amp;rsquo;s disorientation, which was not only evident in the content of literary works but also characterised by the absence of one specific major school of thought or movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Corrupt to the Bone’: The Pursuit of Transparency in a Corrupt World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-pursuit-of-transparency-in-a-corrupt-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:15:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/the-pursuit-of-transparency-in-a-corrupt-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Corruption is paid by the poor,&amp;rdquo; warns Pope Francis, highlighting an unsettling reality: those least able to afford it, endure corruption&amp;rsquo;s harshest consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The publication of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transparency.org/en/cpi/2022&#34;&gt;Corruption Perceptions Index&lt;/a&gt; 2022 (CPI), which uses a scale from 0 (highly corrupt) to 100 (very clean), has shed light on the efforts taken by policymakers to combat corruption in different countries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The report indicates that out of the 180 countries assessed, 124 have made no progress in fighting corruption across any levels. This staggering statistic underscores the severity and pervasiveness of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Love for Erdogan&#39;s Autocracy in the Heart of German Democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-love-for-erdogans-autocracy-in-the-heart-of-german-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recep Tayyip Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s name echoes in Istanbul and Berlin alike. As Turkey&amp;rsquo;s President, he commands attention and drives conversation in both these distinct locales, exerting an influence that, to many observers, seems paradoxical. Despite being in the heart of Europe, where democracy is a foundational value, Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s autocratic approach finds a surprisingly receptive audience within a substantial German-Turkish community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Erdogan&amp;rsquo;s influence over this diaspora often equals, and at times even outstrips, his hold over his own nation, a conundrum that pushes against traditional ideas about the strength of democracy. But how can an autocratic leader secure such steadfast loyalty from a community residing in one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most solid democracies?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Arizona&#39;s Hostile Stance Towards Immigrants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/the-hidden-costs-of-arizonas-hostile-stance-towards-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The state of Arizona has been a hotspot for immigrants for many years. The US state, which shares about 600 km of border with Mexico, has become a popular destination for refugees and migrants who escape their homes searching for a better and safer life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While some advocate for mass deportations of these ‘illegal immigrants’, others argue for faster processing and greater protections for those seeking asylum or other forms of humanitarian assistance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Transcending the Moon, a Democratic Encounter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 06:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/utopian-ideas/transcending-the-moon-a-democratic-encounter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this story, we postulate an interview with the representative of a more advanced civilisation; and within this setting, novel visions are juxtaposed to some of our pressing problems. &lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/global-issues/conversations-with-the-dengilauns/&#34;&gt;Learn more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could scarcely believe that I was about to embark on such a venture. The prospect of meeting an otherworldly being – a genuine extraterrestrial – was almost too fantastic to contemplate. And not just any alien, mind you, but the Dengilaun ambassador to our very own Moon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dante Alighieri&#39;s Vision for World Government: The Pathway to Abolishing War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 07:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/culture/dante-alighieris-vision-for-world-government-the-pathway-to-abolishing-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dante&amp;rsquo;s death 700 years ago marked the end of an era. But his lasting legacy may be his vision for a world government, outlined in his work De Monarchia. Written in 1313, this work may be the first literature to present a comprehensive solution to the problem of war.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to imagine any sort of connection between the Russian invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022, and something that occurred in an unremarkable bedroom in Italy almost exactly 700 years prior. It has nothing whatsoever to do with the deep historical connections between Russia and Ukraine, at many times one and the same state, during the preceding seven centuries. But last autumn marked the 700th anniversary of the death of the great Italian poet Dante Alighieri, from malaria, in Ravenna, on September 14, 1321. His bones lie there still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USA vs Canada: A history of residential schools in North America</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/residential-schools-in-canada-and-the-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:05:00 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/residential-schools-in-canada-and-the-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uncovering-of-mass-graves-in-canada-and-the-united-states&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Uncovering of Mass Graves in Canada and the United States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/The-Uncovering-of-Mass-Graves-in-Canada-and-the-United-States-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kamloops Indian Residential School classroom building&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A classroom building of Kamloops Indian Residential School, Kamloops, British Columbia during the 1950. &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&#34;&gt;© CC 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In May 2021, 215 bodies of children were found buried on Kamloops Indian Residential School grounds in Kamloops, British Columbia, Canada. Following the incident, the US Interior Department began their investigation of US schools and uncovered over nine graves of indigenous children at the Carlisle Indian Industrial school in Carlisle, Pennsylvania, United States. What followed since has brought forth to the colonist public’s attention the systemic destruction of indigenous communities, cultures, and peoples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
