<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journalism on UN-aligned</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/journalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journalism on UN-aligned</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:52:52 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/journalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua’s War on the Press: New Report Highlights Escalating Repression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:52:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/nicaraguas-war-on-the-press-new-report-highlights-escalating-repression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN-aligned recently partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fled.ong/&#34;&gt;FLED Nicaragua&lt;/a&gt; to translate their annual report from Spanish into English, highlighting the grave state of press freedom in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assassination of retired Nicaraguan army officer and outspoken critic of President Daniel Ortega, Roberto Samcam, on June 19 while in exile in Costa Rica, underscores the urgency of the crisis and the critical need to raise international awareness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://un-aligned.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Press-Freedom-Report-January%E2%80%93March-2025-%E2%80%93-Copy.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read full report -&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“We’ve seen this before”: Inside Israel’s war on truth, journalists and the free media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 09:17:12 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/human-rights/inside-israels-war-on-truth-journalists-and-the-free-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first casualty in any assault is invariably the truth. But what is it about journalists that tyrants find so terrifying? It is the fear of empowerment that comes with knowledge. Despots thrive in the shadows that ignorance casts, manipulating and controlling through a cocktail of misinformation and deceit. Yet, a journalist can spark a flame in our mind, capable of incinerating the very foundations of tyranny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hiding the truth is not merely the erratic behaviour of the paranoid or the despotically inclined; it is a clear indication of inherent weakness. A government that stands firm in its legitimacy and moral authority does not flinch at criticism nor recoil from dissent. It is the inherent brittleness of despotic rule that dreads the light of scrutiny, much like a rotten structure teetering on the verge of collapse at the merest prod.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Julia Hartley-Brewer&#39;s racism is a common reality for brown man - I know, having experienced it firsthand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 18:48:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/comments/julia-hartley-brewers-racism-is-a-common-reality-for-brown-man-i-know-having-experienced-it-firsthand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the backseat of a taxi, a simple chat took a jarring turn, plunging me into a story that is all too common yet often goes untold. My goal was straightforward: to land a full-time role at a publishing house. However, what unfolded was an unexpected confrontation with racial and sexist prejudices — an incident that, though personal, reflects a broader issue pervasive in our workspaces and media today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journey reached a pivotal moment at the end-of-year company dinner party, a gathering that marked the culmination of a challenging yet rewarding internship. Having broached the subject of future prospects with my immediate male supervisor during training and discussed my aspirations with colleagues, I felt cautiously optimistic. However, the evening took an unforeseen turn on the ride home, sharing a taxi with a female supervisor who was less often seen during office hours. Her reaction to my shared ambitions was not of encouragement or guidance but one of anger and insinuation. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Subtle Manipulation of News Media in the Age of Pseudo-Enlightenment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/global-issues/understanding-the-subtle-manipulation-of-news-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-the-sun-wot-won-it&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the Sun wot won it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The older generation may remember it well. It was 11 April, 1992. Neil Kinnock and his Labour Party were set to win the general election and the best the Conservatives could have hoped for was a hung parliament. Then, however, The Sun, one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s right wing tabloid newspapers owned by Australian-American media mogul Rupert Murdoch, launched an aggressive campaign to swing things around&amp;hellip; and sure enough it did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
